<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1201.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1201.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1201_03">
        <akn:num>38-1201.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Trustees” means the Board of Trustees established under subchapter II of this unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Chief Executive Officer” means the chief executive and administrative officer of the University.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “University” means the University of the District of Columbia authorized and directed to be established under subchapter II of this unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “academic and administrative head” means the academic and administrative head of each of the components of the University.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Office of the Mayor of the District of Columbia established by § 1-204.21.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia established by § 1-204.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Board of Higher Education” means the Board of Higher Education established under § 38-1102.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Vocational Board” means the Board of Vocational Education established under § 38-1122.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Board” means the District of Columbia Board of Education established under § 1-204.95 [repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “financial institution” means an insured bank as defined in § 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. § 1813], or a savings and loan association as defined in § 401 [12 U.S.C. § 1724, repealed] of the National Housing Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “component” means that segment of the whole University such as a school, college, branch or campus, which, because of its nature, the Board of Trustees specifies as constituting an identifiable entity for the purpose of, but not limited to, being administered by an academic and administrative head.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “University of the District of Columbia School of Law” (“School of Law”) means the institution that had been established under § 38-1205.03(b) [repealed] as the District of Columbia School of Law. Any reference to a degree holder of the School of Law shall include any person who received a degree from the Antioch School of Law during the period when it was operated as a part of the Antioch University, as well as any person who received a degree after the establishment of the public School of Law under § 38-1205.03 [repealed] and persons who receive a degree from the University of the District of Columbia School of Law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1201_03_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means any of the 50 states of the United States in addition to the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
