<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1833.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1833.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1833_02">
        <akn:num>38-1833.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Direct Loan Fund for Charter School Improvement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established within the District of Columbia a Direct Loan Fund for Charter School Improvement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Direct Loan Fund for Charter School Improvement shall be administered by the Office of Charter School Financing and Support, except that no loan may be made under this section without the approval of the committee described in section 603(e)(3)(C)(iii) of the Student Loan Marketing Association Reorganization Act of 1996 (20 U.S.C. 1155(e)(3)(C)(iii)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funds distributed under this section shall be for construction, purchase, renovation, and maintenance of charter school facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Loans distributed under this section shall not exceed $2,000,000 per charter school campus.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of Charter School Financing and Support shall determine what interest rates and terms apply to loans granted under this section. In determining the rates and terms of a loan granted to a charter school, the Office of Charter School Financing and Support should do its best to provide low interest options and flexible terms.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be eligible for a loan under this subsection, an applicant shall be one of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In repaying a loan granted under this section, a debtor may use facility maintenance funds granted to them by the District of Columbia Public Schools.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1833_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term of a loan within the context of a New Markets Tax Credit as this term is defined in the Internal Revenue Code, may extend to 7 years; all other loan terms under this subsection shall not exceed 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
