<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1853.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1853.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1853_08">
        <akn:num>38-1853.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Nondiscrimination and other requirements for participating schools.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In general. — An eligible entity or a school participating in any program under this chapter shall not discriminate against program participants or applicants on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, or sex.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Applicability and single sex schools, classes, or activities. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Children with disabilities. — Nothing in this chapter may be construed to alter or modify the provisions of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. § 1400 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Religiously affiliated schools. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rule of construction. — A scholarship (or any other form of support provided to parents of eligible students) under this chapter shall be considered assistance to the student and shall not be considered assistance to the school that enrolls the eligible student. The amount of any scholarship (or other form of support provided to parents of an eligible student) under this chapter shall not be treated as income of the child or his or her parents for purposes of Federal tax laws or for determining eligibility for any other Federal program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Requests for data and information. — Each school participating in a program funded under this chapter shall comply with all requests for data and information regarding evaluations conducted under § 38-1853.09(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rules of conduct and other school policies. — A participating school, including the schools described in subsection (d), may require eligible students to abide by any rules of conduct and other requirements applicable to all other students at the school.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1853_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nationally norm-referenced standardized tests. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
