<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1804.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1804.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1804_01">
        <akn:num>38-1804.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Annual budgets for schools.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In general. — For fiscal year 1997 and for each subsequent fiscal year, the Mayor shall make annual payments from the general fund of the District of Columbia in accordance with the formula established under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Formula. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The requirements to meet IDEA’s Maintenance of Effort Obligation and Use of Formula Special Education Payments are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>DCPS and public charter schools shall provide to OSSE, at least annually, a certified report of all expenditures made with Special Education Payments for each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OSSE shall issue guidance to clarify reporting requirements for the purpose of determining whether DCPS and each public charter school have:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The OSSE, utilizing official budget and expenditure data provided by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, shall monitor the DCPS and public charter schools for compliance with the requirements in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>DCPS and public charter schools shall adhere to monitoring policies issued by OSSE pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event the distribution of a Formula payment is delayed to DCPS or a public charter school, the school shall receive additional time to expend the distribution based upon the difference in the number of days between the scheduled distribution date and the actual distribution date of funds to DCPS or the public charter school.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1804_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
