<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1807.53"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1807.53/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1807_53">
        <akn:num>38-1807.53</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Development of fiscal year 1997 budget request.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1807_53_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In general. — The Board of Education shall develop its fiscal year 1997 gross operating budget and its fiscal year 1997 appropriated funds budget request in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1807_53_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Fiscal Year 1996 Budget Revision. — Not later than 60 days after April 26, 1996, the Board of Education shall develop, approve, and submit to the Mayor, the District of Columbia Council, the Authority, and appropriate Congressional committees, a revised fiscal year 1996 gross operating budget that reflects the amount appropriated in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1996, and which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1807_53_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Zero-Base budget. — For fiscal year 1997, the Board of Education shall build its gross operating budget and appropriated funds request from a zero-base, starting from the local school level through the central office level.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1807_53_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>School-by-school budgets. — The Board of Education’s initial fiscal year 1997 gross operating budget and appropriated funds budget request submitted to the Mayor, the District of Columbia Council, and the Authority shall contain school-by-school budgets and shall also:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
