<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1203.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1203.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1203_01">
        <akn:num>38-1203.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Appropriations; purchase and sale of books.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1203_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There are authorized to be appropriated out of any money in the Treasury to the credit of the District of Columbia such sums as may be necessary for carrying out the purposes of this unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1203_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Trustees are authorized to purchase and sell books at such prices as they determine necessary to approximate the cost of the sale of such books, excluding personnel and overhead costs. All receipts from the sale of such books shall be deposited with the D.C. Treasurer and accounted for within the Municipal University Fund as a separate revenue source allocable to provide authority for the purchase of books as the Board of Trustees may approve. Any unexpended balance at the end of fiscal year 1981 or each succeeding fiscal year thereafter shall be reserved as a restricted fund balance and used to provide authority to expend for subsequent years, for the purchase of books, subject to the direction of the Board of Trustees. Such funds which are available from the general revenues of the District of Columbia and appropriated in fiscal year 1981 for the purpose of the procurement of books by the Trustees and receipts from the sale of such books shall also be deposited with the D.C. Treasurer and accounted for in an account within the Municipal University Fund; provided, that the base of the budget of the University shall be reduced in fiscal year 1982 by an amount equal to the funds appropriated in fiscal year 1981 for the purpose of procurement of such books and receipts from the sale of such books.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
