<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1802.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1802.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1802_10">
        <akn:num>38-1802.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Application of law.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1802_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1802_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Property and sales taxes. — A public charter school shall be exempt from District of Columbia property and sales taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1802_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Education of children with disabilities. — By August 1, 2017, each public charter school shall be its own local educational agency for the purpose of Part B of IDEA and section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act (29 U.S.C. § 794); provided, that the Public Charter School Board may, in its discretion, waive application of this subsection to allow a currently existing public charter school with more than 90% of its students entitled to receive services pursuant to an individualized educational program to continue to be a District of Columbia public school for the purposes of Part B of IDEA and section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act (29 U.S.C. § 794).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1802_10_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Education of children with disabilities in charter schools]. — No newly approved public charter school shall elect to be treated as a District of Columbia public school for the purpose of Part B of IDEA and section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973(29 U.S.C. § 794).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1802_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Waiver of application of duplicate and conflicting provisions. — Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as otherwise provided in this chapter, no provision of any law regarding the establishment, administration, or operation of public charter schools in the District of Columbia shall apply with respect to a public charter school or an eligible chartering authority to the extent that the provision duplicates or is inconsistent with any provision of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1802_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Participation in GSA programs. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
