<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1310"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1310/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1310">
        <akn:num>38-1310</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Exempt institutions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following types of educational institutions or activities are excluded from the coverage of this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A degree-granting institution shall be entitled to a conditional exemption from all other provisions of this chapter if, upon request to the Commission:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An institution entitled to a conditional exemption under subsection (b) of this section that is required by a regional accrediting association to show cause why its accreditation should not be revoked, or that has had its accreditation withdrawn, shall notify the Commission immediately of the action by the regional accrediting association. The exemption shall expire and the institution shall become fully subject to the licensing requirements of this chapter as of the date it receives notice of the withdrawal of accreditation status by the regional accrediting association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission, upon request, may reinstate an institution’s conditional exemption once accreditation is re-established and the Commission has determined that it meets the provisions of this chapter appropriate to the exempt status.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A conditional exemption authorized by this section extends only to programs or courses within the scope of the institution’s accreditation as certified by the accrediting association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall issue a conditional exemption to an off-campus program offered within the District of Columbia by an unconditionally accredited degree training institution or group of institutions. All other requirements of conditional exemptions under this section shall apply to the programs, when the Commission determines that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing shall be stated or implied, in any diploma, degree, certificate, or document evidencing same, or elsewhere in the publications or correspondence of the institution that a program excluded from the requirements of this chapter has been reviewed, approved, or authorized by the Commission, the District government or any officer of the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1310_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any self study undertaken by an educational institution as part of the accreditation process, any site evaluation by an accrediting association, or any other report submitted by the educational institution to the accrediting association or by the accrediting association to the educational institution that contains an evaluation judgment about the institution that is not prepared for publication shall, when submitted to the Commission in accordance with this chapter, be exempt from public disclosure under the provisions of subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2, and the Commission shall not disclose the report or take official licensure action solely on the basis of the contents of the report. The Commission shall disclose whether or not an educational institution has received the award, reaffirmation, amendment, or revocation of accreditation from an accrediting association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
