<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1202.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-1202.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_1202_01">
        <akn:num>38-1202.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Board of Trustees and University.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a body corporate by name of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, which by that name and style shall have perpetual succession. It shall be charged with the responsibility of governing the University of the District of Columbia and shall possess all the powers necessary or convenient to accomplish the objects and perform the duties authorized by this section, and §§ 38-1202.06 and 38-1204.03, including the power to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby authorized to be established an independent agency of the government of the District of Columbia known as the University of the District of Columbia which shall be governed by the Board of Trustees as established in subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Trustees shall consist of 15 voting members selected in the following manner:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Four of the 11 Trustees appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council may be nonresidents of the District of Columbia. At least 7 of the 11 Trustees shall reside in the District of Columbia at the time of their confirmation by the Council. The Mayor shall submit the names of District residents and nonresidents in a proportion to comply with the provisions of this subsection, when submitting nominees to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The student member of the Board of Trustees shall serve for a term of one year, beginning on May 15th following his or her election.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in § 38-1202.02(l) [repealed], each nonstudent member of the Board of Trustees shall serve for a 5-year term, beginning on May 15th following his or her election or confirmation by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member of the Board of Trustees who has completed a full 5-year term in accordance with subsection (e) of this section may be reappointed or re-elected to serve 1 additional term, after which the former member may not become a Trustee by election or by appointment until May 15th of the 5th year following the year in which the former member left the Board. Service pursuant to § 38-1202.02(l) [repealed] for the remainder of the term of a Trustee who has died or resigned shall not, by itself or in conjunction with other service, constitute a bar to the re-election or reappointment of a person who has served as a Trustee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Board of Trustees serving on February 27, 1990, shall continue to serve until May 15th following the conclusion of his or her previously established term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A chairperson and a vice-chairperson of the Board of Trustees:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member of the Board of Education shall not serve as a Trustee of the University. Except as provided in subsection (l) of this section a paid officer or employee of the University of the District of Columbia shall not serve as a Trustee. A retired officer or employee of the University of the District of Columbia, shall, however, be eligible to serve as a Trustee. A Trustee shall forfeit his or her membership on the Board upon failure to maintain the qualifications required by this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Executive Officer of the University shall be a non-voting ex officio member of the Board of Trustees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-1202_01_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
