<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2831"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2831/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2831">
        <akn:num>38-2831</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Budget submission requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2831_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools (“Chancellor”) shall prepare and execute a performance-based budget on an annual basis. The budget prepared by the Chancellor shall have its operations organized by major programs, which in turn will be composed of activities and services. The budget submitted by the Chancellor shall allocate all monies by revenue source for programs, activity, and service levels, and by revenue source for comptroller source group by program and activity. The District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”) submission shall include the number of full-time equivalents with job titles by program and revenue source.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2831_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The DCPS submission shall also include a delineation of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2831_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No later than 21 days before the Mayor’s submission of the District’s budget and financial plan to the Council, the Chancellor shall, annually, make available on the DCPS website and post at each school a detailed estimate, in accordance with this section, of the amount of money required to operate the public schools for the ensuing year, including preliminary school-by-school budgets.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2831_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor’s annual submission of the District’s budget and financial plan to the Council shall include as an attachment an accurate and verifiable report on the positions and employees of the District of Columbia Public Schools to include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2831_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No later than October 30 of each year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a revised appropriated funds operating budget for DCPS for the fiscal year beginning on the preceding October 1 that sets forth the total amount of the approved appropriation and that realigns budgeted data with anticipated actual expenditures with the specification set forth in of subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2831_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in fiscal year 2011, the Mayor shall submit to the Council quarterly financial reports for DCPS setting forth by organization Level 4 approved budget, revised budget, actual expenditures and funds obligated to date, and projected expenditures for the full fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
