<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2021.21"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2021.21/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2021_21">
        <akn:num>38-2021.21</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Adjustment of annuities on basis of price index; computation; definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective December 1, 1965, each annuity payable from the fund which has a commencing date not later than January 1, 1966, shall be increased by: (1) the per centum rise in the price index, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%, determined by the Mayor of the District of Columbia on the basis of the annual average price index for calendar year 1962 and the price index for the month of July 1965; plus (2) 6 1/2% if the commencing date (or in the case of a survivor of a deceased annuitant the commencing date of the annuity of the retired employee) occurred on or before October 1, 1956, or 1 1/2% if the commencing date (or in the case of the survivor of a deceased annuitant the commencing date of the annuity of the retired employee) occurred after October 1, 1956. The month used in determining the increase based on the per centum rise in the price index under this subsection shall be the base month for determining the per centum change in the price index until the next succeeding increase occurs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Eligibility for an annuity increase under this section shall be as provided in subsection (b)(2) of this section, except as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No increase in annuity provided by this section shall be computed on any additional annuity purchased at retirement by voluntary contributions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The monthly installment of annuity after adjustment under this section shall be fixed at the nearest dollar, except that such installments shall after adjustment reflect an increase of at least $1.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2021_21_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term “price index” shall mean the Consumer Price Index (all items — United States city average) published monthly by the Bureau of Labor Statistics. The term “base month” shall mean the month for which the price index showed a per centum rise forming the basis for a cost-of-living annuity increase.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
