<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2971.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2971.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2971_01">
        <akn:num>38-2971.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Public School Capital Improvement Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2971_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a nonlapsing special revenue fund to be known as the Public School Capital Improvement Fund (“Fund”), which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and which shall be used to provide a revenue source for the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2971_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall deposit into the Fund:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2971_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funds deposited in the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this chapter, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2971_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning on October 1, 2006, the Chief Financial Officer shall transfer any funds deposited in the Fund to the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization, subject to the requirements of § 38-2971.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2971_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The appropriation of local funds to, or the existence of retained funds in, the Public School Capital Improvement Fund shall not replace local funding that otherwise would be directed to the capital budget for the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
