<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2906.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2906.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2906_02">
        <akn:num>38-2906.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payments to public charter schools.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall make payments to each public charter school from the escrow account established under § 38-1804.03 to a bank designated by each school. The annual payment shall be made in the form of quarterly payments calculated in accordance with this section; provided, that the entire annual payment for facilities calculated pursuant to § 38-2908 shall be included in the first payment of the fiscal year and that any payment for new charter schools determined pursuant to § 38-1804.03 shall also be included in the first payment of the fiscal year. The first payment shall be made no later than July 15. Subsequent payments shall be made no later than October 25, January 15, and April 15.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payments shall be determined as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payments shall not be reduced or delayed pending the conduct and results of the audit prescribed by § 38-2906(d). If the audit finds that the number of verified resident students enrolled at any public charter school differs from that on which its July 15 and October 25 payments were based, the Mayor shall recalculate the appropriate amount of subsequent payments accordingly, adjusting them by the amount of the discrepancy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to, or concurrent with, any payment made pursuant to this section, the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall provide to each public charter school an accounting indicating the purpose of the payment and how the payment was calculated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During any period in which payments to public charter schools become due on a date when District funding is authorized pursuant to a continuing resolution rather than pursuant to an appropriations act, the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall provide payments for new public charter schools and increased enrollments in other public charter schools from any unexpended and unobligated funds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon application to the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, charter schools offering alternative education or special education services may receive payment for eligible students enrolling after October 5, on a pro-rata basis from the date on which the school begins to provide services to that student; provided, that the student represents a net increase to the school’s enrollment as of October 5. The pro-rata payments for special education students enrolling after October 5 based on the public charter school’s predetermined enrollment schedule shall be disbursed in addition to the quarterly payments at the discretion of the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2906_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an eligible charter authority proposes to revoke the charter of a public charter school as described in § 38-1802.13 during any period prior to a July 15 payment, consistent with this section, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education (“OSSE”) shall hold the July 15 payment in escrow pending a final decision by the eligible charter authority. Upon a final revocation decision, the Mayor shall have no obligation to release the escrow funds. The OSSE, in its discretion, may approve the distribution of the July 15 payment as it considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
