<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2561.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2561.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2561_07">
        <akn:num>38-2561.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certificate of Approval for nonpublic special education schools or Programs — General.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The SEA shall develop and administer a Certificate of Approval process for nonpublic special education schools or programs that serve District of Columbia students with disabilities with funding from the District of Columbia government by January 1, 2009. The Certificate of Approval process shall include an evaluation of the nonpublic special education school or program, including an onsite inspection of the operations and facilities of the school or program. The SEA shall issue a Certificate of Approval to a nonpublic special education school or program after determining that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any nonpublic special education school or program that will be affected by the Certificate of Approval process shall be allowed to participate in the development and revision of applicable standards pursuant to the IDEA.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Certificate of Approval shall be for a period not to exceed 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The SEA shall develop and maintain a list of approved nonpublic special education schools and programs, and shall display this list along with appropriate information about each nonpublic special education school or program on its website.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The initial application and the Certificate of Approval shall include the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A school or program shall operate in a manner that is consistent with the specifications recorded on the Certificate of Approval issued to the individual or entity with legal responsibility for governing and operating the school or program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The SEA may issue a provisional Certificate of Approval to schools or programs that meet minimum requirements to be established by SEA regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_07_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In issuing Certificates of Approval to residential child care facilities, or when otherwise required, the SEA shall coordinate with the Department of Mental Health, the Department of Human Services, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services, and the Medical Assistance Administration of the Department of Health, or any other appropriate public agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
