<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2023.16"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2023.16/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2023_16">
        <akn:num>38-2023.16</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax-sheltered annuity program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2023_16_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of §§ 1-611.11 and 1-617.16, and of any other law or regulation affecting the salary of teachers or school officers employed in the service of the public schools of the District of Columbia, the Mayor of the District of Columbia (hereinafter referred to as the “Mayor”) is authorized to enter into an agreement with a teacher or school officer to reduce the salary of that teacher or school officer by an amount requested by that teacher or school officer, and to contribute that amount for the purchase of an annuity contract described in § 403(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to the taxability of beneficiaries of annuity plans) for that teacher or school official.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2023_16_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The reduction in salary effected under an agreement authorized by this section shall not be considered in computing the salary for any teacher or school officer for any other purpose including, but not limited to, the determination of benefits or contributions under Chapters 81 (relating to workmen’s compensation) and 87 (relating to life insurance) of Title 5 of the United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2023_16_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2023_16_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “teacher or school officer” includes all teachers, school officers, and other employees of the Board of Education of the District of Columbia who receive compensation according to the salary schedules under §§ 1-611.11 and 1-617.16, and to whom the provisions of part A of this subchapter are applicable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2023_16_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall apply with respect to any pay period of any teacher or school officer beginning on or after the 180th day after April 26, 1972.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
