<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2561.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2561.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2561_03">
        <akn:num>38-2561.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Placement and funding of a student with a disability in a nonpublic special education school or program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an LEA anticipates that it may be unable to implement a student’s IEP or provide a student with an appropriate special education placement in accordance with the IDEA and other applicable laws or regulations, the LEA shall notify the SEA. The SEA shall cooperate with the LEA to provide a placement in a more restrictive setting in conformity with the IDEA, and any other applicable laws or regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The SEA shall be responsible for paying the costs of education, including special education and related services, of a student with a disability when the student is placed at a nonpublic special education school or program pursuant to this section; provided, that, in conformity with IDEA, the SEA shall not be responsible for paying the cost of education, including special education and related services, of a student with a disability who attends a nonpublic special education school or program if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the SEA has reason to believe that a child is a neglected child or is being abused, as those terms are defined in § 16-2301(9) and (23), respectively, in an out-of-state nonpublic special education school or program, the SEA shall immediately notify the relevant state’s child welfare agency and the parent or guardian of the child. Upon notification, the SEA shall work with the parent or guardian to take immediate steps to ensure the safety and health of the child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2561_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall issue updated rules to implement the provisions of this section by October 1, 2015.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
