<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2908"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2908/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2908">
        <akn:num>38-2908</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Facilities allowance for Public Charter Schools.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (b-1) of this section, the fiscal year facility allowance for Public Charter Schools shall be determined as follows: DCPS approved capital budget shall be divided by the previous school year (“SY”) DCPS total pupil count, as defined in § 38-2906, to determine the DCPS per pupil facility cost.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For fiscal year 2004 through fiscal year 2008, the facility allowance for Public Charter Schools shall be determined as described in subsection (a) of this section, except that the DCPS per pupil facility cost for all previous years shall be averaged with the current year’s DCPS per pupil facility cost to determine the Public Charter School per pupil facility allowance. The facility allowance shall then be multiplied by the number of students estimated to be attending each Public Charter School to determine the actual facility allowance payments to be received by each Public Charter School. For each year after FY 2004, this “moving average” shall only include the most recent 5-year’s DCPS per pupil facility cost.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For fiscal year 2009 and succeeding fiscal years, the per pupil facility allowance for Public Charter Schools shall be $3000. The facility allowance shall then be multiplied by the number of students estimated to be attending each Public Charter School to determine the actual facility allowance payments to be received by each Public Charter School.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The entire annual payment for facilities shall be included in the first payment of the fiscal year and that any payment for new charter schools shall also be included in the first payment of the fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For DCPS or Public Charter Schools that provide students with room and board in a residential setting, in addition to their instructional program, the facilities allowance determined pursuant to this section shall be multiplied by 2.7 for those students in residence at the school.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2908_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The facilities allowance shall only apply to students receiving instruction at a Public Charter School educational facility or as otherwise approved by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
