<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-281"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-281/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_281">
        <akn:num>38-281</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child and Adult Care Food Program” or “CACF Program” means the program authorized by section 17 of the National School Lunch Act, approved October 7, 1975 (89 Stat. 522; 42 U.S.C. § 1766).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child development facility” means a licensed community-based center, home, or other structure, regardless of its name, that provides care, supervision, guidance, and other services for infants, toddlers, and preschoolers on a regular basis. The term “child development facility” does not include a child development center or program that is sponsored or run by a public or private school.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible child” means a child who is a District resident who occupies a slot funded in whole or in part by the childcare subsidy program, authorized by § 4-402, subchapter I of Chapter 29 of this title [§ 38-2901 et seq.], or the District of Columbia Public Schools’ Head Start program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Farm-to-preschool programs” means programs at child development facilities that connect early care and education settings to local food producers, as an extension of the farm-to-school model, which connect children to local foods through meals and snacks, taste tests, lessons, farmer visits, cooking, field trips, growing food, and community and parent engagement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Infant” means a child younger than 12 months of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Locally grown” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 38-821.01(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“OSSE” means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, established by § 38-2601.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Preschool” or “preschooler” means a child older than 24 months of age but younger than compulsory school attendance age, who is not enrolled in a public, charter, or private school.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sustainable agriculture” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 38-821.01(9).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Toddler” means a child between 12 months of age and 24 months of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unprocessed” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 38-821.01(10).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-281_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“WIC” means the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children, as provided in section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, approved September 26, 1972 (86 Stat. 729; 42 U.S.C. § 1786).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
