<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-203"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-203/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_203">
        <akn:num>38-203</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement; penalties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An accurate daily record of the attendance of all minors covered by ยง 38-202 and this section shall be kept by the teachers of each educational institution. These records shall be open for inspection at all times by the Board, the Superintendent of Schools, school attendance officers, or other persons authorized to enforce this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be the duty of each principal, head teacher, teacher who gives private instruction, or school administrative officer as designated in each educational institution to report to the Board the school attendance of any minor covered by ยง 38-202(a) who is enrolled in a school or who is enrolled for private instruction and who is absent from school or instruction for more than 2 full-day sessions or 4 half-day sessions in any school month, along with a statement of the reasons for the absences.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The absence of a minor covered by ยง 38-202(a) without valid excuse shall be unlawful.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The parent, guardian, or other person who has custody or control of a minor covered by ยง 38-202(a) who is absent from school without a valid excuse shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person convicted of failure to keep a minor in regular attendance in a public, independent, private, or parochial school, or failure to provide regular private instruction acceptable to the Board may be fined not less than $100 or imprisoned for not more than 5 days, or both for each offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each unlawful absence of a minor for 2 full-day sessions or for 4 half-day sessions during a school month shall constitute a separate offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the 1st offense, upon payment of costs, the sentence may be suspended and the defendant may be placed on probation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For any person convicted under this section, the courts shall consider requiring the offender to perform community service as an alternative to fine or imprisonment or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 60 days after the end of a school year, each public, independent, private, or parochial school shall report to the Mayor, or the Mayor&#x27;s designee, and make publicly available, the following data based on the preceding school year:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-203_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>By August 1, 2012, the Mayor shall develop, through rulemaking, appropriate enforcement mechanisms to ensure that each school, principal, and teacher is in full compliance with the requirements of this subchapter and any regulations issued pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
