<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2041.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-2041.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_2041_01">
        <akn:num>38-2041.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Retirement Incentive Program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Education is authorized to establish a retirement incentive program (“program”) which shall apply to eligible employees under the personnel authority of the Board of Education. This authorization is conditioned on the requirement that no District employee who receives an incentive payment under the early out retirement program shall be reemployed with the District government, including the Board of Education, for 5 years, or hired or retained as a sole source personal services contractor for 5 years from the date of retirement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Education may exclude or limit positions from the program based on the needs of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The program shall be effective from December 21, 1994, through September 30, 1995.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The program shall be limited to employees retiring under the early out retirement provisions of 5 U.S.C. 8336(d)(2), employees who become eligible to retire on or before June 15, 1995, under the optional retirement provisions of 5 U.S.C. 8336(a), (b), or (f), and teachers who are eligible to retire under § 38-2021.01(f).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The program shall offer a retirement incentive of 50% of an employee’s annual rate of basic pay paid from the employee’s salary or pay schedule which was in effect on the employee’s date of retirement, not to exceed $24,000, to be paid in 24 equal installments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Retirement incentive payments shall be prorated in the case of a part-time employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Retirement incentive payments shall not be considered basic pay for computing retirement entitlement, insurance entitlement, any category of premium pay entitlement, lump-sum leave, or any other entitlement that is computed on basic pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-2041_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No incentive payments shall be paid to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
