<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-821.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/38-821.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_38_821_02">
        <akn:num>38-821.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Healthy Schools Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Healthy Schools Fund (“Fund”), which shall be used solely as provided in subsection (c) of this section and administered by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education. The Fund shall be funded by annual appropriations, which shall be deposited into the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (c) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds in the Fund shall be used as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education may, by rule, increase the amounts, as set forth in subsection (c) of this section, to further improve the quality and nutrition of school meals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education may withhold local funds provided by subsection (c) of this section from public schools and public charter schools that do not meet any or all of the requirements of §§ 38-822.02, 38-822.03, 38-822.05, and 38-822.06.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning on October 1, 2011, an amount of $4,266,000 from the revenues derived from the collection of the tax imposed upon all vendors by § 47-2002 shall be deposited annually into the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_38-821_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All excess monies remaining in the Fund at the end of a fiscal year shall be administered by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education for the purposes set forth in subsection (c)(6), (7), and (8) of this section, and to further improve health, wellness, and nutrition in schools.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
