<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1501"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1501/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1501">
        <akn:num>34-1501</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means a person who directly or indirectly, or through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, or has directly or indirectly, any economic interest in another person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Aggregator” means a person who acts on behalf of customers to purchase electricity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Aggregation program” means any system developed by an aggregator for organizing customers into a single purchasing unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Anticompetitive condition” means a condition which would allow a party to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Anticompetitive conduct” means an activity which would:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bid premium” means a payment by an electricity supplier to the Commission for the right to provide standard offer service in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Broker” means a person who acts as an agent or intermediary in the sale and purchase of electricity but who does not take title to electricity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Competitive billing” means the right of a customer to receive a single bill from the electric company, a single bill from the electricity supplier, or separate bills from the electric company and the electricity supplier.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commission” means the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_9A">
      <akn:num>(9A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community net metering” means a billing arrangement under which the monetary value of electric energy generated by a community renewable energy facility and delivered to the electric company’s local distribution facilities is used to offset electric energy charges accrued during a subscriber’s applicable billing period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_9B">
      <akn:num>(9B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community renewable energy facility” or “CREF” means an energy facility using renewable resources defined as tier one renewable sources in § 34-1431(15) that is located within the District of Columbia and where the monetary value of electricity generated by the facility is credited to the subscribers of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Competitive Transition Charge” means a rate, charge, credit, or other appropriate mechanism authorized to be imposed for the recovery of transition costs as determined by the Commission under § 34-1510.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Consolidator” means any owner of or property manager for multi-family residential, commercial office, industrial, and retail facilities who combines more than one property for the primary purpose of contracting with an aggregator or electric energy service provider for electric energy services for those properties, and who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Consumer” or “customer” each means a purchaser of electricity for end use in the District of Columbia. The term excludes an occupant of a building where the owner, lessee, or manager manages the internal distribution system serving the building and supplies electricity solely to occupants of the building for use by the occupants.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_12A">
      <akn:num>(12A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“CREF credit rate” means a credit rate applied to subscribers of community renewable energy facilities which shall be equal to the standard offer service rate for the General Service Low Voltage Non-Demand Customer class or its successor, as determined by the Commission, based upon § 34-1518.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Customer-based aggregation program” means a program in which customers pool their loads to shop more effectively for electricity supply, electricity supply services, or any service declared to be a potentially competitive service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Customer choice” or “choice of electricity suppliers” each means the right of electricity suppliers and consumers to use and interconnect with the electric distribution system on a nondiscriminatory basis in order to distribute electricity from any electric supplier to any customer. Under this right, consumers shall have the opportunity to purchase electricity supply from their choice of licensed electricity suppliers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Customer-generator” means a residential or commercial customer that owns and operates an electric generating facility that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_15A">
      <akn:num>(15A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the District Department of the Environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_15B">
      <akn:num>(15B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means the Director of the District Department of the Environment or his or her designee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Effective competition” means, with respect to the markets for electricity supply, billing, and those services declared by the Commission to be potentially competitive services a market structure under which an individual seller is not able to influence significantly the price of the service as a result of the number of sellers of the service, the size of each seller’s share of the market, the ability of the sellers to enter or exit the market, and the price and availability of comparable substitutes for the service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_16A">
      <akn:num>(16A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Electric company” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 34-207.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Electricity supplier” means a person, including an aggregator, broker, or marketer, who generates electricity; sells electricity; or purchases, brokers, arranges or, markets electricity for sale to customers. The term excludes the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_17A">
      <akn:num>(17A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gender identity or expression” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 2-1401.02(12A).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_17B">
      <akn:num>(17B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Individual billing meter” means an individual meter or a set of meters when meters are combined for billing purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Initial implementation date” means the first day on which customers in the District of Columbia shall have the ability to choose an electricity supplier. Unless accelerated or delayed by the Commission under § 34-1502(c), the initial implementation date shall be January 1, 2002.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Marketer” means a person who purchases and takes title to electricity as an intermediary for sale to customers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Market participant” means any electricity supplier (including an affiliate of the electric company) or any person providing billing services or services declared by the Commission to be potentially competitive services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Net energy metering” means measuring the difference between the electricity supplied to an eligible customer-generator from the electric grid and the electricity generated and fed back to the electric grid by the eligible customer-generator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pilot program” means a transitional program approved by the Commission prior to the initial implementation date under which customer choice is implemented for a percentage of each customer class.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Potentially competitive service” means a component of electric service (other than electricity supply and billing) determined by the Commission to be suitable for purchase by customers from alternative sellers under § 34-1504(e).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_24A">
      <akn:num>(24A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Renewable energy credit” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 34-1431(10).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Schedule” means a list of the dates on which each customer class, or a designated percentage of each customer class, is eligible for customer choice and competitive billing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_25A">
      <akn:num>(25A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“SOS administrator” means the provider of standard offer service mandated by § 34-1509.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Standard offer service” means that electric service mandated by § 34-1509.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subscriber” means a retail customer of the electric company who owns a subscription and who has identified an individual billing meter within the District of Columbia to which the subscription shall be attributed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_27A">
      <akn:num>(27A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subscriber organization” means any for-profit or nonprofit entity permitted by District of Columbia law that owns or operates one or more community renewable energy facilities for the benefit of the subscribers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_27B">
      <akn:num>(27B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subscription” means a percentage interest in a community renewable energy facility’s electrical production.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transition costs” means costs, liabilities, and investments (including regulatory assets) allocable to the District of Columbia to the extent the costs, liabilities, and investments:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1501_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Wholesale electricity supplier” means the electric company, which, pursuant to § 34-1509, obtains bids from, and contracts for electric service with, third parties and provides standard offer service to retail customers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
