<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1251.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1251.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1251_03">
        <akn:num>34-1251.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means, when used in relation to any person, another person who owns or controls, or is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with such person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Basic service” means the lowest tier of cable service that includes the retransmission of local broadcast signals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cable service” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cable facility” means antennae, transmitters, poles, wires, cables, conduits, amplifiers, instruments, and any other equipment used to provide cable service in the District, including any appliances used in connection with, or appurtenant to, any item listed in this paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cable operator” means a person or group of persons:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cable system” means the cable facilities, including the set of closed transmission paths and associated signal generation, reception, and control equipment, that are used to provide cable service to multiple subscribers within the District. The term cable system shall not include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Control” means actual working control in whatever manner exercised, including, without limitation, working control through ownership, management, debt instruments, or negative control. A rebuttable presumption of the existence of control shall arise from the beneficial ownership, directly or indirectly, by a person, or group of persons acting in concert, of more than 20% of a person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Converter” means an electronic device that may serve as an interface between a cable signal transmission and a subscriber’s television receiver or other terminal equipment, and which may perform a variety of functions, including signal security, descrambling, electronic polling, frequency conversion, and channel selection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_10A">
      <akn:num>(10A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means the Director of the Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the government of the District of Columbia or the geographic location of the District of Columbia, as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Educational channel” means a specifically designated channel on a cable system set aside for use by a public or private school, scientific or educational institution, or consortium of schools or institutions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_12A">
      <akn:num>(12A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Entertainment industry” means film, television, music, video, photography, gaming, digital media, and entertainment production.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fair market value” means the price that a willing buyer would pay to a willing seller for a cable system as a going concern in an arm’s-length transaction, but with no value allocated to the franchise itself.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal cable act” means the Cable Communications Policy Act of 1984, approved October 30, 1984 (98 Stat. 2779; 47 U.S.C. §§ 521-573).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“FCC” means the Federal Communications Commission or its successor agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Franchise” means an authorization, or renewal of an authorization, issued by the Council, to construct or operate a cable system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Franchise agreement” means a contract entered into pursuant to this chapter, between the District and a cable operator that sets forth, subject to this chapter and other laws, the terms and conditions under which a franchise shall or may be exercised.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross revenues” means all revenues received by a cable operator, or an affiliate of a cable operator, before payment of expenses and other costs, from the operation or use of its cable system or open video system, including revenues derived from cable services including cable modem service, interactive services, the sale or lease of subscriber equipment, installation and other service fees, the sale of advertising time (and related services), earnings from home shopping channels, and any item defined as gross revenue in a franchise agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Government channel” means a specifically designated channel on a cable system set aside for use by the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Installation” means the connection of cable service to a subscriber’s television receiver or other terminal equipment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Institutional network” or “I-Net” means a one-way and two-way network with upstream and downstream capacity, and including dedicated, high speed data, video, television, audio communications and telephony facilities, designed and constructed to connect District government buildings and facilities, and other buildings and facilities designated or authorized by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Office” means the Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment established by  § 34-1252.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Open video system” means the cable facilities, including the set of closed transmission paths and associated signal generation, reception, and control equipment, that are designed to provide cable service to multiple subscribers within the District, and which the FCC, in accordance with section 653 of the federal cable act (47 U.S.C. § 573), has certified as compliant with Title VI of the federal cable act and its rules.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Other programming service” means a service other than cable service that a cable operator makes available to all subscribers generally.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“PEG” means public access, educational, and governmental channels with channel capacity designated for public access channels, educational channels, and government channels, and the facilities and equipment for the use of the channels.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, joint-stock company, trust, or any other legal entity, excluding the government of the District of Columbia and its agencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public access channel” means a channel on a cable system that is reserved for noncommercial use by members of the public on a nondiscriminatory basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public rights-of-way” means the surface, the airspace above the surface, and the area below the surface of any street, road, avenue, highway, parkway, concourse, boulevard, park, public space, bridge, viaduct, tunnel, or any other property to which the District has title, easement, or jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subscriber” means a person who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1251_03_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Video programming” means programming provided by, or generally considered comparable to programming provided by, a television broadcast station.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
