<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1256.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1256.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1256_04">
        <akn:num>34-1256.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Insurance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1256_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At all times during the term of a franchise, including the time for removal of facilities, the cable operator shall hold a valid liability insurance policy and shall pay all premiums for the policy in a timely manner. The policy shall insure the District, its officers, boards, commissions, elected officials, agents, contractors, and employees against liabilities. The policy shall be issued by a company carrying a rating by Best of not less than “A” and the company shall be authorized by the District’s Superintendent of Insurance to do business in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1256_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount of the liability insurance policy, and the terms of the policy, shall be established in the franchise agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1256_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The form of the liability insurance policy shall be acceptable to the Director of the Mayor’s Office of Legal Counsel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1256_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The policy shall require 30 calendar days written notice of any cancellation to both the Office and the cable operator. If the Office or the cable operator receives a cancellation notice, the cable operator shall obtain a new bond, meeting the requirements of this section, within 30 days after receipt of the notice by the Office or the cable operator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1256_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The cable operator shall file with the Office written evidence of payment of premiums and executed duplicate copies of the liability insurance policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1256_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure to comply with the provisions of this section, or with the liability insurance provisions of the franchise agreement, shall constitute a material violation of a franchise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
