<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1313.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1313.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1313_09">
        <akn:num>34-1313.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Consideration of triennial Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall expedite its consideration of an application seeking an order approving a triennial Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan. The Commission shall issue its decision on the application no later than 45 days following the deadline for public comment on the application; provided, that if a protest or objection to the application is timely filed with the Commission and can be resolved without an evidentiary hearing, this period for the Commission’s decision is extended by an additional 15 days. The computation of this time may be tolled, at the Commission’s discretion, for periods in which it determines the electric company and DDOT’s joint application is deficient. If an evidentiary hearing is required, the hearing shall, in the Commission’s discretion and based upon the Commission’s evaluation of all relevant factors, commence on the date set by the Commission and be concluded within 45 days of the close of discovery and the Commission shall issue a decision no more than 60 days of the close of the hearing record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
