<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1313.15"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1313.15/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1313_15">
        <akn:num>34-1313.15</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Application for approval of annual adjustment of Underground Project Charges.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_15_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No later than April 1 of each year following issuance of an order authorizing the imposition and collection of Underground Project Charges and for as long as such order remains in effect, the electric company shall file with the Commission an application for approval of the electric company’s proposed adjustment to set the Underground Project Charges until the next proposed adjustment is approved by the Commission; except, that the Commission may approve any such adjustment sooner in an order approving a triennial Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_15_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Concurrent with filing an application for approval of an annual adjustment that would adjust the level and, if applicable, the allocation between distribution service customer classes of the Underground Project Charges, the electric company shall provide notice to its customers of the application, in the manner provided in § 34-909.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_15_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An application filed pursuant to this section shall include, at a minimum, a narrative description of the proposed adjustments, a proposed form of public notice of the application suitable for publication by the Commission and, as applicable:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_15_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_15_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proposed adjusted Underground Project Charges shall take effect, subject to refund and adjustment, on the date of filing with the Commission. If no objection is timely filed, or having been timely filed, is denied by the Commission, the proposed charges shall become final and no longer subject to refund or adjustment on the date of a final decision as set forth in subsection (f) of this section, unless the Commission rules otherwise before such date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_15_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
