<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1802"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1802/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1802">
        <akn:num>34-1802</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Emergency and Non-Emergency Number Telephone Calling Systems Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a fund designated as the Emergency and Non-Emergency Number Telephone Calling Systems Fund, which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section. The Fund shall be funded by a tax imposed under §§ 34-1803 and 34-1803.02 and from sources identified in § 34-1803.03. All monies collected under § 34-1803, § 34-1803.02, and 34-§ 1803.03 and all interest earned on those monies, shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All monies deposited into the Fund shall not revert to, or be transferred to, the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All authority and operations of the Fund shall be administered by the Office of Unified Communications.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Fund shall be used solely to defray personnel and nonpersonnel costs incurred by the District of Columbia and its agencies and instrumentalities in providing a 911 system, and direct costs incurred by wireless carriers in providing wireless E-911 service. For purposes of this subsection, the term  “costs” shall include obligations incurred both before and after October 19, 2000. The Fund shall not be used for any other purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After October 1, 2008, no monies in the Fund shall be used to defray personnel costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After October 1, 2010, no monies in the Fund shall be used to defray nonpersonal costs related to overhead, including energy, rentals, janitorial services, security, or occupancy costs. The Fund shall be used solely to defray technology and equipment costs directly incurred by the District of Columbia and its agencies and instrumentalities in providing a 911 system and direct costs incurred by wireless carriers in providing wireless E-911 service. The Fund shall not be used for any other purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_b_3">
      <akn:num>(b-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (b-2) of this section, monies in the Fund may be used to defray security costs during fiscal year 2011 and fiscal year 2012.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as a part of the annual budget, a requested appropriation for expenditures from the Fund. Any monies received but not expended in a given fiscal year shall be retained by the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1802_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During fiscal year 2003, the Mayor shall allocate at least $500,000 of any revenue the Fund earns due to the enactment of the Emergency and Non-Emergency Number Telephone Calling Systems Fund Amendment Act of 2002 (title VII of D.C. Law 14-307), in excess of the Fund revenue projection included in the District of Columbia’s budget submission to Congress, to increase the number of emergency call-taking staff who are working during hours when call volume is above average. The Mayor may increase the number of emergency call-taking staff through such measures that he considers appropriate, including hiring new staff, authorizing overtime, employing light-duty sworn police officers or firefighters, or offering a shift differential, in accordance with Chapter 6 of Title 1 and any applicable collective bargaining agreements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
