<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1553"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1553/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1553">
        <akn:num>34-1553</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Energy submetering and energy allocation equipment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1553_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Energy submetering equipment or energy allocation equipment may be used in a building if it is authorized in the rental agreement or lease for the nonresidential rental unit. All energy submetering equipment and energy allocation equipment shall meet the requirements and standards established and enforced by the Commission pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1553_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1553_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Energy allocation equipment shall be tested periodically under Commission rules by the building owner, operator, or manager. Upon the request by a tenant, the building owner, operator, or manager shall test the energy allocation equipment without charge. The test shall be conducted without charge to the tenant and shall not be conducted more frequently than once in a 24-month period for the same tenant. The tenant or his designated representative may be present during the testing of the energy allocation equipment. A written report of the results of the test shall be made to the tenant within 10 business days after the completion of the test.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1553_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A building owner, operator, or manager shall maintain adequate records regarding energy submetering equipment or energy allocation equipment. A tenant may inspect and copy the records for the nonresidential unit during reasonable business hours at a convenient location within the building. The building owner, operator, or manager may impose and collect a reasonable charge for copying documents, reflecting the actual costs of materials and labor for copying, prior to providing copies of the records to the tenant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1553_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any enforcement action undertaken by the Commission pursuant to its authority under ยง 34-1552, tenants and owners, operators, or managers shall retain any private right of action resulting from any breach of the rental agreement or lease terms required by this section or ยง 34-1552.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
