<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1312.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1312.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1312_07">
        <akn:num>34-1312.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bonds not District liability.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds shall not constitute an indebtedness of the District. The Bonds are not general obligations of the District and are not secured by a pledge of or involve the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District. The Bonds are the special limited obligations of the District payable solely from the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Property. Nothing contained in the Bonds, or in the related financing documents and closing documents, shall create an obligation on the part of the District to make payments with respect to the Bonds from sources other than the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Revenue. The Bonds do not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in § 1-206.02(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person, including, but not limited to, any bondholder, shall have any claims against the District or any of its elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents for monetary damages suffered as a result of the failure of the District to perform any covenant, undertaking, or obligation under this chapter, the Bonds, the financing documents, or the closing documents, or as a result of the incorrectness of any representation in or omission from the financing documents or the closing documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District and the electric company shall take such actions as may be reasonably necessary so that the Bonds are not treated as debt on the electric company’s books and records under United States generally accepted accounting principles or by a major United States rating agency, and the Commission shall not take any action or issue any order that may have a contrary effect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in this chapter shall obligate the electric company to take any action or execute any document that would have the effect of causing the Bonds to be treated as debt on the electric company’s books and records under United States generally accepted accounting principles or by a major United States rating agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
