<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1313.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1313.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1313_08">
        <akn:num>34-1313.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Content of application and plan.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An application to the Commission by the electric company and DDOT for approval of the triennial Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 90 days after the Underground Infrastructure Improvements Projects Plan is approved by the Commission, the electric company and DDOT shall identify the estimated start date and projected end date for each project approved in the plan. In determining the construction start date and projected end date, the electric company and DDOT shall consider the following secondary criteria:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The electric company and DDOT shall include the following information for the Underground Infrastructure Improvements Project Plan in the application:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the primary selection criteria set forth in subsection (a) of this section, the Commission may, on its own motion or upon request by the electric company, OPC, or any other party, waive the application of these criteria as to the selection of a particular mainline primary and lateral feeder when to do so is required to relieve an emergency or to correct or forestall a gross inequity or disparity in the customer impacts associated with past, current, or anticipated electric distribution service outages or when actual field conditions or coordination with other projects or such other considerations as the Commission may find reasonably justifies modification of the selection criteria.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1313_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the foregoing, nothing in this section shall require the electric company to obtain Commission authorization to construct and operate a new underground electric plant or impair the Commission’s authority to determine just and reasonable rates with respect to the electric company’s recovery of costs associated with the construction and operation of the underground electric plant, including capital costs, when such costs are to be recovered through rates, as approved by the Commission pursuant to § 34-901 and not through the DDOT Underground Electric Utility Infrastructure Improvement Charges or Underground Project Charges.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
