<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1252.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1252.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1252_01">
        <akn:num>34-1252.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment; Director; General Counsel.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established within the executive branch, as a subordinate agency, the Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment. The Office shall be responsible for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall be administered by an Director who shall be appointed by the Mayor and shall be subject to confirmation by the Council pursuant to § 1-523.01. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director shall become a bona fide resident of the District within 180 days after the effective date of confirmation by the Council and shall remain a District resident for the duration of the appointment. Failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency shall result in forfeiture of the appointment. The Director shall not have, or have had within 2 years preceding his or her nomination, any ownership or business interest of over 5% in, or a substantial business affiliation with, any cable operator in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The duties of the Director shall include the general administration of the Office, the preparation of the budget, hiring of staff, maintaining records, administering and enforcing the provisions of this chapter and regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter, and such other duties required by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall establish an Office of the General Counsel within the Office. The Office of the General Counsel shall be headed by a General Counsel appointed by the Director with the approval of the Director of the Mayor’s Office of Legal Counsel. The General Counsel, with the consent of the Director and the approval of the Director of the Mayor’s Office of Legal Counsel, may appoint Assistant General Counsels. The General Counsel shall have significant experience with cable regulation matters.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There shall be established within the Office a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_d_2">
      <akn:num>(d-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director may establish other offices and divisions as the Director determines are in the interest of the Office and the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1252_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director may appoint a Director of Programming to be the station manager of the government channels.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
