<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1312.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-1312.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_1312_04">
        <akn:num>34-1312.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond details.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to take any action reasonably necessary or appropriate in accordance with this chapter in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, security for, and payment of the Bonds of each series, including, but not limited to, determinations of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds shall contain a legend which shall provide that the Bonds do not constitute an indebtedness of the District, that the Bonds are not general obligations of the District and are not secured by the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District. The legend shall further state that the Bonds are special limited obligations of the District payable solely from the revenues derived from the collection of DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Revenue. The legend shall also state that the Bonds do not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings, as prohibited in § 1-206.02(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor and attested by the Secretary of the District by the Secretary’s manual or facsimile signature.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the Bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds of any series may be issued in accordance with the terms of an indenture to be entered into by the District and a trustee to be selected by the Mayor, and may be subject to the terms of one or more agreements entered into by the District pursuant to § 1-204.90(a)(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time during the 10-year period specified in § 34-1312.02(a) in one or more issues and in one or more series.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The Bonds and the interest on the Bonds and the income from the Bonds, and all monies pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of the Bonds, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District covenants and agrees that it will not limit or alter the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Revenue pledged to secure the Bonds or the basis on which the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Revenue is collected or allocated, will not take any action to impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the Bonds, and will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders of the Bonds, until the Bonds, together with interest on the Bonds, and all costs and expenses in connection with any suit, action, or proceeding by or on behalf of the holders of the Bonds, are fully met and discharged. This covenant and agreement of the District shall be included as part of the contract between the District and the holders of the Bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter constitutes a contract between the District and the holders of the Bonds. To the extent that any acts or resolutions of the Council may be in conflict with this chapter, this chapter shall be controlling.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-1312_04_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consistent with § 1-204.90(a)(4)(B):</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
