<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_2202_04">
        <akn:num>34-2202.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of a board of directors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any Board member or alternate who is an employee of the District government, including an elected official, shall be removed from the Board upon leaving the employment of the District government or elected office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any Board member or alternate who is an employee of the government of one of the other participating jurisdictions, including an elected official, may, upon leaving the employment of the government or elected office, have his or her membership on the Board terminated by the Mayor or, at the Mayor’s initiative, following consultation with the appropriate official set forth in subsection (a)(3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Board members and alternates shall serve 4-year terms. Of the 11 Board members and alternates initially appointed to the Board, 3 District appointees and 2 other participating jurisdiction appointees shall serve 4-year terms, 2 District appointees and 2 other participating jurisdiction appointees shall serve 3-year terms, and 1 District appointee and 1 other participating jurisdiction appointee shall serve 2-year terms.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person appointed to fill a vacancy on the Board shall be appointed only for the unexpired term of the Board member whose vacancy is being filled. If any Board member or alternate is appointed to fill an unexpired term with more than 2 years remaining in the term, upon expiration of the term, that Board member or alternate shall be deemed to have served a full 4-year term. At the end of a term, a Board member or alternate shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall appoint a chairperson of the Board from among the 6 District Board members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall remove any Board member or alternate from office for misconduct or neglect of duty, as defined by the Board in its by-laws, or for other good cause, after notice to the Board member. Prior to removing a Board member or alternate appointed pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section, the Mayor shall consult with the official or officials who recommended the Board member or alternate. The Mayor shall also remove a Board member or alternate appointed pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section upon the request of the official or officials who recommended the board member or alternate, if grounds exist for removal under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Should a Board member or alternate be indicted for the commission of a felony, the Board member or alternate shall be automatically suspended from serving on the Board. Upon a final determination of guilt, the term of the Board member or alternate shall be automatically terminated. Upon a final determination of innocence, the Mayor may reinstate the Board member or alternate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All Board meetings shall be subject to the provisions of § 1-207.42.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before any meeting of the Board, Board members shall be notified of the meeting. Six Board members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The existence of a quorum and an affirmative vote of a majority of the members present, who are permitted to participate in the matter under consideration, shall be required to approve any Board action; except, that 7 affirmative votes shall be required for approval of the Authority’s budget and 8 affirmative votes shall be required for the hiring or firing of the General Manager. No vacancy in membership shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise all rights and perform all duties of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_04_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Board member not otherwise compensated by the District or one of the other participating jurisdictions shall be entitled to compensation by the Authority at the rate of $50 per meeting, not to exceed $4,000 per year. Board members shall not be entitled to reimbursement for expenses, except that transportation, parking, or mileage expenses incurred in the performance of official duties of the Board may be reimbursed, not to exceed $20 per meeting.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
