<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2401.25"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2401.25/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_2401_25">
        <akn:num>34-2401.25</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Water and water service supplied for the use of the government of the United States.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2401_25_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All water and water services furnished from the District water supply system through any connection thereto for direct use by the government of the United States or any department, independent establishment, or agency thereof, situated in the District, except water and water services furnished to the United States for the maintenance, operation, and extension of the water system, shall be paid for at the rates for the furnishing and readiness to furnish water applicable to other water consumers in the District. All water and water services furnished from the District water supply system through any connection thereto for direct use by the government of the United States or any department, independent establishment, or agency thereof, situated outside the District in the States of Maryland or Virginia, except water and water services furnished to the United States for the maintenance, operation, and extension of the water system, shall be paid for at rates comparable to those which may be in effect and charged to state, municipal, or county agencies or other political authorities or jurisdictions within the respective states wherein said federal facilities may be situated for similar water service from the District water supply system; provided, that conditions as to water pressure, quantity, rates of demand, and points of connection available or permissible at any time for service outside the District, if any, shall be fixed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia so as to fully protect the prior interests of water consumers within the District; provided further, that as a condition of service, at each point of federal connection to the water system of the District for service outside the District there shall be installed and maintained at the expense of the department, independent establishment, or agency of the United States which is to use water therefrom a suitable meter or meters and incidental vaults, valves, piping and recording devices, and such other equipment as the Mayor in his discretion deems necessary to control and record the use of water through each such connection. As an additional condition of service, the department, agency, or establishment which is responsible for the maintenance of any such meter shall provide the Mayor (acting through the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority) with such access to the meter as the Mayor may require to measure the actual usage of the department, agency, or establishment (including any entity under the jurisdiction of the department, agency, or establishment) for purposes of making the adjustments to annual estimates required under ยง 34-2401.25a(1). Payment shall be made as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2401_25_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2401_25_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section may be construed to require the District of Columbia to seek payment for water services directly from any Federal entity which is under the jurisdiction of a department, independent establishment, or agency which is required to make a payment for such services under this section, or to allocate any amounts charged for such services among the entities which are under the jurisdiction of any such department, independent establishment, or agency. Each Federal department, independent establishment, and agency receiving water from the District of Columbia shall be responsible for allocating billings for such services among entities under the jurisdiction of the department, establishment, or agency, and shall be responsible for collecting amounts from such entities for any payments made to the District of Columbia under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2401_25_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of water services provided to a department, independent establishment, or agency in Virginia through the Federally owned water main system, if the total of the metered amounts billed for all individual users of the system (as measured by the meters for each individual user) is less than the total amount as measured by the meters at the delivery points into the system at the Francis Scott Key Bridge, the District government shall collect, and the Secretary of Defense shall pay, the difference to the District government in accordance with the requirements for collecting and making payments under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
