<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2002"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2002/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_2002">
        <akn:num>34-2002</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Regulation of local exchange carriers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Public Service Commission may, upon petition by the incumbent local exchange carrier and pursuant to procedures developed by the PSC, reclassify any telecommunications service offered by the incumbent local exchange carrier.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to the federal Telecommunications Act of 1996 (Public Law 104-104), the Public Service Commission shall establish a procedure to facilitate entry into the District for providers of all forms of telecommunications service in order to foster the availability of competitive telecommunications options to consumers in the District, and to encourage the development of a technological infrastructure which will afford District residents increased access to the information highway.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The procedure established by the Public Service Commission shall provide that local exchange carriers will be regulated according to each LEC’s respective market power in the local exchange market, and in such manner as to prohibit abuse of monopoly power and facilitate adjustments in pricing as developing competition dictates a need for market flexibility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Statement of Business Operations required by this section shall contain, at a minimum, the following information of each telecommunications service provider:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All local exchange carriers authorized by the PSC to provide service within the District must file and maintain tariffs with the Public Service Commission for each service offered within the District. The tariffs shall describe the service being offered, list all terms and conditions, and specify the rate or rates charged for the service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Tariffs of competitive telecommunications service providers shall not be regulated or otherwise reviewed by the Public Service Commission, except as otherwise specified in subsection (h) of this section, for interconnection, and in § 34-2003 for Universal Service Trust Fund subsidies. Tariffs filed by competitive telecommunications providers shall be deemed just and reasonable. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the Public Service Commission shall not regulate, fix, or prescribe the tolls, charges, rate structure, terms and conditions of service, rate base, rate of return, operating margin, earnings, cost of service, or the issuance of debt, equity, or other securities of any competitive telecommunications service provider, except that nothing in this chapter shall limit the authority of the PSC to establish service quality standards for such telecommunications service providers, to regulate terms and conditions of service (but not including rates, charges, and rate structure) to protect the public safety and welfare, provide for continued quality of telecommunications service, and safeguard the rights of consumers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All local exchange carriers in the District are required to unbundle network elements to the extent that federal law requires, and to interconnect networks and exchange local exchange service calls under terms that are reasonable and efficient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_h_1">
      <akn:num>(h-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a violation of any provision of this chapter or a violation of any rule or order issued under this chapter, after notice and a hearing, the Commission may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_h_2">
      <akn:num>(h-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_h_3">
      <akn:num>(h-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission may temporarily suspend a certification, issue a temporary cease and desist order, or take any other appropriate temporary remedial action, pending a final determination after notice and hearing, if the Commission determines that there is reasonable cause to believe that customers or the reliability of the telecommunications service in the District of Columbia will be harmed by the actions of a telecommunications service provider.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_h_4">
      <akn:num>(h-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A proceeding under this section may be initiated by the Commission, the Office of the People’s Counsel, the Office of the Attorney General, or any aggrieved party.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_h_5">
      <akn:num>(h-5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In connection with a proceeding under this section, a telecommunications service provider shall provide to the Commission access to any accounts, books, papers, and documents which the Commission considers necessary to resolve the matter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Regulation of the Bell Operating Company:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The BOC may petition the Public Service Commission for an alternative form of regulation, or for forbearance of regulation. The Public Service Commission shall approve or disapprove a plan for alternative regulation or for forbearance within 270 days of the BOC filing its petition, after notice and a public hearing, provided it finds that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 30 days of September 9, 1996, and pursuant to the authority given to State Commissions under the federal Telecommunications Act of 1996, the Public Service Commission shall initiate a proceeding to address and resolve the issues associated with competition in the local exchange, including, but not limited to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Public Service Commission order, including appropriate findings of fact and conclusions of law, resulting from the proceeding required pursuant to subsection (k) of this section shall be issued no later than 12 months subsequent to the initiation of that proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the Public Service Commission shall expend no more than $250,000, and the Office of the People’s Counsel shall expend no more than $150,000 for the proceeding required by subsection (k) of this section unless either of those agencies presents to the Council of the District of Columbia a written determination that funds in excess of these amounts will be required to carry out the provisions of subsections (k) and (l) of this section along with a resolution requesting authorization to expend a specific additional amount, and that resolution shall be deemed approved if not disapproved by the Council within a 30-day period of review.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2002_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 12 months of September 9, 1996, or upon a finding of the PSC, whichever is earlier, the Public Service Commission shall promulgate rules in respect to the notice requirements for abandonment of any service, and delineate the responsibilities, if any, incumbent upon the telecommunications service provider consequent to service abandonment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
