<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_2202_05">
        <akn:num>34-2202.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties of the Board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall have the following duties:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall prepare, within 120 days after the end of each District government fiscal year, a detailed annual report setting forth a description of the Authority’s operations and accomplishments during the year and shall transmit copies of the report to the Mayor and the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall contract with an independent certified public accountant to perform an annual audit of the books and accounts of the Authority and shall submit the audit to the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, and the Inspector General.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall annually develop, adopt, and submit to the Mayor a multiyear financial plan for capital and operating expenses encompassing at least the forthcoming 5 fiscal years. The plan shall be submitted to the Mayor no less than 90 days prior to the beginning of each District government fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall carry insurance sufficient to protect the Authority, the Board, the Board members, officers, and employees of the Board, its lessees or occupants, the District government, and other participating jurisdictions against risks associated with the exercise by the Authority or the Board of any authority conferred by this chapter; provided, however, that no Board member shall be personally liable for any act or omission of the Authority, except with regard to any fraudulent or criminally prosecutable act committed by a Board member in connection with an act or omission of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
