<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_2202_07">
        <akn:num>34-2202.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Water and Sewer Enterprise Fund; assets of the Water and Sewer Utility Administration of the Department of Public Works; transfer of funds and assets; pledge of revenues.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established the Water and Sewer Authority Enterprise Fund (“Fund”) which shall be the successor to the Water and Sewer Enterprise Fund established pursuant to § 47-375(g). The Fund shall be operated by the Authority in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the provisions made by the Authority pursuant to this subchapter for security of revenue bonds, all revenues, proceeds, and moneys from whatever source derived, except those collected or received from the storm water fee, which are collected or received by the Authority shall be credited to the Fund and shall not, at any time, be transferred to, lapse into, or be commingled with the General Fund of the District of Columbia, the Cash Management Pool, or any other funds or accounts of the District of Columbia, except that funds shall be transferred to the District of Columbia Treasurer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any pledge by the Authority of any funds on deposit in the Fund shall be effective, valid, perfected, and binding from the time the pledge is made with or without the delivery of any funds, and with or without any further action. Such pledge shall be effective, valid, perfected, and binding whether or not any statement, document, or instrument relating to such pledge is recorded or filed. The pledged revenues shall be immediately subject to the lien of the pledge, whether or not there has been any physical delivery. The lien of any pledge shall be valid and binding against all parties having claims of any kind in tort, contract, or otherwise against any person receiving distribution of revenues whether or not the parties have notice of the pledge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days of April 18, 1996, the Mayor shall cause to be performed an independent audit of the assets and liabilities of the Department of Public Works, Water and Sewer Utility Administration. The independent audit shall also determine the present day value of services provided by the District government during the preceding 20-year period to the Water and Sewer Utility Administration, or any of its predecessor administrations or agencies. The audit shall determine the amount and adequacy of any funding provided by the Water and Sewer Utility Administration for these services. The Mayor shall provide the Council with a final version of the independent audit. Based upon the results of the independent audit, and notwithstanding the provisions of §§ 1-315.01 through 1-315.07, the Mayor shall, through an intra-District government transfer, permit the Authority to use any assets the Mayor considers to be required for the Authority’s operations upon such terms and conditions as the Mayor finds appropriate, and shall transfer any liabilities that are directly attributable to the water distribution system or sewage collection, treatment, and disposal systems, other than the general obligation bonds referred to in subsection (f) of this section. The District government shall retain full legal title to, and a complete equitable interest in, all assets made available for the Authority’s use. Pending the intra-District government transfer required by this subsection, all assets and liabilities of the Water and Sewer Utility Administration, as indicated on the balance sheet prepared by the Water and Sewer Utility Administration just prior to April 18, 1996, shall be transferred for the Authority’s use on an interim basis. Assets made available to the Authority pursuant to this subsection shall remain under the control of the Authority for as long as Authority revenue bonds are outstanding, unless all of the outstanding revenue bonds are defeased pursuant to § 34-2202.13, or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall transfer to the General Fund of the District funds necessary for the District to make debt service payments on District general obligation bonds related to the Department of Public Works, Water and Sewer Utility Administration. The payments shall be in the amount and made at such times as the Treasurer of the District of Columbia requires in writing, and the payments shall continue until the District’s general obligations bonds related to the Department of Public Works, Water and Sewer Utility Administration are fully paid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
