<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-2202.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_2202_10">
        <akn:num>34-2202.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Delegation of Council authority to issue bonds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may stipulate by resolution the terms for sale of its bonds in accordance with this chapter, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may sell its bonds at public or private sale and may determine the price for sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A resolution authorizing the sale of bonds may contain any of the following provisions, in which case these provisions shall be made part of the contract with holders of the bonds:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A pledge of the Authority is binding from the time it is made. Any funds, or property pledged, are subject to the lien of a pledge without physical delivery. The lien of a pledge is binding as against parties having any tort, contract, or other claim against the Authority regardless of notice. Neither the resolution stipulating the terms for sale of Authority bonds nor any other instrument creating a pledge need be recorded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The signature of any officer of the Authority which appears on a bond shall remain valid if that person ceases to hold office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may secure bonds by a trust indenture between the Authority and a corporate trustee that has trust company powers within the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A trust indenture of the Authority may contain provisions for protecting and enforcing the rights and remedies of holders of the revenue bonds in accordance with the provisions of the resolution authorizing the sale of bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to preexisting agreements with the holders of the revenue bonds, the Authority may purchase its own revenue bonds which may then be cancelled. The price the Authority pays in purchasing its own revenue bonds shall not exceed the following limits:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may establish special or reserve accounts in furtherance of its authority under this chapter. Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section and other applicable District law, and subject to agreements with holders of the bonds, the Authority shall manage its own funds, and may invest funds not required for disbursement in a manner consistent with industry practices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds of the Authority are legal instruments in which public officers and public bodies of the District, insurance companies, insurance company associations, and other persons carrying on an insurance business, banks, bankers, banking institutions, including savings and loan associations, building and loan associations, trust companies, savings banks, savings associations, investment companies, and other persons carrying on a banking business, administrators, guardians, executors, trustees and other fiduciaries, and other persons authorized to invest in bonds or in other obligations of the District, may legally invest funds, including capital, in their control. The bonds are also securities which legally may be deposited with, and received by, public officers and public bodies of the District or any agency of the District for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or other obligations of the District is authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The revenue bonds shall be special obligations of the District. The bonds shall be without recourse to the District. The bonds shall not be general obligations of the District, shall not be a pledge of or involve the faith and credit or the taking power of the District, shall not constitute a debt of the District, shall not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in ยง 1-206.02(a)(2), and shall not constitute debt for purposes of ยง 1-206.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The revenue bonds shall not give rise to any pecuniary liability to the District and the District shall have no obligation with respect to the purchase of the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in the revenue bonds, in the financing documents, or in the closing documents shall create any obligation on the part of the District to make payments with respect to the bonds from sources other than those listed for that purpose in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-2202_10_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District shall not have liability for the payment of any issuance costs or for any transaction or event to be effected by the financing documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
