<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-303"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-303/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_303">
        <akn:num>34-303</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Inspectors of gas and electric meters; inspection of meters; Commission to make rules and regulations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-303_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall appoint inspectors of gas meters, whose duty it shall be, when required by the Commission, to inspect, examine, and ascertain the accuracy of gas meters used or intended to be used for measuring and ascertaining the quantity of gas furnished for light, heat, or power by any person or corporation to or for the use of any person or corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-303_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No corporation or person shall furnish, set, or put in use any gas meter which shall not have been inspected and proved for accuracy, or any meter the type of which shall not have been approved by the Commission or by an inspector of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-303_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall appoint inspectors of electric meters, whose duty it shall be, when required by the Commission, to inspect, examine, and ascertain the accuracy of any and all electric meters used or intended to be used for measuring and ascertaining the quantity of electric current furnished for light, heat, or power by any person or corporation to or for the use of any person or corporation, and to inspect, examine, and ascertain the accuracy of all apparatus for testing and proving the accuracy of electric meters; and when found to be or made to be correct the inspector shall stamp or mark all such meters and apparatus with some suitable device, which device shall be recorded in the office of the Commission. No corporation or person shall furnish, set, or put in use any electric meter the type of which shall not have been approved by the Commission or any meter not approved by an inspector of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-303_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every person shall provide, repair, and maintain such suitable premises and apparatus and facilities as may be required and approved by the Commission for testing and proving the accuracy of gas and electric meters furnished for use by it, and by which apparatus every meter may be tested.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-303_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any consumer to whom a meter has been furnished shall request the Commission in writing to inspect such meter, the Commission shall have the same inspected and tested; if the same, on being so tested, shall be found to be more than 2 per centum defective or incorrect to the prejudice of the consumer, the inspector shall order the person furnishing the meter forthwith to remove the same and to place instead a correct meter, and the expense of such inspection and test shall be borne by the person; if the same, on being so tested, shall be found to be correct, the expense of such inspection and test shall be borne by the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-303_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall prescribe such rules and regulations to carry into effect the provisions of this section as it may deem necessary and shall fix uniform reasonable charges for the inspection and testing of meters upon complaint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
