<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-706"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/34-706/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_34_706">
        <akn:num>34-706</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Failure to perform duty or obey Commission order; violation of pipeline safety regulation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-706_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any public utility shall violate any provision of this subtitle, or shall do any act herein prohibited, or shall fail or refuse to perform any duty enjoined upon it for which a penalty has not been provided, or shall fail, neglect, or refuse to obey any lawful requirement or order made by the Commission, or any judgment or decree made by any court upon its application, for every such violation, failure, or refusal such public utility shall forfeit and pay to the District of Columbia the sum of $5,000 for each such offense. In construing and enforcing the provisions of this section, the act, omission, or failure of any officer, agent, or other person acting for or employed by any public utility acting within the scope of his employment and instructions shall in every case be deemed to be the act, omission, or failure of such public utility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-706_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates any regulation issued by the Commission governing safety of pipeline facilities and the transportation of gas, shall be subject to a civil penalty as set forth in the Commission’s regulations, Title 15 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (15 DCMR), for each violation for each day that violation persists. Civil penalties established by the Commission shall not exceed maximum civil penalties established by federal laws and regulations governing the safety of pipeline facilities and the transportation of gas.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-706_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commission may adjudicate the occurrence of a violation under this section and impose sanctions in accordance with its regulations. Any such civil penalty may be compromised by the Commission. In determining the amount of such penalty, or the amount agreed upon in compromise, the appropriateness of such penalty to the size of the business of the person charged, the gravity of the violation, and the good faith of the person charged in attempting to achieve compliance, after notification of a violation, shall be considered. The amount of such penalty when finally determined, or the amount agreed upon in compromise, may be deducted from any sums owing by the District of Columbia to the person charged or may be recovered in a civil action in the District of Columbia courts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-706_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In connection with a proceeding under this section, a public utility shall provide to the Commission access to any accounts, books, papers, and documents which the Commission considers necessary to resolve the matter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_34-706_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
