<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/37-101"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/37-101/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_37_101">
        <akn:num>37-101</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agricultural products” means vegetables, fruits, grains, mushrooms, honey, plants, plant cuttings, flowers, herbs, nuts, seeds, bulbs, and rootstock and includes baked or processed foods that are:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Antiques” means items of personal property manufactured or made more than 100 years ago.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Artist” means an individual who created the works of art offered for sale and includes two or more individuals who work together in creating individual works of art offered for sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Center hall” means the 3,160 square feet of the Eastern Market building on the first and second floors that is between the South Hall and North Hall and which, on April 16, 1999, contained a pottery studio and bathrooms.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chief Property Management Officer” (“CPMO”) means the Chief Property Management Officer of the District of Columbia Department of General Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community Arts Center” means a space operated for the promotion of the arts including performances, exhibitions, sales, demonstrations and instruction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community group” means any District-based not-for-profit association or organization whose mission in some way serves the interests of the District’s residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Compatible or complementary uses” means uses similar to the other permitted uses of Eastern Market Square or uses that would enhance and not detract from those uses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Crafter” means an individual who created the hand-crafted goods offered for sale and includes two or more individuals who work together in creating individual hand-crafted goods offered for sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eastern Market” means the building at Lot 800, Square 872 in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee” (“EMCAC”), means the advisory committee created in § 37-111.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eastern Market Special Use Area” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eastern Market Square” means the area between the south curb of North Carolina Avenue, S.E., and the north curb of C Street, S.E., and between the west curb of 7th Street, S.E., and the building line with the Capitol Hill Natatorium.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eastern Market Tenants Council” means an Eastern Market tenants’ group comprised of one representative of each major activity, including, but not limited to, the farmers, South Hall stall holders, Center Hall tenants, North Hall tenants, arts and crafts market vendors, and flea market vendors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Farmer” means a market vendor who sells agricultural products, of which at least 70%, during the April-November harvest season was: (A) grown on land owned or leased by the market vendor; (B) grown on land neighboring the land owned or leased by the market vendor; (C) obtained directly from others who have grown the product on land which is owned or leased by the producer; or (D) in the non-harvest season of December-March, a market vendor who sells agricultural products in the harvest season, of which at least 30% was either (A), (B), or (C) of this paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Farmers’ line” means that portion of the Eastern Market Square (under the existing shed) and extending north to North Carolina Avenue, S.E., and south of the shed along the sidewalk of 7th Street, S.E., to C Street, S.E., as well as the portion of the Eastern Market square between Eastern Market and the curb of C Street, S.E.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Food merchant” means a market vendor who sells agricultural products or prepared food, both home-grown and food obtained from wholesalers, but primarily from food wholesalers, to retail customers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Food wholesaler” means vendors who sell agricultural products grown by themselves and others to a food merchant for resale to retail customers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hand-crafted goods” means items produced or created from raw or basic materials that are changed into a significantly different shape, design, form or function using a special skill, trade or manual art.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Importers of hand-crafted and indigenous goods” means market vendors who sell items that are ethno-specific and are designed, produced and representative of the country of origin and purchased by the applicant in the country of origin or imported by the market vendor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Market manager” means a person or persons, having experience relevant to operating an historic urban fresh food or farmers’ market, employed to provide unified and coordinated management for the Eastern Market Special Use Area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Market vendor” means an individual, association or corporation (including, but not limited to, any partnership, society, club, joint-stock company, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, or referee, and any combination of individuals acting as a unit) with a currently enforceable contract or agreement with the market manager and engaged in selling any good in or about the Eastern Market Square and includes any artist, any crafter, any farmer and any merchant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“North Hall” means the 4,500 square feet of space on the ground floor of the North end of Eastern Market.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“North Plaza” means that portion of Eastern Market Square bounded by the private right of way on the west, North Carolina Avenue, S.E., on the north, the Farmers’ Line on the east, and the north face of the Eastern Market building on the south.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sidewalk market” means the areas, covered and uncovered, between the building and the street curbs on the south, east and north sides of the Eastern Market building on the Eastern Market Square.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sidewalk market stall” means a sidewalk space of at least 32 square feet (normally eight feet by four feet) within which a market vendor is permitted to display and sell goods.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“South Hall” means the 9,500 square feet of the ground floor and basement of the Eastern Market building at the southern end of the building closest to C Street, S.E.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tenant” means an individual, association or corporation (including, but not limited to, any partnership, society, club, joint-stock company, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, or referee, and any combination of individuals acting as a unit) but not limited to organizations and community groups having a written contract with the market manager to occupy space inside the Eastern Market building.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Vintage goods or collectibles” means any items of personal property previously purchased at retail.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-101_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Works of art” means drawings, paintings, sculptures, photographs, ornamental textiles, ornamental glass, ornamental pottery, and any other items created primarily for aesthetic appreciation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
