<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/37-111"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/37-111/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_37_111">
        <akn:num>37-111</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby established the Eastern Market Community Advisory Committee (“EMCAC”) to be comprised of no more than 11 voting members. The EMCAC shall be comprised as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the EMCAC shall represent, and be appointed or elected by his or her constituency, in accordance with its internal procedures except that the independent member, as set out in subsection (a)(4) of this section, shall be selected by the EMCAC for such membership after such positions are advertised to the community for no less than 30 days. The initial selection shall be made as soon as practicable after formation of the EMCAC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the EMCAC shall serve for 2-year terms, except that the representative from ANC 6B shall not serve for any period longer than his or her service as a Commissioner. ANC 6B shall identify the EMCAC representative within 45 days after April 16, 1999. To create staggered terms, the initial non-ANC members shall determine by lot that half shall serve for one year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With the exception of the voting representatives of the food market vendors and non-food market vendors, no member of the EMCAC shall have an economic interest in, or fiduciary responsibility for, any business or other activity operated or conducted on the Eastern Market Square, or subject to control or regulation under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All members of the EMCAC shall serve without compensation. Direct expenses may be reimbursed according to policies to be determined by the EMCAC. The EMCAC may establish a bank account and receive and disburse funds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The members of the EMCAC shall meet no later than 45 days of April 16, 1999, and shall establish suitable bylaws governing its operations, including provisions for the election of a chair, vice-chair and other offices as deemed necessary. Within 90 days after December 7, 2004, the EMCAC shall revise its bylaws to be consistent with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The EMCAC shall have the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The EMCAC shall be involved in any Eastern Market renovation as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The EMCAC shall create at least two standing committees as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the provisions of this chapter and relevant regulation, the EMCAC may propose, and shall review and advise on recommendations by the market manager, to amend standards, operational guidelines, and rules for the conduct of operations and activities at Eastern Market and the Eastern Market Square. In making proposals, or considering recommendations, the market manager and the EMCAC shall take into account:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37-111_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provided the Mayor or his designee approves gifts and donations, the EMCAC may promote and seek outside funding for the preservation and enhancement of Eastern Market and the Eastern Market Square, through fund-raising events, contributions, grants, sales, the establishment of an endowment and other appropriate activities. Any funds raised in this way shall be deposited into the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
