<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-1302.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-1302.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_1302_03">
        <akn:num>4-1302.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Access to Register; release of information generally.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff which maintains the Child Protection Register shall grant access to information contained in said Register only to the following persons:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The investigators of a report may divulge the information obtained from the Child Protection Register to medical professionals for the purpose of obtaining a diagnosis of the child who is the subject of the report.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each person seeking access to the Child Protection Register shall show identification satisfactory to the staff which maintains said Register before access is allowed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff which maintains the Child Protection Register shall not release to those persons identified in paragraphs (5), (6), and (7) of subsection (a) of this section any information that identifies the source of a report or the witnesses to the incident referred to in a report unless said staff first obtains permission from the source of the report or from the witnesses named in the report.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff which maintains the Child Protection Register shall release only that information which is necessary for the purpose of the request and which does not violate the confidentiality of the persons identified in the report, except as is necessary to meet the requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff which maintains the Child Protection Register shall not release the information contained in said Register to another jurisdiction unless:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff which maintains the Child Protection Register shall maintain a record of each release of information, which record shall contain the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1302_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The information in the Child Protection Register shall be released orally only to the Metropolitan Police Department, to the Office of the Attorney General, and to personnel of the Agency and of the Social Services Agency of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia when they are investigating a report. Any release of information to other persons listed in subsection (a) of this section or pursuant to ยง 4-1302.04 shall be preceded by a written request from the person requesting the information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
