<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-1341.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-1341.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_1341_03">
        <akn:num>4-1341.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Board of Directors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A self-perpetuating Board of Directors is established to manage the affairs of the Trust Fund. The Board of Directors shall have 15 members.  The D.C. Treasurer and the Director of the Department of Human Services shall serve as members of the Board of Directors. The remaining 13 members shall have a demonstrated knowledge in the area of child abuse and child neglect prevention and shall reflect a diversity of gender and ethnicity. Each ward in the District shall be represented on the Board of Directors. Through its by-laws, the Board of Directors may expand the number of members of the Board to include a business representative.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The D.C. Treasurer and the Director of the Department of Human Services shall serve terms as members of the Board of Directors for the same duration as the terms of their offices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The 12 initial nongovernmental members shall serve the following terms: 3 members shall serve 3 years; 5 members shall serve 2 years; and 4 members shall serve 1 year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The 12 initial nongovernmental members shall be appointed by resolution of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event that 1 of the 12 initial nongovernmental members is unable to serve or is removed, the remaining members shall select a replacement member according to the representational requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors shall appoint nongovernmental replacement members so that subsequent Board of Directors meet the representational requirements of subsection (a) of this section and the bylaws adopted by the Board of Directors. A succeeding member shall serve the balance of the term of the member that he or she succeeds if the term is unexpired. A succeeding member who succeeds a member whose term has expired shall serve a term of 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members shall be compensated only for out-of-pocket expenses incurred from the accomplishment of their responsibilities as members of the Board of Directors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-1341_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors shall elect a chairperson from among the members. The Board of Directors may elect other officers and form committees as it considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
