<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_205_05">
        <akn:num>4-205.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_05_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Earned income” means income in cash or in kind produced as a result of the performance of services currently rendered by an individual. In the case of an applicant or recipient of TANF, the term “earned income” shall not include the amount of earned income credit payments actually received.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_05_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Family” means the total applicant or assistance unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_05_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross income” means total earned income before any deductions required by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_05_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Income” means earned or unearned money received by an individual that is of gain or benefit to the individual or assistance unit. The term “income” includes the following: wages; salary; gross income from self-employment; training allowances, stipends or other payments for work experience (to the extent that they are countable as income pursuant to § 4-205.13a); District public assistance payments; federal public assistance payments (to the extent permitted under federal law); pensions; retirement benefits; annuities; unemployment compensation; worker’s compensation; child support or alimony payments made directly to a member of the assistance unit from someone who is not a member of the assistance unit; interest; dividends; scholarships; rent received from a tenant or lessee; and money that is required by District or federal law to be deemed from a person who is not a member of the assistance unit. The term “income” does not include: a non-recurring lump-sum payment (which shall be considered a resource); payments made by a government agency to a third party for child care, housing, or medical assistance; a relocation payment under § 42-2851.05; or any payment that is specifically excluded by federal or District law from consideration as income for the purpose of determining eligibility for public assistance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_05_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mandatory deductions” means those deductions required by law or as a condition of employment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
