<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.19b"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.19b/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_205_19b">
        <akn:num>4-205.19b</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Job search and job readiness requirements for TANF applicants.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19b_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19b_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As a condition of eligibility, all work-eligible TANF applicants shall complete an employment program orientation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19b_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19b_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Following the assessment, each parent in a 2-parent assistance unit who is not engaged in paid employment for at least 35 hours per week (or an average of 140 hours per month) and who is not required to meet the school attendance requirements of ยง 4-205.65 shall be required to sign and comply with an agreement to participate in job search or job readiness activities as a condition of eligibility for TANF benefits, unless the TANF recipient is exempt pursuant to ยง 4-205.19f, or the other parent in the family is engaged in paid employment and the 2 parents together work for at least 35 hours per week (or for at least 55 hours per week, if the family receives federally-funded child care and no adult in the family has a disability, or caring for a child disability). The Mayor shall determine the nature and scope of the activities based on the assessment. In no event shall the Mayor require the TANF recipient to participate in job search or job readiness activities for more hours than would be necessary for the combined number of hours of participation of both parents to equal 35 hours per week (or 55 hours per week, if the family receives federally-funded child care and no adult in the family has a disability, or caring for a child with a disability).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19b_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall promulgate rules to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
