<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.19f"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.19f/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_205_19f">
        <akn:num>4-205.19f</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sanctions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19f_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19f_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not consider an applicant or recipient to have complied with program requirements until the individual participates satisfactorily for at least one week.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19f_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, if the Mayor cannot schedule the applicant or recipient for participation, by no fault of the applicant or recipient, the Mayor shall consider the applicant or recipient to have complied on the day the applicant or recipient notifies the Mayor that he or she agrees to participate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19f_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a sanction terminates because the TANF applicant or recipient complies with program requirements, the applicant or recipient shall not receive TANF benefits for the remainder of the month of compliance, and instead shall begin receiving TANF benefits again in the following month, for the following month, and for subsequent months so long as the recipient continues to comply and remains otherwise eligible.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19f_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A TANF applicant or recipient who is aggrieved by the Mayor’s action concerning a sanction may seek redress under subchapter X of this chapter. A TANF applicant or recipient who has been sanctioned shall not be entitled to a conciliation process.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19f_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a TANF recipient fails to complete his or her annual review or is otherwise terminated while under sanctions, and makes a new application for benefits, the TANF applicant shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
