<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.65"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.65/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_205_65">
        <akn:num>4-205.65</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Eligibility for public assistance; learnfare.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The types of schools that can be attended to meet the school attendance requirements of subsection (a) of this subsection are as follows: a public school, private school, independent school, parochial school, private instruction, or a course of study or home school program meeting the standards established by the Board for granting a high school equivalency diploma.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A pregnant or parenting teen who fails to meet the school attendance requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section shall be provided counseling, tutoring, or other supportive services deemed appropriate by the Department to help the pregnant or parenting teen improve school attendance, or in the case of a drop-out, to return to school. Such supportive services will be provided as appropriations are available and in accordance with regulations issued by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The determination of a pregnant or a parenting teen’s ineligibility for federally-funded TANF benefits made pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be effective for one month for each month that the pregnant or parenting teen fails to meet the school attendance requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section. In the case of a dropout, the sanctions shall remain in force until the dropout provides written proof from a school that the dropout has re-enrolled in school and met the school attendance requirements of subsection (a) of this section for one calendar month. Any month in which school is in session for at least 10 days may be used to meet the school attendance requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Department determines that a pregnant or parenting teen who has been determined ineligible for federally-funded TANF benefits pursuant to subsection (a) of this section has satisfied the requirements of subsection (d) of this section, the determination of ineligibility for federally-funded TANF benefits shall be rescinded in the next possible payment month. The pregnant or parenting teen shall not receive payment for the remainder of the month in which compliance occurs. The first payment that resumes after the pregnant or parenting teen complies with subsection (d) of this section may be delayed, depending on the date of compliance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A pregnant or parenting teen’s absence on any particular day shall be determined to be an excused or an unexcused absence based on the policies of the Board or other entity that determines the attendance policies at the teen’s educational institution or program. Notwithstanding such policies, a pregnant or parenting teen’s absence on a particular day shall be excused under the following circumstances:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The determination of a pregnant or parenting teen’s ineligibility for federally-funded TANF benefits provided by subsection (a) of this section shall not apply if the information about the pregnant or parenting teen’s school attendance is not available or cannot be verified by the school or the approved alternative educational or training program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The pregnant or parenting teen, or his or her parent, caretaker, or legal guardian, shall cooperate in providing information to verify enrollment information or good cause for absence from school. If at least one of these individuals does not cooperate, the pregnant or parenting teen shall be determined ineligible for federally-funded TANF benefits for each month in which one of the individuals does not cooperate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall request school attendance information for a pregnant or parenting teen compiled by a school whenever necessary to ascertain school attendance requirements as required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall request information from the pregnant or parenting teen’s school, institution, or educational program about the attendance of a pregnant or parenting teen who is applying for or receiving federally-funded TANF benefits, and shall otherwise implement procedures for monitoring compliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>School attendance records shall be open for inspection at all times to the Department or other persons authorized to enforce this section; provided, that prior written informed consent is given by the parent, caretaker, or legal guardian of a pregnant or parenting teen or by an emancipated pregnant or parenting teen.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be the duty of each person designated by the Superintendent of Schools, every parochial school teacher, every private school teacher, and every teacher who gives instruction privately, to provide information, upon the request of the Department, as soon as practicable to the Department concerning the school attendance of a pregnant or parenting teen who is applying for or receives federally-funded TANF benefits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_65_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall apply to all applicants for, or recipients of, federally-funded TANF benefits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
