<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.19c"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-205.19c/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_205_19c">
        <akn:num>4-205.19c</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Failure to comply with job search and job readiness requirements for TANF applicants.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19c_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a TANF applicant who is not exempt pursuant to ยง 4-205.19g(a) fails, without good cause, to participate in work activities pursuant to ยง 4-205.19b, the failure shall result in a sanction pursuant to ยง 4-205.19f.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19c_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall promulgate rules defining what constitutes good cause for failure to participate in work activities, in addition to those circumstances described in subsections (c), (d), and (e) of this subsection. The rules promulgated by the Mayor shall require that notice be provided to TANF applicants of what constitutes good cause for failure to participate in work activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19c_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not sanction a TANF applicant based on the failure of an applicant to participate in work activities if the Mayor has failed to make a preliminary assessment pursuant to ยง 4-205.19b(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19c_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not sanction a TANF applicant based on the failure of a TANF applicant to participate in work activities if the applicant is a single custodial parent caring for a child under 6 years old, and the applicant proves that he or she has a demonstrated inability, as determined by the Mayor, to obtain needed child care for one or more of the following reasons:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19c_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-205_19c_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (c), (d), or (e) of this section, the Mayor may sanction a TANF applicant if the applicant quits paid employment without good cause or voluntarily reduces income without good cause within 60 days before the determination of eligibility for TANF.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
