<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-201.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-201.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_201_01">
        <akn:num>4-201.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adult” means a person who is not a minor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_1B">
      <akn:num>(1B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Assistance unit” means all individuals whose needs, income and resources are considered in determining eligibility for, and the amount of, public assistance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_1C">
      <akn:num>(1C)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Caretaker relative” means a relative by blood, half-blood, or legal adoption caring for a dependent child, who is a child’s parent, or, if a parent is not in the home exercising responsibility for the care and control of the dependent child, the child’s sibling; aunt; uncle; first cousin; first cousin once removed; second cousin; nephew; niece; grandparent; step-parent; step-sibling; relative of a preceding generation as denoted by prefixes of grand-, great-, great-great-, or great-great-great-; or the spouse of a parent or other relative listed in this paragraph, even after the marriage is terminated by death or divorce.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_1D">
      <akn:num>(1D)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Human Services of the District of Columbia, or any successor organizational unit (in whole or in part).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“GAC” means the General Assistance for Children program established by § 4-205.05a.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Head of assistance unit” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the agents, agencies, officers, and employees designated by him or her to perform any function vested in them by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Minor” means a person who is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_5B">
      <akn:num>(5B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Parent” means a child’s natural or adoptive parent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_5C">
      <akn:num>(5C)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Parent who is the principal household income earner” means whichever parent, in a home in which both parents of a minor child are living, earned the greater amount of income in a 24-month period, the last month of which immediately preceded the month in which a TANF application was filed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_5D">
      <akn:num>(5D)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“POWER” means the Program on Work, Employment, and Responsibility established by § 4-205.72.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public assistance” means payment in or by money, medical care, remedial care, goods or services to, or for the benefit of, needy persons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Recipient” means a person to whom or on whose behalf public assistance is granted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means each of the states of the United States. The term “state” includes Puerto Rico, Guam, and the United States Virgin Islands.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Stepparent” means a person who is living in the home of a minor child for whom TANF or POWER is requested, and who is legally married to the natural or adoptive parent of the child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“TANF” means the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Program established by subchapter II of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-201_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“IV-D agency” means the organizational unit, or any successor organizational unit (in whole or in part), that is responsible for administering or supervising the administration of the District’s State Plan under title IV, Part D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.), pertaining to paternity establishment and the establishment, modification, and enforcement of child support orders and certain spousal support orders (those in which the spouse or former spouse is living with a child for whom the spousal support obligor also owes support).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
