<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-217.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-217.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_217_08">
        <akn:num>4-217.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Condition of eligibility — Cooperation in identifying and locating parents, establishing paternity, obtaining support payments, and other payments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-217_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As a condition of eligibility for assistance under programs specified in § 4-217.07, unless good cause for refusing to cooperate is determined to exist pursuant to § 4-217.09, each applicant for, or recipient of, assistance shall be required to cooperate in good faith with the District of Columbia in:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-217_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before requiring cooperation under this section, the Mayor shall notify the applicant or recipient in writing of the right to be excepted from the requirement upon a showing of good cause. The notice shall include each requirement applicable to a good cause determination, and facts concerning the benefits, risks, and consequences of cooperation and pursuing child support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-217_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor determines an applicant or recipient has failed to cooperate as required by subsection (a) of this section, without good cause, the IV-D agency shall promptly notify the applicant or recipient. The IV-D agency shall provide the basis for its determination of noncooperation in writing as part of the notice to the applicant or recipient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-217_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any applicant or recipient aggrieved by the action or inaction of the Mayor regarding the determination of cooperation, noncooperation, or good cause for refusal to cooperate shall be entitled to a hearing. Hearing rights shall be provided in accordance with subchapter X of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-217_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each District of Columbia government agency involved in the administration of public assistance or the enforcement of child support obligations under title IV-D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.) shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that the applicant’s, recipient’s, or child’s whereabouts are kept confidential and take other reasonable measures, within the agency’s scope of authority, that are necessary to protect the applicant or recipient and the child from harm in any case in which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
