<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_301">
        <akn:num>4-301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Adoption subsidy payments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the Mayor may conclude arrangements with persons or institutions at such rates as may be agreed upon.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any public agency or licensed child-placing agency, having a child with special needs in foster care or institutional care, or any foster parent having such a child in his home may recommend to the Mayor a subsidy for the adoption of such child, and may include in the recommendation advice as to the appropriate level of payments and any other information likely to assist the Mayor in carrying out the provisions of this section. The Mayor shall make the determination as to whether or not an appropriate adoptive home exists for the child, but in so doing the Mayor shall refer to the recommendations of the referring agency. If the Mayor concludes that the child referred is a child with special needs within the meaning of this section, and that an appropriate adoptive home exists for the child, the Mayor is authorized to enter into a tentative adoption subsidy agreement with the prospective adoptive family, and upon entering into such an agreement, the Mayor may accept a transfer of relinquishment of parental rights from the referring agency pursuant to § 4-1406.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a child in the custody of the Mayor or a licensed child-placing agency has been in foster care or institutional care for at least 6 months after the child is considered legally available for adoptive placement, the Mayor or agency shall inform the family or institution providing care of the possibility of financial aid for adoption under this section. If the family caring for the prospective adoptee applies to the Mayor for adoption of the child, and if it appears to the Mayor after study that the family would be an appropriate adoptive family for the child but for the family’s economic inability to meet the child’s needs, the Mayor shall enter into a tentative agreement with the family concerning the amount and duration of a proposed subsidy in the event the child is placed for adoption with that family. Thereafter the Mayor may accept a transfer of relinquishment of parental rights from the referring agency in appropriate cases. The Mayor shall in all cases take all steps necessary to assist the family in completing the legal and procedural requirements necessary to effectuate the adoption, including payment for legal fees and court costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No adoption subsidy payment shall be made on behalf of any child with respect to whom an adoption decree has been entered by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, pursuant to Chapter 3 of Title 16, prior to April 2, 1974.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Once during each calendar year the Mayor shall review the need for continuing each family’s subsidy. At the time of such review and at other times during the year when changed conditions, including variations in medical opinions, prognosis, and costs are deemed by the Mayor to warrant such action, appropriate adjustments in payments shall be made based upon changes in the needs of the child. Any parent who is a party to a subsidy agreement may at any time in writing request, for reasons set forth in the request, a review of the amount of any payment or the level of continuing payments. Such review shall be begun not later than 30 days from the receipt of the request. Any adjustment may be made retroactive to the date the request was received by the Mayor. If the request is not acted on within 30 days after it has been received by the Mayor, or if the Mayor modifies or terminates an agreement without the concurrence of all parties, any party to the agreement shall be entitled to a hearing under the applicable provisions of subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-301_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All rules and regulations adopted by the Mayor pursuant to §§ 4-116, 4-117, 4-301 and 4-302 shall be published in the District of Columbia Register as required by § 2-505.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
