<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-411"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-411/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_411">
        <akn:num>4-411</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Standards for in-home care.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In-home care within the child’s own home, by an in-home caregiver, shall be used only when other day care plans are not feasible and in-home care offers greater benefits to the mother or other responsible relative and the child;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In-home care may be provided, as appropriate and available, for children of eligible persons in training and during their subsequent employment, and for TANF or POWER children living with caretaker relatives (not parents) when day or night care is required due to employment of the caretaker relative;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In-home care shall be arranged by mutual agreement between the child’s own mother or caretaker relative, the in-home caregiver, and the Department;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Selection of the in-home caregiver shall be made by the parent, subject to final approval by the Department;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall make direct payments to the in-home caregiver for services rendered;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The in-home caregiver shall be of an age between 21 and 70 years;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The in-home caregiver shall furnish the Department with the same medical certification of good health as that required for licensed caregivers pursuant to § 403 (j) of Regulation No. 74-34 (Child Development Facilities Regulation). Further, the in-home caregiver shall furnish the Department with medical certification of good health for any child of her own whom she brings to the home of the mother or caretaker relative;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Duties of the in-home caregiver shall be limited to supervision of the child or children in her care, preparation and serving of appropriate meals or snacks, and washing of dishes and utensils used in the preparation of food;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The in-home caregiver shall have no more than 2 preschool children of her own;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The in-home caregiver shall not care for children other than her own and the child or children of the TANF or Power mother or caretaker relative;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the in-home caregiver brings her own children to the home of the TANF or POWER mother or caretaker relative, an agreement shall be reached between them as to the amount of food she brings for their needs; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-411_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The in-home caregiver shall have prior experience in child care, either with her own children or siblings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
