<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-415"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-415/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_415">
        <akn:num>4-415</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Comprehensive child development programs.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding §§ 4-402 through 4-410, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education (“OSSE”) shall establish a pilot community-based Quality Improvement Network (“QIN”) composed of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Child development centers and child development homes within the QIN shall receive technical assistance from child development hubs to achieve the following within 18 months of being selected by OSSE to participate in the QIN:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OSSE may set payment rates and develop policies and procedures for high-quality early learning and development services set under the authority of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be eligible for infant and toddler child development services provided by child-care partners in the QIN, a child shall be a resident of the District of Columbia and between birth and 3 years of age; provided, that a child who turns 3 years old during a program year may continue to receive services for the duration of the program year before transitioning into a pre-kindergarten or Head Start preschool program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To the extent possible, priority enrollment shall be given to children between birth and 3 years of age whose families are living at or below the federal poverty level, who are homeless or in the foster care system, or who live with a grandparent, godparent, or relative who is receiving a grandparent caregiver subsidy pursuant to Chapter 2A of this title [§ 4-251.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OSSE shall monitor the child development hubs and partner participants in the QIN for adherence to policies and procedures set under the authority of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OSSE may terminate, in whole or in part, the grant provided to a child development hub or partner participant at any time if OSSE determines that the hub or partner participant has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-415_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OSSE shall continue on-site monitoring for health and safety licensing compliance of child-care partners participating in the QIN; provided, that OSSE may delegate to the child development hubs on-site monitoring of the compliance of participating child development centers and homes with federal Head Start Program Performance Standards; provided, that relevant data collected by child development hubs is regularly reported to OSSE.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
