<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-501"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-501/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_501">
        <akn:num>4-501</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Board” means the Crime Victims Compensation Appeals Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Claimant” means a person who makes a claim for compensation under this chapter and who is a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Collateral source” means a source of benefits or compensation available to a claimant for economic loss resulting from a crime of violence. This term includes payments or benefits from:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commission” means the Crime Victims Compensation Advisory Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Crime of violence” or “crime” means the offense of, or the attempt to commit the offense of, an act of terrorism, use, dissemination, or detonation of a weapon of mass destruction, manufacture or possession of a weapon of mass destruction, arson, assault, assault with a dangerous weapon, aggravated assault, assault on a police officer, assault with intent to kill, assault with intent to commit any offense, burglary, stalking, threats, negligent homicide, sexual abuse, kidnapping, maliciously disfiguring another, manslaughter, murder, mayhem, riot, robbery, carjacking, cruelty to children, unlawful use of an explosive, forced labor, benefitting financially from human trafficking, using a minor in a sexual performance, promoting a sexual performance by a minor, attending or possessing a sexual performance by a minor, trafficking in labor or commercial sex acts, sex trafficking of children, a felony violation of an act codified in Chapter 27 of Title 22, where a person was compelled to engage in prostitution or was a minor; a violation of an act codified in Title 50 that resulted in death or bodily injury to a person, including these offenses when motivated by bias as provided by Chapter 37 of Title 22, or any violation of §§ 50-2201.04 and 50-2201.05, notwithstanding that the offender lacked the capacity to commit the offense by reason of infancy, insanity, intoxication, or otherwise. These terms include an offense where the perpetrator and victim are members of the same family or household, an offense whether prosecuted under the District of Columbia Official Code or the United States Code, and a terrorist act or act of mass violence as defined in 18 U.S.C. § 2331, committed in the District of Columbia against any person or outside of the United States against a resident of the District of Columbia. A crime occurs whether or not any person is identified, arrested, prosecuted, or convicted. Unless an application for rehearing, appeal, or petition for certiorari is pending or a new trial or hearing has been ordered, the conviction of a person whose acts gave rise to the claim is conclusive evidence that a crime was committed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fund” means the Crime Victims Compensation Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medical expenses” include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personal injury” means physical injury, emotional trauma, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Program” means the Crime Victims Compensation Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Provider of services” means a person or entity providing services pursuant to paragraphs (7) and (9) of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Secondary victim” means a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Victim” means a person who suffers personal injury or death in the District of Columbia, a person who is a resident of the District of Columbia and suffers personal injury or death as a result of a terrorist act or act of mass violence committed outside of the United States, or a person who is a resident of the District of Columbia and who suffers personal injury or death outside the District of Columbia in a state that does not have a crime victims compensation program that is eligible for funding under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (98 Stat. 2170; 42 U.S.C. § 10601 et seq.), as a direct result of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-501_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Victims assistance grants agency” means the District of Columbia agency that is responsible for the administration of federal funds received for crime victims assistance under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984, approved October 12, 1984 (98 Stat. 2170; 42 U.S.C. § 10601 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
