<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-754.41"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-754.41/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_754_41">
        <akn:num>4-754.41</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Fair hearings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of Administrative Hearings shall grant a fair hearing to any client or client representative who wishes to appeal a decision listed in subsection (b) of this section and who requests such a hearing, orally or in writing, within 90 days of receiving written notice of the adverse action. A request for a fair hearing shall be made to the client’s provider, the Department, the Mayor, or the Mayor’s designee. If the request is made orally, the individual receiving the request shall promptly acknowledge the request, reduce it to writing, and file the request for a fair hearing with the Office of Administrative Hearings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A client or client representative may request a fair hearing to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall treat a fair hearing request made by a client representative in the same manner as it would be treated if it were made directly by the client; provided, that the Mayor subsequently receives written documentation authorizing the client representative to act on behalf of the client in accordance with the requirements of § 4-210.05.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In accordance with § 4-754.11(18), any client who requests a fair hearing within 15 days of receipt of written notice of a suspension or termination of shelter or supportive housing shall continue to receive shelter or supportive housing pending a final decision from the fair hearing proceedings. This right to continuation of shelter or supportive housing pending appeal shall not apply in the case of an emergency suspension or termination pursuant to § 4-754.38.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In accordance with § 4-754.11(20), any client in an interim eligibility placement who requests a fair hearing within 48 hours or before the close of the next business day, whichever occurs later, of receipt of written notice of a denial of eligibility for shelter placement shall continue in that interim eligibility placement pending a final decision from the fair hearing proceedings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a fair hearing request, the Mayor or the Mayor’s designee shall offer the client or client representative an opportunity for an administrative review by the Department of the decision that is the subject of the fair hearing request.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All fair hearings shall be conducted in the following manner:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Materials and documents filed with the Office of Administrative Hearings during fair hearing proceedings shall be maintained in compliance with § 2-1831.13(d), the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, approved August 21, 1996 (Pub. L. No. 104-191; 110 Stat. 1936), and any other District or federal law pertaining to confidentiality of records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_41_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or the Mayor’s designee shall maintain a file of final fair hearing and administrative review decisions, indexed by issue, with identifying information redacted. The file shall be accessible to clients, their representatives, and other persons upon request to the Mayor or the Mayor’s designee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
