<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-752.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-752.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_752_02">
        <akn:num>4-752.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers and duties of the Interagency Council on Homelessness.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-752_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Interagency Council shall provide leadership in the development of strategies and policies that guide the implementation of the District’s policies and programs for meeting the needs of individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-752_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In fulfilling the responsibility described in subsection (a) of this section, the Interagency Council shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-752_02_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning 5 years from May 3, 2014, and every 2 years thereafter, the Interagency Council shall evaluate the service needs of the District’s LGBTQ homeless youth as compared to homeless youth in the general population. If the Interagency Council determines, based on data, that the needs of LGBTQ homeless youth are being met at a rate equal to or higher than the needs of homeless youth in the general population, the provisions of § 4-755.01(c) shall expire.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-752_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall, no later than February 1 of each year, make available to all Interagency Council members the District’s proposed budget breakdown of each agency’s appropriations for services within the Continuum of Care. The Interagency Council shall give comments to the Mayor regarding the proposed budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-752_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member agency of the Interagency Council shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-752_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Human Services shall administer the Homeless Prevention Program, established pursuant to Chapter 7B of this title [§  4-771.01], in consultation with the Interagency Council on Homelessness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
