<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-754.33"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-754.33/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_754_33">
        <akn:num>4-754.33</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All providers shall give to any client to whom they have denied services oral and written notice of the right to appeal the denial, including information about how to request a fair hearing pursuant to § 4-754.41 and administrative review pursuant to § 4-754.42.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All providers shall give to any client in an interim eligibility placement prompt oral and written notice that the Mayor has denied eligibility for shelter placement and that the interim eligibility placement will end 48 hours or at the close of the next business day, whichever occurs later, following the client’s receipt of the written notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All providers shall give written and oral notice to clients of their transfer to another provider or of their suspension, termination, or discontinuation from services at least 15 days before the effective date of the transfer or the suspension, termination, or discontinuation of services except:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any notice issued pursuant to subsection (b) or (c) of this section must be mailed or served upon the client and shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any written notice issued pursuant to subsection (b-1) of this section must be served upon the client and shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_33_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Providers shall establish procedures to provide effective notice of rights, rules, sanctions, and denials to clients with special needs, including those who may be mentally impaired or mentally ill, or who may have difficulty reading or have limited English proficiency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
