<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-754.52"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-754.52/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_754_52">
        <akn:num>4-754.52</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers and duties of the Office.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall monitor the conditions, services, and practices at shelters, evaluating the following, to the extent applicable:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall conduct inspections on the premises of each shelter covered by § 4-754.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall receive complaints about programs, facilities, and services provided within the continuum of care and shall investigate programs not in compliance with the applicable standards established in this subchapter or with other requirements or agreements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall establish procedures for notifying providers of deficiencies and procedures for correcting those deficiencies in a timely manner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During any inspection or investigation conducted pursuant to this section, the provider shall make available to the Office for examination any records or other materials related to the delivery of its services, including records related to clients and to internal complaints, in accordance with the confidentiality requirements of 4-754.11(a)(7)§ .</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall ensure confidential treatment of the personal, social, legal, financial, educational, and medical records and information related to a client or any member of a client’s family, whether obtained from the client or from any other source, consistent with confidentiality requirements of District and federal law. The Office shall not disclose the identity of any person who brings a complaint or provides information to the Office without the person’s consent, unless the Office determines that disclosure is unavoidable or necessary to further the ends of an inspection or investigation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall encourage appropriate use of mediation, fair hearing, and administrative review processes for resolving grievances, pursuant to §§ 4-754.39, 4-754.41, and 4-754.42.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-754_52_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall post in prominent places at each program and shelter site its contact information, its procedures for accepting complaints, and procedures for requesting mediation, a fair hearing, or administrative review of grievances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
