<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-751.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-751.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_751_01">
        <akn:num>4-751.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Administrative Procedure Act” or “APA” means Chapter 5 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adult” means any individual who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apartment style” means a housing unit with:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Appropriate permanent housing” means permanent housing that does not jeopardize the health, safety, or welfare of its occupants, meets the District’s building code requirements, and is affordable for the client.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Appropriately trained and qualified” means having received specialized training designed to teach the skills necessary to successfully perform one’s job and to work compassionately with individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Basic necessities” means a dinette set, refrigerator, stove, exhaust fan or window, storage cabinets, cookware, flatware, and tableware.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Client” means an individual or family seeking, receiving, or eligible for services from a program covered by § 4-754.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Continuum of Care” means the comprehensive system of services for individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless and designed to serve clients based on their individual level of need. The Continuum of Care may include crisis intervention, outreach and assessment services, shelter, transitional housing, permanent supportive housing, and supportive services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Crisis intervention” means assistance to prevent individuals and families from becoming homeless, which may include, but need not be limited to, cash assistance for security deposits, rent or mortgage payments, utility assistance, credit counseling, mediation with landlords, and supportive services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Culturally competent” means the ability of a provider to deliver or ensure access to services in a manner that effectively responds to the languages, values, and practices present in the various cultures of its clients so the provider can respond to the individual needs of each client.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Day program” means a facility that provides open access to structured activities during set hours of the day to meet the supportive services needs of individuals and families who are homeless or at imminent risk of becoming homeless.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_11A">
      <akn:num>(11A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DC General Family Shelter replacement unit” means a private room that includes space to store and refrigerate food and is constructed by or at the request of the District for the purpose of sheltering a homeless family.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia government, its agents, or its designees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drop-in center” means a facility that delivers supportive services that may include food, clothing, showers, medical services, and employment services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drug” means a controlled substance as defined in § 48-901.02(4), or the Controlled Substances Act of 1970, approved October 27, 1970 (84 Stat. 1242; 21 U.S.C. § 801 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Family” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Group home” means a housing unit with:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_17A">
      <akn:num>(17A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gender identity or expression” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 2-1401.02(12A).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Homeless” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing First” means a program that provides clients with immediate access to independent permanent housing and supportive services without prerequisites for sobriety or participation in psychiatric treatment. Clients in Housing First programs may choose the frequency and type of supportive services they receive and refusal of services will have no consequence for their access to housing or on continuation of their housing and supportive services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hyperthermia shelter” means a public or private building that the District shall make available, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals or families who are homeless and cannot access other shelter, whenever the actual or forecasted temperature or heat index rises above 95 degrees Fahrenheit. The term “hyperthermia shelter” does not include overnight shelter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hypothermia shelter” means a public or private building that the District shall make available, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals or families who are homeless and cannot access other shelter, whenever the actual or forecasted temperature, including the wind chill factor, falls below 32 degrees Fahrenheit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Individual with a disability” means a person with a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits the major life activities of the person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Imminent risk of becoming homeless” means the likelihood that an individual’s or family’s circumstances will cause the individual or family to become homeless in the absence of prompt government intervention.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Imminent threat to the health or safety” means an act or credible threat of violence on the grounds of a shelter or supportive housing facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interagency Council” means the Interagency Council on Homelessness established pursuant to § 4-752.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_25A">
      <akn:num>(25A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interim eligibility placement” means a short-term shelter placement for a family, for the purpose of conducting an in-depth assessment to facilitate an eligibility determination for shelter and appropriate supportive services pursuant to § 4-753.02(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_25B">
      <akn:num>(25B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“LGBTQ” means a person who self-identifies as lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, gender nonconforming, queer, or questioning their sexual orientation or gender identity and expression.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low barrier shelter” means an overnight housing accommodation for individuals who are homeless, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals without imposition of identification, time limits, or other program requirements;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member agency” or “member agencies” means the District agencies or divisions thereof represented on the Interagency Council pursuant to § 4-752.01(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_27A">
      <akn:num>(27A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Office” means the Office of Shelter Monitoring established pursuant to § 4-754.51.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Permanent supportive housing” means supportive housing for an unrestricted period of time for individuals and families who were once homeless and continue to be at imminent risk of becoming homeless, including persons with disabilities as defined in 24 C.F.R. § 582.5, for whom self-sufficient living may be unlikely and whose care can be supported through public funds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_28A">
      <akn:num>(28A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Private room” means a part or division of a building that has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Program Rules” means the set of provider rules, client rights, and complaint and appeal procedures, including those enumerated in this chapter, proposed by a particular provider for the purpose of governing the behavior and treatment of its clients and approved by the Mayor subject to § 4-754.32.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Provider” means an individual or entity within the Continuum of Care that operates a program covered by § 4-754.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public assistance” means government-funded payments in or by money, medical care, remedial care, shelter, goods or services to, or for the benefit of, needy persons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_31A">
      <akn:num>(31A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Rapid Re-Housing” means a program that provides a homeless individual or family with financial assistance to obtain permanent housing, by providing some or all of a security deposit, first month’s rent, short-term rental subsidy, and supportive services to help the recipient become self-sufficient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident of the District” means an individual or family who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_32A">
      <akn:num>(32A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Safe housing” means housing that does not jeopardize the health, safety, or welfare of its occupants and that permits access to electricity, heat, and running water for the benefit of occupants.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sanction” means an adverse action taken by a provider affecting the delivery of services to a client, and may include loss of privileges or denial, reduction, delay, transfer for inappropriate or punitive reasons, suspension, or termination of services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Service plan” means a written plan collaboratively developed and agreed upon by both the provider and the client, consisting of time-specific goals and objectives designed to promote self-sufficiency and attainment of permanent housing and based on the client’s individually assessed needs, desires, strengths, resources, and limitations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Severe weather conditions” means the outdoor conditions whenever the actual or forecasted temperature, including the wind chill factor or heat index, falls below 32 degrees Fahrenheit or rises above 95 degrees Fahrenheit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Severe weather shelter” means hyperthermia shelter or hypothermia shelter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Shelter” means severe weather shelter, low barrier shelter, and temporary shelter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Supportive housing” means transitional housing and permanent supportive housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Supportive services” means services addressing employment, physical health, mental health, alcohol and other substance abuse recovery, child care, transportation, case management, and other health and social service needs which, if unmet, may be barriers to obtaining or maintaining permanent housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Temporary shelter” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transitional housing” means a 24-hour housing accommodation, the purpose of which is to facilitate the movement of homeless individuals and families to permanent housing within 2 years or a longer period approved by the provider, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for individuals and families who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_41A">
      <akn:num>(41A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Verifier” means a District resident or a provider who knows where an individual or family seeking shelter lives and who produces evidence of his or her employment as a provider in the case of a provider, or own District residency in the case of a District resident by providing a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Weapon” means any pistol or other firearm (or imitation thereof), or other dangerous or deadly weapon, including a sawed-off shot gun, shot gun, machine gun, rifle, dirk, bowie knife, butcher knife, switch blade knife, razor, black jack, billy club or metallic or other false knuckles, as referenced in § 22-4502, and any air gun, air rifle, canon, torpedo, bean shooter, sling, projectile, dart, BB gun, spring gun, blow gun, other dangerous missile or explosive, or other dangerous weapon or ammunition of any character, as referenced in Chapter 23 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-751_01_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Youth” means a person who is under 24 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
