<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-802"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-802/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_802">
        <akn:num>4-802</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties; prohibited acts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-802_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person shall be guilty of a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than $500 or imprisonment not to exceed 1 year, or both, for each violation of the following prohibitions in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-802_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No one may, with intent to defraud, by means of a false claim, false statement, failure to disclose information, or other fraudulent scheme or device, obtain or attempt to obtain:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-802_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No one may solicit, accept, or agree to accept any type of remuneration for the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-802_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No one may confer, offer, or agree to confer or offer any type of remuneration for the conduct described in subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-802_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No one may charge, solicit, accept, or attempt to charge, solicit, accept or receive anything of value from a recipient or provider in addition to the amount of money payable under the District of Columbia Medicaid Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-802_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No one may solicit, receive, or attempt to solicit or receive anything of value as a precondition for admitting a recipient to a hospital, skilled nursing facility, intermediate care facility, or any other facility, or as a condition for providing any item or service to a recipient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
