<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-804"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-804/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_804">
        <akn:num>4-804</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Prosecutions; investigations; subpoenas; witness fees; perjury; compulsion of obedience to subpoena; oaths; access to records.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Criminal prosecutions under § 4-802 may be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel or the Office of the Inspector General. Civil actions under § 4-803(e) may be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any power to bring criminal or civil actions or otherwise carry out the duties under this chapter, the Corporation Counsel or the Office of the Inspector General shall have the authority to investigate all alleged violations of this chapter and, in exercising this power, may issue subpoenas for witnesses to appear and testify or to produce all books, records, papers, or documents in any investigation into alleged violations of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Witnesses, other than those employed by the District of Columbia, summoned under subsection (b) of this section shall be paid the same fees and mileage that witnesses are paid in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, but the fees need not be tendered to the witnesses before they appear and testify or produce books, records, papers, or documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any willful false swearing on the part of any witness testifying about a material fact pursuant to a subpoena issued under subsection (b) of this section shall be subject to prosecution pursuant to § 22-2402.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any witness having been personally summoned shall neglect or refuse to obey the subpoena, the Corporation Counsel or the Office of the Inspector General may report that fact to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. The Superior Court of the District of Columbia may compel obedience to the subpoena to the same extent as witnesses may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of that court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Corporation Counsel or the Office of the Inspector General may administer oaths to witnesses summoned in any investigation under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-804_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person holding records required to be maintained by the Medicaid legislation or regulations promulgated pursuant to that legislation may refuse to provide the Corporation Counsel or the Office of the Inspector General with access to the records on the basis that release would violate any recipient’s right of privacy, any recipient’s privilege against disclosure or use, or any professional or other privilege or right.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
