<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-904"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/4-904/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_4_904">
        <akn:num>4-904</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Management of areas designated for facilities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Utilization of the space described in ยง 4-903 for child care shall be subject to terms and conditions set forth by the Director of the Department of Administrative Services.  The terms shall include payment of rent, proof of financial responsibility, and maintenance of space.  The District government shall not be liable for negligent acts or acts of omission on the part of the child care facility operator, or its employees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Space for child care facilities shall first be made available to employees who wish to establish nonprofit child care facilities at a rate to be established by the Director of the Department of Administrative Services, based upon the actual cost to the District, or the average cost of District-controlled office space, whichever is less.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Space for child care facilities may be made available to private organizations that wish to establish child care facilities in District government buildings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rates for the rental of space in District buildings to be made available for child care facilities shall be established by the Director of the Department of Administrative Services, who shall attempt to keep these costs as low as possible so that fees paid by employees for child care services will not be substantially impacted by high overhead costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Contracts with private organizations to provide child care services shall be competitively bid and awarded, and may include factors in addition to price, such as the provision of early childhood education programs, infant care, and other developmental models.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The department or departments occupying any building shall notify the employee-occupants of the availability of space to be used for child care facilities no earlier than 180 days prior to the projected date of occupancy of a new building or space provided as the result of additions, alterations, or repairs that both change the use of 25% of the net square foot area of the building and include the addition to, alteration of, or repair of the 1st floor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The space may be reconverted for child care purposes within 180 days of the notice, if, at a later date, the employee-occupants:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4-904_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days of February 24, 1987, the Mayor shall promulgate proposed rules governing the operation of child care facilities in District government buildings. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for approval, in whole or in part, by resolution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
