<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-114"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-114/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_51_114">
        <akn:num>51-114</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payment of administrative expenses.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-114_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All moneys received by the Director from the United States under title III of the Social Security Act or from other sources for administering this subchapter shall, immediately upon such receipt, be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as a special deposit to be used solely to pay such administrative expenses (including expenditures for rent, for suitable office space in the District of Columbia, and for lawbooks, books of reference, and periodicals), traveling expenses when authorized by the Director, premiums on the bonds of the Director’s employees, and allowances to investigators for furnishing privately-owned motor vehicles in the performance of official duties at rates not to exceed $65 per month. All such payments of expenses shall be made by checks drawn by the Director and shall be subject to audit by the Mayor of the District of Columbia in the same manner as are payments of other expenses of the District. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section and the provisions of §§ 51-102 and 51-108, the Director is authorized to requisition and receive from the Director’s account in the Unemployment Trust Fund in the Treasury of the United States of America, in the manner permitted by federal law, such moneys standing to the District’s credit in such Fund, as are permitted by federal law to be used for expenses incurred by the Director for the administration of this subchapter and to expend such moneys for such purposes. Moneys so received shall, immediately upon such receipt, be deposited in the Treasury of the United States in the same special account as are all other moneys received for the administration of this subchapter. All moneys received by the Director pursuant to § 302 of the Social Security Act shall be expended solely for the purposes and in the amounts found necessary by the Department of Labor for the proper and efficient administration of this subchapter. In lieu of incorporation in this subchapter of the provision described in § 303(a)(9) of the Social Security Act, the Mayor shall include in the Mayor’s annual report to Council of the District of Columbia, provided in § 51-113, a report of any moneys received after July 1, 1941, from the Department of Labor under title III of the Social Security Act, and any unencumbered balances in the Employment Compensation Administration Fund as of that date, which the Department of Labor finds have, because of any action or contingency, been lost or have been expended for purposes other than, or in amounts in excess of, those found necessary by the Department of Labor for the proper administration of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-114_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-114_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-114_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
