<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-103"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-103/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_51_103">
        <akn:num>51-103</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Employer contributions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employer who employs 1 or more individuals in any employment shall for each month, beginning with the month of January 1936, and ending December 31, 1939, pay contributions equal to the following percentages of the total wages payable (regardless of the time of payment) with respect to such employment by him during such month:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employer shall pay contributions equal to 2.7% of wages paid by him during the calendar year 1940 and thereafter with respect to employment after December 31, 1939. After December 31, 1978, each employer shall pay contributions at the rate in effect for the current year as provided by subsections (c)(3), (c)(4)(B), and (c)(8)(A) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The contributions payable pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall become due and be paid by each employer to the Director, and shall not be deducted in whole or in part from the wages of individuals in such employer’s employ.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Contributions due under this subchapter with respect to wages for insured work shall, for the purpose of this section, be deemed to have been paid to the Fund as of the date payment was made as contributions therefor under another state or federal employment security law if payment into the Fund of such contributions is made on such terms as the Director finds will be fair and reasonable as to all affected interests; provided, that liability to the Fund shall not exceed contributions for the 3 calendar years next preceding the quarter in which liability was determined. Payments to the Fund under this subsection shall be deemed to be contributions for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, benefits paid to employees of nonprofit organizations shall be financed in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. For the purpose of this subsection and subsection (i) of this section, a nonprofit organization is an organization (or group of organizations) described in § 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 which is exempt from income tax under § 501(a) of such Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provisions in subsection (h) of this section, any nonprofit organization that prior to January 1, 1969, paid contributions required by subsection (c) of this section and, pursuant to subsection (h) of this section, elects within 30 days after January 1, 1972, to make payments in lieu of contributions, shall not be required to make any such payment on account of any benefits paid, on the basis of wages paid by such organization to individuals for weeks of unemployment which began on or after the effective date of such election until the total amount of such benefits equals the amount of the positive balance in the experience rating account of such organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this subchapter, no employer’s experience rating account shall be charged and no employer shall be liable for payments in lieu of contributions with respect to extended benefit payments which are wholly reimbursed to the District of Columbia by the federal government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provisions of this subchapter, no employer’s experience rating account shall be charged with respect to benefits paid to any individual whose base-period wages include wages for previously uncovered services as defined in § 51-101(3)(C) to the extent that the Unemployment Insurance Fund is reimbursed for such benefits pursuant to § 121 of the Unemployment Compensation Amendments of 1976 (26 U.S.C. § 3304, note).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-103_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, all assignments of contribution rates and transfers of experience in any year commencing after December 31, 2005 shall be made in accordance with the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
