<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-119"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-119/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_51_119">
        <akn:num>51-119</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties for false statements or representations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-119_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whoever makes a false statement or representation knowing it to be false, or knowingly fails to disclose a material fact, to obtain or increase any benefit or other payment provided for in this subchapter or under an employment security law of any other state, of the federal government, or a foreign government for himself or any other individual, shall, for each such offense, be fined not more than $100 or imprisoned not more than 60 days, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-119_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any employing unit, and any officer or agent of any employing unit or any other person, who furnishes a false record or makes a false statement or representation, knowing it to be false, or who knowingly fails to disclose a material fact to avoid the payment of any or all of the contributions required of such employing unit under this subchapter, or to prevent or reduce the payment of benefits to any individual entitled thereto, or who fails or refuses to pay the contributions or other payment or to furnish any reports required of him under this subchapter, shall for each such offense be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned not more than 6 months, or both. For purposes of this subsection an officer of a corporation charged with any duty required by this subchapter shall be personally liable to prosecution under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-119_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who shall wilfully violate any provision of this subchapter or any rule or regulation thereunder, the violation of which is made unlawful or the observance of which is required under the terms of this subchapter, and for which a penalty is neither prescribed herein nor provided by any other applicable statute, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $200 or by imprisonment for not longer than 60 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment, and each day such violation continues shall be deemed to be a separate offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-119_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-119_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-119_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In all cases where an employer subject to this subchapter makes an award of back pay to a claimant who has received benefits during the same period covered by the back pay award, the employer shall withhold an amount equal to the benefits paid from the back pay award and shall repay the amount to the Director, who shall deposit it in the Fund and credit the accounts of charged base period employers. If the employer does not comply with this subsection, the Director may treat the unrefunded amount as an unpaid contribution and collect it in the manner provided for collection of delinquent contributions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
