<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-107"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-107/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_51_107">
        <akn:num>51-107</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Determination of amount and duration of benefits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On and after January 1, 1938, benefits shall become payable from the Benefit Account of the District Unemployment Fund. All benefits shall be paid through employment offices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any otherwise eligible individual shall be entitled during any benefit year to a total amount of benefits equal to 26 times his weekly benefit amount or 50% of the wages for employment paid to such individual by employers during his base period whichever is the lesser; provided, that the maximum duration of benefits determined on any initial claim made prior to March 15, 1983, shall continue to be 34 weeks during the benefit year to which the initial claim relates. Such total amount of benefits, if not a multiple of $1, shall be computed to the next lower multiple of $1.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual who is unemployed in any week as defined in § 51-101(5) and who meets the conditions of eligibility for benefits of § 51-109 and is not disqualified under the provisions of § 51-110 shall be paid with respect to such week an amount equal to the individual’s weekly benefit amount less any earnings payable to the individual with respect to such week deductible in accordance with the following formula: $20 will be added to the weekly benefit amount; from the resulting sum will be subtracted 80% of any earnings payable to the individual for such week. The resulting benefits, if not a multiple of $1, shall be computed to the next lower multiple of $1. In no event shall the amount paid for any week exceed the individual’s established weekly benefit amount.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the benefits payable under the foregoing subsections of this section, each eligible individual who is unemployed in any week shall be paid with respect to such week $5 for each dependent relative, but not more than $20 shall be paid to an individual as dependent’s allowance with respect to any 1 week of unemployment nor shall any weekly benefit which includes a dependent’s allowance be paid in the amount of more than the established maximum benefit amount. An individual’s number of dependents shall be determined as of the day with respect to which he first files a valid claim for benefits in any benefit year, and shall be fixed for the duration of such benefit year. The dependent’s allowance is not to be taken into consideration in calculating the claimant’s total amount of benefits in subsection (d) of this section; provided, however, that this section shall not apply to claims for benefit years commencing on or after January 5, 1997.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For claims for benefit years commencing after August 9, 2009, and before January 1, 2011, in addition to benefits payable under subsections (a) through (e) of this section, each eligible individual who is unemployed in any week shall be paid with respect to that week $15 for each dependent relative, but no more than $50 or 1/2 of the individual’s weekly benefit amount, whichever is less, with respect to any 1 week of unemployment. The amount of the dependent’s allowance paid to an individual shall not be charged to the individual account of an employer. The number of dependents of an individual shall be determined as of the day with respect to which the individual first files a valid claim for benefits in any benefit year and shall remain fixed for the duration of the benefit year. The dependent’s allowance shall not be taken into consideration in the total amount of benefits calculated pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, this subsection provides a program of extended benefits on and after January 1, 1972.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective October 1, 1983, in the calculation of an individual’s weekly benefit amount, all amounts shall be rounded down to the next lower dollar.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-107_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
