<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-113"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/51-113/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_51_113">
        <akn:num>51-113</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administration of provisions of subchapter; disclosure of information.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director is hereby authorized and directed to administer the provisions of this subchapter. The Director is further authorized to employ such officers, examiners, accountants, attorneys, experts, agents, and other persons, and to make such expenditures as may be necessary to administer this subchapter, and to authorize any such person to do any act or acts which could lawfully be done by the Director. The Council of the District of Columbia may, in its discretion, require bond from any employees of the Director engaged in carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall each year, not later than May 1st, submit to Council a report covering the administration and operation of this subchapter during the preceding calendar year, and containing such recommendations as the Mayor wishes to make.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as hereinafter otherwise provided, information obtained from any employing unit or individual pursuant to the administration of this subchapter and determinations as to the benefit rights of any individual shall be held confidential and shall not be disclosed or be open to public inspection in any manner, whether by subpoena or otherwise, revealing the individual’s or employing unit’s identity. Any claimant (or his legal representative) shall be supplied with information from the records of the division, to the extent necessary for the proper presentation of his claim in any proceeding under this subchapter with respect thereto. Subject to such restrictions as the Director may by regulation prescribe, such information may be made available to any agency of this or any other state, or any federal agency, charged with the administration of an unemployment compensation law or the maintenance of a system of public employment offices, or the agency of any state or the federal agency charged with the administration of programs for food stamps, parent locator services and other support or paternity establishment services, public housing, Medicaid, Temporary Assistance for Needy Families, Program on Work, Employment, and Responsibility, and supplemental security income, or the Department of Public Welfare of the government of any state, or the National Directory of New Hires established pursuant to section 316(f) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, approved August 22, 1996 (110 Stat. 2209, 42 U.S.C. § 653a) or any District of Columbia State Directory of New Hires established pursuant to § 313(b) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, or the United States Accounting Office or the Internal Revenue Service of the United States Department of the Treasury, or the District of Columbia Office of Tax and Revenue, and information obtained in connection with the administration of the employment service may be made available to persons or agencies for purposes appropriate to the operation of a public employment service. Upon request therefor the Director shall furnish to any agency of the United States charged with the administration of public works or assistance through public employment, and may furnish to any state agency similarly charged, the name, address, ordinary occupation, and employment status of each recipient of benefits and such recipient’s rights to further benefits under this subchapter. The Director may request the Comptroller of the Currency of the United States to cause an examination of the correctness of any return or report of any national banking association rendered pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter, and may in connection with such request transmit any such report or return to the Comptroller of the Currency of the United States as provided in § 1606(c) of the federal Internal Revenue Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the discharge of the duties imposed by this subchapter, the Director and any duly authorized representative thereof shall have power to administer oaths and affirmations, take depositions, certify to official acts, and issue subpoenas to compel attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, and other records deemed necessary as evidence in connection with a disputed claim or the administration of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Director may invoke the aid of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, and other records. Such Court may issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Director or officer designated by the Director, there to produce records, if so ordered, or to give testimony touching the matter in question; and any failure to obey such order of the Court may be punished by such Court as a contempt thereof. Any person who shall, without just cause, fail or refuse to attend and testify or to answer any lawful inquiry or to produce books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, and other records, if in his power so to do, in obedience to the subpoena of the Director, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or to imprisonment for a term of not more than 1 year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51-113_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall be excused from attending and testifying or from producing books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, and other records before the Director or in obedience to the subpoena of the Director or any officer designated by the Director, or in any cause or proceeding instituted by the Director, on the ground that the testimony or evidence, documentary or otherwise, required of him may tend to incriminate him or subject him to a penalty or forfeiture; but no individual shall be prosecuted or subjected to any penalty or forfeiture for or on account of any transaction, matter, or thing concerning which he is compelled, after having claimed his privilege against self-incrimination, to testify or produce evidence, documentary or otherwise, except that such individual so testifying shall not be exempt from prosecution and punishment for perjury committed in so testifying.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
