<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3814"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3814/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_3814">
        <akn:num>28-3814</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Debt collection.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section only applies to conduct and practices in connection with collection of obligations arising from consumer credit sales, consumer leases, and direct installment loans (other than a loan directly secured on real estate or a direct motor vehicle installment loan covered by Chapter 36 of Title 28).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, the term —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall collect or attempt to collect any money alleged to be due and owing by means of any threat, coercion, or attempt to coerce in any of the following ways:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall unreasonably oppress, harass, or abuse any person in connection with the collection of or attempt to collect any claim alleged to be due and owing by that person or another in any of the following ways:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall unreasonably publicize information relating to any alleged indebtedness or debtor in any of the following ways:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall use any fraudulent, deceptive, or misleading representation or means to collect or attempt to collect claims or to obtain information concerning consumers in any of the following ways:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall use unfair or unconscionable means to collect or attempt to collect any claim in any of the following ways:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall use, or distribute, sell, or prepare for use, any written communication that violates or fails to conform to United States postal laws and regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor or debt collector shall take or accept for assignment any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3814_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No creditor, debt collector, or collection agency, or their representatives or agents shall contact consumers by telephone before 8 a.m. and after 9 p.m. EST or EDT, whichever time zone is in effect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
