<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3811"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3811/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_3811">
        <akn:num>28-3811</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Home solicitation sales.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, “home solicitation sale” means a cash sale or a consumer credit sale of goods, other than farm equipment, or services in which the seller or a person acting for him engages in a personal solicitation of the sale at or near a residence of the buyer and the buyer’s agreement or offer to purchase is there given to a seller or a person acting for him. It does not include a sale made pursuant to a preexisting revolving credit account or prior negotiations between the parties at a business establishment at a fixed location where goods or services are offered or exhibited for sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, in addition to any right otherwise to revoke an offer, the buyer has the right to cancel a home solicitation sale until midnight of the third business day after the day on which the buyer signs an agreement or offer to purchase which complies with this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Cancellation occurs when the buyer gives written notice of cancellation to the seller at the address stated in the agreement or offer to purchase.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of cancellation, if given by mail, is given when it is deposited in a mail box properly addressed and the postage prepaid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of cancellation given by the buyer need not take a particular form and is sufficient if it indicates by any form of written expression the intention of the buyer not to be bound by the home solicitation sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The buyer may not cancel a home solicitation sale if the buyer requests the seller to provide goods or services without delay because of an emergency, and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3811_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f) of this section shall not apply to a home solicitation sale between a buyer and a public insurance adjuster, as defined in [§ 31-1631.01(c)]. [Section 31-1631.07] shall apply to all such sales.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
