<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3862"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3862/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_3862">
        <akn:num>28-3862</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Security freeze.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A credit reporting agency shall place a security freeze on a consumer’s credit report if a consumer, providing proper identification, makes a request to the credit reporting agency by certified mail. In addition, on or before January 31, 2009, a credit reporting agency shall make available an Internet-based method of requesting a security freeze and shall accept requests by one of the following methods: telephone or regular mail.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A credit reporting agency shall place the security freeze on the consumer’s credit report no later than 3 business days after receiving the request.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The credit reporting agency shall send a written confirmation of the security freeze to the consumer within 5 business days of placing the freeze and at the same time shall provide the consumer with a unique personal identification number or password to be used by the consumer when providing authorization for the release of his or her credit report to a specific party or for a specific period of time.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A consumer may thereafter request that a credit reporting agency allow his or her credit report to be accessed by a specific party or for a specific period of time by providing the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A credit reporting agency may develop procedures involving the use of telephone, fax, or, upon the consent of the consumer in the manner required by the Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act, approved June 30, 2000 (114 Stat. 464; 15 U.S.C. § 7001 et seq.), for legally required notices, by the Internet, e-mail, or other electronic media, to receive and process a request from a consumer to temporarily lift a freeze on a credit report pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A credit reporting agency may permanently remove a freeze placed on a credit report, without a request from the consumer, if the credit reporting agency placed the freeze as a result of a material misrepresentation of fact by the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A credit reporting agency shall send written notification to the consumer 5 business days prior to permanently removing a freeze on a credit report pursuant to subsection (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a third party requests access to a credit report on which a security freeze is in effect in connection with an application for credit and the consumer does not allow his or her consumer report to be accessed by that specific party or for that period of time, the third party may treat the application as incomplete.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a security freeze is in place, a credit report shall not be released to a third party without prior express authorization from the consumer. A credit reporting agency may advise a third party that a security freeze is in effect with respect to the credit report.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security freeze shall remain in place until the consumer requests its permanent removal in writing. On or before January 31, 2009, a credit reporting agency shall remove a security freeze within 3 business days of receiving a request for permanent removal from the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A credit reporting agency shall not suggest or otherwise state or imply to a third party that the consumer’s security freeze reflects a negative credit score, history, report, or rating.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall prevent the lawful use of a credit report by any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following persons are not required to place a security freeze on a credit report:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3862_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A consumer reporting agency may charge a consumer for a security freeze service only as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
