<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3818"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3818/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_3818">
        <akn:num>28-3818</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Layaway plans.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Definitions. — As used in this section the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Disclosures. — The seller shall, prior to the time of executing a layaway plan agreement, provide the buyer with a copy of a written, clear, and conspicuous disclosure. Failure of the seller to comply with this provision shall be deemed an executed trade practice in violation of the law of the District of Columbia for which the penalties in section 6(i)(3) of the District of Columbia Consumer Protection Procedures Act, effective July 22, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-76) [§ 28-3905(i)(3)] shall apply. The disclosure required by this subsection shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Buyer’s right to cancel. — The buyer, at his option, has the right to cancel an executed layaway plan within two (2) weeks after entering into the layaway plan and to obtain a full refund of any amount of money paid toward the purchase of consumer goods under the layaway plan. Such refund is payable upon cancellation or within two (2) weeks after cancellation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Cancellation fee. — If a buyer notifies a seller of his intention to cancel a purchase of consumer goods under a layaway plan after the expiration of the two (2) week cancellation period set forth in subsection (c) of this section, the seller shall promptly refund the full amount of money paid by the buyer towards the purchase of the consumer goods under the layaway plan. The seller may, however, retain an amount not to exceed eight percent (8%) of the purchase price of the consumer goods purchased under the layaway plan or sixteen dollars ($16.00), whichever is less.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Seller’s default. — If, for any reason, the seller is unable to provide the consumer goods identified in the layaway plan or their exact duplicate to the buyer upon final payment or within fourteen (14) days thereafter, the seller shall refund the entire amount paid by the buyer towards the purchase of such goods under the layaway plan plus eight percent (8%) of the purchase price of the consumer goods purchased under the layaway plan or sixteen dollars ($16.00), whichever is less.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Charges restricted. — The seller shall not require a buyer who has executed a layaway plan to pay a charge or fee of any kind on such goods except for those fees pursuant to subsections (d), (g), and (j) of this section to the extent applicable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Late fee. — If, for any reason, the buyer is unable to make payment in accordance with the terms of a layaway plan, the seller shall send prompt notice informing the buyer of the delinquency in payment. If the seller does not receive payment on the consumer goods identified in the layaway plan within fourteen (14) days after such notice is sent to the buyer, the seller may deduct an amount not to exceed one dollar ($1.00) from the full amount of money paid by the buyer towards the purchase of such goods under the layaway plan and refund the remaining amount to the buyer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Acceleration of payment prohibited. — The seller shall not accelerate any payments under a layaway plan. The seller shall be entitled to the amount of payments due to date under the layaway plan including those charges pursuant to subsections (d) and (g) of this section to the extent applicable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Receipt and statement of payments. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3818_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Service charge. — The seller is allowed to charge the buyer a service charge, which is not to exceed one dollar ($1.00), for goods purchased under a layaway plan, to cover the administrative costs associated with such layaway plan; provided, that the one dollar ($1.00) service charge shall cover all layaway plan transactions between the retailer and a single consumer occurring in the same business day.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
