<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-3301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_3301">
        <akn:num>28-3301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rate of interest expressed in contract.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this section, section 28-3308, and chapter 36 of this subtitle, the parties to an instrument in writing for the payment of money at a future time may contract therein for the payment of interest on the principal amount thereof at a rate not exceeding 24% per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be lawful to contract for a rate of interest not exceeding 24% per annum on a loan or financial transaction which is secured by: (1) a first purchase mortgage or first purchase deed of trust on residential real property; (2) a first purchase security interest in stock or a membership certificate issued to a tenant stockholder or resident member by a cooperative housing organization; or (3) the assignment by way of a first security of the borrower’s interest in the proprietary lease or first right of tenancy in property covered by such organization. The first sentence of this subsection shall apply only to a loan or financial transaction which is both contracted for and consummated after the effective date of the Interest Rate Ceiling Amendment Act of 1983 and for which no written commitment to make the loan or financial transaction at a lower rate of interest was issued by the lender to the borrower prior to the effective date of the Interest Rate Ceiling Amendment Act of 1983.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be lawful to contract for a rate of interest not exceeding 24% per annum on a loan or financial transaction which is secured directly or indirectly by: (1) a mortgage or deed of trust, other than a first purchase mortgage or first purchase deed of trust, on residential real property; (2) a security interest in stock or a membership certificate issued to a tenant stockholder or resident member by a cooperative housing organization; or (3) the assignment by way of a security, other than a first security interest, of the borrower’s interest in the proprietary lease or first right of tenancy in property covered by such organization. The first sentence of this subsection shall apply only to a loan or financial transaction which is both contracted for and consummated after the effective date of the Interest Rate Ceiling Amendment Act of 1983 and for which no written commitment to make the loan or financial transaction at a lower rate of interest was issued by the lender to the borrower prior to the effective date of the Interest Rate Ceiling Amendment Act of 1983.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A loan or financial transaction which is secured by a mortgage or deed of trust on residential real property, or a security interest in stock or a membership certificate issued to a tenant stockholder or resident member by a cooperative housing organization, or the assignment by the way of security of the borrower’s interest in the proprietary lease or right of tenancy in property covered by such organization shall meet all of the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to any international banking facility time deposit or international banking facility loan, but shall be governed solely by regulations promulgated by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. For purposes of this subsection the terms “international banking facility time deposit” and “international banking facility loan” shall have the same meaning as defined in part 204.8(a)(2) and (3), respectively, of Federal Reserve System Regulation D (12 CFR 204.8(a)(2) and (3)) (1983).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of this chapter shall apply to consumer credit transactions, including modifications (including refinancing, consolidations, and deferrals), occurring in the District of Columbia. For the purposes of this chapter, a consumer credit transaction occurs in the District of Columbia if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-3301_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this chapter, the term “consumer” shall have the same meaning as in § 28-3901(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
