<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4915"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4915/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_4915">
        <akn:num>28-4915</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transferable records.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4915_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In this section, “transferable record” means an electronic record that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4915_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person has control of a transferable record if a system employed for evidencing the transfer of interests in the transferable record reliably establishes that person as the person to which the transferable record was issued or transferred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4915_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A system satisfies subsection (b) of this section, and a person is deemed to have control of a transferable record, if the transferable record is created, stored, and assigned in such a manner that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4915_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise agreed, a person having control of a transferable record is the holder, as defined in § 28:1-201(20), of the transferable record and has the same rights and defenses as a holder of an equivalent record or writing under Subtitle I of this title, including, if the applicable statutory requirements under § 28:3-302(a), § 28:7-501, or § 28:9-308 are satisfied, the rights and defenses of a holder in due course, a holder to which a negotiable document of title has been duly negotiated, or a purchaser, respectively. Delivery, possession, and indorsement are not required to obtain or exercise any of the rights under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4915_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise agreed, an obligor under a transferable record has the same rights and defenses as an equivalent obligor under equivalent records or writings under Subtitle I of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4915_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If requested by a person against which enforcement is sought, the person seeking to enforce the transferable record shall provide reasonable proof that the person is in control of the transferable record. Proof may include access to the authoritative copy of the transferable record and related business records sufficient to review the terms of the transferable record and to establish the identity of the person having control of the transferable record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
