<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4914"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4914/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_4914">
        <akn:num>28-4914</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Time and place of sending and receipt.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise agreed between the sender and the recipient, an electronic record is sent when it:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise agreed between a sender and the recipient, an electronic record is received when:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (b) of this section applies even if the place the information processing system is located is different from the place the electronic record is deemed to be received under subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise expressly provided in the electronic record or agreed between the sender and the recipient, an electronic record is deemed to be sent from the sender’s place of business and to be received at the recipient’s place of business. For purposes of this subsection, the following rules apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An electronic record is received under subsection (b) of this section even if no individual is aware of its receipt.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Receipt of an electronic acknowledgment from an information processing system described in subsection (b) of this section establishes that a record was received but, by itself, does not establish that the content sent corresponds to the content received.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4914_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person is aware that an electronic record purportedly sent under subsection (a) of this section, or purportedly received under subsection (b) of this section, was not actually sent or received, the legal effect of the sending or receipt is determined by other applicable law. Except to the extent permitted by the other law, the requirements of this subsection may not be varied by agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
