<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4001"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4001/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_4001">
        <akn:num>28-4001</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“audiologist” means any person who has at least a master’s degree in audiology and meets the requirements of the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association Certificate of clinical competence or the equivalent in the determination of the Board of Medicine. The title “audiologist” shall not be used singly or in combination with other words unless the person using the title holds the appropriate certification from the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“fitting and selling of hearing aids” means those practices used for the purpose of making selection, adaptation or sale of hearing aids.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“hearing aid” means any wearable instrument or device designed or offered for the purpose of aiding or compensating for impaired human hearing and any parts, attachments, or accessories of that wearable instrument, excluding batteries, cords or earmolds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“hearing test evaluation” means a written statement, based on testing conducted by an audiologist, otolaryngologist, or a medical technician directly supervised by an otolaryngologist. The statement shall include the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“medical clearance” means a written statement based upon a medical examination by an otolaryngologist, that concludes that the patient may benefit from a hearing aid and that there are no medical conditions to contraindicate the use of a hearing aid. The statement must include the date of the medical examination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Office” means the Office of Consumer Protection of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“otolaryngologist” means a physician licensed in the District of Columbia who specializes in medical problems of the ear, nose, and throat.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“person” means any individual, partnership, association, organization, or corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“registrant” means a hearing aid dispenser, audiologist, or otolaryngologist who engages in the practice of fitting and selling hearing aids and who has registered pursuant to section § 28-4003.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“sell” or “sale” means any transfer of title or of the right of use by sale, conditional sales contract, lease, bailment, hire-purchase, or any other means, excluding wholesale transactions of dealers and distributors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“telephone option” means an option available on hearing aids which enables the wearer to hear the electrical signal on the telephone line rather than the acoustic signal produced by the telephone.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“used hearing aid” means a hearing aid which has been worn for any period of time by a buyer or potential buyer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4001_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“hearing aid dispenser” means a person who is at least 18 years of age, has a high school diploma or the equivalent, and has received a certificate of competence from the National Hearing Aid Society or another recognized national organization approved by the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
