<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4004"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4004/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_4004">
        <akn:num>28-4004</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Special provisions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No registrant shall fit, offer for sale, or sell a hearing aid to a person unless, within the preceding three (3) months, the person has received a medical clearance after an examination by an otolaryngologist and a hearing test evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No registrant shall sell a hearing aid not conforming to the hearing test evaluation required without prior consultation and written approval from the signer of the hearing test evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Sections 28-4004(a) and 28-4004(b) do not apply to —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a prospective hearing aid user has a bona fide religious belief which precludes him or her from having a medical examination as required in section 28-4004(a), the prospective hearing aid user may waive the medical examination requirement; provided, that the prospective hearing aid user signs the following statement, printed in ten (10)-point type:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No hearing aid shall be sold to any person unless accompanied by a thirty (30) day money-back written guarantee providing that if the customer returns the hearing aid within thirty (30) days in the same condition as when purchased the customer shall be entitled to the return of the cost of the hearing aid and accessories as itemized on the bill provided pursuant to section 28-4005(a), but in no case shall the hearing aid dealer be permitted to retain a service charge greater than five percent (5%) of the cost of the hearing aid and accessories and the cost of the earmold.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4004_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No registrant or agent thereof shall visit the home or shall telephone any potential buyer for the purpose of inducing a sale of a hearing aid without having obtained, prior to the visit, the express written consent of the buyer to that visit. Any consent shall clearly and conspicuously state that the buyer is aware that the seller may attempt to sell a hearing aid during the visit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
