<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4507"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4507/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_4507">
        <akn:num>28-4507</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Damages and injunctive relief for injuries to or within the District of Columbia.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4507_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever the District of Columbia government is injured in its business or property by a violation of this chapter, the Corporation Counsel may bring a civil action in the name of the District of Columbia for damages, or for appropriate injunctive or other equitable relief, or for both, without prejudice to the right of the District of Columbia to bring similar or identical actions under any other statute. In such an action, in addition to any appropriate injunctive or equitable relief, the court may award the District of Columbia damages and the cost of suit, including reasonable attorney’s fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4507_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Corporation Counsel may bring a civil action in the name of the District of Columbia as parens patriae on behalf of any individual residing in the District of Columbia in any court of competent jurisdiction for injury sustained by such individual to such individual’s property by reason of any violation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4507_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4507_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any action under subsection (b) of this section, in which there has been a determination that a defendant violated a provision of this chapter, damages may be proved and assessed in the aggregate by the computation of illegal overcharges, or by such other reasonable system of estimating aggregate damages as the court may permit, without the necessity of separately proving the individual claim of, or amount of damage to, persons on whose behalf the suit was brought.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4507_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court may award under this section, pursuant to a motion by the District of Columbia promptly made, simple interest on actual damages for the period beginning on the date of service of the pleading of the District of Columbia setting forth a claim under this chapter and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein, if the court finds that the award of such interest for such period is just under the circumstances. In determining whether an award of interest under this section for any period is just under the circumstances, the court shall consider only:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
