<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4525"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-4525/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_4525">
        <akn:num>28-4525</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4525_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Injunctive relief. — Any appropriate agency of the District of Columbia or any person injured by any violation of the provisions of this chapter, or any trade association representative of such a person, may bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to prevent, restrain, or enjoin such a violation. In such an action, it shall not be necessary that actual damages to the plaintiff be alleged or proved, but where alleged and proved, in addition to equitable and injunctive relief, the court shall award the plaintiff as monetary relief threefold the total damage sustained by the person, and, as determined by the court, the costs of suit, including reasonable attorney’s fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4525_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Monetary relief. — In the event no injunctive relief is sought or required, any person injured by a violation of the provisions of this chapter may maintain an action for damages alone in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. In such an action, the court shall award the plaintiff as monetary relief threefold the total damage sustained by the person, and, as determined by the court, the costs of suit, including reasonable attorney’s fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-4525_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Suspension or revocation of license. — The Mayor may suspend or revoke any business license or permit of any wholesaler or retailer engaged in the retail or wholesale trade of cigarettes upon sufficient cause appearing of the violation of any provision of this chapter. Such a wholesaler or retailer shall be entitled to due process, including notice and the opportunity for a hearing before the appropriate agency of the District of Columbia. Any suspension shall be for a period not to exceed 5 consecutive business days. A revocation shall be issued only upon a finding by the appropriate agency of the District of Columbia that the affected business license or permit holder is guilty of wilful and persistent violations of the provisions of this chapter. Any person who has had a business license or permit revoked, pursuant to the terms of this section, may apply to the appropriate agency of the District of Columbia for reinstatement only after the expiration of 1 year. Any suspension or revocation issued pursuant to this section shall be reviewable by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
