<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-5001"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28-5001/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28_5001">
        <akn:num>28-5001</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-5001_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Assist in the transmission” means actions taken by a person to procure, enable, finance, or otherwise actively support the transmission of a commercial electronic mail message by another person, if the person or entity providing the assistance knows or should have known that the initiator of the commercial electronic mail message is engaged, or intends to engage, in any practice that violates this chapter. The term “assist in the transmission” shall not include activities of any person or entity related to the design, manufacture, or distribution of any technology, product, or component that has a commercially significant use other than to violate or circumvent this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-5001_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial electronic mail message” means an electronic mail message sent for the purpose of encouraging the purchase, rental of, or investment in, property, goods, intangibles, or services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-5001_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Electronic mail” means an electronic message or computer file containing an image of a message that is transmitted between 2 or more computers, electronic terminals, or cellular telephones, and includes electronic messages that are transmitted within or between computer networks.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-5001_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Electronic mail service provider” means any entity that is an intermediary in sending or receiving electronic mail or that provides to end-users of electronic mail services the ability to send or receive electronic mail.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28-5001_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Header information” means the source, destination, and routing information attached to an electronic mail message, including the originating domain name and originating electronic mail address, and any other information that appears in the line identifying, or purporting to identify, a person initiating the message.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
