<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:4-208"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:4-208/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:4_208">
        <akn:num>28:4-208</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Presentment warranties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:4-208_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an unaccepted draft is presented to the drawee for payment or acceptance and the drawee pays or accepts the draft, (i) the person obtaining payment or acceptance, at the time of presentment, and (ii) a previous transferor of the draft, at the time of transfer, warrant to the drawee that pays or accepts the draft in good faith that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:4-208_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A drawee making payment may recover from a warrantor damages for breach of warranty equal to the amount paid by the drawee less the amount the drawee received or is entitled to receive from the drawer because of the payment. In addition, the drawee is entitled to compensation for expenses and loss of interest resulting from the breach. The right of the drawee to recover damages under this subsection is not affected by any failure of the drawee to exercise ordinary care in making payment. If the drawee accepts the draft (i) breach of warranty is a defense to the obligation of the acceptor, and (ii) if the acceptor makes payment with respect to the draft, the acceptor is entitled to recover from a warrantor for breach of warranty the amounts stated in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:4-208_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a drawee asserts a claim for breach of warranty under subsection (a) of this section based on an unauthorized indorsement of the draft or an alteration of the draft, the warrantor may defend by proving that the indorsement is effective under section 28:3-404 or 28:3-405 or the drawer is precluded under section 28:3-406 or 28:4-406 from asserting against the drawee the unauthorized indorsement or alteration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:4-208_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If (i) a dishonored draft is presented for payment to the drawer or an indorser or (ii) any other item is presented for payment to a party obliged to pay the item, and the item is paid, the person obtaining payment and a prior transferor of the item warrant to the person making payment in good faith that the warrantor is, or was, at the time the warrantor transferred the item, a person entitled to enforce the item or authorized to obtain payment on behalf of a person entitled to enforce the item. The person making payment may recover from any warrantor for breach of warranty an amount equal to the amount paid plus expenses and loss of interest resulting from the breach.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:4-208_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The warranties stated in subsections (a) and (d) of this section cannot be disclaimed with respect to checks. Unless notice of a claim for breach of warranty is given to the warrantor within 30 days after the claimant has reason to know of the breach and the identity of the warrantor, the warrantor is discharged to the extent of any loss caused by the delay in giving notice of the claim.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:4-208_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A cause of action for breach of warranty under this section accrues when the claimant has reason to know of the breach.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
