<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:7-210"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:7-210/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:7_210">
        <akn:num>28:7-210</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement of warehouse’s lien.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A warehouse may enforce its lien on goods, other than goods stored by a merchant in the course of its business, only if the following requirements are satisfied:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before any sale pursuant to this section, any person claiming a right in the goods may pay the amount necessary to satisfy the lien and the reasonable expenses incurred in complying with this section. In that event, the goods may not be sold and must be retained by the warehouse subject to the terms of the receipt and this article.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A warehouse may buy at any public sale held pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A purchaser in good faith of goods sold to enforce a warehouse’s lien takes the goods free of any rights of persons against which the lien was valid, despite the warehouse’s noncompliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A warehouse may satisfy its lien from the proceeds of any sale pursuant to this section but shall hold the balance, if any, for delivery on demand to any person to which the warehouse would have been bound to deliver the goods.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The rights provided by this section are in addition to all other rights allowed by law to a creditor against a debtor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a lien is on goods stored by a merchant in the course of its business, the lien may be enforced in accordance with subsection (a) or (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:7-210_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A warehouse is liable for damages caused by failure to comply with the requirements for sale under this section and, in case of willful violation, is liable for conversion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
