<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:8-210"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:8-210/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:8_210">
        <akn:num>28:8-210</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Overissue.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:8-210_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section the term “overissue” means the issue of securities in excess of the amount the issuer has corporate power to issue, but an overissue does not occur if appropriate action has cured the overissue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:8-210_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the provisions of this article which validate a security or compel its issue or reissue do not apply to the extent that validation, issue, or reissue would result in overissue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:8-210_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an identical security not constituting an overissue is reasonably available for purchase, a person entitled to issue or validation may compel the issuer to purchase the security and deliver it if certificated or register its transfer if uncertificated, against surrender of any security certificate the person holds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:8-210_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a security is not reasonably available for purchase, a person entitled to issue or validation may recover from the issuer the price the person or the last purchaser for value paid for it with interest from the date of the person’s demand.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
