<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-523"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-523/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_523">
        <akn:num>28:9-523</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Information from filing office; sale or license of records.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-523_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person that files a written record requests an acknowledgment of the filing, the filing office shall send to the person an image of the record showing the number assigned to the record pursuant to ยง 28:9-519(a)(1) and the date and time of the filing of the record. However, if the person furnishes a copy of the record to the filing office, the filing office may instead:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-523_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person files a record other than a written record, the filing office shall communicate to the person an acknowledgment that provides:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-523_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The filing office shall communicate or otherwise make available in a record the following information to any person that requests it:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-523_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In complying with its duty under subsection (c), the filing office may communicate information in any medium. However, if requested, the filing office shall communicate information by issuing a record that can be admitted into evidence in the courts of the District without extrinsic evidence of its authenticity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-523_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The filing office shall perform the acts required by subsections (a) through (d) at the time and in the manner prescribed by filing-office rule, but not later than 2 business days after the filing office receives the request.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-523_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At least weekly, the Mayor shall offer to sell or license to the public on a nonexclusive basis, in bulk, copies of all records filed in it under this part, in every medium from time to time available to the filing office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
