<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-334"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-334/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_334">
        <akn:num>28:9-334</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Priority of security interests in fixtures and crops.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest under this article may be created in goods that are fixtures or may continue in goods that become fixtures. A security interest does not exist under this article in ordinary building materials incorporated into an improvement on land.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This article does not prevent creation of an encumbrance upon fixtures under real property law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In cases not governed by subsections (d) through (h), a security interest in fixtures is subordinate to a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the related real property other than the debtor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (h), a perfected security interest in fixtures has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if the debtor has an interest of record in or is in possession of the real property and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A perfected security interest in fixtures has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest in fixtures, whether or not perfected, has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The priority of the security interest under subsection (f)(2) continues for a reasonable time if the debtor’s right to remove the goods as against the encumbrancer or owner terminates.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A mortgage is a construction mortgage to the extent that it secures an obligation incurred for the construction of an improvement on land, including the acquisition cost of the land, if a recorded record of the mortgage so indicates. Except as otherwise provided in subsections (e) and (f), a security interest in fixtures is subordinate to a construction mortgage if a record of the mortgage is recorded before the goods become fixtures and the goods become fixtures before the completion of the construction. A mortgage has this priority to the same extent as a construction mortgage to the extent that it is given to refinance a construction mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-334_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A perfected security interest in crops growing on real property has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real property if the debtor has an interest of record in or is in possession of the real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
