<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-313"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-313/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_313">
        <akn:num>28:9-313</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>When possession by or delivery to secured party perfects security interest without filing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b), a secured party may perfect a security interest in tangible negotiable documents, goods, instruments, money, or tangible chattel paper by taking possession of the collateral. A secured party may perfect a security interest in certificated securities by taking delivery of the certificated securities under § 28:8-301.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to goods covered by a certificate of title issued by the District, a secured party may perfect a security interest in the goods by taking possession of the goods only in the circumstances described in § 28:9-316(d).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to collateral other than certificated securities and goods covered by a document, a secured party takes possession of collateral in the possession of a person other than the debtor, the secured party, or a lessee of the collateral from the debtor in the ordinary course of the debtor’s business, when:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If perfection of a security interest depends upon possession of the collateral by a secured party, perfection occurs no earlier than the time the secured party takes possession and continues only while the secured party retains possession.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest in a certificated security in registered form is perfected by delivery when delivery of the certificated security occurs under § 28:8-301 and remains perfected by delivery until the debtor obtains possession of the security certificate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person in possession of collateral is not required to acknowledge that it holds possession for a secured party’s benefit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person acknowledges that it holds possession for the secured party’s benefit:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A secured party having possession of collateral does not relinquish possession by delivering the collateral to a person other than the debtor or a lessee of the collateral from the debtor in the ordinary course of the debtor’s business if the person was instructed before the delivery or is instructed contemporaneously with the delivery:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-313_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A secured party does not relinquish possession, even if a delivery under subsection (h) violates the rights of a debtor. A person to which collateral is delivered under subsection (h) does not owe any duty to the secured party and is not required to confirm the delivery to another person unless the person otherwise agrees or law other than this article otherwise provides.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
