<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-403"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-403/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_403">
        <akn:num>28:9-403</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Agreement not to assert defenses against assignee.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-403_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In this section, “value” has the meaning provided in § 28:3-303(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-403_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this section, an agreement between an account debtor and an assignor not to assert against an assignee any claim or defense that the account debtor may have against the assignor is enforceable by an assignee that takes an assignment:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-403_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (b) does not apply to defenses of a type that may be asserted against a holder in due course of a negotiable instrument under § 28:3-305(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-403_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a consumer transaction, if a record evidences the account debtor’s obligation, law other than this article requires that the record include a statement to the effect that the rights of an assignee are subject to claims or defenses that the account debtor could assert against the original obligee, and the record does not include such a statement:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-403_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section is subject to law other than this article which establishes a different rule for an account debtor who is an individual and who incurred the obligation primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-403_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), this section does not displace law other than this article which gives effect to an agreement by an account debtor not to assert a claim or defense against an assignee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
