<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-316"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-316/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_316">
        <akn:num>28:9-316</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Effect of change in governing law.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest perfected pursuant to the law of the jurisdiction designated in § 28:9-301(1) or 28:9-305(c) remains perfected until the earliest of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a security interest described in subsection (a) becomes perfected under the law of the other jurisdiction before the earliest time or event described in that subsection, it remains perfected thereafter. If the security interest does not become perfected under the law of the other jurisdiction before the earliest time or event, it becomes unperfected and is deemed never to have been perfected as against a purchaser of the collateral for value.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A possessory security interest in collateral, other than goods covered by a certificate of title and as-extracted collateral consisting of goods, remains continuously perfected if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a security interest in goods covered by a certificate of title which is perfected by any method under the law of another jurisdiction when the goods become covered by a certificate of title from the District remains perfected until the security interest would have become unperfected under the law of the other jurisdiction had the goods not become so covered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest described in subsection (d) becomes unperfected as against a purchaser of the goods for value and is deemed never to have been perfected as against a purchaser of the goods for value if the applicable requirements for perfection under § 28:9-311(b) or 28:9-313 are not satisfied before the earlier of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest in deposit accounts, letter-of-credit rights, or investment property which is perfected under the law of the bank’s jurisdiction, the issuer’s jurisdiction, a nominated person’s jurisdiction, the securities intermediary’s jurisdiction, or the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction, as applicable, remains perfected until the earlier of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a security interest described in subsection (f) becomes perfected under the law of the other jurisdiction before the earlier of the time or the end of the period described in that subsection, it remains perfected thereafter. If the security interest does not become perfected under the law of the other jurisdiction before the earlier of that time or the end of that period, it becomes unperfected and is deemed never to have been perfected as against a purchaser of the collateral for value.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following rules apply to collateral to which a security interest attaches within 4 months after the debtor changes its location to another jurisdiction:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-316_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a financing statement naming an original debtor is filed pursuant to the law of the jurisdiction designated in § 28:9-301(1) or § 28:9-305(c) and the new debtor is located in another jurisdiction, the following rules apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
