<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-312"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-312/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_312">
        <akn:num>28:9-312</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Perfection of security interests in chattel paper, deposit accounts, documents, goods covered by documents, instruments, investment property, letter-of-credit rights, and money; perfection by permissive filing; temporary perfection without filing or transfer of possession.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest in chattel paper, negotiable documents, instruments, or investment property may be perfected by filing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in ยง 28:9-315(c) and (d) for proceeds:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>While goods are in the possession of a bailee that has issued a negotiable document covering the goods:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>While goods are in the possession of a bailee that has issued a nonnegotiable document covering the goods, a security interest in the goods may be perfected by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security interest in certificated securities, negotiable documents, or instruments is perfected without filing or the taking of possession or control for a period of 20 days from the time it attaches to the extent that it arises for new value given under an authenticated security agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A perfected security interest in a negotiable document or goods in possession of a bailee, other than one that has issued a negotiable document for the goods, remains perfected for 20 days without filing if the secured party makes available to the debtor the goods or documents representing the goods for the purpose of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A perfected security interest in a certificated security or instrument remains perfected for 20 days without filing if the secured party delivers the security certificate or instrument to the debtor for the purpose of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-312_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After the 20-day period specified in subsection (e), (f), or (g) expires, perfection depends upon compliance with this article.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
