<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-707"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/28:9-707/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_28:9_707">
        <akn:num>28:9-707</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Amendment of pre-effective-date financing statement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-707_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In this section, “pre-effective-date financing statement” means a financing statement filed before July 1, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-707_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On or after July 1, 2001, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or otherwise amend the information provided in, a pre-effective-date financing statement only in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Part 3. However, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement also may be terminated in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-707_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), if the law of the District governs perfection of a security interest, the information in a pre-effective-date financing statement may be amended after July 1, 2001 only if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-707_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the law of the District governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement may be continued only under § 28:9-705(d) and (f) or 28:9-706.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28:9-707_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whether or not the law of the District governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement filed in the District may be terminated after July 1, 2001 by filing a termination statement in the office in which the pre-effective-date financing statement is filed, unless an initial financing statement that satisfies § 28:9-706(c) has been filed in the office specified by the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Part 3 as the office in which to file a financing statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
