<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/23-1503"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/23-1503/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_23_1503">
        <akn:num>23-1503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certificate providing for attendance of witnesses at criminal prosecutions in the District of Columbia; travel allowance; penalty.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1503_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person in any State, which by its laws has made provision for commanding persons within its borders to attend and testify in criminal prosecutions or grand jury investigations in the District of Columbia, is a material witness in such a prosecution or a grand jury investigation in the District of Columbia which has commenced or is about to commence, a judge may issue a certificate under seal stating these facts and specifying the number of days the witness will be required. The certificate may include a recommendation that the witness be taken into immediate custody and delivered to an officer of the United States or the District of Columbia to assure his attendance in the District of Columbia. This certificate shall be presented to a judge of a court of record in the county in which the witness is found.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1503_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the witness is summoned to attend and testify in the District of Columbia he shall be tendered the fees and allowances authorized for witnesses in criminal cases in United States district courts. A witness who has appeared in accordance with the provisions of the summons shall not be required to remain within the District of Columbia for a period longer than that specified in the certificate, unless otherwise ordered by the court. If the witness, after coming into the District of Columbia, fails without good cause to attend and testify as directed in the summons, he may be punished in the manner provided for the punishment of any other witness who disobeys a summons issued from the court in the District of Columbia where the prosecution has been instituted or the grand jury investigation has commenced or is about to commence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
