<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/23-1331"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/23-1331/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_23_1331">
        <akn:num>23-1331</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1331_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “judicial officer” means, unless otherwise indicated, any person or court in the District of Columbia authorized pursuant to section 3041 of Title 18, United States Code, or the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, to bail or otherwise release a person before trial or sentencing or pending appeal in a court of the United States, and any judge of the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1331_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “offense” means any criminal offense committed in the District of Columbia, other than an offense triable by court-martial, military commission, provost court, or other military tribunal, which is in violation of an Act of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1331_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “dangerous crime” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1331_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “crime of violence” means aggravated assault; act of terrorism; arson; assault on a police officer (felony); assault with a dangerous weapon; assault with intent to kill, commit first degree sexual abuse, commit second degree sexual abuse, or commit child sexual abuse; assault with significant bodily injury; assault with intent to commit any other offense; burglary; carjacking; armed carjacking; child sexual abuse; cruelty to children in the first degree; extortion or blackmail accompanied by threats of violence; gang recruitment, participation, or retention by the use or threatened use of force, coercion, or intimidation; kidnapping; malicious disfigurement; manslaughter; manufacture or possession of a weapon of mass destruction; mayhem; murder; robbery; sexual abuse in the first, second, or third degrees; use, dissemination, or detonation of a weapon of mass destruction; or an attempt, solicitation, or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1331_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “addict” means any individual who habitually uses any narcotic drug as defined by section 4731 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 so as to endanger the public morals, health, safety, or welfare.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1331_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “physical injury” means bodily harm greater than transient pain or minor temporary marks.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
