<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/23-1329"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/23-1329/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_23_1329">
        <akn:num>23-1329</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties for violation of conditions of release.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who has been conditionally released pursuant to section 23-1321 and who has violated a condition of release shall be subject to revocation of release, an order of detention, and prosecution for contempt of court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Contempt sanctions may be imposed if, upon a hearing and in accordance with principles applicable to proceedings for criminal contempt, it is established that such person has intentionally violated a condition of his release. Such contempt proceedings shall be expedited and heard by the court without a jury. Any person found guilty of criminal contempt for violation of a condition of release shall be imprisoned for not more than six months, or fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01], or both. A judicial officer or a prosecutor may initiate a proceeding for contempt under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any warrant issued by a judge of the Superior Court for violation of release conditions or for contempt of court, for failure to appear as required, or pursuant to § 23-1322(d)(7), may be executed at any place within the jurisdiction of the United States. Such warrants shall be executed by a United States marshal or by any other officer authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who has been conditionally released and who violates a condition of that release by using a controlled substance or by failing to comply with the prescribed treatment for use of a controlled substance, may be ordered by the court, in addition to or in lieu of the penalties and procedures prescribed in subsections (a) through (d) of this section, to temporary placement in custody, when, in the opinion of the court, such action is necessary for treatment or to assure compliance with conditions of release. A person shall not be subject to an order of temporary detention under this subsection, unless before any such violation and order, the person has agreed in writing to the imposition of such an order as a sanction for the person’s violation of a condition of release.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23-1329_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
