<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/19-113"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/19-113/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_19_113">
        <akn:num>19-113</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Renunciation of devises and bequests; election; time limitations; renunciation or election by guardian or fiduciary; maximum rights; effect of no devise or bequest or if nothing passes under either; antenuptial or postnuptial agreements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-113_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to section 19-114, a surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner is, by a devise or bequest specified in section 19-112, barred on any statutory rights or interest he has in the real and personal estate of the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner unless, within 6 months after the will of the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner is admitted to probate, he files in the Probate Court a written renunciation to the following effect: “I, A B, surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner of  late of , deceased, renounce and quit all claim to any devise or bequest made to me by the last will of my spouse or domestic partner exhibited and proved according to law; and I elect to take in lieu thereof my legal share of the real and personal estate of my deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-113_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-113_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, during the period of 6 months specified by subsection (a) of this section, a suit is instituted to construe the will of the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner, the period of 6 months for the filing of the renunciation or election commences to run from the date when the suit is finally determined. A renunciation or election may be made in behalf of a spouse or domestic partner unable to act for himself by reason of infancy, incompetency, or inability to manage his property, by the guardian or other fiduciary acting for the spouse or domestic partner when so authorized by the court having jurisdiction of the person of the spouse or domestic partner. The time for renunciation by a spouse or domestic partner may be extended before its expiration by an order of the Probate Court for successive periods of not more than 6 months each upon petition showing reasonable cause and on notice given to the personal representative and to the other persons herein referred to in such manner as the Probate Court directs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-113_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where a decedent has not made a devise or bequest to the spouse or domestic partner, or nothing passes by a purported devise or bequest, the surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner is entitled to his legal share of the real and personal estate of the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner without filing a written renunciation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-113_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The legal share of a surviving spouse or surviving domestic partner under subsection (a) or (d) of this section is such share or interest in the real or personal property of the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner as he would have taken if the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner had died intestate, not to exceed one-half of the net estate bequeathed and devised by the will.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-113_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A valid antenuptial or postnuptial agreement entered into by the spouses or domestic partners determines the rights of the surviving spouse or the surviving domestic partner in the real and personal estate of the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner and the administration thereof, but a spouse or domestic partner may accept the benefits of a devise or bequest made to him by the deceased spouse or deceased domestic partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
