<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/19-1502"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/19-1502/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_19_1502">
        <akn:num>19-1502</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Disclaimant” means the person to whom a disclaimed interest or power would have passed had the disclaimer not been made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Disclaimed interest” means the interest that would have passed to the disclaimant had the disclaimer not been made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Disclaimer” means the refusal to accept an interest in or power over property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fiduciary” means a personal representative, trustee, agent acting under a power of attorney, or other person authorized to act as a fiduciary with respect to the property of another person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Jointly held property” means property held in the name of 2 or more persons under an arrangement in which all holders have concurrent interests and under which the last surviving holder is entitled to the whole of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, government; governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality; public corporation, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. The term “state” includes an Indian tribe or band, or Alaskan native village, recognized by federal law or formally acknowledged by a state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1502_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Trust” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
