<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/19-1101"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/19-1101/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_19_1101">
        <akn:num>19-1101</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adult” means an individual who is at least 18 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Beneficiary” means an individual for whom property has been transferred to or held under a declaration of trust by a custodial trustee for the individual’s use and benefit under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Conservator” means a person appointed or qualified by a court to manage the estate of an individual or a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Custodial trust property” means an interest in property transferred to or held under a declaration of trust by a custodial trustee under this chapter and the income from and proceeds of that interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Custodial trustee” means a person designated as trustee of a custodial trust under this chapter or a substitute or successor to the person designated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 32-701(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Guardian” means a person appointed or qualified by a court as a guardian of an individual, including a limited guardian, but not a person who is only a guardian ad litem.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Incapacitated” means lacking the ability to manage property and business affairs effectively by reason of mental illness, mental deficiency, physical illness or disability, chronic use of drugs, chronic intoxication, confinement, detention by a foreign power, disappearance, minority, or other disabling cause.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Legal representative” means a personal representative or conservator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member of the beneficiary’s family” means a beneficiary’s spouse, descendant, stepchild, parent, stepparent, grandparent, brother, sister, uncle, or aunt, whether of the whole or half blood or by adoption.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, joint venture, association, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personal representative” means an executor, administrator, or special administrator of a decedent’s estate, a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions, or a successor to any of them.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transferor” means a person who creates a custodial trust by transfer or declaration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19-1101_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Trust company” means a financial institution, corporation, or other legal entity, authorized to exercise general trust powers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
