<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/49-1101.17"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/49-1101.17/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_49_1101_17">
        <akn:num>49-1101.17</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Withdrawal and dissolution.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1101_17_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Once effective, the compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each and every member state; provided, that a member state may withdraw from the compact by specifically repealing the statute that enacted the compact into law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1101_17_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Withdrawal from this compact shall be by the enactment of a statute repealing the statute that enacted the compact into law, but the repeal shall not take effect until one year after the effective date of such statute and until written notice of the withdrawal has been given by the withdrawing state to the Governor of each other member jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1101_17_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairperson of the Interstate Commission in writing upon the introduction of legislation repealing this compact in the withdrawing state. The Interstate Commission shall notify the other member states of the withdrawing state’s intent to withdraw within 60 days of its receipt of the notice of withdrawal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1101_17_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The withdrawing state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of withdrawal, including the performance of obligations that extend beyond the effective date of withdrawal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1101_17_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reinstatement following withdrawal of a member state shall occur upon the withdrawing state reenacting the compact or upon such later date as determined by the Interstate Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1101_17_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
