<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/49-1003"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/49-1003/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_49_1003">
        <akn:num>49-1003</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Purposes of the Office of Veterans Affairs.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provide assistance to veterans, their dependents and survivors that augments, and is not be duplicative of, assistance already provided to District residents by other District agencies;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Assist veterans, their dependents and survivors receive all benefits to which they are entitled from the District and federal governments;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to its annual appropriation, endeavor to secure support for its operations from outside the District government, including the solicitation and receipt of donations, grants, and volunteer services in accordance with District law;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Satisfy the unmet needs of veterans, their dependents and survivors through federal benefits insofar as practicable instead of through District government benefits;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Assist unemployed and under-employed veterans in finding suitable employment;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Partner with federal and state governments, veterans service organizations, community groups, corporations, and other organizations to identify the needs of veterans, their dependents and survivors, and design and implement programs and services to meet these needs;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Educate the public, including District residents and employers, about the rights and needs of veterans, their dependents and survivors;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Obtain recognition of the Office by the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs as the “State organization” for the District of Columbia;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Employ and train, as needed, individuals who are accredited by the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establish a database on veterans, including an archive of DD-214’s and other documents required in the adjudication of veterans’ claims, and linkages with federal databases;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Research the demographics of veterans and analyze their needs and priorities;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Inform and counsel veterans, their dependents and survivors concerning benefits, procedures for filing claims, and status of claims when the Office is assisting in the claims process;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provide, or assist in securing representation for appeals by veterans, their dependents and survivors to the federal Board of Veterans Appeals;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Liaison with the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, other federal agencies, state and local government agencies, community groups, veteran service organizations, other organizations, and individuals to promote veterans issues;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursue opportunities through public-private partnerships with veterans service organizations, businesses, labor organizations, religious organizations, private charities, and others to serve veterans more effectively;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In collaboration with the Mayor, initiate, review, and support legislation beneficial to veterans, their dependents, and their survivors;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Propose programs and services that are specific to meet the changing needs of veterans, from all service periods, and their dependents and survivors;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Engage volunteers to assist the Office, including from veterans service organizations and the work-study and work therapy programs of the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prepare the Office’s annual budget for use by the Mayor and the District’s Chief Financial Officer;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prepare an annual report for the Mayor and the Council on the Office’s activities and recommendations;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Monitor and evaluate the quality of services that the District and federal governments furnish to veterans, their dependents and survivors;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In accordance with District law, solicit, receive, and use donations of money and services from individuals and organizations, including funds and services to assist in maintaining and repairing the D.C. Veterans War Memorial and surrounding flora;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Coordinate with and, on request, advise the Mayor and other agencies of the District government concerning veteran-related issues;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the Mayor’s request, represent the District government at veteran-related events and programs; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49-1003_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Engage in other activities as needed to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
