<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-109.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-109.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_109_02">
        <akn:num>9-109.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Dedicated highway fund and repayment of temporary waiver amounts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-109_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment of fund. — Not later than December 31, 1995, the District of Columbia shall establish a dedicated highway fund to be comprised, at a minimum, of amounts equivalent to receipts from motor fuel taxes and, if necessary, motor vehicle taxes and fees collected by the District of Columbia to pay in accordance with this section the cost-sharing requirements established under Title 23, United States Code, and to repay the United States for increased Federal shares of eligible projects paid pursuant to § 9-109.01(a). The fund shall be separate from the general fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-109_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payment of non-federal share. — For fiscal year 1997 and each fiscal year thereafter, amounts in the fund shall be sufficient to pay, at a minimum, the cost-sharing requirements established under Title 23, United States Code, for such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-109_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repayment requirements. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-109_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Enforcement. — If the District of Columbia does not meet any requirement established by subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section and applicable in a fiscal year, the Secretary of Transportation shall not approve any highway project in the District of Columbia under Title 23, United States Code, until the requirement is met.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-109_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Inspector General audit. — Not later than February 1, 2001, and each February 1 thereafter, the Inspector General of the District of Columbia shall audit the financial statements of the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund for the preceding fiscal year and shall submit to Congress, the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, and the Council a report on the results of such audit. Not later than March 15, 2011, and each March 15 thereafter, the Inspector General shall examine the statements forecasting the conditions and operations of the Trust Fund for the next 5 fiscal years commencing on the previous October 1 and shall submit to Congress, the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, and the Council a report on the results of such examination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
