<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-107.51"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-107.51/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_107_51">
        <akn:num>9-107.51</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Authorized Signatory” means the Chief Financial Officer, the District of Columbia Treasurer, or any deputy mayor of the executive office of the Mayor to whom the Mayor has delegated any of the Mayor’s functions under this part pursuant to § 1-204.22(6).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bond Counsel” means a firm or firms of attorneys designated as bond counsel from time to time by the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bonds” means the District of Columbia revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, and other obligations), in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to this part and § 1-204.90.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chairman” means the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chief Financial Officer” means the Chief Financial Officer established pursuant to § 1-204.24(a)(1) [§ 1-204.24a(a)].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Closing Documents” means all documents and agreements, other than Financing Documents, that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the GARVEE Bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Debt Service” means payment of principal, premium, if any, and interest on the GARVEE Bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financing Documents” means the documents, other than Closing Documents, that relate to the financing or refinancing of transactions to be effected through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the GARVEE Bonds, including any offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“GARVEE” means grant anticipation revenue vehicle debt financing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“GARVEE Bonds” means bonds secured by GARVEE Revenues and issued to finance the Qualified Transportation Project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“GARVEE Revenues” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home Rule Act” means Chapter 2 of Title 1 [§ 1-201.01 et seq.)].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Transportation Project” means the following projects that meet the eligibility requirements of the Federal Highway Administration as permissible transportation expenditures under Title 23 of the Code of Federal Regulations:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-107_51_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Transportation Project Costs” means all costs incurred in the construction of the Qualified Transportation Project, including, without limitation:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
