<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-1113.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-1113.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_1113_01">
        <akn:num>9-1113.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Acquisition of bus companies; franchise cancelled; charter bus service by Authority; corporate status of D.C. Transit System, Inc.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1113_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Based on the findings set forth in § 2 of this Act, it is the sense of the Congress that the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Transit Authority”) should initiate negotiations as soon as possible with the ownership of D.C. Transit System, Incorporated (and its subsidiary, the Washington, Virginia, and Maryland Coach Company), the Alexandria, Barcroft, and Washington Transit Company, and the WMA Transit Company for acquisition by the Transit Authority of capital stock or facilities, plant, equipment, real and personal property of such bus companies of whatever nature, whether owned directly or indirectly, used or useful for mass transportation by bus of passengers within the Washington metropolitan area. It is further the sense of the Congress that representatives of the Transit Authority should participate in any labor contract negotiations undertaken prior to acquisition by the Transit Authority of such bus companies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1113_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The franchise to operate a system of mass transportation of passengers for hire granted to D.C. Transit System, Incorporated, by the Act of July 24, 1956 (70 Stat. 598) is hereby canceled, effective upon the date immediately preceding the date on which the Transit Authority acquires the transit facilities of D.C. Transit System, Incorporated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1113_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1113_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
