<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-1111.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-1111.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_1111_01">
        <akn:num>9-1111.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1111_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “adopted regional system” means that system described in the Transit Authority’s report entitled “Adopted Regional Rapid Rail Transit Plan and Program, March 1, 1968 (revised February 7, 1969),” as that system may hereafter be altered, revised, or amended in accordance with the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1111_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Compact” means the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact (80 Stat. 1324, Public Law 89-774).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1111_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Transit Authority” means the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority established under Article III of the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1111_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Agreement” means the Initial Bond Repayment Participation Agreement executed by the Transit Authority and the United States Department of Transportation on September 18, 1979, and amendments thereto, including the Supplemental Agreement described in § 302 of the Initial Bond Repayment Participation Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-1111_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “local participating governments” means those governments which comprise the Washington Metropolitan Transit Zone, as defined by paragraph 3 of Article III of Title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
