<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-202.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-202.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_202_09">
        <akn:num>9-202.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Approval subject to contingencies; relocation assistance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-202_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council may make the approval of a closing of all or part of a street or alley contingent upon any or all of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-202_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-202_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to be eligible for the relocation assistance provided in subsection (b) of this section, a retail tenant:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-202_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A retail tenant shall refund any relocation payment provided under this section if the retail tenant relocates outside the District of Columbia within a period of 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-202_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall not apply to applications by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority for closing all or part of a street or alley for the sole purpose of construction of transit facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-202_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant who obtains a street or alley closing or a zoning density increase and who is required to construct or rehabilitate affordable housing pursuant to section 308b of the Comprehensive Plan (10 DCMR) [10 DCMR § 308b] shall not be issued a building permit for the applicant’s commercial development until the applicant certifies to the District either that a building permit has been issued for the required amount of affordable housing, or that the applicant has contributed sufficient funds to a housing provider to construct or rehabilitate the required amount of affordable housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
