<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-203.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-203.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_203_06">
        <akn:num>9-203.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Improvement of street — Prerequisites.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-203_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to the improvement or issuance of a permit to improve a street that has been acquired for street purposes by the District but has neither been improved nor used as a public right-of-way for vehicles within 10 years of its acquisition, the Mayor shall submit a proposed street improvement, a proposed resolution to consider the proposed improvement, and supporting documents regarding the proposed improvement to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed improvement, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed improvement shall be deemed approved, and the Mayor may improve or issue a permit to improve the street.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-203_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to submitting the resolution to the Council required in subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall solicit comments on the proposed improvement from appropriate executive branch agencies and public utilities, the Advisory Neighborhood Commission within whose area the street is located, and each owner of property within the squares adjacent to the street to be improved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-203_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The supporting documents required to be submitted to the Council by subsection (a) of this section shall include at a minimum:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-203_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to a proposal that consists of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
