<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-501"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-501/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_501">
        <akn:num>9-501</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rates; maintenance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No more than the following rates shall be paid for lighting avenues, streets, roads, alleys, and public spaces:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized, in his discretion, to purchase or construct from street-lighting appropriations made in the Act of June 26, 1912 (37 Stat. 181), posts, lanterns, street designations, and all necessary fixtures or appurtenances for any of the systems of lighting above named; provided, that whenever the said Mayor shall furnish a lamppost including only the globe, the ornamental top, and the street-designation frame and signs for the electric incandescent lamps, or including only the street-designation frame and signs for gas lamps, or including only the street-designation frame and signs and the arm or top for arc lamps, $1.65 per lamp per annum for gas or electric incandescent lamps and $4.40 per lamp per annum for electric arc lamps shall be deducted from the rates above fixed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is further authorized, in his discretion, to adopt other forms of electric street lighting than those named, in which event payments under appropriations made in the Act of June 26, 1912 (37 Stat. 181), shall be made for the lighting service rendered at not to exceed $.03 per kilowatt-hour for current consumed, and, in addition thereto, 11 per centum per annum of the cost to the lighting company of furnishing and installing lamps, posts, street designations, fixtures, and the cable from lamps to the nearest point of current supply, and a fair sum for the cost of maintenance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When ordered to do so by the said Mayor, lighting companies shall move and readjust any lamps maintained by them at the following rates:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When ordered by the Mayor to do so, lighting companies in the District of Columbia shall discontinue any public lamps maintained by them without further payment therefor, and shall remove from the streets, at their own expense, all posts, lanterns, and fixtures connected therewith.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-501_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds received under this section and ยง 9-502 shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall not be accounted for by a separate fund or account within the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
