<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-906"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/9-906/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_9_906">
        <akn:num>9-906</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authority rules and regulations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall have power to adopt, amend, and repeal rules and regulations pertaining to the use, maintenance and operation of its facilities and governing the conduct of persons and organizations using its facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless the Authority shall by unanimous vote of all members present determine that an emergency exists, the Authority shall, before the adoption of any rule or regulation or alteration, amendment or modification:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority’s rules and regulations shall be available for public inspection in the Authority’s principal office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority’s rules and regulations relating to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The violation of any rule or regulation of the Authority establishing a noise limitation on aircraft that operate at the Authority Facilities shall subject the violator, in the discretion of the circuit court of any political subdivision where the facility is located to a civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 for each violation. The penalty shall be paid to the Authority. With consent of the violator or the accused violator of a rule establishing aircraft noise limits, the Authority may provide, in an order issued against the violator or accused violator, for the payment of civil charges in specific sums not to exceed the limit that could be imposed by the court. Such civil charge when paid shall be in lieu of any civil penalty that could be imposed by the Court. Any court proceeding shall be within the exclusive jurisdiction of the circuit court and shall be a civil proceeding at law brought by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The violation of any Authority rule or regulation, having the force and effect of law, shall be a Class 1 misdemeanor unless otherwise specified by chapter 598 of the 1985 Acts of Assembly or unless a lesser penalty is set by the Authority in the rule or regulation. The rules of criminal procedure and evidence that apply throughout the Commonwealth of Virginia (“Commonwealth”) shall apply to the adjudication of any case involving the violation of any Authority rule or regulation having the force and effect of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The courts of the Commonwealth shall take judicial notice of the Authority’s regularly adopted rules and regulations. For the convenience of the courts which may regularly hear cases arising under the Authority’s rules and regulations, the Authority may certify to the clerk of such court a copy of its rules and regulations. Any such certification, when signed by the chairman of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, shall be accepted as evidence of the facts therein stated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9-906_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to the violation of any statute of the Commonwealth, local ordinance, or Authority rule or regulation having the force and effect of law occurring at the Authority Facilities:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
