<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-1722"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-1722/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_21_1722">
        <akn:num>21-1722</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Prohibition from exercising powers conferred upon trustee.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1722_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1722_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1722_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If (1) a power described in subsection (b) of this section is exercisable in favor of a beneficiary, and (2) a power is conferred on that beneficiary to remove or replace the trustee, the beneficiary may exercise the power only to replace the trustee with a person who is either an adverse party or a party who is not related or subordinate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1722_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the governing instrument contains a power described under subsection (b) of this section and there is no trustee who can exercise the power, the trustee then serving may appoint a special trustee who is either an adverse party or a party who is not related or subordinate to exercise the power. If the trustee fails to appoint a special trustee, upon application of any party in interest, a court may appoint a special trustee who is not disqualified under this subsection to exercise the power during the period of time that the court designates.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1722_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to a trust if and to the extent that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1722_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
