<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-1201"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-1201/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_21_1201">
        <akn:num>21-1201</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Administer” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Developmental disability” means a severe chronic disability of a person 5 years of age or older which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“General supervision” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intellectual disability” means a substantial limitation in mental capacity that manifests before 18 years of age, characterized by significantly below-average intellectual functioning, existing concurrently with related limitations in 2 or more of the following applicable, adaptive skills:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Licensed practitioner” means a medical doctor, dentist, or advanced registered nurse.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medication” means a controlled (excluding Classes I and II) or noncontrolled substance or treatment regarded as effective in bringing about recovery, restoration of health, alleviation of pain or symptoms of an illness, or the normal functioning of the body.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Monitor” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prescription” means an order for medication signed by a licensed practitioner or transmitted by the licensed practitioner to a pharmacist, registered nurse, or licensed practical nurse by word of mouth, telephone, telegraph, or other means of communication, and recorded in writing by the pharmacist, registered nurse, or licensed practical nurse.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Program” means an agency licensed, certified, or approved by the District government as a child care facility, private school, day program, community based residence, or other agency providing residential services, education, habilitation, vocational, or employment training services to individuals with intellectual disabilities or other developmental disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Program participant” means an individual with an intellectual disability or other development disability who is enrolled in or attending a public or private program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Self-administration of medication” means that the program participant has the ability to identify, pour, and administer medication without assistance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-1201_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Trained employee” means an individual employed to work in a program who has successfully completed a training program approved by the Mayor and is certified to administer medication to program participants, or an individual who has successfully completed a training program in medication administration approved by the State of Maryland or the Commonwealth of Virginia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
