<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-2071"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-2071/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_21_2071">
        <akn:num>21-2071</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Distributive duties and powers of conservator.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2071_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The conservator shall consider recommendations relating to the appropriate standard of support, education, and benefit of the protected individual or dependent made by the protected individual and a parent or guardian, if any. The conservator may not be surcharged for sums paid to persons furnishing support, education, or care to the protected individual or a dependent pursuant to the recommendations of a guardian of the protected individual unless the conservator knows that the guardian derives personal financial benefit from the recommendation, including relief from any personal duty of support, or knows that the recommendations are clearly not in the best interest of the protected individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2071_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The conservator shall expend or distribute sums reasonably necessary for the support, education, care, or benefit of the protected individual and dependents with due regard to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2071_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The conservator may expend funds of the estate for the support of individuals legally dependent on the protected individual and others who are members of the protected individual’s household who are unable to support themselves and who are in need of support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2071_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funds expended under this section may be paid by the conservator to any person, including the protected individual, to reimburse for expenditures that the conservator might have made, or in advance for services to be rendered to the protected individual if it is reasonable to expect that the services will be performed and advance payments are customary or reasonably necessary under the circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2071_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A conservator, in discharging the responsibilities conferred by court order and this section, shall implement the principles described in section 21-2055(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
