<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-2041"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-2041/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_21_2041">
        <akn:num>21-2041</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Procedure for court-appointment of a guardian of an incapacitated individual.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An incapacitated individual or any person interested in the welfare of the incapacitated individual may petition for appointment of a guardian, either limited, temporary, or general.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The petition shall state the name, address, and interest of the petitioner, state the name, age, residence, and address of the individual for whom a guardian is sought, and set forth the reasons for which the guardianship is sought with specific particularity so as to enable the court to determine what class of examiner and visitor should examine the person alleged to be incapacitated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The petition shall be served upon the subject of the petition, by first class mail, within 3 days of its filing. Proof of service is to be by certificate of service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After the filing of a petition, the court shall set a date for hearing on the issue of incapacity so that notice may be given as required by section 21-2042 and, unless the allegedly incapacitated individual is represented by counsel, the court shall appoint an attorney to represent the individual in the proceeding. The court shall appoint an appropriately qualified examiner who shall submit a report in writing to the court. The individual alleged to be incapacitated also shall be interviewed by a visitor appointed by the court. The examiner and the visitor shall be separate persons. The court may waive the appointment of a visitor and, where a report has been submitted in writing to the court for the allegedly incapacitated individual, the court may waive the appointment of an examiner. The court shall waive, absent good cause shown, the appointments of a visitor and examiner if the petition seeks appointment of an emergency guardian or a health-care guardian and the petition is supported by the certification of incapacity made pursuant to section 21-2204.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court may utilize the services of additional visitors to evaluate the condition of the allegedly incapacitated individual and to make appropriate recommendations to the court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of an individual whose incapacity is alleged to arise out of an intellectual disability, preference is for the appointment of an examiner and visitor who are qualified developmental disability professionals and who can collectively give a complete social, psychological, and medical evaluation of the individual. The court may waive the appointment of a visitor and, where a current individual habilitation plan prepared pursuant to section 7-1304.03 is submitted to the court, the court may waive the appointment of an examiner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For any individual alleged to be incapacitated, any current social, psychological, medical, or other evaluation used for diagnostic purposes or in the development of a current plan of treatment or any current plan of treatment shall be presented as evidence to the court. For an individual alleged to be incapacitated for health-care decisions, the certification of incapacity made pursuant to section 21-2204 shall be presented as evidence to the court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual alleged to be incapacitated shall be present at the hearing unless good cause is shown for the absence. The individual shall be represented by counsel and is entitled to present evidence and to cross-examine witnesses, including any court-appointed examiner or visitor. The hearing may be closed if the individual alleged to be incapacitated or counsel for the individual so requests.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2041_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person may apply for permission to participate in the proceeding, and the court may grant the request, with or without hearing, upon determining that the best interest of the alleged incapacitated individual will be served. The court may attach appropriate conditions to the permission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
