<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-2403.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/21-2403.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_21_2403_01">
        <akn:num>21-2403.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of guardianship or conservatorship to another state.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2403_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A guardian or conservator appointed in the District of Columbia may petition the Superior Court to transfer the guardianship or conservatorship to another state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2403_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of a petition under subsection (a) of this section shall be given to the persons that would be entitled to notice of a petition in the District of Columbia for the appointment of a guardian or conservator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2403_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On the Superior Court’s own motion or on request of the guardian or conservator, the incapacitated or protected person, or other person required to be notified of the petition, the Superior Court shall hold a hearing on a petition filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2403_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court shall issue a provisional order granting a petition to transfer a guardianship and shall direct the guardian to petition for guardianship in the other state if the Superior Court is satisfied that the guardianship will be accepted by the court in the other state and the Superior Court finds that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2403_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court shall issue a provisional order granting a petition to transfer a conservatorship and shall direct the conservator to petition for conservatorship in the other state if the Superior Court is satisfied that the conservatorship will be accepted by the court of the other state and the Superior Court finds that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21-2403_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court shall issue a final order confirming the transfer and terminating the guardianship or conservatorship upon its receipt of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
