<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/41-136"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/41-136/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_41_136">
        <akn:num>41-136</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All fines levied pursuant to § 41-135(a) are civil in nature.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may issue a notice of violation to any person who violates a provision of this chapter. The notice shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A notice of violation shall be the summons and complaint for purposes of this section. A duplicate of the notice of violation shall be served personally on the person to whom it is issued as provided in subsection (d) of this section. The original or a facsimile thereof shall be filed with the Corporation Counsel and shall be deemed a record kept in the ordinary course of business and shall be prima facie evidence of the facts contained therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A notice of violation shall be served personally upon the alleged violator. If the alleged violator is not present the notice of violation shall be served by affixing such notice to the place of business in a conspicuous place.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall prescribe the form for the notice of violation. A Mayor’s rule or order establishing the amount of collateral shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 30 calendar day review period, excluding days of Council of the District of Columbia recess. No such rules or regulations shall take effect until the end of the 30 calendar day period beginning on the day such rules or regulations are transmitted by the Mayor to the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia, and then, only if during such period, the Council of the District of Columbia does not adopt a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person shall answer a notice of violation within 20 days by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise provided, the conduct of any civil trial commenced pursuant to subsections (b), (c), (d), (e) and (f) of this section shall be governed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In such trial, the complaint of a violation of this chapter shall be brought in the name of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel. The burden of proof shall be upon the District of Columbia and no violation of this chapter may be established except upon proof by a preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All fines, collateral, and fees collected under this section shall be paid into the General Fund of the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A fine or collateral is due and payable pursuant to § 41-135(a) upon default or a finding at trial in favor of the District government or upon the failure of a person to answer a notice of violation within 15 days as provided in subsection (f) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure of a person to pay a fine or collateral when due shall cause such fine or collateral to be due and payable in twice the original amount, not to exceed $20,000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-136_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
