<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/41-102"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/41-102/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_41_102">
        <akn:num>41-102</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apparent owner” means the person whose name appears on the records of the holder as the person entitled to property held by the holder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Attorney General” means the chief legal officer of a state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Banking organization” means any bank, trust company, savings bank, or a private banker or such other individual or organization defined by the laws of the United States or of the District of Columbia as a bank or banking organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business association” means a corporation, joint stock company, investment company, partnership, unincorporated association, joint venture, limited liability company, business trust, trust company, financial organization, insurance company, mutual fund, utility, or other business entity consisting of one or more persons, whether or not for profit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means within the geographical boundaries of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domicile” means, with respect to businesses:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee benefit trust distribution” means any money, life insurance, endowment, or annuity policy or proceeds thereof, securities or other intangible property, and any tangible property that is distributable to a participant, former participant, or the beneficiary, estate, or heirs of a participant, former participant or beneficiary, from a trust or custodial fund established under a plan to provide health and welfare, pension, vacation, severance, retirement benefit, death benefit, stock purchase, profit sharing, employee savings, supplemental unemployment insurance benefits, or similar benefits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial organization” means any savings and loan association, building and loan association, credit union, or investment company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Good faith” means honesty in fact and the observance of reasonable commercial standards of fair dealing in the trade.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Holder” means any person wherever organized or domiciled:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intangible personal property” means all choses or things in action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Last known address” means a description of the location of the apparent owner for the purpose of the delivery and receipt of mail.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Life insurance corporation” means any association or corporation including any nonprofit relief association as defined by § 47-2611, transacting the business of insurance on the lives of persons or insurance appertaining thereto, including, without limitation, endowments and annuities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the Mayor’s authorized agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means a depositor in the case of a deposit; a beneficiary in the case of a trust; a creditor, claimant, or payee in the case of other choses in action; or any person having a legal or equitable interest in property subject to this chapter or his or her legal representative.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, business association, government or governmental subdivision or agency, public corporation, public authority, estate, trust, 2 or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_16A">
      <akn:num>(16A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property” means a fixed and certain interest in or right in an intangible property that is held, issued, or owed in the course of a holder’s business, or by a government or governmental entity, and all income or increments therefrom, including that which is referred to as or evidenced by any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_16B">
      <akn:num>(16B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is sorted in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-102_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Utility” means any person who owns or operates for public use any plant, equipment, property, franchise, or license for the transmission of communications or the production, storage, transmission, sale, delivery, or furnishing of electricity, water, steam, or gas.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
