<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/41-106"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/41-106/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_41_106">
        <akn:num>41-106</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bank deposits and funds in financial organizations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any demand, savings, or matured time deposit with a banking or financial organization, including deposits that are automatically renewable, and any funds paid toward the purchase of shares, a mutual investment certificate, or any other interest in a financial organization is presumed abandoned unless the owner within 3 years has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of subsection (a) of this section, the term “property” includes any interest or dividends thereon.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any sum payable on a traveler’s check issued by a banking or financial institution or a business association in the District that has been outstanding for more than 15 years after its issuance is presumed abandoned if the owner, for more than 15 years, has not communicated in writing with the banking or financial organization or business association concerning it or otherwise indicated an interest as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file prepared by an employee of the banking or financial organization or business association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any sum payable on a money order issued by a banking or financial institution or a business association in the District that has been outstanding for more than 7 years after its issuance is presumed abandoned if the owner, for more than  7 years, has not communicated in writing with the banking or financial organization or business association concerning it or otherwise indicated an interest as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file prepared by an employee of the banking or financial organization or business association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A sum payable on any other written instrument on which a banking or financial organization or business association in the District is directly liable, including, but not limited to, certified checks, or drafts, that has been outstanding for more than 3 years after it was payable, or after its issuance if payable on demand, is presumed abandoned unless the owner has, within 3 years, communicated in writing with the banking or financial organization or business association concerning it or otherwise indicated an interest as evidenced by a memorandum on file prepared by an employee of the banking or financial organization or business association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No holder may impose with respect to property described in subsection (a) of this section any charges due to dormancy or inactivity, or cease payment of interest unless:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No holder shall deduct from the amount of any draft, registered check, money order, certified check, traveler’s check, cashier’s check, treasurer’s check, or any similar written instrument any charges imposed by reason of the failure to present such items for encashment unless:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in this section, in the event that any type of property subject to this section is an asset of an Individual Retirement Account established pursuant to the Employee Retirement Security Act of 1974 (26 U.S.C. § 408 (a)) or of a Keogh Plan established pursuant to the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (26 U.S.C. § 401 (a)), respectively, it shall not be deemed matured or otherwise reportable if, under the terms of such plan, distribution of all or part of the property would not then be mandatory.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41-106_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any property automatically renewable according to its terms that is subject to subsection (a) of this section shall be deemed matured for purposes of this section upon the expiration of its initial term. If at the time provided for delivery in § 41-119, a penalty or forfeiture in the payment of interest would result from the delivery of any such property, the time for delivery shall be extended until such time as no penalty for forfeiture would result.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
