<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/11-1703"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/11-1703/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_11_1703">
        <akn:num>11-1703</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Executive Officer of the District of Columbia courts; appointment; compensation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1703_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There shall be an Executive Officer of the District of Columbia courts (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Executive Officer”). The Executive Officer shall be responsible for the administration of the District of Columbia court system subject to the supervision of the Joint Committee and the chief judges of the respective courts as provided in this chapter. The Executive Officer shall be subject to the supervision of the Joint Committee regarding administrative matters that are enumerated in section 11-1701(b). The Executive Officer shall be subject to the supervision of the chief judges in their respective courts: (1) regarding all administrative matters other than those within the responsibility enumerated in section 11-1701(b), and (2) regarding the implementation in the respective courts of the matters enumerated in section 11-1701(b), consistent with the general policies and directives of the Joint Committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1703_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Officer shall be appointed, and subject to removal, by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration with the approval of the chief judges of the District of Columbia Courts. In making such appointment the Joint Committee shall consider experience and special training in administrative and executive positions and familiarity with court procedures.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1703_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Officer shall be a bona fide resident of the District of Columbia or become a resident not more than 180 days after the date of appointment except that the Executive Officer in office at the effective date of this Act shall not be required to be or to become a resident of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1703_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Officer shall receive the same compensation, including retirement benefits, as an associate judge of the Superior Court, except that the Executive Officer (if initially hired after October 1, 1997) shall be eligible for retirement under subchapter III of Chapter 15 when the Executive Officer has completed 7 years of service as Executive Officer, whether continuous or not.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
