<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/11-1564"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/11-1564/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_11_1564">
        <akn:num>11-1564</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Computation of retirement salary; election to credit other service.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1564_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The retirement salary of a judge who retires pursuant to section 11-1562(a) and (b) shall be paid annually in equal monthly installments during the remainder of the judge’s life and shall bear the same ratio to the judge’s basic salary immediately prior to the date of the judge’s retirement as the total of the judge’s aggregate years of service bears to the period of thirty years. A judge who elects to receive a reduced retirement salary pursuant to section 11-1562(b)(2) shall have retirement salary reduced by one-twelfth of 1 per centum for each month or fraction of a month the judge is under the age of sixty at the time of the commencement of reduced retirement salary. In no event shall the retirement salary (including the amount provided by subsection (c) of this section) of a judge exceed 80 per centum of the judge’s basic salary immediately prior to the date of the judge’s retirement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1564_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The retirement salary of a judge retired for disability pursuant to section 11-1526(b) or section 11-1562(c) or (d) shall be paid annually in equal monthly installments during the remainder of the judge’s life and shall be computed as provided in subsection (a). If a judge is retired for disability, the judge’s retirement salary shall not be reduced because of the judge’s age at the time of retirement. In no event shall the retirement salary of a judge retired for disability be less than 50 per centum or exceed 80 per centum of the judge’s basic salary immediately prior to the date of the judge’s retirement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1564_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In computing the retirement salary of a judge retiring under section 11-1562, the judge shall be entitled, if the judge so elects during the continuance of judicial service or at the time of retirement, to receive, in addition to the amount provided for in subsection (a) of this section, an amount (payable annually in equal monthly installments during the remainder of the judge’s life) based on military and civilian service performed by the judge which is creditable under section 8332 of title 5, United States Code, computed in accordance with section 8339 (a), (b), (c), (d), (g), and (h) of that title, as applicable, subject to the provisions of section 8334 (c) and (d) of that title and the provisions of subsection (d) of this section; except that average pay for the purpose of the computation shall be deemed to be the basic salary of the judge immediately prior to the date of retirement under section 11-1562.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1564_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1564_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subchapter shall prevent a judge eligible therefor from simultaneously receiving retirement salary under this section and any annuity or retired pay to which the judge would otherwise be entitled under any other law without regard to this subchapter. However, in computing the retirement salary of a judge under this section, service used in the computation of such other annuity shall not be credited.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
