<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/11-1732"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/11-1732/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_11_1732">
        <akn:num>11-1732</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Magistrate judges.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With the approval of a majority of the judges of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in active service and subject to standards and procedures established by the rules of the Superior Court, the chief judge of the Superior Court may appoint magistrate judges, who shall serve in the Superior Court and perform the duties enumerated in subsection (j) of this section (or, in the case of magistrate judges for the Family Court or the Domestic Violence Unit of the Superior Court, the duties enumerated in section 11-1732A(d)) and such other functions incidental to these duties as are consistent with the rules of the Superior Court and the Constitution and laws of the United States and of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Magistrate judges shall be selected pursuant to standards and procedures adopted by the Board of Judges. Such procedures shall contain provisions for public notice of all vacancies in magistrate judge positions and for the establishment by the Court of an advisory merit selection panel, composed of lawyer and nonlawyer residents of the District of Columbia who are not employees of the District of Columbia Courts, to assist the Board of Judges in identifying and recommending persons who are best qualified to fill such positions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in section 11-1732A(b), no individual shall be appointed as a magistrate judge unless that individual —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Magistrate judges shall be appointed for terms of four years and may be reappointed for terms of four years. Those individuals serving as magistrate judges on the effective date of this Act shall be automatically appointed for a four year term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the expiration of a magistrate judge’s term, the magistrate judge may continue to perform the duties of office until a successor is appointed, or for 90 days after the date of the expiration of the hearing commissioner’s term, whichever is earlier.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No individual may serve as a magistrate judge under this section after having attained the age of seventy-four.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Judges may suspend, involuntarily retire, or remove a magistrate judge, during the term for which the magistrate judge is appointed, only for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of duty, or physical or mental disability. Suspension, involuntary retirement, or removal requires the concurrence of a majority of the judges in active service. Before any order of suspension, involuntary retirement, or removal shall be entered, a full specification of the charges and the opportunity to be heard shall be furnished to the magistrate judge pursuant to procedures established by rules of the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Board of Judges determines that a magistrate judge position is not needed, the Board of Judges may terminate the position.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A magistrate judge, when specifically designated by the chief judge of the Superior Court, and subject to the rules of the Superior Court and the right of review under subsection (k), may perform the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to proceedings and hearings under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (j) (or proceedings and hearings under section§ 11-1732A(d), in the case of magistrate judges for the Family Court or the Domestic Violence Unit of the Superior Court), a review of the magistrate judge’s order or judgment, in whole or in part, may be made by a judge of the appropriate division (or, in the case of an order or judgment of a magistrate judge of the Family Court or the Domestic Violence Unit of the Superior Court, by a judge of the Family Court or the Domestic Violence Unit) sua sponte and must be made upon a motion of one of the parties made pursuant to procedures established by rules of the Superior Court. The reviewing judge shall conduct such proceedings as required by the rules of the Superior Court. An appeal to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals may be made only after a judge of the Superior Court has reviewed the order or judgment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court shall ensure that all magistrate judges receive training to enable them to fulfill their responsibilities (subject to the requirements of section 11-1732A(f) in the case of magistrate judges of the Family Court of the Superior Court or the Domestic Violence Unit).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With the concurrence of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the Board of Judges of the Superior Court may promulgate rules, not inconsistent with the terms of this section, which are necessary for the fair and effective utilization of magistrate judges in the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11-1732_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term “Board of Judges” means the judges of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Any action of the Board of Judges shall require a majority vote of the sitting judges.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
