<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-1831"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-1831/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_1831">
        <akn:num>22-1831</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Abuse or threatened abuse of law or legal process” means the use or threatened use of law or legal process, whether administrative, civil, or criminal, in any manner or for any purpose for which the law was not designed, to exert pressure on another person to cause that person to take some action or refrain from taking some action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business” means any corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, firm, enterprise, franchise, association, organization, holding company, joint stock, trust, and any legal entity through which business is conducted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Coercion” means any one of, or a combination of, the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial sex act” means any sexual act or sexual contact on account of which or for which anything of value is given to, promised to, or received by any person. The term “commercial sex act” includes a violation of § 22-2701, § 22-2704, §§ 22-2705 to 22-2712, §§ 22-2713 to 22-2720, and § 22-2722.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Debt bondage” means the status or condition of a person who provides labor, services, or commercial sex acts, for a real or alleged debt, where:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Labor” means work that has economic or financial value.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Serious harm” means any harm, whether physical or nonphysical, including psychological, financial, or reputational harm, that is sufficiently serious, under all the surrounding circumstances, to compel a reasonable person of the same background and in the same circumstances to perform or to continue to perform labor, services, or commercial sex acts to avoid incurring that harm.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Services” means legal or illegal duties or work done for another, whether or not compensated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sexual act” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 22-3001(8).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sexual contact” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 22-3001(9).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1831_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Venture” means any group of 2 or more individuals associated in fact, whether or not a legal entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
