<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-1705"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-1705/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_1705">
        <akn:num>22-1705</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Gambling premises; definition; prohibition against maintaining; forfeiture; liens; deposit of moneys in Treasury; penalty; subsequent offenses.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1705_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any house, building, vessel, shed, booth, shelter, vehicle, enclosure, room, lot, or other premises in the District of Columbia, used or to be used in violating the provisions of § 22-1701 or § 22-1704, shall be deemed “gambling premises” for the purpose of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1705_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful for any person in the District of Columbia knowingly, as owner, lessee, agent, employee, operator, occupant, or otherwise, to maintain, or aid, or permit the maintaining of any gambling premises.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1705_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All moneys, vehicles, furnishings, fixtures, equipment, stock (including, without limitation, furnishings and fixtures adaptable to nongambling uses, and equipment and stock for printing, recording, computing, transporting, safekeeping, or communication), or other things of value used or to be used in:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-1705_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whoever violates this section shall be imprisoned not more than 180 days or fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01, or both, unless the violation occurs after the person has been convicted of a violation of this section, in which case the person may be imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
