<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-2603.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-2603.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_2603_01">
        <akn:num>22-2603.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto” means any device carried, worn, or stored that is designed, intended, or readily converted to create, receive or transmit oral or written messages or visual images, access or store data, or connect electronically to the Internet, or any other electronic device that enables communication in any form. The term “cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto” includes portable 2-way pagers, hand-held radios, cellular telephones, Blackberry-type devices, personal digital assistants or PDAs, computers, cameras, and any components of these devices. The term “cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto” also includes any new technology that is developed for communication purposes and includes accessories that enable or facilitate the use of the cellular telephone or other portable communication device.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Grounds” means the area of land occupied by the penal institution or secure juvenile residential facility and its yard and outbuildings, with a clearly identified perimeter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Penal institution” means any penitentiary, prison, jail, or secure facility owned, operated, or under the control of the Department of Corrections, whether located within the District of Columbia or elsewhere.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2603_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Secure juvenile residential facility” means a locked residential facility providing custody, supervision, and care for one or more juveniles that is owned, operated, or under the control of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services, excluding residential treatment facilities and accredited hospitals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
