<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-2724"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-2724/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_2724">
        <akn:num>22-2724</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Impoundment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any vehicle used in furtherance of a violation of a prostitution-related offense shall be subject to impoundment pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a police officer has probable cause to believe that a vehicle is being used in furtherance of a violation of a prostitution-related offense, and an arrest is made for that violation, the police officer, other member of the Metropolitan Police Department, or duly authorized agent thereof shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The notices to be given pursuant to this section shall be provided by hand delivery at the time of the seizure and impoundment of the vehicle to the person in control of the vehicle or to the owner of record of the vehicle. If the owner of record of the vehicle is not available to receive such notice at the time of the seizure, the notice shall be mailed by first class mail, no later than 5 days after the vehicle is received at an impoundment or storage facility, to the last known address of the owner or owners of record of the vehicle, as that information is indicated in the records of the Department of Motor Vehicles or in the records of the appropriate agency of the jurisdiction where the vehicle is registered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An owner, or a person duly authorized by an owner, shall, upon proof of same, be permitted to repossess or secure the release of the immobilized or impounded vehicle at any time (subject to administrative availability) by paying to the District government, as directed by the Department of Public Works, an administrative civil penalty of $150, a booting fee, if applicable, all outstanding fines and penalties for infractions for which liability has been admitted, deemed admitted, or sustained after hearing, and all applicable towing and storage costs for impounded vehicles as provided by § 50-2421.09(a)(6). Payment of such fees shall not be admissible as evidence of guilt in any criminal proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An owner, or person duly authorized by an owner, shall be entitled to refund of the administrative civil penalty, booting fee, and 2 days’ towing and storage costs by showing that the prosecutor dropped the underlying criminal charges (except for instances of nolle prosequi or because the defendant completed a diversion program), that the Superior Court of the District of Columbia dismissed the case after consideration of the merits, or that the case resulted in a finding of not guilty on all prostitution-related charges, or by providing a police report demonstrating that the vehicle was stolen at the time that it was subject to seizure and impoundment. If the vehicle had been stolen at the time of seizure and impoundment, a refund of all towing and storage costs shall be made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An owner, or person duly authorized by an owner, shall be entitled to a due process hearing regarding the seizure of the vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Vehicles seized and impounded under this section shall not be subject to replevin, but shall be deemed to be in the custody of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Vehicles that remain unclaimed for 30 days may be disposed of pursuant to §§ 50-2421.07(c), (d), (e), and (f), 50-2421.08, 50-2421.09, and 50-2421.10; provided, that if the owner wants to claim the vehicle before it is auctioned, the owner must pay the administrative civil penalty imposed by subsection (d) of this section in addition to the amounts required in § 50-2421.09.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or his or her assistants, shall represent the District of Columbia in all proceedings under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-2724_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue rules setting forth the process by which a refund shall be obtained timely pursuant to subsection (e) of this section. Until such rules are published in the District of Columbia Register, this section shall not be enforceable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
