<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3132"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3132/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_3132">
        <akn:num>22-3132</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Any device” means electronic, mechanical, digital or any other equipment, including: a camera, spycam, computer, spyware, microphone, audio or video recorder, global positioning system, electronic monitoring system, listening device, night-vision goggles, binoculars, telescope, or spyglass.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Any means” includes the use of a telephone, mail, delivery service, e-mail, website, or other method of communication or any device.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Communicating” means using oral or written language, photographs, pictures, signs, symbols, gestures, or other acts or objects that are intended to convey a message.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emotional distress” means significant mental suffering or distress that may, but does not necessarily, require medical or other professional treatment or counseling;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial injury” means the monetary costs, debts, or obligations incurred as a result of the stalking by the specific individual, member of the specific individual’s household, a person whose safety is threatened by the stalking, or a person who is financially responsible for the specific individual and includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personal identifying information” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 22-3227.01(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Specific individual” or “individual” means the victim or alleged victim of stalking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3132_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“To engage in a course of conduct” means directly or indirectly, or through one or more third persons, in person or by any means, on 2 or more occasions, to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
