<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3152"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3152/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_3152">
        <akn:num>22-3152</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Act of terrorism” means an act or acts that constitute a specified offense as defined in paragraph (8) of this section and that are intended to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Biological agent” means any microorganism, virus, infectious substance, or biological product that may be engineered as a result of biotechnology, or any naturally occurring or bioengineered component of any such microorganism, virus, infectious substance, or biological product, capable of causing:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hoax weapon of mass destruction” means any device or object that by its design, construction, content, or characteristics, appears to be or to contain, or is represented to be or to contain a weapon of mass destruction, even if it is, in fact, an inoperative facsimile or imitation of a weapon of mass destruction, or contains no weapon of mass destruction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Material support or resources” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nuclear material” means material containing any:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Provision of material support or resources for an act of terrorism” means the act of providing material support or resources to a person or an organization with the purpose or knowledge that the material support or resources will be used, in whole or in part, to plan, prepare, or carry out an act of terrorism, or to flee after committing an act of terrorism.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Solicitation of material support or resources to commit an act of terrorism” means the act of raising, soliciting, or collecting material support or resources with the purpose or knowledge that such material support or resources will be used, in whole or in part, to plan, prepare, or carry out an act of terrorism, or to flee after committing an act of terrorism.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Specified offense” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Toxic or poisonous chemical” means any chemical which, through its chemical action on life processes, can cause death, permanent incapacitation, or permanent harm to humans.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Toxin” means the toxic material of plants, animals, microorganisms, viruses, fungi, or infectious substances, or a recombinant molecule, whatever its origin or method of production, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unit of government” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3152_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Weapon of mass destruction” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
