<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3226.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3226.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_3226_02">
        <akn:num>22-3226.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Application for a certificate of registration of telephone solicitor.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall transact any business as a telephone solicitor without first having obtained a certificate of registration from the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The application for certificate of registration shall be made at least 60 business days prior to offering for sale consumer goods or services by telephone.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide an application form for the annual certificate of registration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The application for a certificate of registration as a telephone solicitor shall include, but not be limited to, the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall serve as the registered agent if no registered agent is appointed or if the individual or organization named ceases to serve as the registered agent and no successor is appointed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall investigate the veracity of an application.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall deny a certificate of registration when the Mayor determines that an application contains false information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide written notification to an applicant when an application has been denied.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall notify the applicant in writing of the information that the Mayor finds to be false.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may conduct telemarketing in the District of Columbia without having first obtained a certificate of registration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall either deny or grant an application within 30 days of the filing of an application.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may establish reasonable fees for filing of applications. The Mayor shall make available printed license application forms as well as electronic forms, which may be downloaded by computer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Certificates of registration issued in accordance with this subchapter shall be valid for one year. Prior to expiration of a certificate of registration, an applicant may obtain a new certificate by the filing of a new application.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3226_02_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any person has obtained a certificate of registration under false pretenses, including providing false information in an application, the certificate of registration shall be revoked and may be reinstated only upon proof of correction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
