<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3153"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-3153/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_3153">
        <akn:num>22-3153</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Acts of terrorism; penalties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits first degree murder that constitutes an act of terrorism shall, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for life without the possibility of release.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits murder of a law enforcement officer or public safety employee that constitutes an act of terrorism shall, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for life without the possibility of release.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits murder in the second degree that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for life.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits manslaughter that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for life.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits kidnapping that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for life.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits any assault with intent to kill that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 30 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits mayhem or maliciously disfiguring another that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits arson that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who commits malicious burning, destruction, or injury of another’s property, if such property is valued at $500,000 or more, that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who attempts or conspires to commit first degree murder, murder of a law enforcement officer or public safety employee, murder in the second degree, manslaughter, or kidnapping that constitutes an act of terrorism may be punished by imprisonment for not more than 30 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who attempts or conspires to commit any assault with intent to kill that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who attempts or conspires to commit mayhem or maliciously disfiguring another, arson, or malicious burning, destruction, or injury of another’s property, if such property is valued at $500,000 or more, that constitutes an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment of not more than 15 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who provides material support or resources for an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-3153_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who solicits material support or resources to commit an act of terrorism may, upon conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
