<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-4517"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-4517/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_4517">
        <akn:num>22-4517</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Dangerous articles; definition; taking and destruction; procedure.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, the term “dangerous article” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A dangerous article unlawfully owned, possessed, or carried is hereby declared to be a nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a police officer, in the course of a lawful arrest or lawful search, or when a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department in the course of a lawful search, discovers a dangerous article which the officer reasonably believes is a nuisance under subsection (b) of this section the officer shall take it into his or her possession and surrender it to the Property Clerk of the Metropolitan Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person claiming a dangerous article shall be entitled to its possession only if: (1) such person shows, on satisfactory evidence, that such person is the owner of the dangerous article or is the accredited representative of the owner, and that the ownership is lawful; (2) such person shows on satisfactory evidence that at the time the dangerous article was taken into possession by a police officer or a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department, it was not unlawfully owned and was not unlawfully possessed or carried by the claimant or with his or her knowledge or consent; and (3) the receipt of possession by the claimant does not cause the article to be a nuisance. A representative is accredited if such person has a power of attorney from the owner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person claiming a dangerous article is entitled to its possession as determined under subsections (d) and (e) of this section, possession of such dangerous article shall be given to such person. If no person so claiming is entitled to its possession as determined under subsections (d) and (e) of this section, or if there be no claimant, such dangerous article shall be destroyed. In lieu of such destruction, any such serviceable dangerous article may, upon order of the Mayor of the District of Columbia, be transferred to and used by any federal or District Government law-enforcing agency, and the agency receiving same shall establish property responsibility and records of these dangerous articles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4517_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Property Clerk shall not be liable in damages for any action performed in good faith under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
