<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-4502"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-4502/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_4502">
        <akn:num>22-4502</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Additional penalty for committing crime when armed.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who commits a crime of violence, or a dangerous crime in the District of Columbia when armed with or having readily available any pistol or other firearm (or imitation thereof) or other dangerous or deadly weapon (including a sawed-off shotgun, shotgun, machine gun, rifle, dirk, bowie knife, butcher knife, switchblade knife, razor, blackjack, billy, or metallic or other false knuckles):</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person sentenced pursuant to paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) above for a conviction of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime while armed with any pistol or firearm, shall serve a mandatory-minimum term of 5 years, if sentenced pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section, or 10 years, if sentenced pursuant to paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this section, and such person shall not be released, granted probation, or granted suspension of sentence, prior to serving such mandatory-minimum sentence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in ยง 22-3571.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as reducing any sentence otherwise imposed or authorized to be imposed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4502_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No conviction with respect to which a person has been pardoned on the ground of innocence shall be taken into account in applying this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
