<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-4504"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/22-4504/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_22_4504">
        <akn:num>22-4504</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Carrying concealed weapons; possession of weapons during commission of crime of violence; penalty.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4504_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall carry within the District of Columbia either openly or concealed on or about their person, a pistol, without a license issued pursuant to District of Columbia law, or any deadly or dangerous weapon. Whoever violates this section shall be punished as provided in ยง 22-4515, except that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4504_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise permitted by law, no person shall carry within the District of Columbia a rifle or shotgun. A person who violates this subsection shall be subject to the criminal penalties set forth in subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4504_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall within the District of Columbia possess a pistol, machine gun, shotgun, rifle, or any other firearm or imitation firearm while committing a crime of violence or dangerous crime as defined in ยง 22-4501. Upon conviction of a violation of this subsection, the person may be sentenced to imprisonment for a term not to exceed 15 years and shall be sentenced to imprisonment for a mandatory-minimum term of not less than 5 years and shall not be released on parole, or granted probation or suspension of sentence, prior to serving the mandatory-minimum sentence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22-4504_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in ยง 22-3571.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
