<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1540"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1540/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1540">
        <akn:num>32-1540</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Special fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1540_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established in the Treasury of the District of Columbia a special fund for the purpose of making payments in accordance with the provisions of §§ 32-1507(c), 32-1507(e), 32-1508(6), and 32-1519(b). Such fund shall be administered by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1540_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall be the custodian of the special fund, and all moneys and securities in such fund shall be held in trust by the Mayor and shall not be used for purposes other than those provided by this chapter. The Mayor may invest any portion of the fund which, in the opinion of the Mayor, is not needed for current requirements in bonds or notes of the United States or any federal land bank; provided, that such investments are made pursuant to the Financial Institutions Deposit and Investment Act of 1997.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1540_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Neither the District of Columbia nor the Mayor shall be liable in respect of payments authorized under §§ 32-1507(c), 32-1507(e), 32-1508(6) and 32-1519(b) in any amount greater than the money or property deposited in or belonging to such fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1540_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payments into such fund shall be made as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1540_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The special fund shall be audited annually by the Department of Employment Services. The Director of the Department of Employment Services shall file an audited financial report with the Council by March 1st detailing the financial status of the fund as of the end of the preceding fiscal year, including the fund’s operation, cash flow, and changes in capital and surplus, using standard accounting principles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1540_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All civil penalties provided for in this chapter shall be collected by civil suit brought by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
