<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1503"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1503/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1503">
        <akn:num>32-1503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Coverage.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (a-1) through (a-3) of this section, this chapter shall apply to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No employee shall receive compensation under this chapter and at any time receive compensation under the workers’ compensation law of any other state for the same injury or death.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not apply if the employee injured or killed was a casual employee except that for the purposes of this chapter, casual, occasional, or incidental employment outside of the District of Columbia by a District of Columbia employer of an employee regularly employed by the employer within the District of Columbia shall be construed to be employment within the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee and his employer who are not residents of the District of Columbia and whose contract of hire is entered into in another state shall be exempted from the provisions of this chapter while such employee is temporarily or intermittently within the District of Columbia doing work for such nonresident employer, if such employer has furnished workers’ compensation insurance coverage under the workers’ compensation or similar laws of such other state, so as to cover such employee’s employment while in the District of Columbia. The benefits under this chapter or similar laws of such other state shall be the exclusive remedy against such employer for any injury, whether resulting in death or not, received by such employee while working for such employer in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every employer subject to this chapter shall be liable for compensation for injury or death without regard to fault as a cause of the injury or death.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of an employer who is a subcontractor, the contractor shall be liable for and shall secure the payment of such compensation to employees of the subcontractor unless the subcontractor has secured such payment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Liability for compensation shall not apply where injury to the employee was occasioned solely by his intoxication or by his willful intention to injure or kill himself or another.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1503_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The requirements of this chapter shall apply with regard to the nonprisoners employed in a prison industries program operating on the grounds of a District correctional facility, whether within the District or elsewhere, and maintained in accordance with the Prison Industries Act of 1996. The requirements of this chapter also shall apply with regard to prisoners employed in a prison industry approved under the Bureau of Justice Assistance Private Sector Prison Industry Enhancement Certification Program as defined in § 24-231.01(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
