<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1101"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1101/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1101">
        <akn:num>32-1101</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Authorized employee representative” means a person or persons selected and authorized by the employee or employees of a workplace to assist or represent the employee or employees in exercising their rights under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Board” means the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Board established by § 32-1105.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commission” means the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Commission established by § 32-1106.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee” means an individual working for an employer for a salary, wage, or other compensation or pursuant to any other contractual obligation, but does not include domestic servants.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employer” means any person, firm, corporation, partnership, stock association, agent, manager, representative, foreman, or any other person having control or custody of any place of employment or of any employee. The term “employer” shall include a District government or quasi-governmental agency and an entity established pursuant to interstate compact. The term “employer” shall not include the United States government or its agencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal Act” means the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, approved December 29, 1970 (84 Stat. 1590; 29 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Inspection” means an examination of a workplace on a routine basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investigation” means an examination of a specific hazard, accident, injury, or death.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Plan” means the occupational safety and health plan for the District provided for in § 32-1104.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Secretary” means the Secretary of the United States Department of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1101_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Standard” means an occupational safety and health standard that requires conditions or the adoption or use of 1 or more practices, means, methods, operations, or processes that are reasonably necessary or appropriate to provide safe or healthful employment and places of employment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
