<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1601"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1601/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1601">
        <akn:num>32-1601</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Council findings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1601_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Many District workers need an integrated workforce investment system to help them assume responsibility for building a better future for themselves and their families.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1601_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A workforce investment system should be consumer-driven, accountable and responsive to the needs of employers and job seekers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1601_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The goals of an integrated workforce development systems are to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1601_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To implement the federal Workforce Investment Act of 1998, approved August 7, 1998 (112 Stat. 936; 29 U.S.C. § 2822 [repealed]), the District of Columbia must apply the necessary resources to carry out its assigned responsibilities and must delegate accountability and authority, as allowed under the federal law, to the governing entity of the workforce investment system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1601_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>These objectives are to be accomplished under the direction of the District’s Workforce Investment Council. This Council will enlist the views of a diverse group of business, labor, community, education and government leaders to develop a strategic plan for workforce development in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1601_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The strategic plan should provide for the development of a comprehensive, consumer-driven employment and career development system that meets the needs  of all members of the workforce, including those entering the workforce for  the first time, those in transition to employment and those currently employed who seek to enhance their skills for continued career advancement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
