<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1106"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1106/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1106">
        <akn:num>32-1106</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Occupational Safety and Health Commission.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1106_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established an Occupational Safety and Health Commission. The Chairperson of the Board or a designee of the Chairperson of the Board shall serve as Chairperson of the Commission. The Chairperson of the Board, 1 labor and 1 management Board member shall serve on the Commission. When the issue is related to employee health, the Commissioner of Public Health or his or her designee shall serve on the Commission as a non-voting member. Members of the Board, other than the Chairperson, shall serve on a rotation basis pursuant to rules established by the Board under ยง 32-1105(b)(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1106_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of carrying out the functions of the Commission, the Commission may operate in panels of 3 members each. Two members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum and any official decision or action shall be made only on the affirmative vote of at least 2 members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1106_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1106_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall conduct proceedings in accordance with rules established by the Board pursuant to ยง 32-1105(b)(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1106_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Board and Commission shall be compensated at a rate to be established by the Mayor in accordance with ยง 1-611.08. No compensation shall be paid to members who are otherwise employed by the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
