<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1308.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1308.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1308_01">
        <akn:num>32-1308.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administrative actions on employee complaints.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When an employee requests administrative enforcement of this chapter, the Minimum Wage Revision Act, the Living Wage Act, and the Sick and Safe Leave Act, the Mayor shall investigate and make an initial determination regarding alleged violations. A signed complaint for non-payment of earned wages shall be filed with the Mayor, no later than 3 years after the last date upon which the violation of this chapter, the Minimum Wage Revision Act, the Sick and Safe Leave Act, or the Living Wage Act is alleged to have occurred or the date on which the employer provided the complainant with actual or constructive notice of the employee’s rights, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the alleged non-payment of earned wages violation is ongoing at the time of the filing of the complaint, the complaint may also seek recovery of amounts that accrue after the filing of the complaint. With regard to amounts that were due at the time the complaint was filed, an aggrieved employee may recover only those amounts that became lawfully due and payable within the 3-year period before the date the complaint was filed. This period is tolled during any period that the employer fails to provide the complainant with actual or constructive notice of the employee’s rights or on other equitable grounds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a respondent fails to timely comply with an administrative order or conciliation agreement that has not been stayed, the Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The administrative remedies established in this chapter shall be in addition to any other criminal, civil, or other remedies established by law that may be pursued to address violations of this chapter and shall not prejudice or adversely affect any other action, civil or criminal, that may be brought to abate a violation or to seek compensation for damages suffered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person may be represented by counsel in any proceeding under this chapter. Any party, including corporate entities, as an alternative to counsel, may be assisted by a non-lawyer authorized by that party in accordance with 1 DCMR § 2835, except where such representation is prohibited by law or disallowed by the administrative law judge for good cause.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1308_01_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
