<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1341"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1341/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1341">
        <akn:num>32-1341</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Applicant” means any person considered or who requests to be considered for employment by an employer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Arrest” means being apprehended, detained, taken into custody, held for investigation, or restrained by a law enforcement agency due to an accusation or suspicion that the person committed a crime.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Conditional offer” means an offer that is conditional solely on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Conviction” means any sentence arising from a verdict or plea of guilty or nolo contendere, including a sentence of incarceration, a suspended sentence, a sentence of probation, or a sentence of unconditional discharge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Criminal accusation” means an existing accusation that an individual has committed a crime, lodged by a law enforcement agency through an indictment, information, complaint, or other formal charge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employer” means any person, company, corporation, firm, labor organization, or association, including the District government, but not including the courts, that employs more than 10 employees in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employment” means any occupation, vocation, job, or work for pay, including temporary or seasonal work, contracted work, contingent work, and work through the services of a temporary or other employment agency or any form of vocational or educational training with or without pay, where the physical location of the employment is in whole or substantial part within the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Inquiry” means any direct or indirect conduct intended to gather criminal history information from or about an applicant using any method, including application forms, interviews, and criminal history checks.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1341_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interview” means any direct contact by the employer with the applicant, whether in person or by telephone, to discuss the employment being sought or the applicant’s qualifications.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
