<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1002"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1002/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1002">
        <akn:num>32-1002</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “employ” includes to suffer or permit to work.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “employee” includes any individual employed by an employer, except that this term shall not include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “employer” includes any individual, partnership, general contractor, subcontractor, association, corporation, business trust, or any person or group of persons acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee, but shall not include the United States or the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “gratuities” means voluntary monetary contributions received by an employee from a guest, patron, or customer for services rendered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the Mayor’s designated agent or representative, including the Department of Employment Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “occupation” means any occupation, service, trade, business, industry, or branch or group of occupations or industries, or employment or class of employment, in which employees are gainfully employed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “office building” means any commercial property where the primary functions are the transaction of administrative, business, civic, or professional services, including properties where handling goods, wares, or merchandise, in limited quantities, is accessory to the primary occupancy or use. The term “office building” does not include libraries, museums, or universities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “regular rate” means all remuneration for employment paid to, or on behalf of, the employee, but shall not be considered to include the items set forth in the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, 29 U.S.C. § 207(e)(1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7). Extra compensation paid as described in § 207(e)(5), (6), and (7) shall be creditable toward overtime compensation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “security officer” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2100 of Title 17 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “wage” means compensation due to an employee by reason of the employee’s employment, payable in legal tender of the United States or checks on banks convertible into cash on demand at full face value, including allowances as may be permitted by any regulation issued under §§ 32-1003 and 32-1006.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Washington metropolitan region” means the area consisting of the District of Columbia, Montgomery, and Prince George’s Counties in Maryland, Arlington and Fairfax Counties and the Cities of Alexandria, Fairfax and Falls Church in Virginia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1002_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “working time” means all the time the employee:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
