<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1009"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1009/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1009">
        <akn:num>32-1009</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Posting of act and regulations on premises; distribution of copies to employers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1009_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every employer who is subject to any provision of this subchapter or any regulation issued under this subchapter shall keep a copy or summary of this subchapter and any applicable regulation issued under this subchapter, in a form prescribed or approved by the Mayor, posted in a conspicuous and accessible place in or about the premises at which any employee covered by the regulation is employed. If an employer fails to comply with this requirement, the period prescribed in ยง 32-1308(c) shall not begin until the employer posts or provides the required notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1009_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Employers shall be furnished copies or summaries of this subchapter by the Mayor without charge, in accordance with subchapter II of Chapter 19 of Title 2 [ยง 2-1931 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1009_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Employers shall be furnished with copies or summaries of this subchapter within 60 days of February 26, 2015. An employer shall not be liable for failure to post notice if the Mayor has failed to provide to the employer the notice required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
