<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1508"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1508/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1508">
        <akn:num>32-1508</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Compensation for disability.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In case of total disability adjudged to be permanent, 66 2/3% of the employee’s average weekly wages shall be paid to the employee during the continuance thereof. Loss of both hands, or both arms, or both feet, or both legs, or both eyes, or of any 2 thereof shall, in the absence of conclusive proof to the contrary, constitute permanent total disability. In all other cases permanent total disability shall be determined only if, as a result of the injury, the employee is unable to earn any wages in the same or other employment;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In case of disability total in character but temporary in quality, 66 2/3% of the employee’s average weekly wages shall be paid to the employee during the continuance thereof;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In case of disability partial in character but permanent in quality, the compensation shall be 66 2/3% of the employee’s average weekly wages which shall be in addition to compensation for temporary total disability or temporary partial disability paid in accordance with paragraph (2) or (4) of this subsection respectively, and shall be paid to the employee, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any compensation to which any claimant would be entitled under paragraph (3) of this section, excepting paragraph (3)(V) of this section, shall, provided the death arises from causes other than the injury, be payable in full to and for the benefit of the persons following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In case of temporary partial disability, the compensation shall be 66 2/3% of the injured employee’s wage loss to be paid during the continuance of such disability, but shall not be paid for a period exceeding 5 years. Wage loss shall be the difference between the employee’s average weekly wage before the employee had the disability and the employee’s actual wages after the employee had the disability. If the employee voluntarily limits his income or fails to accept employment commensurate with his abilities, then his wages after the employee had the disability shall be deemed to be the amount he would earn if he did not voluntarily limit his income or did accept employment commensurate with his abilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In each case, payment of benefits shall be 66 2/3 % of the employee’s average weekly wage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may approve lump-sum settlements agreed to in writing by the interested parties, discharging the liability of the employer for compensation, notwithstanding §§ 32-1516 and 32-1517, in any case where the Mayor determines that it is in the best interest of an injured employee entitled to compensation or individuals entitled to benefits pursuant to § 32-1509. The Mayor shall approve the settlement, where both parties are represented by legal counsel who are eligible to receive attorney fees pursuant to § 32-1530. These settlements shall be the complete and final dispositions of a case and shall be a final binding compensation order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1508_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An award for disability may be made after the death of an injured employee from causes other than work-related injury. If the award made is for permanent partial disability, pursuant to paragraph (3)(A) through (U) of this section, the award shall be payable in full pursuant to paragraph (4) of this section. If the award made is for any other category of disability, the amount of the award shall be computed from the date of the injury to the date of death, and shall be payable in full in the same manner as an award payable pursuant to paragraph (4) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
