<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-131.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-131.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_131_02">
        <akn:num>32-131.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Provision of paid leave.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Paid leave accrued under this section may be used by an employee for any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee shall make a reasonable effort to schedule paid leave under subsection (b) of this section in a manner that does not unduly disrupt the operations of the employer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an employee does not suffer a loss of income when absent from work, for the number of days up to the days of paid leave provided for in subsection (a)(1), (2), and (3) of this section, an employer shall not be required to provide paid leave for such employee in accordance with this chapter. Notwithstanding the foregoing sentence, the provisions of § 32-131.08 shall apply to employees who do not suffer a loss of income when absent from work.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If employees of beauty, hair, and nail salons are paid by commission (whether commission only or base wage plus commission), the sick leave rate of pay shall be calculated as follows: divide the employee’s total earnings in base wages and commissions for the prior calendar year by the total hours worked as a commissioned employee during the prior calendar year. If employees do not have a prior calendar year’s work history, divide the employee’s total earnings in base wages and commissions since the employee’s date of hire by the total hours worked as a commissioned employee since that date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-131_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the requirements in subsections (a)(1)-(4) of this section, for an employee of a restaurant or bar who regularly receive [sic] tips, commissions, or other gratuities to supplement a base wage that is below the minimum wage as established in § 32-1003(a), the employer shall provide the employee not less than one hour of paid leave for every 43 hours worked, not to exceed 5 days per calendar year. The paid leave shall be compensated in accordance with the District minimum wage, as established in § 32-1003(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
