<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1610"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-1610/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_1610">
        <akn:num>32-1610</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Use of funds for employment and training activities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District’s state workforce investment board shall develop policies and procedures pertaining to the use of funds pursuant to section 134 [29 U.S.C. § 2864] of the Federal Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The WIC shall establish policies and procedures for the development of a one- stop delivery system consistent with the requirements of sections 121 and 134(c) of the Federal Act, including policies and procedures for the certification of American Job Centers and the selection of one-stop operators consistent with the requirements of section 121(d) of the Federal Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The WIC shall develop policies and procedures to ensure that American Job Centers provide:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Intensive services offered by the one-stop delivery system may include addiction recovery. Consistent with this subchapter, intensive services may also include short-term prevocational services that raise job seekers’ basic reading, writing and computational skills to enable them to compete for jobs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The policies and procedures required by subsection (b-2) of this section shall ensure that eligible individuals seeking services through American Job Centers receive an initial assessment of aptitudes and abilities that is non-gender biased and that assesses a woman’s interest in high-wage employment, including for positions that are nontraditional employment for women.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consistent with this subchapter, job seekers who are employed, but do not earn a self-sufficient wage, shall be eligible for intensive services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-1610_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any funds expended pursuant to this section shall be appropriated by the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
