<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-242"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-242/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_242">
        <akn:num>32-242</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Programs for employment and training of young District domiciliaries.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall establish and implement programs, subject to the annual appropriation of funds, for the employment and training of young persons who are domiciliaries of the District of Columbia, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Employment under the programs established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may be provided directly with the government of the District of Columbia or with the private sector on a fully funded, partially or match-funded basis through grants to or by contract with nonprofit or profit-making organizations, associations, institutions or businesses. The Mayor shall not use more than 10% of funds for the programs for administrative and vendor costs. The Mayor may enter into performance-based contracts to implement programs described in subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The programs established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may include, but shall not be limited to, the following supportive services and activities: Transportation; orientation; counseling and training; supplies and equipment; and program promotion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, to give priority to participants who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act means to engage in a good-faith effort to fill at least 30% of a program’s available positions with persons who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employer required by law to pay a minimum wage higher than that specified in this section shall pay such higher wage to persons employed pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall issue regulations to implement this section. The rules and regulations issued by the Mayor for the purpose of implementing the provisions of this section shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 45 calendar-day review period, excluding days of Council recess. No such rules or regulations shall take effect until the end of the 45 calendar-day period beginning on the day such rules or regulations are transmitted by the Mayor to the Chairman of the Council, and then only if during such period the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-242_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
