<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-303"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-303/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_303">
        <akn:num>32-303</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Committee for Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Individuals with Severe Disabilities — Established.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-303_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby created a Committee for Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Individuals with Severe Disabilities (hereinafter referred to as the “Committee”) to be appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia (hereinafter referred to as the “Mayor”). The Committee shall be composed of 2 private citizens conversant with the problems incident to the employment of the blind and other individuals with severe disabilities, 2 citizens representing individuals who are consumers with severe disabilities employed in qualified nonprofit agencies for the blind and other individuals with severe disabilities, 2 citizens representing the general public and a representative of each of the following agencies: Directors of the Department of General Services, the Office of Budget and Management Systems and the Department of Human Services. The members of the Committee shall be appointed by the Mayor for a term of 4 years and shall not serve beyond the expiration of their term: Except, that of the 6 private citizen members first appointed, 2 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, 2 shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, and 2 shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, as designated by the Mayor at the time of appointment. The members of the Committee shall designate 1 of their number to be chairperson.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-303_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any private citizen member, appointed under subsection (a) of this section to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his or her predecessor was appointed, shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-303_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation other than reimbursement for expenses actually incurred in connection with the work of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-303_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to such rules as may be adopted by the Committee, the Mayor may appoint and fix the pay of any personnel which the Committee determines is necessary to assist it in carrying out its duties and powers under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-303_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Committee may secure directly from any agency of the District of Columbia government (hereinafter referred to as “District government”) information which the Committee deems necessary to carry out this chapter. Upon request of the chairperson of the Committee, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-303_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Committee shall, not later than 90 days following the close of each fiscal year, transmit to the Mayor and to the Council of the District of Columbia (hereinafter referred to as the “Council”) a report which shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
