<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-405"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-405/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_405">
        <akn:num>32-405</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Requirements for operation of employment counseling services.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employment counseling service shall maintain a file of all of its advertisements identified by date and publication. All advertisements and other promotional material shall carry the name under which the employment counseling service is licensed to do business, and shall carry a notice stating that the employment counseling service is not an employment agency, does not arrange job interviews, and does not provide job placement services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any employment counseling service which uses any statistics regarding its success rate or other similar statistics in its advertising, promotional materials, or oral or written statements to job-seekers shall maintain records from which the Mayor can determine the accuracy of these statistics.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employment counseling service shall keep detailed records of the following information on forms approved by the Mayor:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The records required by subsections (a) through (c) of this section shall be maintained for 4 years from the date the record was made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employment counseling service shall file with the Mayor a schedule of fees to be charged to job-seekers. These fees may be changed by filing an amended schedule showing the changes at least 30 days before the changes are to take effect. It shall be unlawful to charge, demand, or receive a fee greater than is specified in the most recent schedule filed with the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No employment counseling service shall charge any job-seeker a registration fee or collect from any job-seeker any payment for any service in advance of performing the service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employment counseling service shall give to every job-seeker a numbered receipt for each payment received by the employment counseling service from the job-seeker. Each receipt shall have printed or written on it the name of the job-seeker, the date and amount of the payment, the name and address of the employment agency, the purpose for which the payment was made, and the legible signature of the person receiving payment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-405_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No employment counseling service doing business in the District or any person employed by or acting as an agent of that employment counseling service shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
