<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-602"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-602/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_602">
        <akn:num>32-602</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Temporary Commission on Pay Equity and Training established.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a Temporary Commission on Pay Equity and Training (“Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall consist of 15 members appointed as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To the extent practicable, appointments under this section shall be made with a view towards maintaining a fair balance reflecting the gender and racial compositions of the District workforce. All Commission members shall be residents of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Commission shall be appointed within 30 days of February 24, 1987. The chairperson of the Commission shall convene an organizational meeting no later than 15 days after the appointments have been made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall cease to exist 60 days after its report has been submitted to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Vacancies occurring within the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointees, as provided for in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall determine its organization and may elect its own officers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A written transcript or a transcription shall be kept for all meetings at which a vote is taken.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall meet at the call of the chair or a majority of its members, but at least once every 2 months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-602_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Commission shall not be considered to be employees of the District by reason of appointment to the Commission and shall not receive pay by reason of service as members. In the event that a member is a District employee, that person shall not lose pay as a result of time served on the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
