<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-752"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/32-752/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_32_752">
        <akn:num>32-752</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment and administration of the Job Opportunity Bank.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-752_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a Job Opportunity Bank for the purpose of providing grants and other forms of financial assistance to increase job opportunities for low-income District residents to upgrade their job skills and provide customized skills training for new and incumbent workers employed by District employers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-752_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Job Opportunity Bank shall be subject to the general policy guidance and direction of the Workforce Investment Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-752_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Workforce Investment Council shall serve in an advisory capacity to the Mayor and the Director in matters pertaining to the operation and administration of the Job Opportunity Bank.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-752_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Job Opportunity Bank shall be funded by annual appropriations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-752_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds shall be administered by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32-752_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development may fund applications for grants or other assistance as may be recommended by the Director under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
