<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1004.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1004.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1004_05">
        <akn:num>29-1004.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Approval of amendment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to ยง 29-1004.04 and subsections (c) and (d) of this section, an amendment to the articles of organization shall be approved by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to ยง 29-1004.04 and subsections (c), (d), (e) and (f) of this section, an amendment to the bylaws shall be approved by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The organic rules may require that the percentage of votes under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) of this section be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consent in a record by a member shall be delivered to a limited cooperative association before delivery of an amendment to the articles of organization or restated articles of organization for filing pursuant to ยง 29-1004.07 if, as a result of the amendment, the member will have:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The vote required to amend bylaws shall satisfy the requirements of subsection (a) of this section if the proposed amendment modifies:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except for the matters described in subsection (e) of this section, the articles of organization may delegate amendment of all or a part of the bylaws to the board of directors without requiring member approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1004_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the articles of organization delegate amendment of bylaws to the board of directors, the board shall provide a description of any amendment of the bylaws made by the board to the members in a record not later than 30 days after the amendment, but the description may be provided at the next annual members meeting if the meeting is held within the 30-day period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
