<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1005.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1005.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1005_05">
        <akn:num>29-1005.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Right of member and former member to information.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On reasonable notice a member may inspect and copy, at the principal office or a reasonable location specified by the limited cooperative association, required information listed in ยง 29-1001.10(a)(1) through (8) during regular business hours. A member need not have any particular purpose for seeking the information. The association shall not be required to provide the same information listed in ยง 29-1001.10(a)(2) through (8) to the same member more than once during a 6-month period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On reasonable notice, a member may inspect and copy, at the principal office or a reasonable location specified by the limited cooperative association, required information listed in ยง 29-1001.10(a)(9), (10), (12), (13), (16), and (18) during regular business hours, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 10 business days after receipt of a demand pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, a limited cooperative association shall provide, in a record, the following information to the member that made the demand:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 10 business days after a limited cooperative association receives a demand made in a record, a dissociated member may have access to information to which the person was entitled while a member if the information pertains to the period during which the person was a member, the person seeks the information in good faith, and the person satisfies the requirements imposed on a member by subsection (b)(2) of this section. The association shall respond to a demand made pursuant to this subsection in the manner provided in subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 10 business days after receipt by a limited cooperative association of a demand made by a member in a record, but not more often than once in a 6-month period, the association shall deliver to the member a record stating the information with respect to the member required by ยง 29-1001.10(a)(17).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any restriction or condition stated in its organic rules, a limited cooperative association, as a matter within the ordinary course of its activities and affairs, may impose reasonable restrictions and conditions on access to and use of information to be furnished under this section, including designating information as confidential and imposing nondisclosure and safeguarding obligations on the recipient. In a dispute concerning the reasonableness of a restriction under this subsection, the association shall have the burden of proving reasonableness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A limited cooperative association may charge a person that makes a demand under this section reasonable costs of copying, limited to the costs of labor and material.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member or dissociated member may exercise rights under this section through an agent or, in the case of an individual under legal disability, a legal representative. Any restriction or condition imposed by the organic rules or subsection (f) of this section applies both to the agent or legal representative and the member or dissociated member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The rights stated in this section shall not extend to a person as transferee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1005_05_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The organic rules may require a limited cooperative association to provide more information than required by this section and may establish conditions and procedures for providing the information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
