<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1303.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1303.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1303_02">
        <akn:num>29-1303.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Benefit director.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1303_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The board of directors of a benefit corporation shall include one director, who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1303_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The benefit director shall be elected, and may be removed, in the manner provided by subchapter VI of Chapter 3 of this title, and shall be an individual who is independent. The benefit director may serve as the benefit officer at the same time as serving as the benefit director. The articles of incorporation or bylaws of a benefit corporation may prescribe additional qualifications of the benefit director not inconsistent with this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1303_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The benefit director shall prepare, and the benefit corporation shall include in the annual benefit report to shareholders required by ยง 29-1304.01, the opinion of the benefit director on each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1303_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The acts of an individual in the capacity of a benefit director shall constitute for all purposes acts of that individual in the capacity of a director of the benefit corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1303_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1303_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Regardless of whether the articles of incorporation of a benefit corporation include a provision eliminating or limiting the personal liability of directors authorized by ยง 29-302.02(b)(4), a benefit director shall not be personally liable for any action taken, or any failure to take any action, as a director, except liability for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
