<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-101.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-101.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_101_02">
        <akn:num>29-101.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Biennial report” means the report required by § 29-102.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business corporation” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business trust” means a trust formed under the statutory law of another state which is not a foreign statutory trust and does not have a predominately donative purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial registered agent” means a person listed under § 29-104.05.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Common-law business trust” means a common-law trust that does not have a predominately donative purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Debtor in bankruptcy” means a person that is the subject of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Distributional interest” means the right under an unincorporated entity’s organic law and organic rules to receive distributions from the entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic”[,] with respect to an entity, means governed as to its internal affairs by the law of the District or created under the provisions of a special act of congress unless otherwise noted under its Congressional Charter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Effective date”, when referring to a record filed by the Mayor, means the time and date determined in accordance with § 29-102.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Entity filing” means a record delivered for filing to the Mayor pursuant to this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Filed record” means a record filed by the Mayor pursuant to this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Filing entity” means an entity that is formed by filing a public organic record. The term does not include a limited liability partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign”, with respect to an entity, means an entity governed as to its internal affairs by the law of a jurisdiction other than the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“General cooperative association” means a domestic general cooperative association formed under or subject to Chapter 9 of this title or a foreign general cooperative association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“General partnership” means a domestic general partnership formed under or subject to Chapter 6 of this title or a foreign general partnership. The term “general partnership” includes a limited liability partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Governance interest” means a right under the organic law or organic rules of an unincorporated entity, other than as a governor, agent, assignee, or proxy, to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Governor” means a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interest” means a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interest holder” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Jurisdiction”, used to refer to a political entity, means the United States, a state, a foreign country, or a political subdivision of a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Jurisdiction of formation” means the jurisdiction whose law includes the organic law of an entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited cooperative association” means a domestic limited cooperative association formed under or subject to Chapter 10 of this title or a foreign limited cooperative association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited liability company” means a domestic limited liability company formed under or subject to Chapter 8 of this title or a foreign limited liability company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited liability limited partnership” means a domestic limited liability limited partnership formed under or subject to Chapter 7 of this title or a foreign limited liability limited partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited liability partnership” means a domestic limited liability partnership that has a statement of qualification in effect under Chapter 6 of this title or a foreign limited liability partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited partnership” means a domestic limited partnership formed under or subject to Chapter 7 of this title or a foreign limited partnership. The term includes a limited liability limited partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Noncommercial registered agent” means a person that is not a commercial registered agent and is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonfiling entity” means an entity that is formed other than by filing a public organic record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonprofit corporation” means a domestic nonprofit corporation incorporated under or subject to Chapter 4 of this title or a foreign nonprofit corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonregistered foreign entity” means a foreign entity that is not registered to do business in the District pursuant to a statement of registration filed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Organic law” means the law of an entity’s jurisdiction of formation which governs the internal affairs of the entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Organic rules” means the public organic record and private organic rules of an entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Principal office” means the principal executive office of an entity, whether or not the office is located in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Private organic rules” means the rules, whether or not in a record, that govern the internal affairs of an entity, are binding on all of its interest holders, and are not part of its public organic record, if any. The term “private organic rules” shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Proceeding” includes a civil action, arbitration, mediation, administrative proceeding, criminal prosecution, and investigatory action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Professional limited liability company” means a limited liability company organized under Chapter 8 of this title solely for the purpose of rendering professional services through its members, managers, employees, or agents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property” means all property, whether real, personal, or mixed, or tangible or intangible, or any right or interest therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public organic record” means a record the filing of which by the Mayor is required to form an entity and any amendment to or restatement of that record. The term “public organic record” shall include the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Receipt” or “receive”, as used in this chapter, means actual receipt.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Record”, used as a noun, means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registered agent” means an agent of an entity which is authorized to receive service of any process, notice, or demand required or permitted by law to be served on the entity. The term “registered agent” includes a commercial registered agent and a noncommercial registered agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_44">
      <akn:num>(44)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registered foreign entity” means a foreign entity that is registered to do business in the District pursuant to a statement of registration filed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_45">
      <akn:num>(45)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sign” means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_46">
      <akn:num>(46)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_47">
      <akn:num>(47)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Statutory trust” means a domestic statutory trust formed under or subject to Chapter 12 of this title or a trust formed under a statute of a jurisdiction other than the District which would be a statutory trust if formed under the law of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_48">
      <akn:num>(48)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Superior Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_49">
      <akn:num>(49)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transfer” includes an assignment, conveyance, sale, lease, or encumbrance, including a mortgage or security interest, a gift, or a transfer by operation of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_50">
      <akn:num>(50)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Type of entity” means a generic form of entity:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_51">
      <akn:num>(51)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unincorporated nonprofit association” means a domestic unincorporated nonprofit association formed under or subject to Chapter 11 of this title or a nonprofit association formed under the law of a jurisdiction other than the District which would be an unincorporated nonprofit association if formed under the law of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-101_02_52">
      <akn:num>(52)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Written” means inscribed on a tangible medium. “Writing” has a corresponding meaning.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
