<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1206.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1206.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1206_03">
        <akn:num>29-1206.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Contribution by beneficial owner.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1206_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A contribution of a beneficial owner to a statutory trust may consist of property transferred, services performed, or another benefit provided to the statutory trust, or an agreement to transfer property, perform services, or provide another benefit. A person may become a beneficial owner of a statutory trust and may receive a beneficial interest in a statutory trust without making a contribution or being obligated to make a contribution to the trust.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1206_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person’s obligation to contribute money or other property or other benefit to, or to perform services for, a statutory trust is not excused by the person’s death, disability, or other inability to perform the person’s obligations personally. If a person does not fulfill an obligation to make a contribution, other than a monetary contribution, the person is obligated at the option of the trustee to contribute money equal to the value of the part of the contribution which has not been made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1206_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The governing instrument may provide that a beneficial owner that fails to make a required contribution, or comply with the terms and conditions of the governing instrument, shall be subject to specified penalties for or consequences of the failure, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
