<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1001.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1001.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1001_13">
        <akn:num>29-1001.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Approval of entity transaction by limited cooperative association.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a limited cooperative association to approve an entity transaction under subchapter XV of this chapter or Chapter 2 of this title, a plan must be approved by a majority of the board of directors, or a greater percentage if required by the organic rules, and the board of directors must call a members meeting to consider the plan, hold the meeting not later than 90 days after approval of the plan by the board, and mail or otherwise transmit or deliver in a record to each member:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a plan must be approved by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The organic rules may require that the percentage of votes under subsection (b)(1) of this section is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The vote required to approve a plan may not be less than the vote required for the members of the limited cooperative association to amend the articles of organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_13_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consent in a record to a plan by a member must be delivered to the limited cooperative association before delivery to the Mayor for filing of articles of merger, interest exchange, conversion, or domestication, if, as a result of the merger, interest exchange, conversion, or domestication, the member will have interest holder liability for debts, obligations, or other liabilities that arise after the transaction becomes effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_13_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The voting requirements for districts, classes, or voting groups under ยง 29-1004.04 apply to the approval of a transaction under this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
