<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1001.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1001.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1001_02">
        <akn:num>29-1001.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Board of directors” means the board of directors of a limited cooperative association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bylaws” means the bylaws of a limited cooperative association. The term “bylaws” shall include the bylaws as amended or restated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Contribution”, except as used in § 29-1010.08(c), means a benefit that a person provides to a limited cooperative association to become or remain a member or in the person’s capacity as a member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cooperative” means a limited cooperative association or an entity organized under any cooperative law of any jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means a director of a limited cooperative association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Distribution”, except as used in § 29-1010.07(e), means a transfer of money or other property from a limited cooperative association to a member because of the member’s financial rights or to a transferee of a member’s financial rights.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial rights” means the right to participate in allocations and distributions as provided in subchapters X and XII of this chapter, but shall not include rights or obligations under a marketing contract governed by subchapter VII of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign cooperative” means an entity organized in a jurisdiction other than the District under a law similar to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investor member” means a member that has made a contribution to a limited cooperative association and is not:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited cooperative association”, “domestic limited cooperative association”, “association”, or “domestic association” means an association formed under this chapter or that becomes subject to this title under Chapter 2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member” means a person that is admitted as a patron member or investor member, or both, in a limited cooperative association. The term “member” shall not include a person that has dissociated as a member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member’s interest” means the interest of a patron member or investor member under § 29-1006.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Members meeting” means an annual members meeting or special meeting of members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Organizer” means an individual who signs the initial articles of organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Patron member” means a member that has made a contribution to a limited cooperative association and is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Patronage” means business transactions between a limited cooperative association and a person which entitle the person to receive financial rights based on the value or quantity of business done between the association and the person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registered foreign cooperative” means a foreign cooperative that is registered to do business in this state pursuant to a statement of registration filed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Required information” means the information a limited cooperative association is required to maintain under § 29-1001.10.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Voting group” means any combination of one or more voting members in one or more districts or classes that under the organic rules or this chapter are entitled to vote and can be counted together collectively on a matter at a members meeting.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Voting member” means a member that, under the organic law or organic rules, has a right to vote on matters subject to vote by members under the organic law or organic rules.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1001_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Voting power” means the total current power of members to vote on a particular matter for which a vote may or is to be taken.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
