<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1209.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-1209.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_1209_01">
        <akn:num>29-1209.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Application to existing relationships.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1209_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not limit, prohibit, or invalidate the existence, acts, or obligations of any common-law trust created or doing business in the District before or after the applicability date of this chapter. The laws of the District other than this chapter pertaining to trusts shall apply to common-law trusts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1209_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A common-law trust arising under the law of the District before or after the applicability date of this chapter that does not have a prevailingly donative purpose may elect to be governed by this chapter by filing of a certificate of trust under ยง 29-1202.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1209_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A trust created pursuant to a statute of the District that was required by that statute to file a certificate of trust with the Mayor before the applicability date of this chapter may elect to be governed by this chapter by filing an amendment to its certificate of trust under ยง 29-1202.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-1209_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On and after one year after the applicability date of this chapter, this chapter shall govern the organization and internal affairs of all trusts created pursuant to a statute of the District that was required by that statute to file a certificate of trust with the Mayor before the applicability date of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
