<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-205.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-205.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_205_06">
        <akn:num>29-205.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Effect of domestication.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a domestication becomes effective:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in the organic law or organic rules of the domesticating entity, the domestication shall not give rise to any rights that an interest holder, governor, or third party would otherwise have upon a dissolution, liquidation, or winding-up of the domesticating entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a domestication becomes effective, a person that did not have interest holder liability with respect to the domesticating entity and that becomes subject to interest holder liability with respect to a domestic entity as a result of the domestication shall have interest holder liability only to the extent provided by the organic law of the entity and only for those liabilities that arise after the domestication becomes effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a domestication becomes effective:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a domestication becomes effective, a foreign entity that is the domesticated entity may be served with process in the District for the collection and enforcement of any of its liabilities in the manner provided in ยง 29-104.12.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the domesticating entity is a registered foreign entity, the certificate of registration or other foreign qualification of the domesticating entity shall be canceled when the domestication becomes effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-205_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A domestication shall not require the entity to wind up its affairs and shall not constitute or cause the dissolution of the entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
