<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-305.21"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-305.21/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_305_21">
        <akn:num>29-305.21</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Voting entitlement of shares.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_21_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (d) of this section or unless the articles of incorporation provide otherwise, each outstanding share, regardless of class, shall be entitled to one vote on each matter voted on at a shareholders’ meeting. Only shares shall be entitled to vote.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_21_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Absent special circumstances, the shares of a corporation shall not be entitled to vote if they are owned, directly or indirectly, by a second corporation, domestic or foreign, and the first corporation owns, directly or indirectly, a majority of the shares entitled to vote for directors of the second corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_21_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (b) of this section shall not limit the power of a corporation to vote any shares, including its own shares, held by it in a fiduciary capacity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_21_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Redeemable shares shall not be entitled to vote after notice of redemption is mailed to the holders and a sum sufficient to redeem the shares has been deposited with a bank, trust company, or other financial institution under an irrevocable obligation to pay the holders the redemption price on surrender of the shares.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
