<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-309.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-309.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_309_02">
        <akn:num>29-309.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Merger.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>One or more domestic business corporations may merge with one or more domestic or foreign business corporations pursuant to a plan of merger, or 2 or more foreign business corporations or domestic may merge into a new domestic business corporation to be created in the merger, in the manner provided in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A foreign business may be a party to a merger with a domestic business corporation, or may be the survivor in such a merger, if the merger is permitted by the jurisdiction of the foreign business corporation is incorporated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the organic law of a domestic eligible entity does not provide procedures for the approval of a merger, a plan of merger may be adopted and approved, the merger effectuated, and appraisal rights exercised in accordance with the procedures in this subchapter and subchapter XI of this chapter. For the purposes of applying this subchapter and subchapter XI of this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan of merger shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Terms of a plan of merger may be made dependent on facts objectively ascertainable outside the plan in accordance with ยง 29-301.04.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan of merger may also include a provision that the plan may be amended by the directors or shareholders of a domestic business corporation; provided, that the shareholders that were entitled to vote on the plan shall be entitled to vote on any amendment of the plan that will change:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-309_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A merger in which a business corporation and another form of entity are parties shall be governed by Chapter 2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
