<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-310.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-310.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_310_02">
        <akn:num>29-310.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Shareholder approval of certain dispositions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of assets, other than a disposition described in § 29-310.01, shall require approval of the corporation’s shareholders if the disposition would leave the corporation without a significant continuing business activity. If a corporation retains a business activity that represented at least 25% of total assets at the end of the most recently completed fiscal year, and 25% of either income from continuing operations before taxes or revenues from continuing operations for that fiscal year, in each case of the corporation and its subsidiaries on a consolidated basis, the corporation shall conclusively be deemed to have retained a significant continuing business activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A disposition that requires approval of the shareholders under subsection (a) of this section shall be initiated by a resolution by the board of directors authorizing the disposition. After adoption of such a resolution, the board of directors shall submit the proposed disposition to the shareholders for their approval. The board of directors shall also transmit to the shareholders a recommendation that the shareholders approve the proposed disposition, unless the board of directors makes a determination that because of conflicts of interest or other special circumstances, it should not make such a recommendation, in which case the board of directors shall transmit to the shareholders the basis for that determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The board of directors may condition its submission of a disposition to the shareholders under subsection (b) of this section on any basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a disposition is required to be approved by the shareholders under subsection (a) of this section, and if the approval is to be given at a meeting, the corporation shall notify each shareholder, whether or not entitled to vote, of the meeting of shareholders at which the disposition is to be submitted for approval. The notice shall state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider the disposition and shall contain a description of the disposition, including the terms and conditions thereof and the consideration to be received by the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless the articles of incorporation or the board of directors acting pursuant to subsection (c) of this section requires a greater vote, or a greater number of votes to be present, the approval of a disposition by the shareholders shall require the approval of the shareholders at a meeting at which a quorum consisting of at least a majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the disposition exists.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After a disposition has been approved by the shareholders under subsection (b) of this section, and at any time before the disposition has been consummated, it may be abandoned by the corporation without action by the shareholders, subject to any contractual rights of other parties to the disposition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A disposition of assets in the course of dissolution under subchapter XII of this chapter shall not be governed by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-310_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The assets of a direct or indirect consolidated subsidiary shall be deemed the assets of the parent corporation for the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
