<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-305.24"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-305.24/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_305_24">
        <akn:num>29-305.24</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Corporation’s acceptance of votes.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_24_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the name signed on a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment corresponds to the name of a shareholder, the corporation, if acting in good faith, shall be entitled to accept the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment and give it effect as the act of the shareholder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_24_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the name signed on a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment does not correspond to the name of its shareholder, the corporation if acting in good faith may nevertheless accept the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment and give it effect as the act of the shareholder if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_24_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The corporation may reject a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment if the secretary or other officer or agent authorized to tabulate votes, acting in good faith, has reasonable basis for doubt about the validity of the signature on it or about the signatory’s authority to sign for the shareholder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_24_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The corporation and its officer or agent who accepts or rejects a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment in good faith and in accordance with the standards of this section or § 29-301.03(d) shall not be liable in damages to the shareholder for the consequences of the acceptance or rejection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-305_24_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Corporate action based on the acceptance or rejection of a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment under this section shall be valid unless the Superior Court determines otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
