<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-304.21"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-304.21/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_304_21">
        <akn:num>29-304.21</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Issuance of shares.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The powers granted in this section to the board of directors may be reserved to the shareholders by the articles of incorporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The board of directors may authorize shares to be issued for consideration consisting of any tangible or intangible property or benefit to the corporation, including money, promissory notes, services performed, contracts for services to be performed, and other securities of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before the corporation issues shares, the board of directors shall determine that the consideration received or to be received for shares to be issued is adequate. That determination by the board of directors shall be conclusive insofar as the adequacy of consideration for the issuance of shares relates to whether the shares are validly issued, fully paid, and nonassessable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the corporation receives the consideration for which the board of directors authorized the issuance of shares, the shares issued therefor shall be fully paid and nonassessable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The corporation may place in escrow shares issued for a contract for future services or benefits or a promissory note, or make other arrangements to restrict the transfer of the shares, and may credit distributions in respect of the shares against their purchase price, until the services are performed, the note is paid, or the benefits received. If the services are not performed, the note is not paid, or the benefits are not received, the shares escrowed or restricted and the distributions credited may be canceled in whole or part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An issuance of shares or other securities convertible into or rights exercisable for shares, in a transaction or a series of integrated transactions, shall require the approval of the shareholders at a meeting at which a quorum consisting of at least a majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the matter exists, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-304_21_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this subsection:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
