<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-311.31"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-311.31/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_311_31">
        <akn:num>29-311.31</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Court costs and expenses.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-311_31_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court in an appraisal proceeding commenced under § 29-311.2 [§ 29-311.12] shall determine all court costs of the proceeding, including the reasonable compensation and expenses of appraisers appointed by the court. The court shall assess the court costs against the corporation, except that the court may assess court costs against all or some of the shareholders demanding appraisal, in amounts which the court finds equitable, to the extent the court finds the shareholders acted arbitrarily, vexatiously, or not in good faith with respect to the rights provided by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-311_31_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court in an appraisal proceeding may also assess the expenses of the respective parties in amounts the court finds equitable:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-311_31_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Superior Court in an appraisal proceeding finds that the expenses incurred by any shareholder were of substantial benefit to other shareholders similarly situated and that the expenses should not be assessed against the corporation, the court may direct that the expenses be paid out of the amounts awarded the shareholders who were benefited.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-311_31_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To the extent the corporation fails to make a required payment pursuant to § 29-311.14, § 29-311.15, or § 29-311.16, the shareholder may sue directly for the amount owed, and to the extent successful, shall be entitled to recover from the corporation all expenses of the suit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
