<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-409.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-409.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_409_03">
        <akn:num>29-409.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Membership exchange.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Through a membership exchange:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A foreign nonprofit corporation or eligible entity may be a party to a membership exchange only if the membership exchange is permitted by the organic law of the corporation or eligible entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the organic law of a domestic eligible entity does not prohibit a membership exchange with a nonprofit corporation but does not provide procedures for the approval of an exchange of interests similar to a membership exchange, a plan of membership exchange may be adopted and approved, and the membership exchange effectuated, in accordance with the procedures, if any, for a merger. If the organic law of a domestic eligible entity does not provide procedures for either an interest exchange or a merger, a plan of membership exchange may be adopted and approved, and the membership exchange effectuated, in accordance with the procedures in this subchapter. For the purposes of applying this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan of membership exchange shall be in the form of a record and include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan of membership exchange may also include a provision that the plan may be amended prior to filing articles of membership exchange, but if the members of a domestic nonprofit corporation that is a party to the membership exchange are required or permitted to vote on the plan, the plan shall provide that subsequent to approval of the plan by such members the plan shall not be amended to change:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Terms of a plan of membership exchange may be made dependent on facts objectively ascertainable outside the plan in accordance with ยง 29-401.04.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not limit the power of a domestic nonprofit corporation to acquire memberships in another corporation or eligible interests in an eligible entity in a transaction other than a membership exchange.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any debt security, note, or similar evidence of indebtedness for money borrowed, whether secured or unsecured, or a contract of any kind, issued, incurred, or signed by a domestic exchanging entity before the effective date of this chapter contains a provision applying to a merger or change in control of the exchanging entity that does not refer to a membership exchange, the provision shall be deemed to apply to a membership exchange of the exchanging entity until such time as the provision is amended subsequent to that date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
