<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-406.30"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-406.30/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_406_30">
        <akn:num>29-406.30</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Standards of conduct for directors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the board of directors, when discharging the duties of a director, shall act:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The members of the board of directors or a committee of the board, when becoming informed in connection with their decision-making function or devoting attention to their oversight function, shall discharge their duties with the care that a person in a like position would reasonably believe appropriate under similar circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In discharging board or committee duties a director shall disclose, or cause to be disclosed, to the other board or committee members information not already known by them but known by the director to be material to the discharge of their decision-making or oversight functions, except that disclosure is not required to the extent that the director reasonably believes that doing so would violate a duty imposed by law, a legally enforceable obligation of confidentiality, or a professional ethics rule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In discharging board or committee duties, a director who does not have knowledge that makes reliance unwarranted may rely on the performance by any of the persons specified in subsection (f)(1), (3), or (4) of this section to whom the board may have delegated, formally or informally by course of conduct, the authority or duty to perform one or more of the board’s functions that are delegable under applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In discharging board or committee duties a director who does not have knowledge that makes reliance unwarranted may rely on information, opinions, reports, or statements, including financial statements and other financial data, prepared or presented by any of the persons specified in subsection (f) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A director may rely, in accordance with subsection (d) or (e) of this section, on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_30_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A director shall not be a trustee with respect to the nonprofit corporation or with respect to any property held or administered by the corporation, including property that may be subject to restrictions imposed by the donor or transferor of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
