<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-410.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-410.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_410_02">
        <akn:num>29-410.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Member approval of certain dispositions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, a sale, lease, exchange, or other disposition of assets, other than a disposition described in § 29-410.01, shall require approval of the nonprofit corporation’s members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A disposition that requires approval of the members under subsection (a) of this section shall be initiated by a resolution by the board of directors authorizing the disposition. After adoption of the resolution, the board of directors shall submit the proposed disposition to the members for their approval. The board of directors shall also transmit to the members a recommendation that the members approve the proposed disposition, unless the board of directors makes a determination that because of conflicts of interest or other special circumstances, it should not make such a recommendation, in which case the board of directors shall transmit to the members the basis for that determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The board of directors may condition its submission of a disposition to the members under subsection (b) of this section on any basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a disposition is required to be approved by the members under subsection (a) of this section, and if the approval is to be given at a meeting, the nonprofit corporation shall give notice to each member, whether or not entitled to vote, of the meeting of members at which the disposition is to be submitted for approval. The notice shall state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider the disposition and shall contain a description of the disposition, including the terms and conditions thereof and the consideration to be received by the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws, or the board of directors acting pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, requires a greater vote, or a greater number of votes to be present, the approval of a disposition by the members shall require the approval of the members at a meeting at which a quorum exists, and, if any class of members is entitled to vote as a separate group on the disposition, the approval of each such separate voting group at a meeting at which a quorum of the voting group exists.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After a disposition has been approved by the members under subsection (e) of this section, and at any time before the disposition has been consummated, it may be abandoned by the nonprofit corporation without action by the members, subject to any contractual rights of other parties to the disposition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A disposition of assets in the course of dissolution under subchapter XII of this chapter shall not be governed by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The assets of a direct or indirect consolidated subsidiary shall be deemed the assets of the parent nonprofit corporation for the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-410_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the approval of a disposition of assets by the board of directors and members as required by this section, the disposition shall also be approved in the form of a record by any person or group of persons whose approval is required under § 29-408.40 to amend the articles of incorporation or bylaws.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
