<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-405.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-405.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_405_02">
        <akn:num>29-405.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Special meeting.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-405_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A membership corporation shall hold a special meeting of members:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-405_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, a demand for a special meeting may be revoked by notice to that effect received by the membership corporation from the members calling the meeting prior to the receipt by the corporation of demands sufficient in number to require the holding of a special meeting.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-405_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If not otherwise fixed under § 29-405.03 or § 29-405.07, the record date for determining members entitled to demand a special meeting shall be the date the first member signs a demand.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-405_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (f) of this section, special meetings of the members may be held in or outside of the District at the place stated in or fixed in accordance with the articles of incorporation or bylaws. If no place is stated or fixed in accordance with the articles or bylaws, special meetings shall be held at the corporation’s principal office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-405_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Only business within the purpose or purposes described in the meeting notice required by § 29-405.05(c) may be conducted at a special meeting of the members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-405_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The articles of incorporation or bylaws may provide that a special meeting of members does not need to be held at a geographic location if the meeting is held by means of the Internet or other electronic communications technology in a fashion pursuant to which the members have the opportunity to read or hear the proceedings substantially concurrently with their occurrence, vote on matters submitted to the members, pose questions, and make comments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
