<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-409.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-409.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_409_08">
        <akn:num>29-409.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Abandonment of a merger or membership exchange.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise provided in a plan of merger or membership exchange or in the organic law of a foreign nonprofit corporation that is a party to a merger or a membership exchange, after the plan has been adopted and approved as required by this subchapter, and at any time before the merger or membership exchange has become effective, it may be abandoned by a domestic nonprofit corporation that is a party thereto without action by its members, in accordance with any procedures set forth in the plan of merger or membership exchange or, if no such procedures are set forth in the plan, in the manner determined by the board of directors, subject to any contractual rights of other parties to the merger or membership exchange.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a merger or membership exchange is abandoned under subsection (a) of this section after articles of merger or membership exchange have been delivered to the Mayor for filing but before the merger or membership exchange has become effective, a statement that the merger or membership exchange has been abandoned in accordance with this section, executed on behalf of a party to the merger or membership exchange by an officer or other duly authorized representative, shall be delivered to the Mayor for filing prior to the effective date of the merger or membership exchange. Upon filing, the statement shall be effective and the merger or membership exchange shall be deemed abandoned and shall not become effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
