<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-406.22"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-406.22/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_406_22">
        <akn:num>29-406.22</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Call and notice of meeting.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_22_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws provide otherwise, regular meetings of the board of directors shall be held with notice of the date, time, place, or purpose of the meeting; provided, that at the beginning of each one-year period, the corporation may provide a single notice of all regularly scheduled meetings for that year, or for a lesser period, without having to give notice of each meeting individually.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_22_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws provide for a longer or shorter period, special meetings of the board of directors shall be preceded by at least 2 days’ notice of the date, time, and place of the meeting. The notice need not describe the purpose of the special meeting unless required by the articles of incorporation or bylaws.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_22_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws provide otherwise, the chair of the board, the highest ranking officer of the corporation, or 20% of the directors then in office may call and give notice of a meeting of the board of directors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-406_22_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The articles of incorporation or bylaws may authorize oral notice of meetings of the board of directors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
