<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-409.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-409.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_409_02">
        <akn:num>29-409.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Merger.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>One or more domestic nonprofit corporations may merge with one or more domestic or foreign nonprofit corporations pursuant to a plan of merger or 2 or more foreign nonprofit corporations or domestic nonprofit corporations may merge into a new domestic nonprofit corporation to be created in the merger in the manner provided in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A foreign nonprofit corporation may be a party to a merger with a domestic nonprofit corporation, or may be created by the terms of the plan of merger, only if the merger is permitted by the organic law of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the organic law of a domestic eligible entity shall not prohibit a merger with a nonprofit corporation but does not provide procedures for the approval of such a merger, a plan of merger may be adopted and approved, and the merger may be effectuated, in accordance with the procedures in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan of merger shall be in the form of a record and include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan of merger may also include a provision that the plan may be amended prior to filing articles of merger, but if the members of a domestic corporation that is a party to the merger are required or permitted to vote on the plan, the plan shall provide that subsequent to approval of the plan by such members the plan shall not be amended to change:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Terms of a plan of merger may be made dependent on facts objectively ascertainable outside the plan in accordance with ยง 29-401.04.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-409_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A merger in which a nonprofit corporation and another form of entity are parties is governed by Chapter 2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
