<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-601.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-601.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_601_02">
        <akn:num>29-601.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business” includes every trade, occupation, and profession.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Contribution”, except in the phrase “right of contribution”, means property or a benefit described in § 29-604.03 provided by a person to a partnership to become a partner or in the person’s capacity as a partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Distribution” means a transfer of money or other property from a partnership to person on account of a transferable interest or in a person’s capacity as a partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic partnership” means a partnership whose internal relations are governed by the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign limited liability partnership” means a foreign partnership whose partners have limited liability for the debts, obligations, or other liabilities of the foreign partnership under a provision similar to § 29-603.06(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign partnership” means an unincorporated entity formed under the law of a jurisdiction other than the District which would be a partnership if formed under the law of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited liability partnership” or “domestic limited liability partnership” means a partnership that has filed a statement of qualification under § 29-610.01 and does not have a similar statement in effect in any other jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partner” means a person that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partnership” means an association of 2 or more persons to carry on as co-owners a business for profit formed under § 29-602.02, predecessor law, or comparable law of another jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partnership agreement” means the agreement, whether written, oral, or implied, among the partners concerning the partnership, including amendments to the partnership agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partnership at will” means a partnership in which the partners have not agreed to remain partners until the expiration of a definite term or the completion of a particular undertaking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partnership interest” or “partner’s interest in the partnership” means all of a partner’s interests in the partnership, including the partner’s transferable interest and all management and other rights.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registered foreign limited liability partnership” means a foreign limited liability partnership that is registered to do business in this state pursuant to a statement of registration filed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Surviving partnership” means a domestic or foreign partnership into which one or more domestic or foreign partnerships are merged. A surviving partnership may preexist the merger or be created by the merger.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transferable interest” means the right, as initially owned by a person in the person’s capacity as a partner, to receive distributions from a partnership in accordance with the partnership agreement, whether or not the person remains a partner or continues to own any part of the right. The term applies to any fraction of the interest, by whomever owned.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-601_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transferee” means a person to which all or part of a transferable interest has been transferred, whether or not the transferor is a partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
