<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-604.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-604.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_604_01">
        <akn:num>29-604.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Partner’s rights and duties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each partner shall deemed to have an account that is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each partner shall be entitled to an equal share of the partnership profits and shall be chargeable with a share of the partnership losses in proportion to the partner’s share of the profits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partnership shall reimburse a partner for payments made, and indemnify a partner for liabilities incurred, by the partner in the ordinary course of the business of the partnership or for the preservation of its business or property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partnership shall reimburse a partner for an advance to the partnership beyond the amount of capital the partner agreed to contribute.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A payment or advance made by a partner which gives rise to a partnership obligation under subsection (c) or (d) of this section shall constitute a loan to the partnership which accrues interest from the date of the payment or advance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partnership shall indemnify and hold harmless a person with respect to any claim or demand against the person and any debt, obligation, or other liability incurred by the person by reason of the person’s former or present capacity as partner, if the claim, demand, debt, obligation, or other liability does not arise from the person’s breach of this section, § 29-604.07, or § 29-610.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the ordinary course of its business, a partnership may advance reasonable expenses, including attorney’s fees and costs, incurred by a person in connection with a claim or demand against the person by reason of the person’s former or present capacity as a partner, if the person promises to repay the partnership if the person ultimately is determined not to be entitled to be indemnified under subsection (f) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partnership may purchase or maintain insurance against liability arising from a partner’s status and asserted against or incurred by a partner acting in his or her capacity. Such insurance may be purchased and maintained even if, under § 29-601.04(b)(13), the partnership agreement does not permit limitation or elimination of partner liability.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each partner shall have equal rights in the management and conduct of the partnership business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partner shall use or possess partnership property only on behalf of the partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partner shall not be entitled to remuneration for services performed for the partnership, except for reasonable compensation for services rendered in winding up the business of the partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A difference arising as to a matter in the ordinary course of business of a partnership shall be decided by a majority of the partners. An act outside the ordinary course of business of a partnership and an amendment to the partnership agreement shall be undertaken only with the consent of all of the partners.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-604_01_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not affect the debts, liabilities, or other obligations of a partnership to other persons under § 29-603.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
