<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-603.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-603.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_603_03">
        <akn:num>29-603.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Statement of partnership authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A partnership may deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of partnership authority, which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a statement of partnership authority names an agent, the agent shall maintain a list of the names and mailing addresses of all of the partners and make it available to any person on request for good cause shown.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a filed statement of partnership authority is executed pursuant to § 29-601.05(c) and states the name of the partnership, but does not contain all of the other information required by subsection (a) of this section, the statement shall nevertheless operate with respect to a person not a partner as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g) of this section, a filed statement of partnership authority shall supplement the authority of a partner to enter into transactions on behalf of the partnership as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person not a partner shall be deemed to know of a limitation on the authority of a partner to transfer real property held in the name of the partnership if a certified copy of the filed statement containing the limitation on authority is of record in the office for recording transfers of that real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section and §§ 29-607.04 and 29-608.05, a person not a partner shall not be deemed to know of a limitation on the authority of a partner merely because the limitation is contained in a filed statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-603_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless earlier canceled, a filed statement of partnership authority shall be canceled by operation of law 5 years after the date on which the statement, or the most recent amendment, was delivered to the Mayor for filing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
