<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-708.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-708.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_708_11">
        <akn:num>29-708.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Court proceedings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-708_11_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A dissolved limited partnership that has published a notice under § 29-708.06(b) may file an application with the Superior Court, or, if the principal office is not located in the District, in an appropriate court where the company’s principal office is located, for a determination of the amount and form of security to be provided for payment of claims that are contingent, have not been made known to the partnership, or are based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution but which, based on the facts known to the partnership, are reasonably expected to arise after the effective date of dissolution. Security is not required for any claim that is or is reasonably anticipated to be barred under § 29-708.06(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-708_11_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 10 days after the filing of an application under subsection (a) of this section, the dissolved limited partnership shall give notice of the proceeding to each claimant holding a contingent claim known to the partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-708_11_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a proceeding brought under this section, the court may appoint a guardian ad litem to represent all claimants whose identities are unknown. The reasonable fees and expenses of the guardian, including all reasonable expert witness fees, must be paid by the dissolved limited partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-708_11_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A dissolved limited partnership that provides security in the amount and form ordered by the court under subsection (a) of this section satisfies the partnership’s obligations with respect to claims that are contingent, have not been made known to the partnership, or are based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution, and such claims may not be enforced against a partner or transferee that received assets in liquidation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
