<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-707.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-707.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_707_02">
        <akn:num>29-707.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of partner’s transferable interest.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transfer, in whole or in part, of a partner’s transferable interest:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transferee shall have a right to receive, in accordance with the transfer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a dissolution and winding up, a transferee shall be entitled to an account of the limited partnership’s transactions only from the date of dissolution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon transfer, the transferor retain the rights of a partner other than the interest in distributions transferred and shall retain all duties and obligations of a partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A limited partnership need not give effect to a transferee’s rights under this section until the limited partnership has notice of the transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transfer of a partner’s transferable interest in the limited partnership in violation of a restriction on transfer contained in the partnership agreement shall be ineffective as to a person having notice of the restriction at the time of transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transferee that becomes a partner with respect to a transferable interest shall be liable for the transferor’s obligations under §§ 29-705.02 and 29-705.09. However, the transferee shall not be obligated for liabilities unknown to the transferee at the time the transferee became a partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-707_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transferable interest may be evidenced by a certificate of the interest issued by a limited partnership in a record, and, subject to this section, the interest represented by the certificate may be transferred by a transfer of the certificate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
