<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-701.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-701.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_701_03">
        <akn:num>29-701.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Knowledge and notice.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person knows a fact if the person has actual knowledge of it.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person has notice of a fact if the person:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certificate of limited partnership on file in the office of the Mayor shall be notice that the partnership is a limited partnership and the persons designated in the certificate as general partners are general partners. Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, the certificate shall not be notice of any other fact.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person has notice of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person notifies or gives a notification to another person by taking steps reasonably required to inform the other person in ordinary course, whether or not the other person learns of it.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person receives a notification when the notification:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (h) of this section, a person other than an individual knows, has notice, or receives a notification of a fact for purposes of a particular transaction when the individual conducting the transaction for the person knows, has notice, or receives a notification of the fact, or in any event when the fact would have been brought to the individual’s attention if the person had exercised reasonable diligence. A person other than an individual exercises reasonable diligence if it maintains reasonable routines for communicating significant information to the individual conducting the transaction for the person and there is reasonable compliance with the routines. Reasonable diligence shall not require an individual acting for the person to communicate information unless the communication is part of the individual’s regular duties or the individual has reason to know of the transaction and that the transaction would be materially affected by the information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-701_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A general partner’s knowledge, notice, or receipt of a notification of a fact relating to the limited partnership shall be effective immediately as knowledge of, notice to, or receipt of a notification by the limited partnership, except in the case of a fraud on the limited partnership committed by or with the consent of the general partner. A limited partner’s knowledge, notice, or receipt of a notification of a fact relating to the limited partnership shall not be effective as knowledge of, notice to, or receipt of a notification by the limited partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
