<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-704.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-704.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_704_07">
        <akn:num>29-704.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Right of general partner and former general partner to information.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A general partner, without having any particular purpose for seeking the information, may inspect and copy during regular business hours:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each general partner and the limited partnership shall furnish to a general partner:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (e) of this section, on 10 days’ demand made in a record received by the limited partnership, a person dissociated as a general partner may have access to the information and records described in subsection (a) of this section at the location specified in subsection (a) of this section if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The limited partnership shall respond to a demand made pursuant to subsection (c) of this section in the same manner as provided in § 29-703.04(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a general partner dies, § 29-707.04 shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The limited partnership may impose reasonable restrictions on the use of information under this section. In any dispute concerning the reasonableness of a restriction under this subsection, the limited partnership shall have the burden of proving reasonableness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A limited partnership may charge a person dissociated as a general partner that makes a demand under this section reasonable costs of copying, limited to the costs of labor and material.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A general partner or person dissociated as a general partner may exercise the rights under this section through an attorney or other agent. Any restriction imposed under subsection (f) or by the partnership agreement shall apply both to the attorney or other agent and to the general partner or person dissociated as a general partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_07_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The rights under this section shall not extend to a person as transferee, but the rights under subsection (c) of this section of a person dissociated as a general may be exercised by the legal representative of an individual who dissociated as a general partner under § 29-706.03(7)(B) or (C).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
