<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-704.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-704.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_704_04">
        <akn:num>29-704.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>General partner’s liability.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, all general partners shall be liable jointly and severally for all debts, obligations, and other liabilities of the limited partnership unless otherwise agreed by the claimant or provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person that becomes a general partner of an existing limited partnership is not be personally liable for a debt, obligation, or other liability of a limited partnership incurred before the person became a general partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A debt, obligation, or other liability of a limited partnership incurred while the limited partnership is a limited partnership, whether arising in contract tort, or otherwise, and that is incurred while the limited partnership is a limited liability partnership, is solely an obligation of the limited partnership. A general partner shall not be personally liable, directly or indirectly, by way of contribution or otherwise, for such debt, obligation, or other liability solely by reason of being or acting as a general partner. This subsection shall apply despite anything inconsistent in the partnership agreement that existed immediately before the consent required to become a limited liability limited partnership under § 29-704.06(b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The failure of a limited liability limited partnership to observe formalities relating to the exercise of its powers or management of its activities and affairs is not a ground for imposing liability on a general partner of the limited liability limited partnership for a debt, obligation, or liability of the partnership.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-704_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An amendment of a certificate of limited partnership which deletes a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership does not affect the limitation in this section on the liability of a general partner for a debt, obligation, or other liability of the limited partnership incurred before the amendment became effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
