<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-804.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-804.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_804_09">
        <akn:num>29-804.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Standards of conduct for members and managers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member of a member-managed limited liability company owes to the company and, subject to § 29-808.01(b), the other members the duties of loyalty and care stated in subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The duty of loyalty of a member in a member-managed limited liability company shall include the duties to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The duty of care of a member of a member-managed limited liability company in the conduct or winding up of the company’s activities and affairs requires the member to refrain from engaging in grossly negligent or reckless conduct, willful or intentional misconduct, or a knowing violation of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member in a member-managed limited liability company or a manager-managed limited liability company shall discharge the duties and obligations under this chapter or under the operating agreement and exercise any rights consistently with the contractual obligation of good faith and fair dealing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be a defense to a claim under subsection (b)(2) of this section and any comparable claim in equity or at common law that the transaction was fair to the limited liability company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All of the members of a member-managed limited liability company or a manager-managed limited liability company may authorize or ratify, after full disclosure of all material facts, a specific act or transaction that otherwise would violate the duty of loyalty.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member does not violate a duty or obligation under this chapter or under the operating agreement solely because the member’s conduct furthers the member’s own interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, as permitted by subsection (f) of this section or the operating agreement, a member enters into a transaction with the limited liability company which otherwise would be prohibited by subsection (b)(2) of this section, the member’s rights and obligations arising from the transaction are the same as those of a person that is not a member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_09_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a manager-managed limited liability company, the following rules apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
