<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-805.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-805.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_805_02">
        <akn:num>29-805.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of transferable interest.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to § 29-805.03(f), a transfer, in whole or in part, of a transferable interest:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transferee shall have the right to receive, in accordance with the transfer, distributions to which the transferor would otherwise be entitled.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a dissolution and winding up of a limited liability company, a transferee shall be entitled to an account of the company’s transactions only from the date of dissolution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transferable interest may be evidenced by a certificate of the interest issued by the limited liability company in a record, and, subject to this section, the interest represented by the certificate may be transferred by a transfer of the certificate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A limited liability company need not give effect to a transferee’s rights under this section until the company has notice of the transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transfer of a transferable interest in violation of a restriction on transfer contained in the operating agreement shall be ineffective as to a person having notice of the restriction at the time of transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in § 29-806.02(4)(B), when a member transfers a transferable interest, the transferor shall retain the rights of a member other than the interest in distributions transferred and shall retain all duties and obligations of a member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-805_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a member transfers a transferable interest to a person that becomes a member with respect to the transferred interest, the transferee shall be liable for the member’s obligations under §§ 29-804.03 and 29-804.06(c) known to the transferee when the transferee becomes a member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
