<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-804.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-804.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_804_10">
        <akn:num>29-804.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Right of members, managers, and dissociated members to information.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a member-managed limited liability company, the following rules shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a manager-managed limited liability company, the following rules shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On 10 days’ demand made in a record received by a limited liability company, a dissociated member shall have access to information to which the person was entitled while a member if the information pertains to the period during which the person was a member, the person seeks the information in good faith, and the person satisfies the requirements imposed on a member by subsection (b)(2) of this section. The company shall respond to a demand made pursuant to this subsection in the manner provided in subsection (b)(3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A limited liability company may charge a person that makes a demand under this section the reasonable costs of copying, limited to the costs of labor and material.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member or dissociated member may exercise rights under this section through an agent or, in the case of an individual under legal disability, a legal representative. Any restriction or condition imposed by the operating agreement or under subsection (g) of this section shall apply both to the agent or legal representative and the member or dissociated member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The rights under this section shall not extend to a person as transferee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-804_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any restriction or condition stated in its operating agreement, a limited liability company, as a matter within the ordinary course of its activities and affairs, may impose reasonable restrictions and conditions on access to and use of information to be furnished under this section, including designating information confidential and imposing nondisclosure and safeguarding obligations on the recipient. In a dispute concerning the reasonableness of a restriction under this subsection, the company shall have the burden of proving reasonableness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
