<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-803.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/29-803.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_29_803_02">
        <akn:num>29-803.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Statement of authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A limited liability company may deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of authority. The statement:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To amend or cancel a statement of authority filed by the Mayor under ยง 29-802.05(a), a limited liability company shall deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment or cancellation stating:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A statement of authority shall affect only the power of a person to bind a limited liability company to persons that are not members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (c) of this section and ยง 29-801.03(d) and except as otherwise provided in subsections (f), (g), and (h) of this section, a limitation on the authority of a person or a position contained in an effective statement of authority shall not by itself [be] evidence of knowledge or notice of the limitation by any person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (c), a grant of authority not pertaining to transfers of real property and contained in an effective statement of authority shall be conclusive in favor of a person that gives value in reliance on the grant, except to the extent that when the person gives value:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, an effective statement of authority that grants authority to transfer real property held in the name of the limited liability company and that is recorded by certified copy in the office for recording transfers of the real property shall be conclusive in favor of a person that gives value in reliance on the grant without knowledge to the contrary, except to the extent that when the person gives value:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, if a certified copy of an effective statement containing a limitation on the authority to transfer real property held in the name of a limited liability company is recorded in the office for recording transfers of that real property, all persons shall be deemed to know of the limitation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (i) of this section, an effective statement of dissolution or termination shall be a cancellation of any filed statement of authority for the purposes of subsection (f) of this section and shall be a limitation on authority for the purposes of subsection (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After a statement of dissolution becomes effective, a limited liability company may deliver to the Mayor for filing and, if appropriate, may record a statement of authority that is designated as a post-dissolution statement of authority. The statement shall operate as provided in subsections (f) and (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless earlier canceled, an effective statement of authority shall be canceled by operation of law 5 years after the date on which the statement, or its most recent amendment, becomes effective. This cancellation shall operate without need for any recording under subsection (f) or (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29-803_02_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An effective statement of denial shall operate as a restrictive amendment under this section and may be recorded by certified copy for the purposes of subsection (f)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
