<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/36-302.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/36-302.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_36_302_05">
        <akn:num>36-302.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Violations; notice, order, injunction, and penalties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-302_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever the Mayor has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating any provision of subchapter II or IV of this chapter or the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, he shall cause written notice to be served upon such person in the manner provided by law. Such notice shall specify the provision or provisions that the Mayor has reason to believe that the person has violated or is violating and the ultimate facts or actions upon which the Mayor bases his belief. The Mayor shall also cause a written order to be served upon such person directing such person to immediately cease and desist from continuing such violation. If the person so ordered refuses or fails to comply with such order, the Mayor shall be authorized to apply to any court of competent jurisdiction for a temporary restraining order, preliminary injunction, or permanent injunction restraining such person from continuing such violation. The court shall have jurisdiction to grant such temporary restraining order, preliminary injunction, permanent injunction, or other relief as may be appropriate under the circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-302_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any violation of any provision of subchapter II or IV of this chapter or the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, shall constitute a misdemeanor and shall, upon conviction thereof, be punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than 90 days or both. In the event of any violation of any provision of subchapter II or IV of this chapter or the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, each and every day of such violation shall constitute a separate offense and the penalties provided for herein shall be applicable to each such separate offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-302_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this subchapter or ยง 36-304.01, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of those sections, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
