<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/36-303.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/36-303.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_36_303_05">
        <akn:num>36-303.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sale, assignment, or other transfer of a marketing agreement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-303_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No distributor shall unreasonably withhold his approval of any sale, assignment, or other transfer, including any transfer of the retail dealer’s right, privilege, or authority to occupy a retail service station pursuant to a marketing agreement, of a marketing agreement or any interest therein to another person by a retail dealer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-303_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No retail dealer shall sell, assign, or otherwise transfer a marketing agreement or any interest therein unless he furnishes prior written notice to the distributor of his intention to make such sale, assignment, or other transfer. Such notice shall be sent to the distributor by registered or certified mail and shall include the prospective transferee’s name and address, a statement of the prospective transferee’s financial qualifications, a statement of the prospective transferee’s business experience during the previous 5 years, and a statement of the prospective transferee’s ability, character, and credit history.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-303_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The distributor shall either approve or disapprove such sale, assignment, or other transfer in writing within 60 days after receipt of the notice specified in subsection (b) of this section. A distributor’s failure to notify the retail dealer of his approval or disapproval shall be construed as an approval of the proposed sale, assignment, or other transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-303_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order for a sale, assignment, or other transfer of a marketing agreement to be valid, the prospective transferee shall agree in writing to comply with all valid requirements, conditions, and provisions of the existing marketing agreement which may be applicable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-303_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-303_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
