<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/36-304.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/36-304.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_36_304_01">
        <akn:num>36-304.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Prohibition on conversions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “full service retail service station” means any retail service station location which provides a garage, service bay, work area, or similar enclosed area for repairing, maintaining, servicing, or otherwise working on motor vehicles, or any service islands. Such repair, maintenance, and service work may include, but is not limited to, the installation or replacement of batteries, tires, fan belts, lights, brakes, water pumps, mufflers and other parts and accessories and the performance of motor oil changes, lubrications, wheel alignments, tune-ups, tire repairs, brake adjustments, and general repair and maintenance work and services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No retail service station which is operated as a full service retail service station on or after April 19, 1977, may be discontinued, nor may be structurally altered, modified, or otherwise converted, irrespective of the type or magnitude of the alteration, modification, or conversion, including, but not limited to, any alteration, modification, or conversion which has the effect of merely obstructing access to an existing garage, service bay, work area, or similar enclosed area by any motor vehicle which was previously accommodated, into a nonfull service facility or into any other use.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person who is an operator of any full service retail service station on or after April 19, 1977, including any person who is a subsequent operator of any such retail service station, or who, in any manner, controls the operation of any such retail service station, shall substantially reduce the number, types, quantity, or quality of the repair, maintenance, and other services, including the retail sale of motor fuels, petroleum products, and automotive products, previously offered. Such operators shall maintain the retail service station’s existing garages, service bays, work areas, and similar areas in a fully operational condition and reasonably equipped to perform repair, maintenance, and service work on motor vehicles, including the provision of a qualified individual or individuals who is or are capable of performing repair, maintenance, and service work on motor vehicles during a reasonable number of hours per day and of days per week. This subsection shall not be construed as prohibiting any person who operates or controls a full service retail service station from discontinuing the retail sale of motor fuels at such retail service station, provided that less than 20% of such retail service station’s gross revenue derived from the retail sale of motor fuels, petroleum products, and automotive products and from the repair, maintenance, and servicing of motor vehicles is derived from the retail sale of motor fuels, and provided further that such discontinuance of the retail sale of motor fuels shall not authorize any other substantial reduction in repair, maintenance, or other services previously offered. This subsection shall not be construed as prohibiting a full service retail service station from selling motor fuels on a self-service basis, provided that such retail service station continues to sell motor fuels on a nonself-service basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A distributor shall not attempt to threaten or coerce an operator of a full service retail service station into:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall study the motor vehicle repair, maintenance, and other services being offered by existing full service retail stations and non-full service retail service stations to residents, commercial establishments, commuters, and other affected persons in the District of Columbia, both in terms of adequacy and in terms of convenience. This study shall include an analysis of the impact of converting existing full service retail service stations to non-full service retail service stations in various areas of the District of Columbia. The Mayor shall study the adequacy of existing retail service stations to serve the needs and convenience of residents, commercial establishments, commuters, and other affected persons with respect to the retail sale of motor fuels, petroleum products, and automotive products in various areas of the District of Columbia. The study shall include an examination of the petroleum products and automotive products being offered by commercial establishments other than retail service stations. The Mayor shall, if necessary, present to the Council a preliminary report within 30 days after September 21, 2000. A final report detailing the findings of the study, including the Mayor’s recommendations or proposals with respect to any necessary or desirable legislation or other actions, shall be submitted to the Council no later than June 1, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On January 1, 2009, the Gas Station Advisory Board shall provide to the Council a report on the impact of the Retail Service Station Amendment Act of 2007 [D.C. Law 17-80]. The report shall include statistical data as to the impact on independent dealers as a result of jobbers operating the retail service stations they own on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Office of Energy, unless another agency is designated by the Mayor shall, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, issue rules to implement the provisions of this section which shall include a requirement that each petition for exemption include an estimated date of completion for each phase of a full service retail station conversion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of Energy or successor agency, unless the Mayor shall direct otherwise, shall be the agency charged with the civil enforcement of this section. The adjudication of any civil infraction under this section shall be pursuant to Chapter 18A of Title 2 [§ 2-1831.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36-304_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall notify the Gas Station Advisory Board of any building or construction permit application filed by or on behalf of an owner or operator of a full service retail service station. The Mayor shall provide a copy of the permit application within 10 days of receipt.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
