<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1131_12">
        <akn:num>7-1131.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of functions, property, and personnel.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All real and personal property, Career and Excepted Service, Management Supervisory Service, and trainee positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, operations, and administration of the Commission on Mental Health Services under receivership in Dixon, et al. v. Williams, et al., shall become the property of the Department on December 18, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All real and personal property, positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, and operations of the “Compact Administrator” of the Interstate Compact on Mental Health as set forth in Chapter 11 of this title, shall become the property of the Department on December 18, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All positions, real and personal property, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, and operations of the Department of Health in regulating mental health facilities, mental health services, and mental health supports, shall be transferred to the Department no later than September 30, 2001, in accordance with the terms of the memoranda of agreement executed pursuant to § 7-1131.04(17).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall recognize and bargain with collective bargaining representatives that have been duly certified by the District of Columbia Public Employees Relations Board and shall assume and be bound by all existing collective bargaining agreements entered into by the Commission on Mental Health Services, if those agreements have been approved by the Council, unless Council approval is not required by law and, during a control year as defined in § 47-393(4), the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every employee of the Commission on Mental Health Services shall be transferred to the Department. An employee transferred to the Department shall be transferred in the same classification he or she held at the Commission on Mental Health Services or other department at the time of the transfer. Subject to the District’s authority to convert them to the Management Supervisory Service and the Legal Service consistent with Chapter 6 of Title 1, transferred employees shall retain all rights and privileges related to their individual pay and benefits, including retirement status, so long as the employee is continuously employed by the Department or the District government, including any applicable rights and privileges provided for in § 44-906.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following rules and regulations pertaining to the licensing, certification, and delivery of mental health services and mental health supports shall remain in full force and effect unless and until repealed or superseded by action of the Department of Mental Health:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_12_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following rules and regulations pertaining to the licensing, certification, and delivery of mental health services and mental health supports shall remain in full force and effect until the Department of Mental Health promulgates standards and procedures in accordance with § 7-1131.14(2)-(4):</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
