<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.19"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.19/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1131_19">
        <akn:num>7-1131.19</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Behavioral Health Ombudsman Program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As of October 1, 2012, there is established within the Department a Behavioral Health Ombudsman Program (“Ombudsman Program”) to provide District residents with assistance in accessing behavioral health programs and services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman Program may use volunteers with appropriate training and supervision to assist with counseling, outreach, and other tasks.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman, or his or her designee, shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 30 days of the end of each fiscal year, the Ombudsman shall submit a report to the Department, the Council, and the Mayor, and make it available to the public upon request, regarding the activities of the Ombudsman Program during the prior fiscal year, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman Program shall enter into a business associate agreement with the Department of Health Care Finance to allow the Ombudsman Program access to information about the Medicaid eligibility status of consumers whom it serves and that requires the Ombudsman Program to safeguard that information pursuant to the Privacy Rule (45 C.F.R. §§ 160 and 164) adopted pursuant to HIPPA.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman shall request and promptly receive, with reasonable notice, the cooperation, assistance, and data from other District agencies, as necessary to enable the Ombudsman Program to investigate a resident’s complaint under District or federal law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No employee, subcontractor, designee, or representative of the Ombudsman Program shall be held liable for the good-faith performance of responsibilities under this section; except, no immunity shall extend to criminal acts or other acts that violate District or federal law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person, agency, provider, or facility shall obstruct the Ombudsman, or his or her designee, from the lawful performance of any duty or the exercise of any power.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_19_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall prohibit a corporation, organization, or consortia of organizations contracted to operate the Ombudsman Program from raising private money through foundation resources to supplement government funds for the Ombudsman Program.”.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
