<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.14"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.14/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1131_14">
        <akn:num>7-1131.14</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rules.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_14_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Definitions for priority populations, including, but not limited to persons with serious mental illness and children or youth with serious emotional disturbance;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_14_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Standards for the operation of mental health services and mental health supports, including, but not limited to requirements regarding:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_14_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Standards and procedures for internal and external monitoring and evaluation of the delivery of mental health services and mental health supports, including, but not limited to standards and procedures for granting certification or full or conditional licensure to providers of mental health services or mental health supports, and limitations on providers of mental health services or mental health supports that are granted conditional licensure;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_14_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Standards and procedures for revoking the certifications or licenses, other than professional licenses, of providers of mental health services or mental health supports who do not continue to meet the standards established by the Department, and procedures for facilitating the ongoing delivery of mental health services and mental health supports to consumers of such providers;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_14_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_14_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A joint consent for the use of protected mental health information by participating providers that is consistent with 45 C.F.R. Parts 160 and 164 and Chapter 12 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
