<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1131.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1131_03">
        <akn:num>7-1131.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment and purposes of the Department of Mental Health.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as a separate cabinet-level Department, subordinate to the Mayor, the Department of Mental Health.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall be the successor in interest to the Commission on Mental Health Services, established by Mayor’s Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, effective January 3, 1987 (part B of subchapter VII of Chapter 15 of Title 1), and Mayor’s Order No. 88-168, effective July 13, 1988, and under receivership in the case of Dixon, et al. v. Williams, et al., C.A. No. 74-285 (NHJ), in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this chapter are intended to be construed in a manner consistent with all outstanding orders of the United States District Court inDixon, et al. v. Williams, et al., including the Final Plan adopted by the District Court in its April 2, 2001 order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall have as its purposes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In assessing or meeting the service needs of consumers of mental health services, the Department shall not discriminate against consumers based upon their eligibility or non-eligibility for Medicaid, Medicare, or private insurance coverage; provided, that nothing in this section shall preclude the Department from establishing by regulation a mental-health-benefit program or plan based upon eligibility or non-eligibility for Medicaid, Medicare, or private insurance coverage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter requires or shall be construed as requiring the Department or any provider with which the Department contracts to provide mental health services or mental health supports to persons who are not residents of the District, except where those persons are likely to injure themselves or others if services are not provided or where services are otherwise required by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall limit the civil rights of consumers of mental health services who have reached the age of majority under District law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1131_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall affect the authority of the Medical Assistance Administration as the single state agency for the administration of the Medicaid Program under section 1902(a)(5) of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 344; 42 U.S.C. § 1396a(a)(5)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
