<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1231.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1231.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1231_09">
        <akn:num>7-1231.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Freedom from seclusion and restraint.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consumers have the right to be free from seclusion and restraint of any form that is not medically necessary or that is used as a means of coercion, discipline, convenience, or retaliation by staff.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Seclusion or restraint may only be used by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Seclusion or restraint can be used only in an emergency when:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any use of seclusion or restraint shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All staff having direct consumer contact must have ongoing education and training in the proper and safe use of seclusion and restraint techniques and in alternative methods for handling behavior, symptoms, and situations that traditionally have been treated through the use of seclusion or restraint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any consumer to whom seclusion or restraint is applied must be seen by his or her attending or treating physician within one hour after the initiation of the seclusion or restraint. The physician shall evaluate the continued need for seclusion or restraint, and upon expiration of the original order, may renew the original order only within the following durational limitations:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No use of seclusion or restraint may extend beyond a 24-hour period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Seclusion and restraint may not be used simultaneously unless the consumer is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Providers must report to the Department any death that occurs while a consumer is secluded or restrained and any death that could reasonably have been the result of the use of seclusion or restraint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_09_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall establish standards for the use of seclusion and restraint that minimize circumstances giving rise to the use of seclusion and restraint and that maximize safety when seclusion or restraint is used. The standards shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
