<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1231.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1231.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1231_07">
        <akn:num>7-1231.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Consent to mental health services and mental health supports.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except in accordance with the procedure described in subsection (c)(3) of this section or as otherwise provided by law, no mental health services or mental health supports shall be provided absent a consumer’s informed consent. In seeking a consumer’s informed consent, the Department or other provider shall present the consumer with information about the proposed services or supports, including their purpose, side effects, and potential risks and benefits, as well as information about feasible alternative treatments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, after providing such information, the consumer’s physician is of the opinion that the consumer is incapable of making a decision regarding the provision of particular mental health services and mental health supports, the physician shall seek certification of the consumer’s incapacitation in accordance with Chapter 22 of Title 21.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a consumer is certified as incapacitated in accordance with § 21-2204, his or her physician shall seek to obtain consent to the provision of particular mental health services and mental health supports as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Family members and personal representatives to whom the consumer has authorized release of information in accordance with Chapter 12 of this title shall be notified as soon as possible whenever mental health services and mental health supports are provided without the consent of the consumer pursuant to subsection (c)(3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1231_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Electroconvulsive treatment shall not be administered to a consumer without the consumer’s own informed and written consent unless authorized by an order of the court issued in accordance with §§ 21-2047(c)(2) and 21-2211(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
