<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1305.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1305.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1305_12">
        <akn:num>7-1305.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Maintenance of records; information considered privileged and confidential; access; contents.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Complete records for each individual shall be maintained and shall be readily available to professional persons and to the staff workers who are directly involved with the particular individual and to the Department on Disability Services without divulging the identity of the individual. All information contained in an individual’s records shall be considered privileged and confidential. The individual’s parent or guardian who petitioned for the commitment, the individual’s counsel, the individual’s advocate for a person with an intellectual disability and any person properly authorized in writing by the individual, if such individual is capable of giving such authorization, shall be permitted access to the individual’s records. These records shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, information contained in an individual’s record may be used or disclosed for the purposes of and in accordance with Chapter 2A of this title [§ 7-251 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
