<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1305.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1305.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1305_05">
        <akn:num>7-1305.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Visitors; mail; access to telephones; religious practice; personal possessions; privacy; exercise; diet; medical attention; medication.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to restrictions by a physician for good cause, each individual has the right to receive visitors of his or her own choosing daily. Hours during which visitors may be received shall be limited only in the interest of effective treatment and the reasonable efficiency of the facility, and shall be sufficiently flexible to accommodate the individual needs of the individual and his or her visitors. Notwithstanding the above, each individual has the right to receive visits from his or her attorney, physician, psychologist, clergyman, social worker, parents or guardians, or advocate for a person with an intellectual disability in private at any reasonable time, irrespective of visiting hours, provided the visitor shows reasonable cause for visiting at times other than normal visiting hours.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Writing material and postage stamps shall be reasonably available for the individual’s use in writing letters and other communications. Reasonable assistance shall be provided for writing, addressing and posting letters and other documents upon request. The individual shall have the right to send and receive sealed and uncensored mail. The individual has the right to reasonable private access to telephones and, in case of personal emergencies when other means of communications are not satisfactory, he or she shall be afforded reasonable use of long distance calls. An individual who is unable to pay shall be furnished such writing, postage, and telephone facilities without charge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each individual shall have the right to follow or abstain from the practice of religion. The facility shall provide appropriate assistance in this connection including reasonable accommodations for religious worship and/or transportation to nearby religious services. Individuals who do not wish to participate in religious practice shall be free from pressure to do so or to accept religious beliefs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each individual shall have the right to a humane psychological and physical environment. He or she shall be provided a comfortable bed and adequate changes of linen and reasonable storage space, including locked space, for his or her personal possessions. A record shall be kept of each individual’s personal possessions. Except when curtailed for reason of safety or therapy as documented in his or her record by a physician, he or she shall be afforded reasonable privacy in his sleeping and personal hygiene practices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each individual shall have reasonable daily opportunities for physical exercise and outdoor exercise and shall have reasonable access to recreational areas and equipment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each individual has the right to a nourishing, well-balanced, varied, and appetizing diet, and where ordered by a physician and/or nutritionist, to a special diet.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each individual shall have the right to prompt and adequate medical attention for any physical ailments and shall receive a complete physical examination upon admission and at least once a year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All individuals have a right to be free from unnecessary or excessive medication. No medication shall be administered unless at the written or verbal order of a licensed physician, noted promptly in the patient’s medical record and signed by the physician within 24 hours. Medication shall be administered only by a licensed physician, registered nurse or licensed practical nurse, or by a medical or nursing student under the direct supervision of a licensed physician or registered nurse, or by a Director acting upon a licensed physician’s instructions. The attending physician shall review on a regular basis the drug regimen of each individual under his or her care. All prescriptions for psychotropic medications shall be written with a termination date, which shall not exceed 30 days. Medication shall not be used as a punishment, for the convenience of staff, as a substitute for programs, or in quantities that interfere with the individual’s habilitation program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
