<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1303.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1303.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1303_04">
        <akn:num>7-1303.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Petition for commitment of individual 14 years of age or older filed by parent or guardian or by the District.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1303_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A written petition by a parent or guardian may be filed with the Court to have an individual 14 years of age or older, who is or is believed to have an intellectual disability, committed to a facility. Upon the filing of such petition, the Court shall promptly conduct a hearing in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter IV of this chapter. If the Court determines that the individual is competent to refuse such commitment and the individual so refuses, the Court shall dismiss the petition and order that the individual not be committed to a facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1303_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, on a petition filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Court determines that the individual is not competent to refuse commitment, the Court shall determine whether to order the commitment. The Court shall order the commitment only if it determines beyond a reasonable doubt that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1303_04_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For an individual found incompetent in a criminal case, a written petition by the District may be filed with the Court to have the individual committed to a facility. Upon the filing of the petition, the Court shall promptly conduct a hearing in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter IV of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1303_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The facility, its sponsoring agency, or the Department on Disability Services shall provide a written certification to the Court, before commitment to the facility is ordered, that the habilitation indicated by the individual habitation plan will be implemented.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
