<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1305.07a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1305.07a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1305_07a">
        <akn:num>7-1305.07a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Health-care decisions policy, annual plan, and quarterly reports.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_07a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be the policy of the District government to ensure that all persons who become incapable of making or communicating health-care decisions for themselves have available health-care decision-makers. In addition, it shall be the policy of DDS to ensure that every individual served by DDS has the opportunity to execute a durable power of attorney pursuant to ยง 21-2205, and has one or more individuals identified as reasonably available, mentally capable, and willing to provide substituted consent pursuant to ยง 21-2210, if the individual were to become certified as incapacitated to make a health-care decision in accordance with ยง 21-2204.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_07a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The DDS Administrator shall issue by November 1 of each year an annual plan describing how DDS will comply with subsection (a) of this section during the current fiscal year. The plan shall include data from the prior fiscal year for assessing the current and potential health-care decision-making needs of all individuals served by DDS. The plan shall include, at a minimum:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_07a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The DDS Administrator shall produce a quarterly report on all substituted consent activities pursuant to subsection (a) of this section until October 2010. Quarterly reports shall be complete by the 15th day of October, January, April, and July and shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_07a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1305_07a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring any person to execute a durable power of attorney for health care.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
