<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1531.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1531.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1531_01">
        <akn:num>7-1531.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adult” means an individual who is at least 18 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agent” means an individual:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Anatomical gift” means a donation of all or part of a human body to take effect after the donor’s death for the purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Decedent” means a deceased individual whose body or part is or may be the source of an anatomical gift. The term “decedent” includes a stillborn infant and, subject to restrictions imposed by law other than this subchapter, a fetus.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Disinterested witness” means a witness other than the spouse, domestic partner, child, parent, sibling, grandchild, grandparent, or guardian of the individual who makes, amends, revokes, or refuses to make an anatomical gift, or another adult who exhibited special care and concern for the individual. The term “disinterested witness” does not include a person to which an anatomical gift could pass under § 7-1531.10. An individual is not disqualified from being a disinterested witness solely because the individual is employed by a transplant hospital.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Document of gift” means a donor card or other record used to make an anatomical gift. The term “document of gift” includes a statement or symbol on a driver’s license, identification card, or donor registry.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 32-701(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Donor” means an individual whose body or part is the subject of an anatomical gift.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Donor registry” means a database that contains records of anatomical gifts and amendments to or revocations of anatomical gifts. The term “donor registry” includes the Registry.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Driver’s license” means a license or permit issued by the Department of Motor Vehicles to operate a vehicle, whether or not conditions are attached to the license or permit. The term “driver’s license” includes a learner’s permit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eye bank” means a person that is licensed, accredited, or regulated under federal or state law to engage in the recovery, screening, testing, processing, storage, or distribution of human eyes or portions of human eyes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Guardian” means a person appointed by a court to make decisions regarding the support, care, education, health, or welfare of an individual. The term “guardian” does not include a guardian ad litem, unless the guardian ad litem is expressly authorized by a court to consent to a donation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hospice” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 44-501(a)(6).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hospital” means a facility licensed as a hospital under the law of any state or a facility operated as a hospital by the United States, a state, or a subdivision of a state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Identification card” means a special identification card issued by the Department of Motor Vehicles pursuant to 18 DCMR § 112.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Know” means to have actual knowledge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Minor” means an individual who is under 18 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Organ procurement organization” means a person designated by the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services as an organ procurement organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Parent” means a parent whose parental rights have not been terminated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Part” means an organ, an eye, or tissue of a human being. The term “part” does not include the whole body.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Physician” means an individual authorized to practice medicine or osteopathy under the law of any state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Procurement organization” means an eye bank, organ procurement organization, or tissue bank.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prospective donor” means an individual who is dead or whose death is imminent and has been determined by a procurement organization to have a part that could be medically suitable for transplantation, therapy, research, or education. The term “prospective donor” does not include an individual who has made a refusal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reasonably available” means able to be contacted by a procurement organization without undue effort and willing and able to act in a timely manner consistent with existing medical criteria necessary for the making of an anatomical gift.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Recipient” means an individual into whose body a decedent’s part has been or is intended to be transplanted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Refusal” means a record created under § 7-1531.06 that expressly states an intent to bar other persons from making an anatomical gift of an individual’s body or part. The term “refusal” does not include a revocation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registry” means the organ and tissue donor registry for the District of Columbia established by § 7-1531.19.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Revocation” means the cancellation of an anatomical gift that was made previously. The term “revocation” does not include a refusal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sign” means, with the present intent to authenticate or adopt a record:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Technician” means an individual determined to be qualified to remove or process parts by an appropriate organization that is licensed, accredited, or regulated under federal or state law. The term “technician” includes an enucleator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tissue” means a portion of the human body other than an organ or an eye. The term “tissue” does not include blood unless the blood is donated for the purpose of research or education.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tissue bank” means a person that is licensed, accredited, or regulated under federal or state law to engage in the recovery, screening, testing, processing, storage, or distribution of tissue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1531_01_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transplant hospital” means a hospital that furnishes organ transplants and other medical and surgical specialty services required for the care of transplant patients.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
