<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1703"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1703/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1703">
        <akn:num>7-1703</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Smoking restrictions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any elevator, except in a single-family dwelling;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any public selling area of a retail store, except in a tobacco shop or store primarily concerned with selling tobacco and smoking equipment;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any public assembly or hearing room which is owned or leased by any branch, agency, or instrumentality of the District of Columbia government; this subsection shall not apply to the District of Columbia National Guard Armory or to the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any educational facility except as provided in ยง 7-1702(1);</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>While transporting passengers within the corporate limits of the District of Columbia, any passenger vehicle owned or operated by the District of Columbia government, or any passenger vehicle for hire regulated under ยง 47-2829;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any area of a health care facility frequented by the general public, including hallways, waiting rooms and lobbies. The operator of a health care facility may designate separate areas as smoking areas.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any restaurant except as permitted in ยง 7-1703.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any public or private workplace, except as provided in ยง 7-1703.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a playground or public recreational facility or while sitting or standing within 25 feet of the property line of a playground or public recreational facility when another person is present; provided, that the following shall be exempt from this prohibition:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1703_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a bus stop or while sitting or standing within 25 feet of a posted bus stop sign located at any bus stop controlled or maintained by the District when another person is present; provided, that the following shall be exempt from this prohibition:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
