<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1704"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1704/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1704">
        <akn:num>7-1704</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>“No Smoking” signs.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1704_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any place, elevator, or vehicle in which smoking is prohibited, the owner, manager, or person in charge of the place, elevator, or vehicle shall post or cause to be posted signs that read, “No Smoking Under Penalty of Law”, “No Smoking Except in Smoking Areas”, or “Smoking in Accordance With Employer’s Smoking Policy Only”. In any place, elevator, or vehicle where smoking is restricted, the sign shall include the following warning: “Smoking causes lung cancer, heart disease, emphysema, and may cause fetal injury, premature birth, and low birth weight in pregnant women.” Signs posted shall clearly state the maximum fine for a violation of this subchapter. Signs shall be visible to the public at the entrance to the area and on the interior of the area in sufficient number in a manner that gives notice to the public of the applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1704_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a public recreational facility, the Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation shall post or cause to be posted signs that read “No Smoking. Need to quit? Contact the D.C. Quitline at 1-800-Quit-Now (784-8669).”</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1704_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a private playground, the owner, manager, or individual or entity responsible for maintaining the private playground shall post or cause to be posted signs that read “No Smoking. Need to quit? Contact the D.C. Quitline at 1-800-Quit-Now (784-8669).”</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1704_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where smoking is prohibited pursuant to this subchapter all signs posted shall include the internationally recognized no smoking symbol. Where smoking is restricted pursuant to this subchapter all signs posted shall include the internationally recognized smoking symbol.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1704_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful for any person to obscure, remove, deface, mutilate, or destroy any sign posted in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
