<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1811.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1811.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1811_03">
        <akn:num>7-1811.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Allocation of funds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1811_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1811_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds of the Fund shall be used as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1811_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The R13BA fund, including all accrued interest, shall be used as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1811_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of financing the costs of the National Capital Medical Center, healthcare related issues, or other capital projects, and repayment of outstanding indebtedness issued for certain capital projects and other undertakings of the District, the Fund may sell to the Corporation all of the Fund’s right, title, and interest in and to the Residual Bond, including all the moneys, and any interest thereon, payable to or received by the Fund, in exchange for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1811_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the authorization and restrictions of this subchapter, the terms and conditions of the Residual Bond Purchase Agreement shall be determined by the Mayor, which determination shall be conclusively evidenced by his execution of the Residual Bond Purchase Agreement. The Mayor may execute and deliver any administrative or other documents or agreements that are necessary or desirable relating to the sale of the Fund’s right, title, and interest in and to the Residual Bond or in connection with the issuance of the Bonds. Proceeds from the sale of the Bonds and other moneys received by the Corporation pursuant to the Residual Bond Purchase Agreement shall be used to repay certain outstanding indebtedness of the District, to finance or refinance the National Capital Medical Center, healthcare related issues, or other capital projects or undertakings of the District, to pay costs of issuance of the Bonds, to establish and fund reserve funds, and to pay other expenses and fees related to the issuance of the Bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
