<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1831.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1831.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1831_03">
        <akn:num>7-1831.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the District of Columbia Tobacco Settlement Financing Corporation; powers and authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Tobacco Settlement Financing Corporation is established as a special purpose, independent instrumentality of the District government. The Corporation shall be a corporate body, intended, created, and empowered to effectuate the purposes stated in this subchapter, and shall have a legal existence separate from the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The purpose of the Corporation is to purchase all of the District’s right, title, and interest in the Master Settlement Agreement, including all the moneys, and any interest thereon, payable to or received by the District thereunder (except for the first payment of $16.05 million which has already been received by the District) and the Residual Bond, issuing Bonds to pay the purchase price therefor, and to repay certain of the outstanding indebtedness of the District issued for capital projects and other undertakings. The Corporation may enter into the Purchase Agreement or the Residual Bond Purchase Agreement  and may perform any acts necessary or convenient to effectuate its purposes, including financing the costs of the National Capital Medical Center indebtedness of the District, to finance or refinance the National Capital Medical Center, healthcare related issues, or other capital projects or undertakings of the District, or other capital projects, repayment, refinancing, or defeasance of certain indebtedness issued for capital projects and other undertakings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other powers or authority conferred by this section or subchapter, the Corporation shall have all the powers of a corporate body under the laws of the District to the extent not inconsistent with or restricted by the provisions of this section or subchapter, including the power to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All operating and administrative expenses of the Corporation and costs of issuance of the Bonds shall be paid by the Corporation out of payments received by the Corporation under the Master Settlement Agreement and from the proceeds of the Bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the request of the Corporation, the Mayor and the governing officer or body of each instrumentality of the District, by delegation, contract, or agreement, may direct that personnel or other resources of a District department, office, agency, establishment, or instrumentality be made available to the Corporation on a full cost reimbursable basis to carry out the Corporation’s duties. Personnel detailed to the Corporation under this subsection shall not be considered employees of the Corporation, but shall remain employees of the department, agency, establishment, or instrumentality from which the employees were detailed. With the consent of an executive agency, department, or independent agency of the federal government or the District government, the Corporation may use the information, services, staff, and facilities of the department or agency on a full cost reimbursable basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All assets and income of the Corporation shall be exempt from District taxation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Corporation shall have the same fiscal year as the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An independent accountant, appointed by the board of directors of the Corporation, shall conduct an annual audit of the accounts and records of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No District laws, rules, or orders governing procurement or administrative procedures or personnel shall apply to the Corporation, its activities, board members, officers, or employees, except as otherwise provided for in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1831_03_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
