<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1803.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1803.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1803_05">
        <akn:num>7-1803.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reporting of information; escrow installments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1803_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 20 calendar days after the end of each calendar quarter, and more frequently if so directed by the Mayor, each Wholesaler shall submit such information as the Mayor requires to facilitate compliance with this part, including a list, by Brand Family, of the total number of cigarettes, or, in the case of roll your own, the equivalent stick count, for which the Wholesaler affixed stamps during the previous calendar quarter or otherwise paid the tax due for such cigarettes. The Wholesaler shall maintain, and make available to the Mayor, all invoices and documentation of sales of all Non-Participating Manufacturer cigarettes and any other information relied upon in reporting to the Mayor for a period of 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1803_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Attorney General is authorized to disclose any information to the Mayor received under this part and requested by the Mayor for purposes of determining compliance with and enforcing the provisions of this part. The Attorney General and the Mayor shall share with each other the information received under this part, and may share such information with other federal, state, District, or local agencies only for purposes of enforcement of this part, part A of this subchapter, or corresponding laws of other jurisdictions. The Attorney General may also disclose the information received under this part with the data clearinghouse created to implement the term sheet agreed to by the District and Participating Manufacturers, and given effect by a March 12, 2013, arbitral award.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1803_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may require, at any time, from the Non-Participating Manufacturer, proof from the financial institution in which the Manufacturer has established a Qualified Escrow Fund, for the purpose of compliance with ยง 7-1801.02(2), of the amount of money in the fund, exclusive of interest, the amount and date of each deposit to the fund, and the amount and date of each withdrawal from the fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1803_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the information required to be submitted pursuant to this part, the Mayor may require a Wholesaler or Tobacco Product Manufacturer to submit any additional information, including samples of the packaging or labeling of each Brand Family, as is necessary to enable the Mayor to determine whether a Tobacco Product Manufacturer is in compliance with this part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1803_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To promote compliance with this part, the Mayor may promulgate regulations requiring a Tobacco Product Manufacturer, subject to the requirements of ยง 7-1803.03(a)(2), to make the escrow deposits required in quarterly installments during the year in which the sales covered by such deposits are made. The Mayor may require production of information sufficient to enable the Mayor to determine the adequacy of the amount of the installment deposit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
