<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1905"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-1905/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_1905">
        <akn:num>7-1905</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Provision of protective services.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the availability of resources, the Department may provide protective services if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an adult in need of protective services due to abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation objects to the provision of particular services and it does not manifestly appear to the APS worker that the adult is incapacitated or that the objection is prompted by fear or intimidation instilled by another, the adult shall be entitled to refuse those services and this right of refusal shall be fully respected.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any case under this section involving abuse, neglect, or exploitation by a third party that does not meet the requirements of subsection (a)(1) of this section, the Department or other agency designated by the Mayor may provide protective services only after the Attorney General obtains a protection order pursuant to ยง 7-1906 or ยง 7-1907.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any case under this section involving self-neglect, if an APS worker has good cause to believe that an adult is incapacitated, the APS worker, the Department, or the Attorney General may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In accordance with procedures to be established under ยง 7-1909(1), the Mayor shall ensure that, when appropriate, an APS worker is accompanied by a police officer while providing protective services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When determining the appropriateness of particular services, the Department or other designated agency shall first consider those protective services that encourage maximum self-determination and are least restrictive of personal liberty.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-1905_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No provision of subsections (a-1) or (c-1) of this section shall be construed to create an entitlement (either direct or implied) on the part of any individual or family to any services under this chapter for an adult who meets the criteria for self-neglect or who is determined to be at risk due to self-neglect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
