<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2071.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2071.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2071_02">
        <akn:num>7-2071.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Health Care Ombudsman Program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall establish the Health Care Ombudsman Program by contracting with a qualified private, community-based, nonprofit corporation, organization, or consortia of organizations, with offices located in the District, to operate the program. If the Department is unable to contract with a qualified corporation, organization, or consortia of organizations that meets the requirements of subsection (c) of this section, the Department shall operate the Ombudsman Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman Program shall be administered by the Health Care Ombudsman, who shall be appointed by the Director of the Department. The Health Care Ombudsman shall be an individual with management experience and substantive experience in the fields of health care, health benefits plans, or health care advocacy. Unless the Department is operating the program, the Health Care Ombudsman shall be an employee of the nonprofit corporation, organization, or consortia of organizations selected by the Department to operate the program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall establish selection criteria for the qualified, private, nonprofit corporation, organization, or consortia of organizations that will perform the functions of the Ombudsman Program. The criteria shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman Program may subcontract with advocacy organizations that are affiliated with health providers that exclusively represent the interests of consumers and do not represent the health care entity in any disputes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall accord preference in the selection process to corporations or organizations that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman Program may use volunteers with appropriate training and supervision to assist with counseling, outreach, and other tasks.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
