<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2071.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2071.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2071_01">
        <akn:num>7-2071.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Accessible” means providing:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Consumer” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Health.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health benefits plan” means a group or individual insurance policy or contract, medical or hospital service agreement, membership or subscription contract, or similar group arrangement provided by an insurer, or subcontracting facility of an insurer, or an employer for the purpose of providing, paying for, or reimbursing expenses for health-related services. The term “health benefits plan” shall include health coverage provided through a government program, including Medicaid. The term “health benefits plan” shall not include disability income or accident-only insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health Care Ombudsman” or “Ombudsman” means the individual responsible for running the Health Care Ombudsman Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health Care Ombudsman Program” or “Ombudsman Program” means the program established by the District to counsel and assist uninsured District residents and individuals insured by health benefits plans in the District regarding matters pertaining to their health care coverage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2071_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health care services” means items or services provided under the supervision of a physician or other person trained or licensed to render health care necessary for the prevention, care, diagnosis, or treatment of human disease, pain, injury, deformity, or other physical or mental condition, including the following: pre-admission, outpatient, inpatient, and post-discharge care; home care; physician’s care; nursing care; medical care provided by interns or residents in training; other paramedical care; ambulance service and care; bed and board; drugs; supplies; appliances; equipment; laboratory services; any form of diagnostic imaging or therapeutic radiological services; and services mandated under Chapter 31 of Title 31.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
