<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-210"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-210/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_210">
        <akn:num>7-210</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>New certificates of birth for adoption and determination of parentage.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Registrar shall establish a new certificate of birth for a person born in the District, upon receipt of one of the following documents:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Registrar shall not establish a new certificate of birth if so requested by the adoptive parents pursuant to ยง 16-314(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The actual place and date of birth shall be shown on a new certificate of birth. The new certificate shall be substituted for the original certificate of birth in the files. The new certificate shall nowhere on its face show that parentage has been established by judicial process or by acknowledgement. The original certificate of birth and the evidence of adoption, parentage determination, or parentage acknowledgement shall not be subject to inspection; except, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certificate of birth shall be amended upon receipt of an adoption form concerning an amended decree of adoption. The Registrar shall issue regulations to govern amendment of certificates of birth.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Registrar shall restore the original certificate of birth to its place in the files upon receipt of the report or decree of invalidation of adoption. The new certificate and evidence shall not be subject to inspection except upon order of the Court or as provided by regulations implementing this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If no certificate of birth is on file for the person for whom a new birth certificate is to be established under this section, and the date and place of birth have not been determined in the adoption or parentage proceedings, a delayed certificate of birth shall be filed with the Registrar under ยง 7-207 or  ยง 7-208 before a new certificate of birth is established. The new birth certificate shall be prepared on the delayed birth certificate form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-210_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each copy of the original certificate of birth shall be sealed from inspection when a new certificate of birth is established.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
