<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-217"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-217/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_217">
        <akn:num>7-217</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Amendment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-217_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Registrar shall issue regulations governing amendment of vital records, which shall protect the integrity and accuracy of the vital records. A certificate, or report registered under this chapter may be amended only in accordance with this chapter and regulations issued under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-217_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a certificate or report that is amended under this section shall be marked “amended”. The date of amendment and a summary description of the evidence submitted in support of the  amendment shall be endorsed on or made a part of the records. The Registrar shall issue regulations which prescribe the conditions under which additions or minor corrections may be made to certificates, or reports, within 1 year after the date of the event without the certificate or record being marked “amended”.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-217_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a certified copy of an order of a court of competent jurisdiction changing the name of a person born in the District and upon request of such person, his or her guardian or legal representative, or, in the case of a minor, his or her parents, the Registrar shall amend the certificate of birth to show the new name.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-217_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-217_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Registrar shall not amend the vital record if: (1) an applicant does not submit the minimum documentation required in the regulations for amending a vital record; or (2) when the Registrar has reasonable cause to question the validity or adequacy of the applicant’s sworn statements or the documentary evidence, and the deficiencies are not corrected. The Registrar shall state in writing the reason for this action. Upon the Registrar’s refusal to amend the vital record, the applicant shall have a cause of action in the Court to amend the vital record. The Registrar shall give the applicant written notice of this right.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
