<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-214"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-214/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_214">
        <akn:num>7-214</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Final disposition of dead body or fetus.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funeral director or person acting as such or person who first assumes custody of a dead body, before he or she may dispose of the body, must have: (1) Authorization for final disposition of the body from the next of kin; and (2) a death certificate. If the body is to be cremated, authorization for cremation must also be obtained from the Medical Examiner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before final disposition of a dead fetus, regardless of the duration of pregnancy, the funeral director, the person in charge of the institution, or other person responsible for final disposition of the fetus, shall get authorization from the next of kin for final disposition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A dead body shall be removed from the place of death for the purpose of being prepared for final disposition only under the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Authorization for final disposition of a dead body or fetus brought into the District, issued by another state and accompanying the dead body or fetus, is sufficient authority for final disposition in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A sexton or person in charge of a place for interment or other disposition of dead bodies may not inter or allow interment or other disposition of a dead body or fetus unless it is accompanied by authorization for final disposition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each person in charge of a place for final disposition shall include the date of disposition in the authorization and shall sign and return the authorization to the funeral director or person acting as the funeral director, within 10 days after the date of disposition. Where there is no person in charge of the place for final disposition, the funeral director or his or her designee shall endorse the authorization. At the close of each calendar month the funeral director or the person acting as the funeral director shall transmit to the Mayor all endorsed authorizations received during the month.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-214_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Authorization for disinterment and reinterment is required before disinterment of a dead body or fetus. The authorization may be issued by the Registrar to a licensed funeral director or person acting as such, upon proper application.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
