<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-222"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-222/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_222">
        <akn:num>7-222</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Persons required to keep records.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-222_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person in charge of an institution shall keep a record of personal data concerning each person admitted or confined to their institution. This record shall only include such information as required under this chapter for completion of certificates of birth and death and the reports of fetal death. The person being admitted or confined shall provide the information at the time of admission. If that person is unable to provide the necessary information, a relative or other person familiar with the pertinent facts shall supply the information. The record shall include the name and address of the person providing the information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-222_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a dead body or dead fetus is released or disposed of by an institution, the person in charge of the institution shall keep a record showing the name of the decedent, date of death, name and address of the person to whom the body or fetus is released, and the date of removal from the institution. If final disposition is made by the institution, the date, place, and manner of disposition shall also be recorded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-222_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A funeral director, embalmer, sexton, or other person who removes from the place of death, transports, or makes final disposition of a dead body or fetus, shall keep a record that identifies the body, and includes information pertaining to his or her receipt, removal, delivery, burial, or cremation of such body as may be required by regulations. This requirement supplements any other filing or reporting requirement imposed by this chapter or regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-222_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Records maintained under this section shall be retained for not less than 5 years and shall be made available for inspection by the Registrar according to regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
