<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2306"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2306/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2306">
        <akn:num>7-2306</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duration of emergency executive order; extension; publication of order; regional programs and agreements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2306_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An emergency executive order, or a public health emergency executive order, issued by the Mayor shall be effective for a period of no more than 15 calendar days from the day it is signed by the Mayor, but may be rescinded in whole or in part by the Mayor within that period should the Mayor determine that the public emergency no longer exists, or no longer warrants the part rescinded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2306_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An emergency executive order, or a public health emergency executive order, may be extended for up to an additional 15-day period, only upon request by the Mayor for, and the adoption of, an emergency act by the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2306_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Should extenuating circumstances, such as death, destruction or other perilous conditions prohibit the convening of at least two-thirds of the members of the Council of the District of Columbia for consideration of emergency legislation, the Mayor shall make a reasonable attempt to consult with those members of the Council of the District of Columbia not affected by death, destruction, or other perilous conditions, after which the Mayor may extend the emergency executive order for up to 15 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2306_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the issuance of any emergency executive order, or a public health emergency executive order, as soon as practicable given the condition of the emergency, the order shall be published in the District of Columbia Register, in 2 daily newspapers of general circulation in the District of Columbia, and shall be posted in such public places in the District of Columbia as the Mayor determines by regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2306_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may adopt and implement such rules and regulations as the Mayor finds necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, pursuant to the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (ยง 2-501 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2306_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may join or enter into, on behalf of the District of Columbia government, regional programs, and agreements with the federal government, neighboring states, and political subdivisions thereof, for the coordination of disaster preparedness programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
