<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2341.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2341.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2341_04">
        <akn:num>7-2341.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Emergency medical response vehicles: license or certification required.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, no ambulance or other emergency medical response vehicle intended to transport patients may be operated in the District without a currently valid license having been issued by the Mayor for that vehicle and for its use as an emergency medical response vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, no vehicle or other conveyance may be operated as an emergency medical response vehicle not intended to transport patients in the District without a currently valid certification having been issued by the Mayor for the emergency medical response equipment and supplies contained therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for a license or certification to operate an emergency medical response vehicle shall establish to the satisfaction of the Mayor that the vehicle, including its emergency medical response equipment and supplies, meets all applicable requirements set forth in this chapter and in rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for a license or certification shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No license for an emergency medical response vehicle intended to transport patients shall be issued unless the Mayor finds that the vehicle is, and will be at all times when in such use, in compliance with all applicable laws and ordinances relating to health, sanitation, and safety.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No ground emergency medical response vehicle shall be operated to transport patients in the District unless it is staffed by at least 2 persons, each of whom is certified pursuant to this chapter and to rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter at a level equal to or greater than a basic emergency medical technician.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No air or water emergency medical response vehicle shall be operated to transport patients in the District unless it is staffed by at least 2 persons, one of whom is a validly licensed pilot and the other of whom is certified pursuant to this chapter and to rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter at a level equal to or greater than an intermediate emergency medical technician or a paramedic.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A license or certification for the operation of an emergency medical response vehicle shall be issued for a period of time not to exceed one year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_04_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A license or certification for the operation of an emergency medical response vehicle shall be valid only for the persons and vehicle named as applicants in the application. No emergency medical response vehicle license or certification shall be sold, transferred, or assigned without the approval of the Mayor. Approval may be granted only upon a demonstration that the vehicle and its operation will conform to all licensing or certification requirements set forth in this chapter and in rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
