<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2361.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2361.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2361_01">
        <akn:num>7-2361.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Disaster relief organization” means an entity that provides emergency or disaster relief services that include health or veterinary services provided by volunteer health practitioners and that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emergency” means an event or condition that is a public emergency, as defined by § 7-2301(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emergency declaration” means a declaration of emergency issued by a person authorized to do so under the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emergency Management Assistance Compact” means the interstate compact approved by Congress by the Joint Resolution Granting the consent of Congress to the Emergency Management Assistance Compact, approved October 19, 1996 (Pub. L. No. 104-321; 110 Stat. 3877) [see also D.C. Code § 7-2332].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Entity” means a person other than an individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health facility” means an entity licensed under the laws of this or another state to provide health or veterinary services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health practitioner” means an individual licensed under the laws of this or another state to provide health or veterinary services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health services” means the provision of treatment, care, advice or guidance, or other services, or supplies, related to the health or death of individuals, or human populations, to the extent necessary to respond to an emergency, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Host entity” means an entity operating in the District that uses volunteer health practitioners to respond to an emergency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“License” means authorization by a state to engage in health or veterinary services that are unlawful without the authorization. The term includes authorization under the laws of the District to an individual to provide health or veterinary services based upon a national certification issued by a public or private entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity. The term “person” includes the government of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registration system” means a system for registering volunteer health practitioners that meets the requirements in § 7-2361.04.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Scope of practice” means the extent of the authorization to provide health or veterinary services granted to a health practitioner by a license issued to the practitioner in the state in which the principal part of the practitioner’s services are rendered, including any conditions imposed by the licensing authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Veterinary services” means the provision of treatment, care, advice or guidance, or other services, or supplies, related to the health or death of an animal or to animal populations, to the extent necessary to respond to an emergency, including the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2361_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Volunteer health practitioner” means a health practitioner who provides health or veterinary services, whether or not the practitioner receives compensation for those services, including an employee of the federal government. The term “volunteer health practitioner” does not include a practitioner who receives compensation pursuant to a preexisting employment relationship with a host entity or affiliate that requires the practitioner to provide health services in the District, unless the practitioner is employed by a disaster relief organization while an emergency declaration is in effect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
