<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2332"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2332/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2332">
        <akn:num>7-2332</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authority to execute Compact.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_I">
      <akn:num>I</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose and Authorities</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_II">
      <akn:num>II</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>General Implementation</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_III">
      <akn:num>III</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Party State Responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_IV">
      <akn:num>IV</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Limitations</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_V">
      <akn:num>V</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Licenses and Permits Whenever any person holds a license, certificate, or other permit issued by any state party to the compact evidencing the meeting of qualifications for professional, mechanical, or other skills, and when such assistance is requested by the receiving party state, such person shall be deemed licensed, certified, or permitted by the state requesting assistance to render aid involving such skill to meet a declared emergency or disaster, subject to such limitations and conditions as the Governor of the requesting state, or Mayor of the District of Columbia, may prescribe by executive order or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_VI">
      <akn:num>VI</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Liability Officers or employees of a party state rendering aid in another state pursuant to this compact shall be considered agents of the requesting state for tort liability and immunity purposes. No party state or its officers or employees rendering aid in another state pursuant to this compact shall be liable on account of any act or omission in good faith on the part of such forces while so engaged or on account of the maintenance or use of any equipment or supplies in connection therewith. Good faith in this article shall not include willful misconduct, gross negligence, or recklessness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_VII">
      <akn:num>VII</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Supplementary Agreements Inasmuch as it is probable that the pattern and detail of the machinery for mutual aid among two or more states may differ from that among the states that are party hereto, this compact contains elements of a broad base common to all states, and nothing herein contained shall preclude any state from entering into supplementary agreements with another state or affect any other agreements already in force between states. Supplementary agreements may comprehend, but shall not be limited to, provisions for evacuation and reception of injured and other persons and the exchange of medical, fire, police, public utility, reconnaissance, welfare, transportation and communications personnel, and equipment and supplies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_VIII">
      <akn:num>VIII</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Compensation Each party state shall provide for the payment of compensation and death benefits to injured members of the emergency forces of that state and representatives of deceased members of such forces in case such members sustain injuries or are killed while rendering aid pursuant to this compact, in the same manner and on the same terms as if the injury or death were sustained within their own state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_IX">
      <akn:num>IX</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reimbursement Any party state rendering aid in another state pursuant to this compact shall be reimbursed by the party state receiving such aid for any loss or damage to or expense incurred in the operation of any equipment and the provisions of any service in answering a request for aid and for the costs incurred in connection with such requests; provided, that any aiding party state may assume in whole or in part such loss, damage, expense, or other cost, or may loan such equipment or donate such services to the receiving party state without charge or cost; and provided further, that any two or more party states may enter into supplementary agreements establishing a different allocation of costs among those states. Article VII expenses shall not be reimbursable under this article.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_X">
      <akn:num>X</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Evacuation Plans for the orderly evacuation and interstate reception of portions of the civilian population as the result of any emergency or disaster of sufficient proportions to so warrant, shall be worked out and maintained between the party states and the emergency management/services directors of the various jurisdictions where any type of incident requiring evacuations might occur. Such plans shall be put into effect by request of the state from which evacuees come and shall include the manner of transporting such evacuees, the number of evacuees to be received in different areas, the manner in which food, clothing, housing, and medical care will be provided, the registration of evacuees, the providing of facilities for the notification of relatives or friends, and the forwarding of such evacuees to other areas or the bringing in of additional materials, supplies, and all other relevant factors. Such plans shall provide that the party state receiving evacuees and the party state from which the evacuees come shall mutually agree as to reimbursement of out-of-pocket expenses incurred in receiving and caring for such evacuees, for expenditures for transportation, food, clothing, medicines and medical care, and the like items. Such expenditures shall be reimbursed as agreed by the party state from which the evacuees come. After the termination of the emergency or disaster, the party state from which the evacuees come shall assume the responsibility for the ultimate support of repatriation of such evacuees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_XI">
      <akn:num>XI</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Implementation</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_XII">
      <akn:num>XII</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Validity This compact shall be construed to effectuate the purposes stated in Article I hereof. If any provisions of this compact is declared unconstitutional, or the applicability thereof to any person or circumstances is held invalid, the constitutionality of the remainder of this compact and the applicability thereof to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_XIII">
      <akn:num>XIII</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Additional Provisions Nothing in this compact shall authorize or permit the use of military force by the National Guard of a state at any place outside that state in any emergency for which the President is authorized by law to call into federal service the militia, of [sic  ] for any purpose for which the use of the Army or the Air Force would in the absence of express statutory authorization be prohibited under § 1385 of Title 18 of the United States Code  .</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2332_XIV">
      <akn:num>XIV</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>District of Columbia Provisions</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
