<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2341.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2341.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2341_07">
        <akn:num>7-2341.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Emergency medical services training facilities: certification required.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, no person or entity shall operate an emergency medical services training facility in the District, whether public or private, for-profit or not-for-profit, without first having obtained a certification from the Mayor to do so.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for a certification to operate an emergency medical services training facility shall establish to the satisfaction of the Mayor that the facility meets all requirements set forth in this chapter and in rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for a certification shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certification to operate an emergency medical services training facility shall be issued for a period of time not to exceed 2 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certification to operate an emergency medical services training facility shall be valid only for the persons and premises named as applicants in the application. Any change in the ownership of a facility owned by an individual, partnership, or association, or in the legal or beneficial ownership of 25% or more of the stock of a corporation that owns or operates a facility, shall require recertification.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An emergency medical services training facility shall conform to curriculum and competency evaluation standards as developed by the Mayor. The Mayor may adopt nationally recognized standards or develop standards specific to the emergency medical services needs of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2341_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An emergency medical services training facility shall have a medical director. Except as provided in §§ 5-401, 5-402, 5-404, 5-404.01, and 5-407, an emergency medical services training facility shall have as its medical director a physician licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia. The medical director shall have responsibility for medical oversight of all operations of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
