<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2504.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2504.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2504_03">
        <akn:num>7-2504.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Issuance of dealer’s license; time period; corrections.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2504_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a properly executed application for a dealer’s license, or renewal thereof, the Chief, upon determining through further inquiry, investigation, or otherwise, that the applicant is entitled and qualified under the provisions of this unit thereto, shall issue a dealer’s license. Each dealer’s license shall be in duplicate and bear a unique dealer’s license number, and such other information as the Chief determines is necessary to identify the applicant and premises. The duplicate of the dealer’s license shall be delivered to the applicant and the Chief shall retain the original.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2504_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief shall approve or deny an application for a registration certificate within a 60-day period beginning on the date the Chief receives the application, unless good cause is shown, including nonreceipt of information from sources outside the District government. The Chief may hold in abeyance an application where there is any firearms revocation proceeding pending against such person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2504_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a dealer’s license, each applicant shall examine the same to ensure that the information thereon is correct. If the dealer’s license is incorrect in any respect, the person named thereon shall return the same to the Chief with a signed statement showing the nature of the error. The Chief shall correct the error, if it occurred through administrative error. In the event the error resulted from information contained in the application, the applicant shall be required to file an amended application explaining the error in the original application. Each amended application shall be accompanied by a fee equal to that required for the original application.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2504_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event the Chief learns of an error in a dealer’s license, other than as provided in subsection (c) of this section, he may require the holder to return the dealer’s license for correction. If the error resulted from information contained in the application, the person named therein shall be required to file an amended application as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2504_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each dealer’s license issued by the Chief shall be accompanied by a statement setting forth a dealer’s duties under this unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
