<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2531.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2531.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2531_02">
        <akn:num>7-2531.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Liability.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any manufacturer, importer, or dealer of a firearm who can be shown by a preponderance of the evidence to have knowingly and willfully engaged in the illegal sale of a firearm shall be held strictly liable in tort, without regard to fault and without regard to either: (1) an intent to interfere with a legally protected interest; or (2) a breach of duty to exercise reasonable care, for all direct and consequential damages that arise from bodily injury or death if the bodily injury or death proximately results from the discharge of the firearm in the District of Columbia, regardless of whether or not the person operating the firearm is the original, illegal purchaser.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual who can be shown by a preponderance of the evidence to have knowingly and willfully engaged in the illegal sale, loan, lease, or rental of a firearm for money or anything of value shall be held strictly liable in tort, without regard to fault and without regard to either: (1) an intent to interfere with a legally protected interest; or (2) a breach of duty to exercise reasonable care, for all direct and consequential damages that arise from bodily injury or death if the bodily injury or death proximately results from the discharge of the firearm in the District of Columbia regardless of whether or not the person operating the firearm is the original, illegal purchaser.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this unit shall relieve from liability any person who commits a crime, is negligent, or who might otherwise be liable for acts committed with the firearm.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
