<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2531.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-2531.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_2531_04">
        <akn:num>7-2531.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Firearms Bounty Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a fund to be known as the Firearms Bounty Fund (“Fund”) to be administered by the Metropolitan Police Department. The Fund shall be operated as a proprietary fund and shall consist of monies appropriated to the Fund, federal grants to the Fund, or private monies donated to the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Disbursements from the Fund shall be used exclusively for the payment of cash rewards to persons who provide District of Columbia law enforcement agencies with tips that lead to the adjudication or conviction of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount of each cash reward shall be determined at the discretion of the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department and the cash reward may range up to $100,000 per tip.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department shall report annually to the Mayor and Council all income and expenditures of the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, by a proposed notice to the Council, may terminate the Fund if the Mayor determines that the Fund is no longer necessary to pay cash rewards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If monies exist in the Fund at the time of its termination, the monies shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-2531_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proposed notice to terminate the Fund shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove by resolution within the 45-day review period, the proposed notice to terminate the Fund shall be deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
