<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-3004"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-3004/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_3004">
        <akn:num>7-3004</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Addiction Recovery Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-3004_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-3004_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established within the Fund a segregated account to be known as the ATR Account, into which shall be deposited the federal grant funds awarded to APRA for ATR, to be expended solely for the purposes of ATR, in accordance with federal requirements and regulations promulgated to implement this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-3004_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the Fund shall be used only for payments directly to treatment providers. The Fund shall be the sole source for payments to treatment providers under the Drug Treatment Choice Program. APRA shall administer the Drug Treatment Choice Program and the Fund from APRA’s appropriated operating budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-3004_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 18 months of July 18, 2000, APRA shall develop a plan to incorporate all APRA funding for substance abuse treatment services into the Fund. APRA may propose to continue then existing contracts and grants upon a finding that the Program would not serve the specific needs of a particular clientele or group.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-3004_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan developed by APRA pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed plan, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed plan shall be deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
