<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-403"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-403/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_403">
        <akn:num>7-403</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Seeking health care for an overdose victim.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law, the offenses listed in subsection (b) of this section shall not be considered crimes and shall not serve as the sole basis for revoking or modifying a person’s supervision status:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following offenses apply to subsection (a) of this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The seeking of health care under subsection (a) of this section, whether or not presented by the parties, may be considered by the court as a mitigating factor in any criminal prosecution or sentencing for a drug or alcohol-related offense that is not an offense listed in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section does not prohibit a person from being arrested, charged, or prosecuted, or from having his or her supervision status modified or revoked, based on an offense other than an offense listed in subsection (b) of this section, whether or not the offense arises from the same circumstances as the seeking of health care.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A law enforcement officer who arrests an individual for an offense listed in subsection (b) of this section shall not be subject to criminal prosecution, or civil liability for false arrest or false imprisonment, if the officer made the arrest based on probable cause.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law, it shall not be considered a crime for a person to possess or administer an opioid antagonist, nor shall such person be subject to civil liability in the absence of gross negligence, if he or she administers the opioid antagonist:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall compile and review overdose data to identify changes in the causes and rates of fatal and non-fatal overdoses in the District of Columbia and report the findings to the Council annually. The report may be part of existing mortality reports issued by the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner, and shall include enhanced data collection to measure the effect of this section. The report may include data on the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Health shall educate the public on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-403_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
