<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-704.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-704.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_704_01">
        <akn:num>7-704.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement; penalties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-704_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Civil fines, penalties, or related costs may be imposed against any long-term care facility, owner, executive officer, administrator, employee, or agent, for the violation of any provision of this chapter or any rule issued pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-704_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Procedures for adjudication and enforcement and applicable civil fines, penalties, or costs shall be those prescribed for a Class 2 civil infraction, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-704_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the ombudsman or his or her designee knowingly violates ยง 7-703.06 by releasing a confidential document, record, or other information obtained pursuant to ยง 7-703.02(b), the ombudsman or his or her designee may be prosecuted for a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, subject to a fine of not more than $1,500, imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-704_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall take discriminatory, disciplinary, or retaliatory action against an employee of a long-term care facility or agency, resident, or resident representative for filing in good faith a complaint with, or providing information to, the ombudsman or his designees. A person who violates this provision, or who aids, abets, invites, compels, or coerces another to do so, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $1,000, imprisonment not to exceed 180 days, or both. This subsection shall not infringe upon the rights of an employer to supervise, discipline, or to terminate an employee for other reasons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-704_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who knowingly denies access to the ombudsman or his or her designee in violation of subchapter III of this chapter, or aids, abets, invites, compels, or coerces another to do so, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $1,000, imprisonment not to exceed 180 days, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
