<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-761.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-761.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_761_02">
        <akn:num>7-761.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community-based services” means non-residential specialized or generic services for the evaluation, care, and habilitation of persons with intellectual disabilities, in a community setting, directed toward the intellectual, social, personal, physical, emotional, or economic development of a person with an intellectual disability. The services shall include, but not be limited to, diagnosis, evaluation, treatment, day care, training, education, sheltered employment, recreation, counseling of the person with an intellectual disability and his or her family, protective and other social and socio-legal services, information and referral, and transportation to assure delivery of services to persons of all ages with intellectual disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Consumer” means a resident of the District of Columbia who is receiving, or eligible to receive, services from the Department on Disability Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” or “DDS” means the Department on Disability Services established by § 7-761.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DHCF” means the Department of Health Care Finance as established by § 7-771.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DHS” means the Department of Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means the Director of the Department on Disability Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Habilitation” means the process by which a person is assisted to acquire and maintain those life skills which enable him or her to cope more effectively with the demands of his or her own person and of his or her own environment, including, in the case of a person committed under § 7-1304.06a, to refrain from committing crimes of violence or sex offenses, and to raise the level of his or her physical, intellectual, social, emotional, and economic efficiency. The term “habilitation” includes, but is not limited to, the provision of community-based services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home and community-based services waiver” means a Medicaid home and community-based services waiver approved under section 1915(c) of the Social Security Act, approved August 13, 1981 (95 Stat. 809; 42 U.S.C. § 1396n).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intellectual disability” or “persons with intellectual disabilities” means a substantial limitation in capacity that manifests before 18 years of age and is characterized by significantly below-average intellectual functioning, existing concurrently with 2 or more significant limitations in adaptive functioning.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medical Assistance Program” and “Medicaid Program” mean the program described in the Medicaid State Plan and administered by the DHCF pursuant to § 1-307.02(b), and Title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident of the District of Columbia” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 7-1301.03(22).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-761_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“RSA” means the Rehabilitation Services Agency within the Department of Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
