<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-835"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-835/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_835">
        <akn:num>7-835</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Committee on Metabolic Disorders — Composition; term of office; compensation; vacancies; chairperson; meetings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-835_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Committee on Metabolic Disorders (hereinafter referred to as the “Committee”), shall be composed of 9 members. The members shall be appointed by the Mayor. Each member shall serve a term of 3 years or until his or her successor is appointed and qualified, except that in the initial appointments 3 members shall serve for 1 year, 3 members for 2 years and 3 members for 3 years. No member shall be appointed to more than 3 consecutive 3-year terms. The members of the Committee shall serve without compensation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-835_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Four members of the Committee shall be consumer members. A consumer is defined as a person who is not a health professional, nor involved in the administration or ownership of any health care institution or health insurance organization, nor the spouse of a health professional, administrator, or owner. Two of the consumer members shall be appointed from a list of 5 names submitted to the Mayor by the District of Columbia Association for Retarded Citizens, Inc. Five of the members of the Committee shall be nonconsumers. Four of the nonconsumer members shall be licensed physicians knowledgeable in the diagnosis and treatment of metabolic disorders. At least 1 of the physicians shall be either a geneticist or an endocrinologist. The Director of the Department of Human Services, or his or her designate, shall serve as an ex officio nonvoting member of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-835_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a vacancy on the Committee occurs for any reason other than the normal expiration of a term of office, a member shall be promptly appointed, to complete the unexpired term of the resigning member. The replacement member shall be selected in the same manner as outlined in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-835_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall appoint a Chairperson from among the members of the Committee to serve from the time of the Committee formation until December 31st of the year of the formation of the Committee. Thereafter the Mayor, each year, shall appoint a Chairperson to serve a 1-year term to run from January 1st to December 31st of each year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-835_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The full Committee shall meet at least twice each year. Business may be conducted if a majority of the members are present.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
