<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-832"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-832/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_832">
        <akn:num>7-832</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “metabolic disorder” means a disorder which results in a defect in the function of a specific enzyme or protein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “hypothyroidism” means those clinical conditions which result from abnormally low circulating levels of thyroid hormone.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “newborn” means any infant born in the District who is under 4 weeks of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “phenylketonuria,” hereinafter referred to as “PKU,” means the metabolic disease of the newborn in which metabolites of phenylalanine appear in urine.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “homocystinuria” means a condition resulting from one of several genetically determined errors of methionine metabolism.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “galactosemia” means a condition involving the inability to convert galactose to glucose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “maple syrup urine disease” means a condition resulting from the impairment of branched chain alpha-ketoacid dehydrogenase.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “sickle hemoglobinopathy” means a condition in which a mutation in the hemoglobin results in abnormally shaped red blood cells that obstruct normal circulation and cause inadequate oxygenation of the body’s tissues and vital organs. The term “sickle hemoglobinopathy” includes sickle cell anemia (homozygous sickle cell disease), sickle cell hemoglobin C disease, and sickle cell beta thalassemia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-832_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The terms “hospital” and “maternity center” mean those terms as they are defined in § 44-501(a)(1) and (2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
