<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-871.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-871.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_871_02">
        <akn:num>7-871.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child” or “Children” means an individual or individuals under the age of 6 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Elevated blood lead level” means an excessive absorption of lead concentration in whole blood of 10 mg/dL (micrograms of lead per deciliter) or greater.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health care facility” means any institution providing individual care or treatment of diseases or other medical, physiological, or psychological conditions, including, but not limited to, hospitals, clinics, laboratories, nursing homes, or homes for the aged or chronically ill, but excluding private medical offices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health care provider” means a physician, clinic, hospital, or neighborhood health center, licensed by the District of Columbia, that is responsible for providing primary care and coordinating referrals, when necessary, to other health care providers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Lead-poisoned child” means a child with a confirmed blood lead level equal to or greater than 15 micrograms of lead per deciliter of blood, or such other lower threshold as the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention may establish.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, a corporation, a partnership, firm, conservator, receiver, trustee, executor, or legal representative.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
