<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-875.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-875.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_875_02">
        <akn:num>7-875.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-related educational program” means public and private schools, including pre-kindergarten, Head Start, child care, and special education.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-related health program” means Medicaid, Children Health Insurance Program (“CHIP”), Healthy Start, Healthy Families, Early Intervention, and private health insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-related human or social services program” means children in foster care and Women, Infants and Children.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Children with special needs who reside or are receiving care in another state” means children:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health benefits plan” means any accident and health insurance policy or certificate, hospital and medical services corporation contract, health maintenance organization subscriber contract, plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or plan provided by another benefit arrangement. The term “health benefit plan” does not mean accident only, credit, or disability insurance; coverage of Medicare services or federal employee health plans pursuant to contracts with the United States government; Medicare supplemental or long-term care insurance; dental only or vision only insurance; specified disease insurance; hospital confinement indemnity coverage; limited benefit health coverage; coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance, insurance arising out of a workers’ compensation or similar law; automobile medical payment insurance; medical expense and loss of income benefits; or insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health insurer” means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District of Columbia, including an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-875_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Uniform health form” means a standardized health assessment form developed by the Mayor for use when enrolling a child in child-related educational, health, and human or social services programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
