<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-871.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/7-871.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_7_871_03">
        <akn:num>7-871.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Childhood lead screening and reporting requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each health care provider or facility shall inform the parent or guardian of every child under the age of 6 years in the District of Columbia, served by the provider or facility, of the requirement for periodic blood tests for lead poisoning as provided in this chapter and rules implementing this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A health care provider or facility shall, unless parental consent is withheld or an identical test has already been performed within the last 12 months, perform a blood test for lead poisoning on every child who resides in the District of Columbia as part of a well-child care visit, once between ages 6 months and 14 months, and a second time between ages 22 months and 26 months. If a child’s age exceeds 26 months, and a blood lead screening has not been performed, the child shall be screened twice prior to the age of 6 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The laboratory that performed the tests pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall forward all test results to the health care provider or facility where the blood sample was taken, and to the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The health care provider or facility shall forward all elevated blood lead level results immediately to the child’s parent or guardian. Upon request of the child’s parent or guardian, the health care provider or facility shall provide written evidence of testing for lead poisoning that includes the date of the test and the test results.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, pursuant to § 7-871.06, shall issue rules governing the conditions under which a health care provider or facility shall administer additional lead screening tests exceeding the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, and the process for reporting lead screening results.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any agreement or contract entered into by the Medical Assistance Administration to provide its services through a health insuring or a managed care organization shall include a requirement for the organization to provide screening and reporting services pursuant to the provisions of this section and the rules implementing this section, or to provide reimbursement for those services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7-871_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue an annual report to the Council summarizing and analyzing the lead screening results obtained pursuant to this chapter. The report shall include recommendations based on or pertaining at a minimum to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
