<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-132"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-132/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_132">
        <akn:num>24-132</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Pretrial services, parole, adult probation and offender supervision trustee.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appointment and removal. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Authority. — Beginning on the date of appointment, and continuing until the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia is established under § 24-133, the Trustee shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Compensation. — The Trustee shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed the basic pay payable for Level IV of the Executive Schedule. The Trustee may appoint and fix the pay of additional staff without regard to the provisions of the District of Columbia Official Code governing appointments and salaries, without regard to the provisions of Title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of Chapter 51 and subchapter III of Chapter 53 of Title 5, United States Code, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates. Upon request of the Trustee, the head of any Federal department or agency may, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, provide services and/or detail any personnel of that department or agency to the Trusteeship to assist in carrying out its duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Procurement and judicial review. — The provisions of the District of Columbia Official Code governing procurement shall not apply to the Trustee. The Trustee may enter into such contracts as the Trustee considers appropriate to carry out the Trustee’s duties. The Trustee may seek judicial enforcement of the Trustee’s authority to carry out the Trustee’s duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Preservation of retirement and certain other rights of federal employee who becomes the Trustee or federal employees who become employed by the Trustee. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Treatment as Federal Employees. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funding. — Funds available for operations of the Trustee shall be made available to the extent provided in appropriations acts to the Trustee, through the State Justice Institute. Funding requests shall be proposed by the Trustee to the President and Congress for each Fiscal Year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Liability and litigation authority. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Certification. — The Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia shall assume its duties pursuant to § 24-133 when, within the period beginning one year after August 5, 1997 and ending three years after August 5, 1997, the Trustee certifies to the Attorney General and the Attorney General concurs that the Agency can carry out the functions described in § 24-133 and the United States Parole Commission can carry out the functions described in § 24-133.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-132_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Exercise of authority on behalf of Public Defender Service. — At the request of the Director of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service, the Trustee may exercise any of the powers and authorities of the Trustee on behalf of such Service in the same manner and to the same extent as the Trustee may exercise such powers and authorities in relation to any agency described in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
