<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-102"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-102/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_102">
        <akn:num>24-102</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Corrections Trustee.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-102_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appointment and removal of trustee. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-102_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Duties of trustee. — Beginning on the date of appointment and continuing until the felony population sentenced pursuant to the District of Columbia Official Code residing at the Lorton Correctional Complex is transferred to a penal or correctional facility operated or contracted for by the Bureau of Prisons, the Corrections Trustee shall carry out the following responsibilities (notwithstanding any law of the District of Columbia to the contrary):</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-102_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funding. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-102_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Compensation and detailees. — The Corrections Trustee shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed the basic pay payable for Level IV of the Executive Schedule. The Corrections Trustee may appoint and fix the pay of additional staff without regard to the provisions of the District of Columbia Code governing appointments and salaries, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates. Upon request of the Corrections Trustee, the head of any Federal department or agency may, on a reimbursable or non reimbursable basis, provide services and detail any personnel of that department or agency to the Corrections Trustee to assist in carrying out his duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-102_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Procurement and judicial review. — The provisions of the District of Columbia Official Code governing procurement shall not apply to the Corrections Trustee. The Corrections Trustee may seek judicial enforcement of his authority to carry out his duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-102_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Preservation of retirement and certain other rights of federal employees who become employed by the Corrections Trustee. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
