<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-263.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-263.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_263_03">
        <akn:num>24-263.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Department of Corrections report.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-263_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Corrections (“Department”) shall survey the communications plans used by the Federal Bureau of Prisons, and all state prison systems. The Department shall explore additional alternative communication plans with telecommunications companies. The explored alternatives shall include prison commissary phone accounts, restricted calling cards, presenting calling cards, and debit calling cards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-263_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No later than 180 days after April 27, 2001, the Department shall report to the Council and the Mayor the results of the survey and the exploration of alternatives. The report shall include the merits and disadvantages of each communication plan examined, including consideration of the security needs of the Department, the financial burden to the families and other individuals telephoned, the availability of telecommunications to the inmates, the feasibility of waiving the gross receipts tax, and other incentives to control the cost of inmate phone service. The report shall include a recommendation for an inmate telephone service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
