<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-231.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-231.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_231_11">
        <akn:num>24-231.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Disbursement of wages to employed prisoners; deductions; accounting.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wages paid to prisoners employed by a prison industry shall be considered taxable income for purposes of subchapter I of Chapter 18 of Title 47.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wages paid to prisoners employed by a prison industry wholly owned and operated by the District shall be paid from the Fund. Wages paid to prisoners employed by a prison industry operated pursuant to a prison industry joint venture agreement shall be paid by each private-sector employer who is a party to the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wages due each prisoner employed in a prison industry shall be disbursed according to a schedule of deductions which, after withholding District, federal, and state income taxes, shall be established by the Director.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except in the case of a prisoner employed in a prison industry approved under a PIE Program, the total amount deducted under subsection (c) of this section, including taxes withheld, shall not exceed 80% of gross wages and may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of a prisoner employed in a prison industry approved under the PIE Program, the total amount deducted under subsection (c) of this section, including taxes withheld, shall not exceed 80% of gross wages and may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The remaining 20% of the wage payment shall be available to the prisoner for the purchase of commissary items for personal use and for deposit in a personal account established for each prisoner by the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_11_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall establish procedures to provide each prisoner employed in a prison industry with a regular accounting showing gross wages earned, amount deducted in each category of deductions, and the amount credited to the prisoner’s personal account maintained by the Department. All wages credited to the prisoner’s personal account shall be made available to the prisoner at the time of release. The prisoner may draw upon funds in his or her personal account for any legal purpose consistent with Department rules.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
