<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-231.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-231.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_231_08">
        <akn:num>24-231.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Employment of prisoners; terms and conditions; opportunities for advancement; qualifications.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A prison industry shall employ eligible prisoners in all entry-level positions to the extent feasible.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prisoners employed in a prison industry shall not work more than 40 hours per week, except that prisoners may volunteer to work overtime hours for overtime payment at 1 1/2 times the normal hourly wage when necessary to meet a prison industry’s production needs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For positions requiring an advanced level of skills or experience and for supervisory positions, a prison industry may employ nonprisoner personnel if the prison industry staff responsible for reviewing the qualifications of eligible prisoner job applicants:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the approval of the Director, each prison industry shall develop and provide the following, in writing, to all prisoner employees and job applicants:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The items described in subsection (d) of this section shall be discussed orally with prisoner job applicants. Each applicant, as a condition of employment, shall sign a statement affirming that he or she:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To qualify as eligible for available employment in a prison industry, a prisoner shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each prisoner may receive educational good time credit for participating in the prison industries program pursuant to § 24-221.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
