<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-231.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-231.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_231_01">
        <akn:num>24-231.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bureau of Justice Assistance Private Sector Prison Industry Enhancement Certification Program”, or “PIE Program”, means the federal grant-in-aid program administered by the Bureau of Justice Assistance, United States Department of Justice, pursuant to 42 U.S.C. 3741-3761, and participation in which by the states or the District of Columbia affords an exemption from the general federal prohibition against open market sale of prisoner-produced goods, pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 1761(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Correctional facility” means any building or group of buildings and concomitant services operated as a single management unit by the District of Columbia Department of Corrections for the purpose of housing and providing services to persons ordered confined pending trial or upon conviction and sentencing for a violation of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the District of Columbia Department of Corrections.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Joint venture” means a production unit in or part of a prison industry, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prison industries” means an organized plan, including equipment and facilities, for the production and distribution of goods or services on the grounds of a correctional facility to aid disciplinary and rehabilitative goals of the prison system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prison Industries Fund” means the revolving fund established by § 24-231.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prisoner” means any person who is confined to an adult correctional facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Private-sector employer” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Substance abuse” means any pattern of pathological use of alcohol or other drug that causes impairment in social or occupational functioning, or that produces physiological dependency as evidenced by physical tolerance or by physical symptoms when it is withdrawn.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-231_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Washington, D.C., region” means the geographic area that encompasses the District of Columbia and adjacent portions of the State of Maryland and the Commonwealth of Virginia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
