<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-463"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-463/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_463">
        <akn:num>24-463</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Board of Parole authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-463_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Parole (“Board”) shall establish a medical and geriatric parole program to be administered by the Department of Corrections (“Department”). The authority to grant medical or geriatric parole shall rest solely with the Board. The Department shall determine for each person considered for geriatric or medical parole, whether the person is a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-463_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding § 24-408, inmates who have not served their minimum sentences shall be considered eligible for parole under this section. Medical and geriatric parole consideration shall be in addition to any other parole for which an inmate may be eligible.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-463_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall determine the appropriate level of supervision and shall develop a comprehensive discharge plan for each inmate released under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-463_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In considering an inmate for medical or geriatric parole, the Board may request that additional medical evidence be produced or that additional medical examinations be conducted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-463_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The parole term of an inmate on medical parole shall be for the remainder of the inmate’s sentence, without diminution of sentence for good behavior. In addition to terms and conditions prescribed by the Board, supervision of an inmate on medical or geriatric parole shall also consist of periodic medical evaluations at intervals to be determined by the Board at the time of release.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-463_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The chairperson of the Board shall report annually to the Mayor, the Chairpersons of the Council of the District of Columbia, and the Council’s Committee on the Judiciary, the number of applications for medical and geriatric parole, the nature of the illness, disease, or condition of the applicants, the reasons for denial of applications for medical or geriatric parole, the number of persons on medical and geriatric parole who have been returned to the custody of the Department, and the reasons for their return.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
