<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-403.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/24-403.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_24_403_01">
        <akn:num>24-403.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sentencing, supervised release, and good time credit for felonies committed on or after August 5, 2000.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For any felony committed on or after August 5, 2000, the court shall impose a sentence that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the maximum term of imprisonment authorized for an offense is a term of years, the term of imprisonment or commitment imposed by the court shall not exceed the maximum term of imprisonment authorized for the offense less the maximum term of imprisonment authorized upon revocation of supervised release pursuant to subsection (b)(7) of this section. If the maximum term of imprisonment authorized for the offense is up to life or if an offense is specifically designated as a Class A felony, the maximum term of imprisonment authorized upon revocation of supervised release pursuant to subsection (b)(7) shall not be deducted from the maximum term of imprisonment or commitment authorized for such offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A sentence under this section of imprisonment, or of commitment pursuant to § 24-903, shall be for a definite term, which shall not exceed the maximum term allowed by law or be less than any minimum term required by law. A person sentenced under this section to imprisonment, or to commitment pursuant to § 24-903, for such a felony shall serve the term of imprisonment or commitment specified in the sentence, less any time credited toward service of the sentence under subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person sentenced to imprisonment, or to commitment pursuant to § 24-903, under this section may receive good time credit toward service of the sentence only as provided in 18 U.S.C. § 3624(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The sentence imposed under this section on a person convicted of assault with intent to commit first or second degree sexual abuse or child sexual abuse in violation of § 22-401, or of armed robbery in violation of § 22-4502, shall be not less than 2 years if the violation occurs after the person has been convicted in the District of Columbia or elsewhere of a crime of violence as defined in § 22-4501, providing for the control of dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia. The sentence imposed under this section on a person convicted of first or second degree sexual abuse or child sexual abuse in violation of § 22-3002, § 22-3003, or § 22-3008 through § 22-3010, shall not be less than 7 years if the violation occurs after the person has been convicted in the District of Columbia or elsewhere of a crime of violence, as so defined.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The sentence imposed under this section shall not be less than 1 year for a person convicted of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24-403_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other penalty provided under this section, a person may be fined an amount not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
