<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1102"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1102/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1102">
        <akn:num>3-1102</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Established; composition; officers; term of office; quorum; residency requirements; reimbursement of expenses; meetings; funding; duration.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a District of Columbia Residential, Commercial, and Institutional Structures Fire Protection Study Commission to advise the Council by investigating and reporting on the feasibility of low-cost residential, commercial, and institutional sprinklers as a means of protecting the public from uncontrolled fires in residential, commercial, and institutional structures and by recommending to the Council comprehensive legislation to establish a residential, commercial, and institutional fire sprinkler program appropriate for the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term of the members shall be 1 year from the 1st meeting of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum.  A quorum of the members shall be necessary for the Commission to conduct its business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The appointment of a member shall terminate if the member becomes a resident of a jurisdiction other than the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Vacancies in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for all reasonable expenses associated with their service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall meet at least once a month and shall determine the time and place of its meetings.  The Council may convene meetings of the Commission at any time.  Meetings of the Commission are open to the public consistent with ยง 1-207.42.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall annually receive funds according to the appropriations process.  These funds may be applied to the costs associated with community hearings, the development of studies and other forms of community interface, and for the hiring of staff.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1102_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall cease to exist 30 days after submitting the comprehensive report referred to in ยง 3-1103(p).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
