<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1209.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1209.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1209_10">
        <akn:num>3-1209.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Speech-language pathology assistants.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who practices as a speech-language pathology assistant shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be eligible for registration as a speech-language pathology assistant, a person shall provide proof acceptable to the Board that he or she:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person shall not practice as a speech-language pathology assistant or use the title of speech-language pathology assistant unless he or she:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A registered speech-language pathology assistant shall not:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensed speech-language pathologist may delegate duties to a speech-language pathology assistant that are appropriate to the training and experience of the speech-language pathology assistant and within the scope of practice of the supervising speech-language pathologist; provided, that the speech-language pathologist shall not delegate to a speech-language pathology assistant any task or function identified, through rulemaking, as a task or function that shall not be delegated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a period of one year following March 26, 2014, unless further time is granted by the Mayor through rulemaking, a person who has received appropriate training for the tasks assigned may practice as a speech-language pathology assistant regardless of registration with the Board, only while under the supervision of a licensed speech-language pathologist, except as provided for in subsection (e)(2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_10_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a period of one year following March 26, 2014, a person practicing as a speech-language pathology assistant may register as a speech-language pathology assistant notwithstanding the educational requirements of subsection (c)(2) of this section provided, that the person has been employed under the direct supervision of a speech-language pathologist for a minimum of 15 hours per week during at least 3 of the 5 years preceding March 26, 2014.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
