<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1251.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1251.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1251_09">
        <akn:num>3-1251.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Description of the Program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Admission to the Program is voluntary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A colleague, employer, or the Board may refer impaired nurses to the Program through a self-report, formal complaint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nurse requesting admission to the Program may not have:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Committee and the nurse shall enter into a written contract that sets forth the requirements and conditions for the nurse’s participation in the Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nurse who fails to comply with the requirements and conditions of the written contract shall be reported to the Board for disciplinary action. The Board may take such action as described in § 3-1205.14 (revocation, suspension, or denial of license or privilege, civil penalty, reprimand) against a nurse who is expelled from the rehabilitation program for noncompliance. The Board shall not be required to recommend a course of remediation, as described in § 3-1205.14(c)(6), for a nurse who is expelled from a rehabilitation program. The license of a nurse who is expelled from the rehabilitation program for noncompliance may be immediately suspended or restricted as described in § 3-1205.15 (summary action).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Evaluation of a nurse for participation in the Program shall be the responsibility of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the request of the Board, the Committee, in consultation with the treatment providers, may evaluate a nurse with a drug or alcohol abuse problem, or mental illness, for readiness to return to the practice of nursing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1251_09_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An impaired nurse who is participating in the rehabilitation program may voluntarily limit or surrender any license issued under Chapter 12 of this title in accordance with § 3-1205.18.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
