<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1212.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1212.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1212_01">
        <akn:num>3-1212.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of personnel, records, property, and funds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Dental Examiners are transferred to the Board of Dentistry established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Commission on Licensure to Practice the Healing Arts are transferred to the Board of Medicine established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Nurses’ Examining Board are transferred to the Board of Nursing established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Examiners for Nursing Home Administrators are transferred to the Board of Nursing Home Administration established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Occupational Therapy Practice are transferred to the Board of Occupational Therapy established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Optometry are transferred to the Board of Optometry established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Physical Therapists Examining Board are transferred to the Board of Physical Therapy established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Pharmacy are transferred to the Board of Pharmacy established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Podiatry Examiners are transferred to the Board of Podiatry established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1212_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Psychologist Examiners are transferred to the Board of Psychology established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
