<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1209.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1209.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1209_05">
        <akn:num>3-1209.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Dental assistant.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who is engaged as a dental assistant in the District of Columbia shall be registered with the Board, renew the registration as required by rule, and pay the required registration fee established by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A dental assistant shall wear a name tag bearing the title “dental assistant” while acting in a professional capacity and display his or her current registration in a conspicuous place in the dental office in which he or she is employed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person shall not engage in the practice, or use the title, of dental assistant unless he or she is registered to practice as a dental assistant under this chapter and practices under the direct supervision of a dentist licensed under this chapter. Unless authorized by the Board to perform duties related to oral care in the District, an individual shall not be permitted to perform any clinical duties or engage in any physical patient contact.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a period of one year following July 7, 2009, unless further time is granted by the Board through rulemaking, persons who have received appropriate training for the tasks assigned may practice as a dental assistant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A dentist may delegate duties to a dental assistant that are appropriate to the training and experience of the dental assistant and within the scope of practice of the supervising dentist; provided, that the dentist shall not delegate to a dental assistant any task or function identified, through rulemaking, as a task or function that shall not be delegated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue rules necessary to implement the provisions of this section, including the standards of education and experience required to qualify as a registered dental assistant and the duties that may be performed by a dental assistant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
