<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1205.09a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1205.09a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1205_09a">
        <akn:num>3-1205.09a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Licenses for foreign doctors of eminence and authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Board shall grant a limited license to practice specialized medicine with a university, hospital or medical center in the District of Columbia to an applicant licensed as a physician in a foreign country or state who by virtue of the recognized and conceded eminence and authority in the profession of medicine or medical research in the international community, if this applicant:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall not issue to any entity under paragraph (1) of this section more than 1 such license in any single year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued under this section shall be issued jointly in the name of the applicant and the sponsoring entity under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining whether an applicant is a recognized and conceded eminence and authority in the profession, the Board shall consider, but not be limited to, whether the applicant meets the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As an exception to the general education and examination requirements of §§ 3-1205.03, 3-1205.04, and 3-1205.06, the Board shall waive those requirements when an applicant under this section shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board of successful completion or satisfaction of the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of this section, and shall provide documentation sufficient to support the application, including, but not limited to, a diploma or certified transcripts of the applicant’s medical or, if applicable, premedical education and certified verification of licensure or registration to practice medicine in a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No license granted under this section shall issue to any candidate until the Board reviews the qualifications for eminence and makes a final decision. The Board shall have the sole authority and responsibility to interpret the qualifications for eminence and for licensure under these provisions, and may qualify, restrict, or otherwise limit a license granted under this section by controlling the type of medical areas of practice and patient care as the applicant has received credentials and acceptance for practice from an institution under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All applicants who have complied with these requirements, and have otherwise complied with the provisions of this subchapter, shall receive from the Board within 90 days after the application is complete by the candidate’s submission of all requirements imposed under subsection (b) of this section, a license entitling them to the right to practice in the District of Columbia. Each such license shall be duly recorded in the office of the Board, in a record to be properly kept for that purpose which shall be open to public inspection, and a certified copy of the record shall be received as evidence in all courts in the District of Columbia in the trial of any case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The holder of the limited license practicing medicine or surgery beyond the areas of the medical specialty or practice as laid down in said license shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be fined not less than $10,000 for each and every offense; and the Board is empowered to revoke such limited license, for cause, after due notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1205_09a_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person granted a limited license under this section who subsequently desires to obtain a license without restriction shall be required to meet all of the requirements of such license as set forth in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
