<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1209.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1209.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1209_11">
        <akn:num>3-1209.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Speech-language pathology clinical fellows.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who practices as a speech-language pathology clinical fellow shall be registered with the Board according to rules adopted by the Mayor, renew the registration as required by rule, and pay the required registration fee established by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be eligible for registration as a speech-language pathology clinical fellow, a person shall provide proof acceptable to the Board that he or she:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person shall not practice as a speech-language pathology clinical fellow or use the title of speech-language pathology clinical fellow unless he or she:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A registered speech-language pathology clinical fellow shall not:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensed speech-language pathologist may delegate duties to a speech-language pathology clinical fellow that are appropriate to the training and experience of the speech-language pathology clinical fellow and within the scope of practice of the supervising speech-language pathologist; provided, that the speech-language pathologist shall not delegate to a speech-language pathology clinical fellow any task or function identified through rulemaking as a task or function that shall not be delegated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1209_11_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a period of one year following March 26, 2014, unless further time is granted by the Mayor through rulemaking, a person who has received appropriate training for the tasks assigned may practice as a speech-language pathology clinical fellow, regardless of registration with the Board, while under the supervision of a licensed speech-language pathologist, except as provided for in subsection (e)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
