<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1208.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1208.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1208_04">
        <akn:num>3-1208.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Licensed independent clinical social worker.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1208_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Social Work shall license as an independent clinical social worker a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter, has a master’s degree or a doctorate from a social work program accredited by the Council on Social Work Education, has satisfactorily completed the examination process at the independent clinical level, and has at least 3,000 hours of post-master’s or postdoctoral experience participating in the diagnosis and treatment of individuals, families, and groups with psychosocial problems, under the supervision of a licensed independent clinical social worker over a period of not less than 2 years or more than 4 years; under special circumstances approved by the Board, supervision by a licensed psychiatrist or psychologist may be substituted for up to 1500 hours of this requirement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1208_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensed independent clinical social worker (“L.I.C.S.W.”) may perform any function described as the practice of social work in this chapter, in an autonomous, self-regulated fashion, in an agency setting or independently, and may supervise other persons in the performance of these functions. A licensed independent clinical social worker shall not engage in the practice of medicine and shall refer patience or clients with apparent medical problems to an appropriate and qualified medical practitioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
