<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1201.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1201.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1201_03">
        <akn:num>3-1201.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Scope of chapter.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1201_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter does not limit the right of an individual to practice a health occupation that he or she is otherwise authorized to practice under this chapter, nor does it limit the right of an individual to practice any other profession that he or she is authorized to practice under the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1201_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The practices of health occupations regulated by this chapter are not intended to be mutually exclusive.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1201_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not be construed to prohibit the practice of a health occupation by an individual enrolled in a recognized school or college as a candidate for a degree or certificate in a health occupation, or enrolled in a recognized postgraduate training program provided that the practice is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1201_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require licensure for or to otherwise regulate, restrict, or prohibit individuals from engaging in the practices, services, or activities set forth in the paragraphs of this subsection if the individuals do not hold themselves out, by title, description of services, or otherwise, to be practicing any of the health occupations regulated by this chapter. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as exempting any of the following categories from other applicable laws and regulations of the District or federal government:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1201_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not be construed to prohibit the practice of a health occupation by an individual who has filed an initial application for licensure in the health occupation and is awaiting action on that initial application, provided the practice is performed:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1201_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter does not prohibit the practice of a health occupation by an individual who is authorized to practice the health occupation under Chapter 23C of Title 7 [ยง 7-2361.01 et seq.], while an emergency declaration is in effect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
