<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1301">
        <akn:num>3-1301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Created; appointment; composition; qualifications; vacancies; term of office; compensation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1301_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby created by the District of Columbia the District of Columbia Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board, hereinafter referred to as the Board. The 1st Board shall be appointed as hereinafter specified within 60 days of March 10, 1981. The Board shall consist of 5 members who shall be appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia with the consent of the Council of the District of Columbia. Of the members appointed, one shall be designated as Chairperson of the Board by the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1301_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Board, at the time of appointment and qualification, shall be a registered voter in the District for at least 5 years preceding appointment and qualification and shall be not less than 21 years of age. In the event of a vacancy on the Board as a consequence of resignation, disability, death, or for other reasons, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall appoint, with the consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, another person to fill the vacancy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1301_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Of the members of the Board first appointed, 2 shall hold office for 2 years, from 1981 to 1983; 2 for 3 years from that date; and the Chairperson, 4 years from that date. Thereafter, members shall be appointed for terms of 4 years from the 1st day of July in the year of their appointment and until their successors are appointed and have qualified.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1301_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Board shall receive a stipend of $15,000 annually, except the Chairperson of the Board, who shall receive an additional stipend of $3,000 annually for a total of $18,000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
