<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1303"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1303/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1303">
        <akn:num>3-1303</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Executive Director and Deputy Director.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1303_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall appoint an Executive Director and a Deputy Director in accordance with ยง 1-609.08, each of whom shall devote his or her full time and attention to the duties of their respective offices and shall serve at the pleasure of the Board. The Executive Director shall be a resident of the District and shall remain a District resident for the duration of his or her employment by the Board. Failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1303_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall determine the compensation for the Executive Director and the Deputy Director, which shall not be less than the basic pay for step 1 of Grade 16 of Schedule 1 of the District Service Schedule, nor shall it exceed the rate of compensation for the Mayor of the District of Columbia pursuant to ยง 1-611.09.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1303_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to performing the duties of their respective offices, the Executive Director and the Deputy Director shall take and subscribe to the same oaths or affirmations as that required by the Board, including an oath or affirmation that he or she is not primarily interested, directly or indirectly, in any firm, partnership, association, organization, or corporation engaged in any activity related to legalized or illegal gambling. The Executive Director and the Deputy Director shall each file an annual financial disclosure statement with the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1303_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Director shall, subject to the direction and supervision of the Board:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1303_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1303_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may delegate to the Executive Director and Deputy Director other duties it deems necessary for the proper and efficient operation of public gambling and charitable activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
