<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1323"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1323/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1323">
        <akn:num>3-1323</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Licenses to conduct bingo games, raffles, and Monte Carlo night parties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1323_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person, firm, partnership, association, organization, or corporation shall sponsor, conduct, or hold a bingo game, raffle, or Monte Carlo night party in the District of Columbia without a license issued by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1323_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may issue a license under this section to a person, firm, partnership, association, organization, or corporation engaged in or existing for charitable, benevolent, eleemosynary, humane, religious, philanthropic, recreational, social, educational, civic, fraternal, or other nonprofit purposes that conducts an activity to which contributions are deductible for federal or municipal income tax purposes if the applicant:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1323_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1323_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may issue a license under this section to a senior citizen group in accordance with rules that may be adopted by the Board pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1323_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may issue a license under this section, upon application, to a citizen-service program established pursuant to ยง 1-1163.38, in accordance with rules that may be adopted by the Board pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
