<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1326"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-1326/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_1326">
        <akn:num>3-1326</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>License to supply bingo equipment and supplies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1326_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person, firm, partnership, association, organization, or corporation licensed by the Board to conduct bingo shall purchase or receive bingo equipment and supplies, as defined by the rules and regulations of the Board, except from a person, firm, partnership, association, organization, or corporation licensed by the Board to supply such equipment. Any person, firm, partnership, association, organization, or corporation intending to sell, supply, or distribute bingo equipment and supplies shall apply for a suppliers license on an application form prescribed by the Board. Such application shall include, but not be limited to: The name and address of the applicant; a designation of the type of business organization of the applicant and the date and place of its original establishment; the name and address of each officer, director, shareholder, partner, or other person with an ownership interest in the applicant business; a statement showing the gross receipts realized in the preceding year on the sale or distribution of bingo supplies and equipment to licensed organizations; the name and address of any supplier of bingo supplies and equipment to the applicant; the number of years the applicant has been in the business of supplying bingo supplies and equipment; and, if the applicant business is organized outside of the District, the name and address of a resident agent who is authorized to be served legal documents and receive notices, orders, and directives of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-1326_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
