<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-407"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-407/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_407">
        <akn:num>3-407</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Terms and conditions of apprenticeship.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-407_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to qualify for a funeral director’s license, an apprentice funeral director (“apprentice”) must serve an apprenticeship under the supervision of a funeral director licensed by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-407_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the requirement of subsection (a) of this section, an apprentice who is required to serve a 2-year minimum apprenticeship may serve up to 1 year of the apprenticeship outside of the District, if the period of apprenticeship served outside of the District is served under the supervision of a funeral director who has passed a nationally approved examination and is the owner or full-time employee of the funeral services establishment where the apprentice is employed. The Mayor shall issue rules and regulations to implement this subsection pursuant to § 3-420.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-407_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An apprentice funeral director may obtain license renewals allowing him to extend his apprenticeship, but the total period of apprenticeship shall not exceed 4 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-407_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every apprentice employed in that capacity within the District shall, within 5 days after terminating his or her employment, notify the Mayor of the termination, indicating the date on which the employment ceased.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-407_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every apprentice whose employment under the supervision of a funeral director is terminated shall, immediately upon being employed to work under the supervision of another funeral director, notify the Mayor of the change of employment, indicating the name, address, and license number of the funeral director under whose supervision the apprentice is continuing his or her apprenticeship.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-407_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A funeral director shall, upon employing an apprentice or terminating the employment of an apprentice, notify the Mayor in writing accordingly. The notification shall contain the name, address, and license number of the apprentice, as well as the date on which the apprentice was employed or terminated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
