<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-406"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-406/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_406">
        <akn:num>3-406</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Issuance and renewal of licenses.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-406_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A license to practice in the District as either a funeral director or apprentice funeral director, or to operate a funeral services establishment shall be issued to each applicant who meets all of the requirements for licensure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-406_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every license in good standing issued in accordance with this chapter shall expire on a date set by the Mayor and shall be renewed as determined by the Mayor in rules and regulations to be issued pursuant to ยง 3-420. On or before the 30th day preceding expiration, the Mayor shall mail an application for renewal to the last known address of each person holding a license in good standing. Failure to receive this application shall not be a proper defense of any person failing to renew any required license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-406_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each person holding a license in good standing issued pursuant to this chapter, and who wishes to continue practice in the District, shall, on or before the last day of each term, file an application for renewal of the license accompanied by the proper fee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-406_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, upon receipt of a renewal application and the proper fee, the Mayor shall issue a renewal for the new license year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-406_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person holding a license issued under the provisions of this chapter who fails to file an application for renewal and pay the required fee on or before the last day of any license term, and who, after the first day of the new term, performs in the District the duties of a licensee, shall be found in violation of this chapter. Any license that is not renewed within 30 days of the expiration of its term, shall be terminated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-406_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person whose license has expired and who subsequently files an application for renewal shall comply with any terms and conditions prescribed by the Mayor not inconsistent with this chapter. The terms and conditions for restoration of a lapsed license may, in the discretion of the Mayor, include the passing of an examination or payment of a penalty fee, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
