<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-604"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-604/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_604">
        <akn:num>3-604</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Commission.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby created a District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission to consist of 3 members nominated by the Mayor and approved by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Other than as provided in subsection (g) of this section, the term of office of a member of the Commission shall be 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a vacancy on the Commission occurs before the end of a term, the Mayor, with the consent of the Council, may appoint a person to complete the remaining period of that term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Commission member may be removed by resolution of the Council:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The members of the Commission shall be residents of the District of Columbia for the duration of their term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The members of the Commission shall receive compensation pursuant to the provisions of ยง 1-611.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-604_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall, within 30 days of October 8, 1975, nominate an individual to serve as Chairperson of the Commission for 3 years, and 2 more individuals to serve as members for 2 years, and 1 year respectively. The Council shall confirm or reject these nominees within 90 days of their nomination, or, in the absence of such action, within 90 days, such nominees shall be deemed confirmed. When at least 2 members have been confirmed, the Commission shall be deemed established.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
