<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-732"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/3-732/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_3_732">
        <akn:num>3-732</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Commission members; qualifications; terms of office; removal.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall consist of 12 members nominated by the Mayor and subject to the consent of the Council in accordance with ยง 1-523.01(f). The makeup of the Commission shall reflect the demographics of the District and shall include prominent business and community leaders and individuals certified in fatherhood training or having documented experience working directly with issues of particular interest and concern to fathers, men, and boys.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Commission shall be residents of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members shall be appointed to serve terms of 4 years and shall serve until their successors are appointed. A member of the Commission may be reappointed but may serve no more than 2 consecutive terms.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a vacancy occurs on the Commission, the Mayor shall, within 90 business days of the vacancy, appoint a successor to fill the unexpired portion of the term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall designate, from among the members appointed, the Chairman, who shall serve in that capacity at the pleasure of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All members of the Commission shall serve without compensation except that expenses incurred by the Commission as a whole, or by a group of its members, shall become an obligation against appropriated District funds designated for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3-732_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may remove, after notice and hearing, any member of the Commission for neglect of duty, incompetence, misconduct, or malfeasance in office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
