<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-211"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-211/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_46_211">
        <akn:num>46-211</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice to withhold to the holder.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount to be withheld, including any fee deducted and retained under § 46-212;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the amount to be withheld shall not exceed the limits imposed under section 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 163; 15 U.S.C. § 1673(b));</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder shall withhold from the obligor’s earnings or other income the amount specified in the notice or order to withhold, pay the withheld amount to the Collection and Disbursement Unit within 7 business days after the date the income would have been paid to the obligor, and report to the Collection and Disbursement Unit the date on which the amount was withheld;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder shall begin withholding no later than the first pay period occurring 10 days after the date the notice or order to withhold was issued;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder may deduct and retain an additional $ 2 for processing costs or, if applicable, an amount permitted under § 46-212(e);</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the withholding is binding on the holder until further notice;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder may be fined in accordance with § 46-219(c) for discharging an obligor from employment, refusing to employ an obligor, or taking disciplinary action against an obligor because of the withholding;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That, if the holder fails to withhold support payments from earnings or other income or remit these payments to the Collection and Disbursement Unit as required under this subchapter, the holder shall be liable as specified in § 46-213;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the withholding has priority over any other legal process under District law;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder may combine withheld amounts from more than one obligor in a single payment and separately identify the portion of the payment that is attributable to each obligor;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder shall withhold according to the requirements of § 46-212; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-211_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the holder shall give notice to the IV-D agency of a termination of the obligor’s employment as required by § 46-216.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
