<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-225"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-225/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_46_225">
        <akn:num>46-225</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reporting and publication of delinquent accounts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency shall report to a consumer credit reporting agency, as defined in section 603(f) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act, approved October 26, 1970 (84 Stat. 1129; 15 U.S.C. § 1681a(f)), each support order that was entered, modified, registered, or is being enforced in the District, if the obligor owes overdue support obligations in the amount of $1,000 or more.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency shall develop standards for consumer credit reporting that shall be consistent with credit reporting industry standards and reporting format.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A report of a support order shall include, at a minimum, the amount of the obligation, the amount paid, the amount overdue (if any), and the names of the obligor and obligee. The IV-D agency shall update this information on at least a quarterly basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency may publish information about an obligor whose support payments are more than $2,000 in arrears, including the obligor’s name, last known address, amount of overdue support, occupation, photograph, and physical description, and the names and ages of the individuals on behalf of whom support is owed. The publication may be made by disseminating the information using any media, or by any other means reasonably likely to assist in locating the obligor or to bring the obligor’s non-payment of support to the attention of the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency is responsible for the accuracy of information provided pursuant to this section. The information shall be based upon the data available at the time the information is provided to a consumer credit reporting agency. The IV-D agency and the credit reporting agency shall follow reasonable procedures to ensure accuracy of the information provided. The IV-D agency shall not be liable for any consequences of the failure of an obligor to contest the accuracy of the information within the time allowed under subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency shall send notice of the publication or initial consumer credit report by first-class mail to the last known address of the obligor at least 30 days before the publication or initial report. The notice shall inform the obligor of the right to contest the accuracy of the information to be released.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency shall provide the obligor with an opportunity to contest in writing the accuracy of the information in a consumer credit report or publication. If the IV-D agency receives a written objection contesting the accuracy of the information, the IV-D agency shall request the credit reporting agency receiving the information to note on the report that the information is being disputed, until the IV-D agency determines the accuracy of the information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The only grounds for contesting the accuracy of the information in a consumer credit report or publication are errors in the identities of the obligor or obligee, the amount of the support order, the amount of payment or arrears, or any other fact published or reported to the credit reporting agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-225_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The IV-D agency may enter into a cooperative agreement with another District government agency, the Superior Court, or a private entity to carry out all or part of the functions required of the IV-D agency under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
