<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-353.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-353.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_46_353_05">
        <akn:num>46-353.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties and powers of responding tribunal.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-353_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a responding tribunal of the District receives a petition or comparable pleading from an initiating tribunal or directly pursuant to ยง 46-353.01(b), it shall cause the petition or pleading to be filed and notify the petitioner where and when it was filed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-353_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A responding tribunal of the District, to the extent not prohibited by other law, may do one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-353_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A responding tribunal of the District shall include in a support order issued under this chapter, or in the documents accompanying the order, the calculations on which the support order is based.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-353_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A responding tribunal of the District may not condition the payment of a support order issued under this chapter upon compliance by a party with provisions for visitation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-353_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a responding tribunal of the District issues an order under this chapter, the tribunal shall send a copy of the order to the petitioner and the respondent and to the initiating tribunal, if any.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-353_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If requested to enforce a support order, arrears, or judgment or modify a support order stated in a foreign currency, a responding tribunal of the District shall convert the amount stated in the foreign currency to the equivalent amount in dollars under the applicable official or market exchange rate as publicly reported.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
