<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-351.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-351.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_46_351_02">
        <akn:num>46-351.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child” means an individual, whether over or under the age of majority, who is or is alleged to be owed a duty of support by the individual’s parent or who is or is alleged to be the beneficiary of a support order directed to the parent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-support order” means a support order for a child, including a child who has attained the age of majority under the law of the issuing state or foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Convention” means the Convention on the International Recovery of Child Support and Other Forms of Family Maintenance, concluded at The Hague on November 23, 2007.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Duty of support” means an obligation imposed or imposable by law to provide support for a child, spouse, or former spouse, including an unsatisfied obligation to provide support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign country” means a country, including a political subdivision thereof, other than the United States, that authorizes the issuance of support orders and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign support order” means a support order of a foreign tribunal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign tribunal” means a court, administrative agency, or quasi-judicial entity of a foreign country which is authorized to establish, enforce, or modify support orders or to determine parentage of a child. The term includes a competent authority under the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home state” means the state or foreign country in which a child lived with a parent or a person acting as parent for at least 6 consecutive months immediately preceding the time of filing of a petition or comparable pleading for support and, if a child is less than six months old, the state or foreign country in which the child lived from birth with any of them. A period of temporary absence of any of them is counted as part of the six-month or other period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Income” includes earnings or other periodic entitlements to money from any source and any other property subject to withholding for support under the law of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Income-withholding order” means an order or other legal process directed to an obligor’s holder, as defined by § 46-201(11), to withhold support from the income of the obligor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Initiating tribunal” means the tribunal of a state or foreign country from which a petition or comparable pleading is forwarded or in which a petition or comparable pleading is filed for forwarding to another state or foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuing foreign country” means the foreign country in which a tribunal issues a support order or a judgment determining parentage of a child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuing state” means the state in which a tribunal issues a support order or a judgment determining parentage of a child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuing tribunal” means the tribunal of a state or foreign country that issues a support order or a judgment determining parentage of a child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Law” includes decisional and statutory law and rules and regulations having the force of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Obligee” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Obligor” means an individual, or the estate of a decedent that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Office of the Attorney General” means the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Outside the District” means a location in another state or a country other than the United States, whether or not the country is a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Register” means to file in a tribunal of the District a support order or judgment determining parentage of a child issued in another state or a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Registering tribunal” means a tribunal in which a support order or judgment determining parentage of a child is registered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Responding state” means a state in which a petition or comparable pleading for support or to determine parentage of a child is filed or to which a petition or comparable pleading is forwarded for filing from another state or a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Responding tribunal” means the authorized tribunal in a responding state or foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Spousal-support order” means a support order for a spouse or former spouse of the obligor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession under the jurisdiction of the United States. The term includes an Indian nation or tribe.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Support enforcement agency” means a public official, governmental entity, or private agency authorized to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Support order” means a judgment, decree, order, decision, or directive, whether temporary, final, or subject to modification, issued in a state or foreign country for the benefit of a child, a spouse, or a former spouse, which provides for monetary support, health care, arrearages, retroactive support, or reimbursement for financial assistance provided to an individual obligee in place of child support. The term may include related costs and fees, interest, income withholding, automatic adjustment, reasonable attorney’s fees, and other relief.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-351_02_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tribunal” means a court, administrative agency, or quasi-judicial entity authorized to establish, enforce, or modify support orders or to determine parentage of a child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
