<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-356.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-356.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_46_356_02">
        <akn:num>46-356.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Procedure to register order for enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-356_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in ยง 46-357.06, a support order or income-withholding order of another state or a foreign support order may be registered in the District by sending the following records to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-356_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On receipt of a request for registration, the registering tribunal shall cause the order to be filed as an order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign support order, together with one copy of the documents and information, regardless of their form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-356_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A petition or comparable pleading seeking a remedy that must be affirmatively sought under other law of the District may be filed at the same time as the request for registration or later. The pleading must specify the grounds for the remedy sought.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-356_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If two or more orders are in effect, the person requesting registration shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-356_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A request for a determination of which is the controlling order may be filed separately or with a request for registration and enforcement or for registration and modification. The person requesting registration shall give notice of the request to each party whose rights may be affected by the determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
