<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-352.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/46-352.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_46_352_07">
        <akn:num>46-352.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Determination of controlling child-support order.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a proceeding is brought under this chapter and only one tribunal has issued a child-support order, the order of that tribunal controls and must be recognized.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a proceeding is brought under this chapter, and 2 or more child-support orders have been issued by tribunals of the District, of another state, or a foreign country with regard to the same obligor and same child, a tribunal of the District having personal jurisdiction over both the obligor and individual obligee shall apply the following rules and by order shall determine which order controls and must be recognized:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If 2 or more child-support orders have been issued for the same obligor and same child, upon request of a party who is an individual or that is a support enforcement agency, a tribunal of the District having personal jurisdiction over both the obligor and the obligee who is an individual shall determine which order controls under subsection (b) of this section. The request may be filed with a registration for enforcement or registration for modification pursuant to subchapter VI of this chapter [ยง 46-356.01 et seq.], or may be filed as a separate proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A request to determine which is the controlling order must be accompanied by a copy of every child-support order in effect and the applicable record of payments. The requesting party shall give notice of the request to each party whose rights may be affected by the determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The tribunal that issued the controlling order under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section has continuing jurisdiction to the extent provided in ยง 46-352.05 or ยง 46-352.06.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A tribunal of the District that determines by order which is the controlling order under subsection (b)(1) or (2) or (c) of this section, or that issues a new controlling order under subsection (b)(3) of this section, shall state in that order:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 30 days after issuance of an order determining which is the controlling order, the party obtaining the order shall file a certified copy of it in each tribunal that issued or registered an earlier order of child support. A party or support enforcement agency obtaining the order that fails to file a certified copy is subject to appropriate sanctions by a tribunal in which the issue of failure to file arises. The failure to file does not affect the validity or enforceability of the controlling order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46-352_07_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order that has been determined to be the controlling order, or a judgment for consolidated arrears of support and interest, if any, made pursuant to this section must be recognized in proceedings under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
