<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1033"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1033/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1033">
        <akn:num>6-1033</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Commission; report.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1033_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall review the operations and administration of the Department of Housing and Community Development (“Department”) and recommend to the Council and the Mayor legislative, regulatory, and administrative changes to improve the operation and administration of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1033_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before the first meeting of the Commission, the Director shall provide to the members of the Commission copies of all relevant studies, reports, correspondence, memoranda, and strategic plans maintained by the Department and completed within the previous 3 years which are related to matters within the purview of the Commission. The documents provided shall include notifications, correspondence, and reports from or to the Department of Housing and Urban Development, reports of the Inspector General, Department spending plans; Department strategic plans, Department policies and manuals, and correspondence with the Council, Council committees, and members of the Council. The Commission may request additional documents pursuant to § 6-1034(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1033_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall provide an assessment or recommendations on the following issues:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1033_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In making recommendations under subsections (a) and (c) of this section, the Commission shall review best practices in other jurisdictions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1033_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall not supersede the Consolidated Plan review and development process or the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1033_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 150 days after the first meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall issue a final report setting forth its recommendations pursuant to this section. The Commission may issue interim reports at the discretion of the Commission. The Commission shall transmit a copy of each report to the Mayor, the Chairman of the Council, and the chairperson of the Council Committee on Economic Development, and the Director.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
