<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1002"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1002/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1002">
        <akn:num>6-1002</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Community Development Program — Annual preparation and submission to Council; content; public hearings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1002_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor annually shall prepare and submit to the Council a proposed Community Development Program (as such program is defined or may hereafter be defined in title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [42 U.S.C. § 5301 et seq.], which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1002_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In preparing the proposed Community Development Program, the Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1002_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to the exercise of any powers granted by this subchapter, the Mayor shall have submitted the proposed Community Development Program to the Council, and the Council shall have approved the same by resolution following a public hearing thereon; provided, that the Council may approve the program with conditions and the program as so conditioned shall be the approved Community Development Program; and provided further, that an approved Community Development Program may be modified at any time in accordance with the procedures herein prescribed for its original approval. Notwithstanding the above, the Mayor shall have the authority to make minor modifications consistent with the intent of the approved program, only after such modifications have been submitted to the Council and have not been disapproved within 30 days, except that the Council may approve such modifications before the 30-day period has expired. The 30-day period for Council review shall not include Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, or days that pass during a recess of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
