<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1104"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1104/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1104">
        <akn:num>6-1104</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Demolitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before the Mayor may issue a permit to demolish an historic landmark or a building or structure in an historic district, the Mayor shall review the permit application in accordance with this section and place notice of the application in the District of Columbia Register.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to making the finding required by subsection (e) of this section, the Mayor may refer the application to the Historic Preservation Review Board for a recommendation, but shall so refer all applications that are not subject to review by the Commission of Fine Arts under the Old Georgetown Act (ยง 6-1201 et seq.). The Mayor shall consider any recommendation by the Review Board or by the Commission of Fine Arts pursuant to such referral.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days after the Review Board receives the referral, the Mayor shall, after a public hearing, make the finding required by subsection (e) of this section; provided, that the Mayor may make such finding without a public hearing in the case of a building or structure in an historic district or on the site of an historic landmark if the Review Board or Commission of Fine Arts has advised in its recommendation that the building or structure does not contribute to the historic district or the historic landmark.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Review Board recommends against granting the permit, it shall promptly notify the applicant in writing of its recommendation and the reasons therefor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No permit shall be issued unless the Mayor finds that issuance of the permit is necessary in the public interest, or that failure to issue a permit will result in unreasonable economic hardship to the owner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner shall submit at the hearing such information as is relevant and necessary to support his application.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1104_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In those cases in which the Mayor finds that the demolition is necessary to allow the construction of a project of special merit, no demolition permit shall be issued unless a permit for new construction is issued simultaneously under ยง 6-1107 and the owner demonstrates the ability to complete the project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
