<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1103"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1103/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1103">
        <akn:num>6-1103</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Historic Preservation Review Board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1103_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to establish an Historic Preservation Review Board comprised of nine members who shall be confirmed by the Council of the District of Columbia. The Review Board shall be constituted and its members qualified so as to meet the requirements of a State Review Board under regulations issued by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to the Act of October 15, 1966 (16 U.S.C. § 470 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1103_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section, all appointments to the Historic Preservation Review Board shall be made with a view toward having its membership represent to the greatest practicable extent the composition of the adult population of the District of Columbia with regard to race, sex, geographic distribution and other demographic characteristics. The term of office of each member of the Review Board shall be 3 years, staggered so that one third of the appointments expire each year. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his or her predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. Upon expiration of his or her term of office, a member shall continue to serve until his or her successor is appointed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1103_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Review Board shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1103_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
