<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1102"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1102/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1102">
        <akn:num>6-1102</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Alter” or “alteration” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commission of Fine Arts” means the United States Commission of Fine Arts established pursuant to the Act of May 17, 1910 (40 U.S.C. § 104).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Demolish” or “demolition” means the razing or destruction, entirely or in significant part, of a building or structure and includes the removal or destruction of any facade of a building or structure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Demolition by neglect” means neglect in maintaining, repairing, or securing an historic landmark or a building or structure in an historic district that results in substantial deterioration of an exterior feature of the building or structure or the loss of the structural integrity of the building or structure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Design” means exterior architectural features including height, appearance, texture, color, and nature of materials.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District of Columbia undertaking” means a project of the District of Columbia government, a public charter school as defined in § 38-1800.02(29), or any other entity not part of the District of Columbia government, that involves or contemplates subdivision of or demolition, alteration, or new construction on a property owned by or under the jurisdiction of the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Historic district” means an historic district:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Historic landmark” means a building, structure, object, or feature, and its site, or a site:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Historic Preservation Office” or “HPO” means the administrative office that serves as the staff to the Historic Preservation Review Board, State Historic Preservation Officer, and Mayor in performing functions pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Historic Preservation Review Board” or “Review Board” means the Board designated pursuant to § 6-1103 and pursuant to regulations promulgated by the United States Secretary of the Interior under the Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (16 U.S.C. § 470 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia, or his designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“National Register of Historic Places” or “National Register” means that national record of districts, sites, buildings, structures, and objects significant in American history, architecture, archaeology, and culture established pursuant to the Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (16 U.S.C. § 470a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Necessary in the public interest” means consistent with the purposes of this subchapter as set forth in § 6-1101(b) or necessary to allow the construction of a project of special merit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_10A">
      <akn:num>(10A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public safety facility” means a fire station, police station, or any other building or structure owned by the District of Columbia used for public safety operations, but excludes facilities used primarily for administrative functions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Special merit” means a plan or building having significant benefits to the District of Columbia or to the community by virtue of exemplary architecture, specific features of land planning, or social or other benefits having a high priority for community services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State Historic Preservation Officer” or “SHPO” means the person designated by the Mayor to administer the National Register Program within the District of Columbia established pursuant to the Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (16 U.S.C. § 470 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subdivide” or “subdivision” means the division or assembly of land into 1 or more lots of record, including the division of any lot of record into 2 or more theoretical building sites as provided by the Zoning Regulations of the District of Columbia (11 DCMR 2516 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1102_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unreasonable economic hardship” means that failure to issue a permit would amount to a taking of the owner’s property without just compensation or, in the case of a low-income owner(s) as determined by the Mayor, failure to issue a permit would place an onerous and excessive financial burden upon such owner(s).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
