<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1315"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1315/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1315">
        <akn:num>6-1315</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Application of travel restrictions to personnel of certain countries and organizations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1315_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Requirement for restrictions. — The Secretary shall apply the same generally applicable restrictions to the travel while in the United States of the individuals described in subsection (b) as are applied under this title to the members of the missions of the Soviet Union in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1315_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Individuals subject to restrictions. — The restrictions required by subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to those individuals who (as determined by the Secretary) are:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1315_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Waivers. — The Secretary, after consultation with the Director of Central Intelligence and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, may waive application of the restrictions required by subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States so require.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1315_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reports. — The Secretary shall transmit to the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, not later than six months after December 23, 1987, and not later than every six months thereafter, a report on the actions taken by the Secretary in carrying out this section during the previous six months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1315_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Definitions. — For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
