<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1304"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1304/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1304">
        <akn:num>6-1304</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Provision of benefits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1304_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the request of a foreign mission, benefits may be provided to or for that foreign mission by or through the Director on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may approve.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1304_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Secretary determines that such action is reasonably necessary on the basis of reciprocity or otherwise:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1304_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Terms and conditions established by the Secretary under this section may include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1304_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of effectuating a waiver of recourse which is required under this section, the Secretary may designate the Director or any other officer of the Department of State as the agent of a foreign mission (or of any assignee of or person deriving rights from a foreign mission). Any such waiver by an officer so designated shall for all purposes (including any court or administrative proceeding) be deemed to be a waiver by the foreign mission (or the assignee of or other person deriving rights from a foreign mission).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1304_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to preclude or limit in any way the authority of the United States Secret Service to provide protective services pursuant to § 3056 or § 3056A of Title 18, United States Code, at a level commensurate with protective requirements as determined by the United States Secret Service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
