<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1313"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1313/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1313">
        <akn:num>6-1313</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Extraordinary protective services.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>General authority. — The Secretary may provide extraordinary protective services for foreign missions directly, by contract, or through state or local authority to the extent deemed necessary by the Secretary in carrying out this chapter, except that the Secretary may not provide under this section any protective services for which authority exists to provide such services under § 3056A(a)(7) and (d) of Title 18, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Requirement of extraordinary circumstances. — The Secretary may provide funds to a state or local authority for protective services under this section only if the Secretary has determined that a threat of violence, or other circumstances, exists which requires extraordinary security measures which exceed those which local law enforcement agencies can reasonably be expected to take.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consultation with Congress before obligation of funds. — Funds may be obligated under this section only after regulations to implement this section have been issued by the Secretary after consultation with appropriate committees of the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Restrictions on use of funds. — Of the funds made available for obligation under this section in any fiscal year:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Period of agreement with state or local authority. — Any agreement with a state or local authority for the provision of protective services under this section shall be for a period of not to exceed 90 days in any calendar year, but such agreements may be renewed after review by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Requirement for appropriations. — Contracts may be entered into in carrying out this section only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation acts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1313_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Working capital fund. — Amounts used to carry out this section shall not be subject to § 6-1308(h).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
