<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1451.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-1451.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_1451_01">
        <akn:num>6-1451.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Addition” has the same meaning as in § 6-1410(a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Applicant” means any individual, firm, limited liability company, association, partnership, government agency, public or private corporation, or other entity that submits construction documents for a building permit or verification.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bond” means a financial instrument posted by an applicant, the proceeds of which shall be paid to the District in its entirety or in part, and deposited in the Green Building Fund, if the project fails to meet the standards required by §§ 6-1451.03 and 6-1451.06.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Building” means any structure used or intended for supporting or sheltering any use or occupancy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Building systems monitoring method” means the specifications for a methodology of collecting information and providing feedback about installed equipment that provide data for the comparison, management, and optimization of actual, as compared to estimated, energy performance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Certificate of occupancy” means the first certificate of occupancy issued for a usable, habitable space at grade or above grade.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_5B">
      <akn:num>(5B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Common space” means gross floor area within a project shared or available for common use by various occupancies within a project that includes both residential and nonresidential occupancies, including lobbies, corridors, stairways, amenity areas, laundry rooms, boiler rooms, furnace rooms, generator rooms, elevator hoistways, mechanical duct shafts, elevator machine rooms, off-street loading facilities, and off-street parking facilities at or above grade.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Construction Codes” means the standards and requirements adopted pursuant to Chapter 14 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Construction documents” has the same meaning as in § 6-1405.02(a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Construction permit application” has the same meaning as in § 6-1410(a)(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Current edition” means the most recent and currently operative edition of a green building standard approved under § 6-1451.11(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DCRA” means the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_9A">
      <akn:num>(9A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DDOE” means the District Department of the Environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_10A">
      <akn:num>(10A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District-financed” or “District instrumentality-financed” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Educational facility” means any building that has the provision of education as its primary use.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“ENERGY STAR Portfolio Manager” means the tool developed by EPA ENERGY STAR that rates the performance of a qualifying building, relative to similar buildings nationwide, accounting for the impacts of year-to-year weather variations, building size, location, and several operating characteristics, using the Environmental Protection Agency’s national energy performance rating system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“ENERGY STAR Target Finder” means the tool developed by EPA ENERGY STAR that helps set performance goals and energy ratings for building projects during their design phase.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Existing building” has the same meaning as in § 6-1410(a)(8).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_14A">
      <akn:num>(14A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“First building permit” means the first permit intended to cover the primary scope of work for a project; provided, that this shall not include permit applications for raze, sheeting and shoring, foundation, or specialty, miscellaneous, or supplemental permits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Full-building commissioning” means the process of verification that a building’s energy related systems are installed, calibrated, and perform according to project requirements, design basis, and construction documents. The systems that require commissioning include mechanical and passive heating, ventilation, air conditioning, and refrigeration systems, and associated controls such as lighting, domestic hot water systems, and renewable energy systems.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“GBAC” means the Green Building Advisory Council established by § 6-1451.09.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Green building” means an integrated, whole-building approach to the planning, design, construction, operation, and maintenance of buildings and their surrounding landscapes that help mitigate the environmental, economic, and social impacts of buildings, so that they are energy efficient, sustainable, safe, cost-effective, accessible, healthy, and productive.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Green building checklist” means a scorecard developed by the USGBC for the purpose of calculating a score on the appropriate LEED rating system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Green Building Fund” or “Fund” means the Green Building Fund established by § 6-1451.07.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Green Communities” means the national green building program designed by Enterprise Community Partners that provides criteria for the design, development, and operation of affordable housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross floor area” has the same definition as found in section 199.1 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (11 DCMR § 199.1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“HVAC&amp;R” means mechanical and passive heating, ventilation, air conditioning, and refrigeration systems.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“ICC” means the International Code Council, a nonprofit organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“IECC” means the International Energy Conservation Code developed by the ICC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“LEED” means the series of Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design green building rating systems designed by the USGBC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“LEED-H” means the LEED for New Homes (LEED-H) green building rating system being designed by the USGBC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_31A">
      <akn:num>(31A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“LEED standard for commercial and institutional buildings” means the green building rating system designed by the USGBC for Core &amp; Shell, New Construction, Schools, and Retail: New Construction &amp; Major Renovations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Maintenance accountability method” means a system for maintaining building performance standards, including annual building performance reporting that publicly compares actual energy consumption to benchmarks using the ENERGY STAR Portfolio Manager tool for all building types for which it is available; the description of changes to operations and maintenance arrangements and procedures for major energy-consuming equipment; the maintenance of manuals, manufacturer’s literature, model numbers, methods of operation, and maintenance practices for installed building systems; the records of metering systems and mechanisms for the monitoring and control of energy consumption; and the collection of complete “as-built” drawing sets and information on best practices for building maintenance, housekeeping, pest management, and mold prevention.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_32A">
      <akn:num>(32A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mixed-use space” means demised space in any residential project that contains at least 50,000 contiguous square feet of gross floor area, exclusive of common space, that is or would be occupied for a nonresidential use.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“New construction” means the construction of any building whether as a stand-alone building or an addition to an existing building. The term “new construction” includes new buildings and additions or enlargements of existing buildings, exclusive of any alterations or repairs to any existing portion of a building.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_33A">
      <akn:num>(33A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonresidential” means any project in which at least 50% of the gross floor area of the project, subject to allocation of area for common space, has nonresidential purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Project” means the construction of single or multiple buildings that are part of one development scheme, built at one time or in phases.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property disposition by lease” means a lease, inclusive of options, of real property, as defined in § 10-801.01, for a period of greater than 20 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property disposition by sale” means a sale of real property, as defined in § 10-801.01, in whole or in part, to the highest bidder for real property 10,000 square feet or more.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public school” means schools owned, operated, or maintained by the District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”), or a public charter school, and those schools’ educational facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_39A">
      <akn:num>(39A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential” means any project in which more than 50% of the gross floor area of the project, subject to allocation for common space, is used for residential purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Substantial improvement” means any repair, alteration, addition, or improvement of a building or structure, the cost of which equals or exceeds 50% of the market value of the structure before the improvement or repair is started.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Total project cost” means the total of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“USGBC” means the United States Green Building Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-1451_01_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Verification” or “verified” means confirmation by an entity described in § 6-1451.04 that the green building requirements of this chapter have been fulfilled.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
