<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-201"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-201/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_201">
        <akn:num>6-201</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Act” means this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apprehension” means the act of seizing or arresting a suspect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Area median income” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Arrest” means the act of seizing and charging a suspect with the commission of a crime or violation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Authority” means the District of Columbia Housing Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Board” means the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia Housing Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Book” means to enter an official charge against an arrested suspect on a police register.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capper/Carrollsburg Public Improvements” means the infrastructure, including streets, sidewalks, walkways, streetscapes, curbs, gutters, and gas, electric, and water utility lines, and other publicly-owned infrastructure, and the relocation, construction, and redevelopment of certain public facilities located within or serving the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area designated pursuant to § 47-4611.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Central labor council” means the regional umbrella federation of all local AFL-CIO unions, including most of the private, federal, and public sector unions in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chief Financial Officer” or “CFO” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District as established by § 1-204.24a(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“City-Wide Resident Council Advisory Board” means the group consisting of the President of each Resident Council and not more than 15 members selected by the residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means a member of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Day” or “Days” means a calendar day or days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_13A">
      <akn:num>(13A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Development costs” means all costs and expenses incurred by or on behalf of the District of Columbia or the Authority relating to the development, redevelopment, purchase, acquisition, protection, financing, construction, expansion, reconstruction, restoration, rehabilitation, renovation, repair, furnishing, equipping, and operating of the Capper/Carrollsburg Public Improvements, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DCHAPD” means the District of Columbia Housing Authority Police Department, the duly constituted police department of the District of Columbia Housing Authority established under § 6-223.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District government” means the Government of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_16A">
      <akn:num>(16A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 32-701(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DPAH” means the former Department of Public and Assisted Housing of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Execute” means to carry out or perform all necessary formalities to effect or enforce the directions of a court order, court decree, or warrant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Executive Director” means the Executive Director of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_19A">
      <akn:num>(19A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Extremely-low income” means an individual or family whose gross income does not exceed 30% of the area median income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_19B">
      <akn:num>(19B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“For-profit activities” means ancillary activities to the main activities of the District of Columbia Housing Authority, such as retail, commercial office, manufacturing, or recreational real property development activities undertaken by for-profit entities intended to support or contribute to the financial viability of Housing Properties, but does not include residential real property development activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fund” means the District of Columbia Housing Authority Fund established by § 6-202.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“General Counsel” means the Officer employed as the general counsel of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“General Population Housing” means a housing community that includes or may include non-elderly singles, families, residents with disabilities, and elderly residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing Act of 1937” means the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved September 1, 1937 (50 Stat. 888; 42 U.S.C. § 1401 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_23A">
      <akn:num>(23A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing Choice Voucher Program” means the federal housing program authorized by section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved September 1, 1937 (50 Stat. 888; 42 U.S.C. § 1437(f) et seq.), and administered in the District of Columbia by the District of Columbia Housing Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing Finance Agency” or “HFA” means the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency established by the Housing Finance Agency Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing Finance Agency Act” means Chapter 27 of Title 42 of the D.C. Official Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing Property” or “Housing Properties” means housing and related facilities for persons of low- and moderate-income, including housing and related facilities for the elderly, and housing and related facilities for people with disabilities; and housing, community facilities, and other properties intended to support or contribute to the financial viability of such housing and related facilities: (A) owned, operated, or managed by the Authority, or (B) the development or administration of which is assisted by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“HUD” means the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low-income families” or “persons of low-income” means families or persons whose incomes do not exceed 80% of the median area income in and for the Washington Metropolitan Area or shall be such other meaning as shall be established by HUD in the Housing Act of 1937.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Members of the DCHAPD” means those persons who are employed as police officers and special police officers by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Metropolitan Police Department” means the District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department or Metropolitan Police Force.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mixed-Income Community” means a housing development which includes rental or homeownership units made available to persons or families of varying incomes and which includes Public-Housing-Assisted Units.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mixed Population Housing” means a housing community that includes elderly and non-elderly residents with disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Moderate-income families” or “persons of moderate-income” means families or persons whose incomes do not exceed 115% of the median area income in and for the Washington Metropolitan Area, or shall have such other meaning as may from time to time be established by HUD in the Housing Act of 1937.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Obligations” means revenue bonds, notes, mortgages, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, or other obligations) to finance or refinance the undertakings of the Authority pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Officer” means an Authority employee who is in a decision-making or supervisory position.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_36A">
      <akn:num>(36A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partnership Program for Affordable Housing” means the District of Columbia Housing Authority Program described in Chapter 93 of Title 14 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personnel Act” means Chapter 6 of Title 1 of the D.C. Official Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Power of arrest” means the ability to seize and arrest an alleged or suspected offender to answer for a crime.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Procurement Act” means Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2 of the D.C. Official Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_39A">
      <akn:num>(39A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Project-based voucher assistance” means funds attached to a particular building, or set of buildings, owned and operated by a private or nonprofit housing provider.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public Employee Relations Board” or “PERB” means the District of Columbia Public Employee Relations Board established under § 1-605.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public-Housing-Assisted Unit” means any unit that is developed, operated, or maintained in whole or in part with federally-appropriated housing funds, including capital or revitalization funds and operating subsidy funds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Receiver” means the receiver appointed to oversee the District of Columbia Housing Authority, operating pursuant to the order entered in Pearson v. Kelly, 92-CA-14030 (Sup. Ct. D.C. May 19, 1995).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_42A">
      <akn:num>(42A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Rent Supplement Program” means the program established under § 6-226 to provide housing assistance to extremely low-income District residents, including those who are homeless and those in need of supportive services, such as elderly individuals or those with disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident” means any individual who resides in a dwelling unit in a Public-Housing Assisted Unit as a signatory on a lease for said dwelling unit; is identified on the lease as a member of the family of the individual who is the signatory on the lease; or is a resident as defined in the Housing Act of 1937.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_43A">
      <akn:num>(43A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sponsor-based voucher assistance” means funds allocated under contract to a particular private or nonprofit housing provider to subsidize the rent, in units owned and operated by the provider, for a maximum number of households established by contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_43B">
      <akn:num>(43B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Supportive housing” means housing provided in connection with voluntary services designed primarily to help tenants maintain housing, including coordination or case management, physical and mental health, substance use management and recovery support, job training, literacy and education, youth and children’s programs, and money management.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-201_44">
      <akn:num>(44)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Weapon” means an instrument or device for offensive or defensive combat, or anything used, or designed to be used, for the purpose of harming, threatening, damaging, or injuring a person or property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
