<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-227"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-227/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_227">
        <akn:num>6-227</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-227_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds allocated under the program for project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance shall be awarded by the Authority pursuant to its Partnership Program For Affordable Housing, except as otherwise provided herein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-227_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall promulgate rules to govern the awarding of rent supplement funds through Partnership Program grants, as described in this section, to providers of sponsor-based housing. The Authority shall designate a portion of these funds to be awarded on a priority basis to sponsors of supportive housing for individuals with special needs. The rules may address eligibility, admission, and occupancy criteria, which serve the supportive housing goals of the housing development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-227_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall apply its existing Partnership Program rules to govern the awarding of Partnership Program grants for project-based voucher assistance and the continuing eligibility for such grants under this section, except where such rules are inconsistent with this legislation. The Authority shall also apply its existing Partnership Program and Housing Choice Voucher Program rules to govern eligibility, admission, and continuing occupancy by tenants in units receiving assistance under this section, ยง 6-226, and ยง 6-228, except if the rules are inconsistent with this section, ยง 6-226, and ยง 6-228. The Authority shall promulgate such additional rules as are necessary to ensure that eligibility for tenancy in the units supported by grants under this section is limited to households with gross income at or below 30% of the area median income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-227_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To maintain consistency for households receiving rental housing support, the Authority shall, to the extent possible, given funding resources available in the Rent Supplement Program, continue to fund project-based and sponsor-based grantees at the same level, adjusted for inflation, on an annual basis, unless the Authority determines that a grantee is not meeting the criteria set forth in the rules governing the Partnership Program or is not adhering to other standards set forth by rule by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-227_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
