<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-226"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-226/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_226">
        <akn:num>6-226</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rent Supplement Program: establishment of program and distribution of funds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-226_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Rent Supplement Program is established to provide housing assistance to extremely low-income District residents, including those who are homeless and those in need of supportive services, such as elderly individuals or those with disabilities. The funding of this program is subject to appropriation. The Authority shall administer the program and shall promulgate rules for its implementation. The assistance under this section, § 6-227, and § 6-228 shall not constitute an entitlement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-226_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall allocate the funds appropriated for the program annually toward project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance, as described in § 6-227, tenant-based assistance, as described in § 6-228, and capital-based assistance, as described in § 6-229.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-226_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall promulgate rules, subject to Council approval, as required in §§ 6-227 and 6-228, which shall govern the distribution of funds under this program. If federal rules affect local funds, the Authority shall incorporate such rules into the submission to the Council required under this section, § 6-227, and § 6-228, except if the rules are inconsistent with this section, § 6-227, and § 6-228. The rules shall provide for allocating project-based, tenant-based, and sponsor-based funds to maintain or create new affordable housing units, including by combining funds under this program with other sources of funds for housing production and development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-226_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-226_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
