<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-641.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-641.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_641_07">
        <akn:num>6-641.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Board of Zoning Adjustment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Board of Zoning Adjustment is hereby created which shall be composed of 1 member of the National Capital Planning Commission or a member of the staff thereof to be designated in either case by such Commission and appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia; 1 member of the Zoning Commission or a member of the staff thereof to be designated in either case by such Commission and appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia; and 3 other members appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, each of whom shall have been a resident of the District of Columbia for at least 3 years immediately preceding his appointment and at least 1 of whom shall own his own home.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The representative of the National Capital Planning Commission may be changed from time to time by such Commission in its discretion and in case of a vacancy in the position by death, resignation, or other disability, a new representative shall be designated by the said Commission and appointed by the Commissioners of the District of Columbia to fill said vacancy. The representative of the Zoning Commission may be changed from time to time by such Commission in its discretion and in case of a vacancy in the position by death, resignation, or other disability, a new representative shall be designated by the said Commission and appointed by the Commissioners of the District of Columbia to fill said vacancy. The terms of the 3 members appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia shall be 3 years each, excepting that, in the case of the initial appointments, 1 shall be for a term of 1 year and one for a term of 2 years. In case of any vacancy in the position of any of the 3 members appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, the same shall be filled for the remainder of the term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Zoning Commission may provide and specify in its zoning regulations general rules to govern the organization and procedure of the Board of Adjustment not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, and the Board of Adjustment may adopt supplemental rules of procedure which shall be subject to the approval of the Zoning Commission after public hearing thereon as provided in § 6-641.03. The Board of Adjustment shall choose its Chairman and its other officers. All meetings of the Board shall be open to the public. The Board shall keep minutes of its proceedings showing the vote of each member upon each question, or if absent or failing to vote indicating such fact, and shall keep records of its examinations and other official actions, all of which shall be immediately filed in the office of the Board and shall be a public record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The regulations adopted by the Zoning Commission may provide that the Board of Adjustment may in appropriate cases and subject to appropriate principles, standards, rules, conditions, and safeguards set forth in the regulations, make special exceptions to the provisions of the zoning regulations in harmony with their general purpose and intent. The Commission may also authorize the Board of Adjustment to interpret the zoning maps and pass upon disputed questions of lot lines or district boundary lines or similar questions as they arise in the administration of the regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Adjustment shall not have the power to amend any regulation or map.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appeals to the Board of Adjustment may be taken by any person aggrieved, or organization authorized to represent such person, or by any officer or department of the government of the District of Columbia or the federal government affected, by any decision of the Inspector of Buildings granting or refusing a building permit or granting or withholding a certificate of occupancy, or any other administrative decision based in whole or in part upon any zoning regulation or map adopted under this subchapter. The Mayor of the District of Columbia may require and fix the fee to be charged for an appeal, which fee shall be paid, as directed by said Mayor, with the filing of the appeal; provided, that no citizens’ association, or association created for civic purposes and not for profit shall be required to pay said fee. There shall be a public hearing on appeal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon appeals the Board of Adjustment shall have the following powers:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The concurring vote of not less than a full majority of the members of the Board shall be necessary for any decision or order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-641_07_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing herein contained shall prohibit the Zoning Commission from providing by regulation for appeals to it from any action of the Board of Zoning Adjustment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
