<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-805"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/6-805/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_6_805">
        <akn:num>6-805</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Cost of work performed by Mayor assessed against property; violation of §§ 6-801 to 6-803; costs of correcting life-or-health threatening condition.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-805_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall determine the cost and expense of any work performed by him under the authority of §§ 6-801 to 6-804, including the cost of making good damage to adjoining premises (except such as may have resulted from carelessness and willful recklessness in the demolition or removal of any structure) less the amount, if any, received from the sale of old material, and shall assess such costs and expense upon the lot or ground whereon such structure, excavation, or nuisance stands, stood, was dug, was located, or existed, and this amount shall be collected in the manner provided in § 6-806. Any person, corporation, partnership, syndicate, or company subject to the provisions of §§ 6-801 to 6-803 who shall neglect or refuse to perform any act required by such sections shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $50 for each and every day said person, corporation, partnership, syndicate, or company fails to perform any act required by such sections. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction by any person, corporation, partnership, syndicate, or company subject to the provisions of §§ 6-801 through 6-803 who shall neglect or refuse to perform any act required by these sections, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6-805_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may assess all reasonable costs, including administrative costs, of correcting a life-or-health threatening condition pursuant to § 6-804(c) and all expenses incident thereto as a tax against the property, may carry this tax on the regular tax rolls, and may collect this tax in the same manner as real estate taxes are collected. Monies in the revolving fund established by § 6-711.01(b)(1) shall be available to cover the costs of correcting life-or-health threatening conditions. If an accounting is made in accordance with, and subject to, § 47-1340(f), any amounts assessed and collected as a tax against real property under this section shall be deposited to the credit of the revolving fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
