<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.16"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.16/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_16">
        <akn:num>1-1001.16</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Initiative and referendum process.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 20 calendar days, of the date on which the Board accepts an initiative or referendum measure, the Board shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After preparation, the Board shall adopt the summary statement, short title, and legislative form at a public meeting and shall within 5 days, notify the proposer of the measure of the exact language. In addition, the Board, within 5 days of adoption, shall submit the summary statement, short title, and legislative form to the District of Columbia Register for publication.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the summary statement, short title, and legislative form of an initiative or referendum measure has been established pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, the Board shall certify such and transmit a copy thereof by certified mail to the proposer. Thereafter, such short title shall be the title of the measure in all petitions, ballots, and other proceedings relating thereto. The Board shall, upon the request of any person, make single copies of the approved short title, summary statement, and full legislative text available at no charge. Additional copies shall be made available at a nominal cost.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon final establishment of the summary statement, short title, and legislative form of an initiative or referendum proposal, the Board shall prepare and provide to the proposer at a public meeting an original petition form which the proposer shall formally adopt as his or her own form. The proposer shall print from the original blank petition sheets on white paper of good writing quality of the same size as the original. Each initiative or referendum petition sheet shall consist of one double-sided sheet providing numbered lines for 20 printed names and signatures with residence addresses (street numbers) and ward numbers, and shall have printed on it, in a manner prescribed by the Board, the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each petition sheet for an initiative or referendum measure shall contain an affidavit, made under penalty of perjury, in a form determined by the Board and signed by the circulator of that petition sheet which contains the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order for any initiative or referendum measure to qualify for the ballot for consideration by the electors of the District of Columbia, the proposer of such an initiative or referendum measure shall secure the valid signatures of registered qualified electors upon the initiative or referendum measure equal in number to 5 percent of the registered electors in the District of Columbia: Provided, that the total signatures submitted include 5 percent of the registered electors in each of 5 or more of the 8 wards. The number of registered electors which is used for computing these requirements shall be consistent with the latest official count of registered electors made by the Board 30 days prior to the initial submission to the Board of the initiative or referendum measure, pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Board refuses to accept an initiative or referendum petition when submitted to it, the person or persons submitting such petition may apply, within 10 days after the Board’s refusal to accept such petition, to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for a writ in the nature of mandamus to compel the Board to accept such petition. The Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall expedite the consideration of the matter. If the Superior Court of the District of Columbia determines that the petition is legal in form and apparently meets the requirement for signatures, both as to number and as to ward distribution, prescribed in subsection (i) of this section, and was submitted within the time limitations established in subsection (j) of this section, and has attached to the petition the proper statements of the circulators prescribed in subsection (h) of this section, it shall issue an order requiring the Board to accept the petition as of the date of submission for filing. Should the Superior Court of the District of Columbia hold in favor of the proposer, it may award court costs and reasonable attorneys’ fees to the proposer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon submission of a referendum petition to the Board, the Board shall notify the appropriate custodian of the act of the Council of the District of Columbia which is the subject of the referendum (either the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives) as provided in §§ 1-204.04 and 1-204.46 and the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall, as appropriate, return such act or part or parts of such act to the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia. No further action may be taken upon such act until after a referendum election is held. If, however, after the counting and validation procedure for signatures, which takes place pursuant to subsection (o) of this section, the referendum measure fails to meet the percentage and distribution requirements for signatures established in subsection (i) of this section, the act which was the subject of the referendum shall be again transmitted to the Congress for review as provided in § 1-206.02(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the Board accepts an initiative or referendum petition, whether in the normal course or at the direction of a court, the Board may detach, in the presence of the person submitting the petition or his or her designated representative, if he or she desires to be present, the sheets containing the signatures, and cause all of them to be firmly attached to 1 or more printed copies of the proposed initiative or referendum measure in such books or volumes as will be most convenient for counting, canvassing, and validating names and signatures.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_16_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If provisions of 2 or more initiative or referendum measures which have been approved by the registered qualified electors at the same election conflict, the provisions of the measure receiving the highest number of affirmative votes shall prevail over the conflicting provision of the other measure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
