<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.09a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.09a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_09a">
        <akn:num>1-1001.09a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Post-election audits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After each general and special election, the Board shall conduct a public manual audit of the voter-verifiable records tabulated by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The precincts audited shall be selected on an entirely random basis; provided, that, within each ward, each precinct in the election shall have an equal chance of being selected. The voter-verifiable records that are tabulated centrally shall also be selected on an entirely random basis. The contests audited shall be selected on an entirely random basis; provided, that, within each category, each contest in the election shall have an equal chance of being selected. The Board shall publicly announce the method by which it intends to randomly select precincts, voter-verifiable records tabulated centrally, and contests, and shall conduct the random selection in such a way as to allow the public to observe and ensure that the selection is random. The selection shall be followed by the audit as soon as is practicable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The date of the audit shall be announced no later than 3 business days after tabulation has been completed, but no fewer than 24 hours in advance of the audit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The audit shall be conducted in public view so that members of the public are able to verify that votes are correctly classified and tallied, but are unable to touch ballots and other official materials or to interfere in any way with the manual audit process.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Individuals performing the manual audit shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The results derived from the manual audits shall be deemed the true and correct results of the election contests at issue with respect to the votes audited and shall be used in lieu of further counting in any automatic recounts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall publish on its website and make available for public inspection a report of results of the manual audit before certification of the official election results. The report shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_09a_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
