<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1051.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1051.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1051_01">
        <akn:num>1-1051.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enactment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1051_01_I">
      <akn:num>I</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>MEMBERSHIP Any State of the United States and the District of Columbia may become a member of this agreement by enacting this agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1051_01_II">
      <akn:num>II</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>RIGHT OF THE PEOPLE IN MEMBER STATES TO VOTE FOR PRESIDENT AND VICE PRESIDENT Each member state shall conduct a statewide popular election for President and Vice President of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1051_01_III">
      <akn:num>III</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>MANNER OF APPOINTING PRESIDENTIAL ELECTORS IN MEMBER STATES Prior to the time set by law for the meeting and voting by the presidential electors, the chief election official of each member state shall determine the number of votes for each presidential slate in each State of the United States and in the District of Columbia in which votes have been cast in a statewide popular election and shall add such votes together to produce a “national popular vote total” for each presidential slate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1051_01_IV">
      <akn:num>IV</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OTHER PROVISIONS This agreement shall take effect when states cumulatively possessing a majority of the electoral votes have enacted this agreement in substantially the same form and the enactments by such states have taken effect in each state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1051_01_V">
      <akn:num>V</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>DEFINITIONS For the purposes of this agreement, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
