<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_08">
        <akn:num>1-1001.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Qualifications of candidates and electors; nomination and election of Delegate, Chairman of the Council, members of Council, Mayor, Attorney General, and members of State Board of Education; petition requirements; arrangement of ballot.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each political party which had in the next preceding election year at least 7,500 votes cast in the general election for a candidate of the party to the office of Delegate, Chairman of the Council, member of the Council, Mayor, or Attorney General, shall be entitled to elect candidates for presidential electors, provided that the party has met all deadlines set out in this subchapter or by regulation for the submission of a party plan for the election. The executive committee of the organization recognized by the national committee of each such party as the official organization of that party in the District of Columbia shall nominate by appropriate means the presidential electors for that party. Nominations shall be made by message to the Board on or before September 1st next preceding a presidential election.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The names of the candidates of each political party for President and Vice President shall be placed on the ballot under the title and device, if any, of that party as designated by the duly authorized committee of the organization recognized by the national committee of that party as the official organization of that party in the District. The form of the ballot shall be determined by that Board. The position on the ballot of names of candidates for President and Vice President shall be determined by lot. The names of persons nominated as candidates for electors of President and Vice President shall not appear on the ballot.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A political party which does not qualify under subsection (d) of this section may have the names of its candidates for President and Vice President of the United States printed on the general election ballot provided a petition nominating the appropriate number of candidates for presidential electors signed by at least 1 per centum of registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia, as shown by the records of the Board as of the 144th day before the date of the presidential election, is presented to the Board on or before the 90th day before the date of the presidential election.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may be elected to the office of elector of President and Vice President pursuant to this subchapter unless: (1) He or she is a registered voter in the District; and (2) He or she has been a bona fide resident of the District for a period of 3 years immediately preceding the date of the presidential election. Each person elected as elector of President and Vice President shall, in the presence of the Board, take an oath or solemnly affirm that he or she will vote for the candidates of the party he or she has been nominated to represent, and it shall be his or her duty to vote in such manner in the electoral college.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_j_1">
      <akn:num>(j-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and pursuant to the June 4, 2014 Order of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in Zukerberg v. D.C. Board of Elections and Ethics, et al., No. 14-CV-222, the Board shall conduct the 2014 election of the Attorney General consistent with the procedural requirements for a special election under this subchapter, and shall have the election of the Attorney General coincide with the November 4, 2014, general election.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The election of the members of the State Board of Education shall be conducted on a nonpartisan basis and in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each candidate in a general or special election for member of the State Board of Education shall be nominated for such office by a nominating petition: (A) Filed with the Board not later than the 90th calendar day before the date of such general or special election; and (B) signed by at least 200 qualified electors who are duly registered under ยง 1-1001.07, who reside in the school district or ward from which the candidate seeks election, or in the case of a candidate running at large, signed by at least 1,000 of the qualified electors in the District of Columbia registered under such ยง 1-1001.07. A nominating petition for a candidate in a general or special election for member of the State Board of Education may not be circulated for signatures before the 144th day preceding the date of such election and may not be filed with the Board before the 115th day preceding such date. In a general or special election for members of the State Board of Education, the Board shall arrange the ballot for each school district or ward to enable a voter registered in that school district or ward to vote for any 1 candidate duly nominated to be elected to such office from such school district or ward, and to vote for as many candidates duly nominated for election at large to such office as there are State Board of Education members to be elected at large in such election.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any election, the order in which the names of the candidates for office appear on the ballot shall be determined by lot, upon a date or dates and under regulations prescribed by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any petition required to be filed under this subchapter by a particular date must be filed no later than 5:00 p.m. on such date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_08_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall submit to the Mayor and Council a feasibility study of mail-ballot voting procedures, within 6 months after October 21, 2000. The study shall outline the advantages and disadvantages of mail-ballot procedures and recommend whether mail-ballot procedures should be implemented in District of Columbia elections. The study shall include an analysis of the following issues and topics that the Board deems appropriate:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
