<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_02">
        <akn:num>1-1001.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “qualified elector” means a person who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Board” means the District of Columbia Board of Elections provided for by § 1-1001.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “ward” means an election ward established by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “State Board of Education” means the State Board of Education established by § 38-2651.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Delegate” means the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “felony” includes any crime committed in the District of Columbia referred to in §§ 1-1001.14, 1-1162.32, and 1-1163.35.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Council” or “Council of the District of Columbia” means the Council of the District of Columbia established pursuant to the District of Columbia Home Rule Act [§ 1-201.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia established pursuant to the District of Columbia Home Rule Act [§ 1-202.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_9A">
      <akn:num>(9A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Attorney General” or “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” means the Attorney General for the District of Columbia provided for by part D-i of subchapter I of Chapter 3 [§ 1-301.81 et seq.] and § 1-204.35.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “initiative” means the process by which the electors of the District of Columbia may propose laws (except laws appropriating funds) and present such proposed laws directly to the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia for their approval or disapproval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “referendum” means the process by which the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia may suspend acts, or some part or parts of acts, of the Council of the District of Columbia (except emergency acts, acts levying taxes, or acts appropriating funds for the general operating budget) until such acts or part or parts of acts have been presented to the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia for their approval or rejection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “recall” means the process by which the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia may call for the holding of an election to remove or retain an elected official of the District of Columbia (except the Delegate to Congress for the District of Columbia) prior to the expiration of his or her term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “elected official” means the Mayor, the Chairman and members of the Council, the Attorney General, members of the State Board of Education, the Delegate to Congress for the District of Columbia, United States Senator and Representative, and advisory neighborhood commissioners of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “printed” shall include any document produced by letterpress, offset press, photo reproduction, multilith, or other mass reproduction means.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “proposer” means one or more of the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia, including any entity, the primary purpose of which is the success or defeat of a political party or principle, or any question submitted to vote at a public election by means of an initiative, referendum or recall as authorized in amendments numbered 1 and 2 to Title IV of the Home Rule Act (§§ 1-204.101 to 1-204.115). Such entities shall be treated as a political committee as defined in § 1-1161.01(44) for purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “voter registration agency” means an office designated under § 1-1001.07(d)(1) and the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to perform voter registration activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “application distribution agency” means an agency designated under § 1-1001.07(d)(14) in whose office or offices mail voter registration applications are made available for general distribution to the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “duly registered voter” means a registered voter who resides at the address listed on the Board’s records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “registered qualified elector” means a registered voter who resides at the address listed on the Board’s records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “qualified registered elector” means a registered voter who resides at the address listed on the Board’s records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “voting system” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Help America Vote Act of 2002” means the Help America Vote Act of 2002, approved October 29, 2002 (116 Stat. 1666; 42 U.S.C. § 15301 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “gender identity or expression” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 2-1401.02(12A).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Election observers” means persons who witness the administration of elections, including individuals representing nonpartisan domestic and international organizations, including voting rights organizations, civil rights organizations, and civic organizations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_02_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified petition circulator” means an individual who is 18 years of age or older and either:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
