<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_05">
        <akn:num>1-1001.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Board of Elections — Duties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Board and persons authorized by the Board may administer oaths to persons executing affidavits pursuant to § 1-1001.08. It may provide for the administering of such other oaths as it considers appropriate to require in the performance of its functions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may permit either persons temporarily absent from the District or persons physically unable to appear personally at an official registration place to register for the purpose of voting in any election held under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding provisions of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (§ 2-501 et seq.), the Board may hear any case brought before it under this subchapter or under Chapter 11A of this title by 1 member panels. An appeal from a decision of any such 1 member panel may be taken to either the full Board or to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, at the option of any adversely affected party. If appeal is taken directly to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the decision of a 1 member panel shall be, for purposes of such appeal, considered to be a final decision of the Board. If an appeal is taken from a decision of a 1 member panel to the full Board, the decision of the 1 member panel shall be stayed pending a final decision of the Board. The Board may, upon a vote of the majority of its members, hear de novo all issues of fact or law relating to an appeal of a decision of a 1 member panel, except the Board may decide to consider only the record made before such 1 member panel. A final decision of the full Board, relating to an appeal brought to it from a 1 member panel, shall be appealable to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in the same manner and to the same extent as all other final decisions of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall cause the following information to be posted at each polling place on the day of each election for federal office:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 90 days after the date of each regularly scheduled general election for federal office, the Board shall submit to the Mayor a report, in the format established by the United States Election Assistance Commission, on the number of absentee ballots sent to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters for the election and the number of ballots which were returned by those voters to the Board.  The report shall be transmitted by the Mayor to the United States Election Assistance Commission, and shall be made available to the general public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_05_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 90 days following a general election, the Board shall publish on its website an after-action report. The report shall include the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
