<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_10">
        <akn:num>1-1001.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Dates for holding elections; votes cast for President and Vice President counted as votes for presidential electors; voting hours; tie votes; filling vacancy where elected official dies, resigns, or becomes unable to serve.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of a tie vote, the resolution of which will affect the outcome of any election, the candidates receiving the tie vote shall cast lots before the Board at 12:00 noon on a date to be set by the Board. This date shall be set no sooner than 2 days following determination by the Board of the results of the election which resulted in a tie. The candidate to whom the lot shall fall shall be declared the winner. If the candidate or candidates fail to appear by 12:00 noon on said day, the Board shall cast lots for him or her or them. For purpose of casting lots, any candidate may appear in person, or by proxy appointed in writing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (e) of this section, if a vacancy of an elected member of the State Board of Education occurs on or after February 1st of the last year of the term of the vacant office, a special election shall not be held and the State Board of Education may appoint a person to fill such vacancy until the unexpired term ends. Any person appointed under this subsection shall have the same qualifications for holding such office as were required of his or her immediate predecessor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A vacancy among the appointed Board members shall be filled within 45 days of its occurrence. The Mayor shall submit a nominee to the Council for confirmation within 30 days of the vacancy. Any Board member appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve until the end of the original term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
