<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.17"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1001.17/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1001_17">
        <akn:num>1-1001.17</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Recall process.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall govern the recall of all elected officers of the District of Columbia except the Delegate to the Congress from the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon filing with the Board the notice of intention of recall and the elected officer’s response, the Board shall prepare and provide to the proponent an original petition form which the proposer shall formally adopt as his or her own form. The proponent shall print from the original blank petition sheets on white paper of good writing quality of the same size as the original. Each recall petition sheet shall be double sided and consist of numbered lines for 20 names and signatures with residence address (street numbers), and, where applicable, the ward numbers, and shall have printed on it the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each petition sheet or sheets for recall shall have attached to it, at the time of submission to the Board, a statement made under penalties of perjury, in a form determined by the Board signed by the circulator of that petition which contains the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proposer of a recall shall have 180 days or, in the case of a proposed recall of an Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner, 60 days, beginning on the date when the proponent of the recall formally adopts the original petition form as his or her own form pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, to circulate the recall petition and file the petition with the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the submission of a recall petition by the proposer to the Board, the Board shall refuse to accept the petition upon any of the following grounds:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After determining that the number and validity of signatures in the recall petition meet the requirements established in this section, the Board shall certify the sufficiency of such recall petition and shall fix the date of a special election to determine whether the elected officer who is the subject of the recall shall be removed from his or her office. The Board shall conduct an election for this purpose within 114 days after the date the petition to recall has been certified as to its sufficiency. If a previously scheduled general, primary, or special election will occur between 54 and 114 days after the date the petition to recall has been certified as to its sufficiency, the Board may present the recall measure at that election. In the case of a proposed recall of an officer elected to represent a particular ward, the recall election shall be conducted only in that ward. In the case of a proposed recall of an Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner, the recall election shall be conducted in one of the following manners unless conducted in accordance with a previously scheduled general, primary, or special election pursuant to this subsection:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall place the recall measure on the ballot in substantially the following form:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1001_17_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Based on the results of the special election held to decide the outcome of the recall measure, the elected officer sought to be recalled shall be removed from that office: Provided, that a majority of the qualified electors voting in the recall election vote to remove him or her. The vacancy, as created by the removal, shall be filled in the same manner as other vacancies, as provided in §§ 1-204.01(b)(3) and (d), 1-204.21(c)(2), 1-309.06(d), and 1-1001.10.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
