<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1162.32"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1162.32/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1162_32">
        <akn:num>1-1162.32</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties; prohibition from serving as lobbyist; citizen suits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_32_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding ยง 1-1162.21 and except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, any person who willfully and knowingly violates any of the provisions of this part shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned for not more than 12 months, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_32_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the penalties provided for in subsection (a) of this section, any person convicted of the misdemeanor specified in that section may be prohibited from serving as a lobbyist for a period of 3 years from the date of the conviction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_32_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who files a report or registration form required under this part in an untimely manner shall be assessed a civil penalty of $10 per day up to 30 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) that the report or registration form is late. The Ethics Board may waive the penalty imposed under this subsection for good cause shown.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_32_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Should any provision of this subchapter not be enforced by the Ethics Board, a citizen of the District of Columbia may bring suit in the nature of mandamus in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, directing the Ethics Board to enforce the provisions of this part. Reasonable attorneys fees may be awarded to the citizen against the District should he or she prevail in this action, or if it is settled in substantial conformity with the relief sought in the petition prior to order by the court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
