<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.33"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.33/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1163_33">
        <akn:num>1-1163.33</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Contribution limitations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person, including a business contributor, may make any contribution, and no person may receive any contribution from any contributor, that when aggregated with all other contributions received from that contributor relating to a campaign for nomination as a candidate or election to public office, including both the primary and general election or special elections, exceeds:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A business contributor shall certify for each contribution that it makes that no affiliated entities have contributed an amount that when aggregated with the business contributor&#x27;s contribution would exceed the limits imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any entity, whether or not considered distinct under Title 29 of the District of Columbia Official Code, may be an affiliated entity for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may make contributions to any one political committee or political action committee in any one election, including primary and general elections, but excluding special elections, that in the aggregate exceed $5,000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No contributor may make a contribution or cause a contribution to be made in the name of another person, and no person may knowingly accept a contribution made by one person in the name of another person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An independent expenditure is not considered a contribution to or an expenditure by or on behalf of the candidate for the purposes of the limitations specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All contributions made by a person directly or indirectly to or for the benefit of a particular candidate or that candidate&#x27;s political committee that are in any way earmarked, encumbered, or otherwise directed through an intermediary or conduit to that candidate or political committee shall be treated as contributions from that person to that candidate or political committee and shall be subject to the limitations established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_33_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No contributions made to support or oppose initiative or referendum measures shall be affected by the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
