<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1162.31"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1162.31/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1162_31">
        <akn:num>1-1162.31</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Prohibited activities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No registrant or anyone acting on behalf of a registrant shall offer, give, or cause to be given a gift or service to an official in the legislative or executive branch or a member of his or her staff that exceeds $100 in value in the aggregate in any calendar year. This section shall not be construed to restrict in any manner contributions authorized in §§ 1-1163.33, 1-1163.34, and 1-1163.38.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No official in the legislative or executive branch or a member of his or her staff shall solicit or accept anything of value in violation of subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall knowingly or willfully make or cause to be made any false or misleading statement or misrepresentation of the facts relating to pending administrative decisions or legislative actions to any official in the legislative or executive branch;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall, knowing a document to contain a false statement relating to pending administrative decisions or legislative actions, cause a copy of the document to be transmitted to an official in the legislative or executive branch without notifying the official in writing of the truth.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No information copied from registration forms and activity reports required by this part or from lists compiled from such forms and reports shall be sold or utilized by any person for the purpose of soliciting campaign contributions or selling tickets to a testimonial or similar fundraising affair or for any commercial purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No public official shall be employed as a lobbyist while acting as a public official, except as provided in § 1-1162.28.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_31_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
