<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1171.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1171.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1171_01">
        <akn:num>1-1171.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Board” means the District of Columbia Board of Ethics and Government Accountability established by § 1-1162.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Candidate” means an individual who seeks nomination or election to any elective office in the District whether or not the person is elected. An individual is deemed to be a candidate if the individual has received political contributions or made expenditures or has consented to another person receiving contributions or making expenditures with a view to bringing about the individual’s nomination or election.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“On duty” means the time period when an employee is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partisan” when used as an adjective means related to a political party.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partisan political group” means any committee, club, or other organization that is regulated by the District and that is affiliated with a political party or candidate for public office in a partisan election, or organized for a partisan purpose, or which engages in partisan political activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partisan political office” means any office in the District government for which any candidate is nominated or elected as representing a party any of whose candidates for Presidential elector received votes in the last preceding election at which Presidential electors were selected, but shall exclude any office or position within a political party or affiliated organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Political party” means a national political party, a State political party, or an affiliated organization that is regulated by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1171_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Political purpose” means an objective of promoting or opposing a political party, candidate for partisan political office, or partisan political group that is regulated by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
