<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1163_04">
        <akn:num>1-1163.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties of Director of Campaign Finance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Develop and furnish prescribed forms, materials, and electronic formats or mediums, including electronic or digital signatures, for the making of the reports and statements required to be filed with him or her pursuant to this subchapter;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Require that all reports filed with the Elections Board pursuant to this subchapter be submitted online, provided that reasonable accommodations shall be made where an actual hardship in complying with this paragraph is demonstrated to the Elections Board. The Elections Board shall issue regulations governing the online submission of reports, pursuant to this paragraph;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_1B">
      <akn:num>(1B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Publish all information submitted by recipients and agencies pursuant to sections of this subchapter online in a publicly accessible, widely accepted, nonproprietary, searchable, platform-independent, sortable, computer-readable format within 24 hours of filing. The database of electronic filings and other data within the portal shall be available via bulk download from the portal website;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Develop a filing, coding, and cross-indexing system consonant with the purposes of this subchapter;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Make the reports and statements filed with him or her available for public inspection and copying, commencing as soon as practicable, but not later than the end of the 2nd day following the day during which it was received, and to permit and facilitate copying of any report or statement by hand and by duplicating machine, as requested by any person, at reasonable cost to the person, except any information copied from the reports and statements shall not be sold or utilized by any person for the purpose of soliciting contributions or for any commercial purpose;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Preserve reports and statements for a period of 10 years from date of receipt;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Compile and maintain a current list of all statements or parts of statements on file pertaining to each candidate;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prepare and publish other reports as he or she may consider appropriate;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Ensure dissemination of statistics, summaries, and reports prepared under this subchapter, including a biennial report summarizing the receipts and expenditures of candidates in the prior 2-year period and the receipts and expenditures of political committees, political action committees, and independent expenditures during the prior 2-year period. The Director of Campaign Finance shall make available to the Mayor, Council, and general public the first biennial report by January 31, 2013, and shall present the summary report on the same date every 2 years thereafter. The report shall describe the receipts and expenditures of candidates for Mayor, Attorney General, Chairman and members of the Council, President and members of the State Board of Education, shadow Senator, and shadow Representative, but shall exclude candidates for Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner. The report shall provide, at a minimum, the following information, as well as other information that the Director of Campaign Finance considers appropriate:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Require a candidate for public office and the treasurer of any political committee, political action committee, or independent expenditure committee to attend a training program conducted by the Director of Campaign Finance concerning compliance with this subchapter. Such training shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Make audits and field investigations with respect to reports and statements filed under this subchapter, and with respect to alleged failures to file any report or statement required under the provisions of this subchapter; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_04_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Perform such other duties as the Elections Board may require.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
