<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.29"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.29/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1163_29">
        <akn:num>1-1163.29</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Legal defense committees — contributions and expenditures.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_29_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each legal defense committee shall have a chairman and a treasurer. No contribution and no expenditure shall be accepted or made by or on behalf of a legal defense committee at a time when there is a vacancy in the office of treasurer for the committee and no other person has been designated and has agreed to perform the functions of treasurer. No expenditure shall be made for or on behalf of a legal defense committee without the authorization of its chairman or treasurer, or their designated agents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_29_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every person who receives a contribution of $50 or more for or on behalf of a legal defense committee shall, on demand of the treasurer, and in any event within 5 days after receipt of the contribution, submit to the treasurer of the committee a detailed account thereof, including the amount, the name and address (including the occupation and the principal place of business, if any) of the person making the contribution, and the date on which the contribution was received. All funds of a legal defense committee shall be segregated from, and may not be commingled with, any personal funds of officers, members, or associates of such committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_29_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The treasurer of a legal defense committee, and each beneficiary, shall keep a detailed and exact account of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_29_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The treasurer or beneficiary shall obtain and preserve such receipted bills and records as may be required by the Elections Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_29_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
