<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1162.24"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1162.24/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1162_24">
        <akn:num>1-1162.24</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Public reporting.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided by this section, all papers filed under this section shall be kept by the Ethics Board in the custody of the Director of Government Ethics for no less than 6 years. The Ethics Board shall publicly disclose before the 2nd day of June each year the names of the candidates, officers, and employees who have filed a report. The Director of Government Ethics shall dispose of papers filed pursuant to this section in accordance with Chapter 17 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reports required by this section shall be filed before May 15th of each year. If a public official ceases before May 15th to hold the office or position, the occupancy of which imposes upon him or her the reporting requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section, the public official shall file the report within 3 months after leaving the office or position. The Ethics Board shall publish, in the District of Columbia Register, before June 15th each year, the name of each public official who has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reports required by this section shall be in a form prescribed by the Ethics Board. The Ethics Board may provide for the grouping of items of income, sources of income, assets, liabilities, dealings in securities or commodities, and purchases and sales of real property, when separate itemization is not feasible or is not necessary for an accurate disclosure of the income, net worth, dealing in securities and commodities, or purchases and sales of rental property of any individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All reports filed under this section shall be maintained by the Ethics Board as public records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of a report required by this section, a person shall be considered to have been a public official if he or she has served as a public official for more than 30 days during any calendar year in a position for which reports are required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ethics Board shall provide for the annual auditing of all reports filed pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1162_24_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall develop a list of each business entity transacting any business with the District government, or providing a service to the District for consideration, to include the business name, address, principals, and brief summary of the business transacted within the immediately preceding 6 months. The list shall be available online and published on January 1st and July 1st annually.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
