<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1163.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1163_09">
        <akn:num>1-1163.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reporting.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following individuals shall file with the Director of Campaign Finance, and with the principal campaign committee, if applicable, reports of receipts and expenditures on forms to be prescribed or approved by the Director of Campaign Finance:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The reports required by subsection (a) of this section shall be filed on the 10th day of March, June, August, October, and December in the 7 months preceding the date on which, and in each year during which, an election is held for the office sought, and 8 days before an election, and also by the 31st day of January of each year. In addition, the reports shall be filed on the 31st day of July of each year in which there is no election. The reports shall be complete as of the date prescribed by the Director of Campaign Finance, which shall not be more than 5 days before the date of filing, except that any contribution of $200 or more received after the closing date prescribed by the Director of Campaign Finance for the last report required to be filed before the election shall be reported within 24 hours after its receipt.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each report under this section shall disclose:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The reports to be filed under subsection (a) of this section shall be cumulative during the calendar year to which they relate, but where there has been no change in an item reported in a previous report during the year, only the unchanged amount need be carried forward. If no contributions or expenditures have been accepted or expended during a calendar year, the treasurer of the committee or candidate shall file a statement to that effect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1163_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each political committee (including principal campaign, inaugural, transition, and exploratory committees) shall, in a separate schedule of its report to be filed under subsection (a) of this section, disclose the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
