<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-123"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-123/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_123">
        <akn:num>1-123</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Call of convention; duties of convention; adoption of constitution; rejection of constitution; election of Senator and Representative.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 60 days after the Board of Elections has certified the election of at-large and ward delegates to the constitutional convention pursuant to § 1-124, the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall call a constitutional convention and assemble the elected delegates. The convention shall write a constitution within 90 days which shall be republican in form and shall not be repugnant to the Constitution or laws of the United States, and it shall otherwise prepare for the admission of a major portion of the territory now known as the District of Columbia as a state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proposed Constitution for the State of New Columbia, approved by Congress June 24, 1987, is amended to read as set forth in Volume 1 of the District of Columbia Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a majority of the registered qualified electors voting reject the constitution, the Mayor shall within 60 calendar days call for the reassembly of the constitutional convention and thereafter a new constitution shall be framed and the same proceedings shall be taken for its submission to the electors of the District of Columbia: Except, that if the proposed constitution of a second constitutional convention is rejected by the registered qualified electors, then the task of writing a constitution acceptable to the electorate shall be abandoned until such time as a new constitutional convention is called for by either legislative action or voter initiative.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Representative or Senator elected pursuant to this subchapter shall be a public official as defined in § 1-1161.01(47), and subscribe to the oath or affirmation of office provided for in § 1-604.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Representative or Senator:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-123_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Representative or Senator elected pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, shall be subject to recall pursuant to § 1-1001.17, during the period of the Representative’s or Senator’s service prior to the admission of the proposed new state into the union.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
