<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1329"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1329/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1329">
        <akn:num>1-1329</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Mayor to revise fees for Surveyor; notice of revision of fee schedule; inspection of fee schedule; employment of registered land surveyor.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1329_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1329_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1329_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person may request in writing that the Surveyor perform any survey or prepare any plat authorized by this chapter. The Surveyor may complete and may record any survey within 60 days after a written request for survey is filed.  Except for those surveying or other functions, duties or obligations specifically reserved to the Surveyor in this chapter, any person may employ, at his expense, a registered land surveyor to perform any survey or prepare any plat authorized by this chapter. Such registered land surveyor employed pursuant to this subsection shall perform the survey under the direction of and in accordance with procedures established by the Surveyor. This subsection shall not apply to any department or agency of the government of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1329_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, a “registered land surveyor” shall mean any person or firm licensed under the provisions of subchapter I-B of Chapter 28 of Title 47 approved and permitted by the Office of the Surveyor to prepare and certify surveys and subdivision plats in the District of Columbia, including, but not limited to, registered civil engineers. The Surveyor is authorized to establish and enforce standards and operating procedures for the performance of surveys by registered land surveyors under subsection (b) of this section. The Surveyor is further authorized to establish and maintain a list of approved registered land surveyors who may be utilized by applicants for surveys pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1329_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including rules to authorize the use of private land surveyors to perform surveys or prepare plats.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1329_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
