<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1511.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1511.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1511_01">
        <akn:num>1-1511.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1992</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment An Unclaimed Property Unit is hereby established in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia, under the supervision and control of the District of Columbia Controller within the Office of the District of Columbia Controller of the Office of Financial Management. The Unclaimed Property Unit hereby established, and the functions and personnel assigned thereto, shall constitute an organizational unit of the Office of the District of Columbia Controller.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The Unclaimed Property Unit is established in the Office of the District of Columbia Controller, under the supervision and control of the District of Columbia Controller, for the purpose of more efficiently operating the Government of the District of Columbia. To effect the enhancement of the District government&#x27;s efficiency, the Unclaimed Property Unit will be aligned with the Office of the District of Columbia Controller, the office that is responsible for the District&#x27;s financial management and control and that maintains the District&#x27;s official accounts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions All of the duties and functions of the Unclaimed Property Unit in the Department of Finance and Revenue established under The District of Columbia Uniform Disposition of Unclaimed Property Act, as amended, effective March 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-160; D.C. Code, sec. 42-201 [ยง 41-101] et seq.) (&quot;the Act&quot;), the rules issued pursuant thereto and Mayor&#x27;s Order 81-82, dated March 27, 1981, 28 DCR 1740 (April 17, 1981) which delegated to the Department of Finance and Revenue, the Mayor&#x27;s authority to administer the Act and to issue rules are hereby transferred to the Office of the District of Columbia Controller within the Office of Financial Management.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfers All positions, property, records and funds relating to the duties and functions transferred in this plan are hereby transferred to the Office of the District of Columbia Controller.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization The District of Columbia Controller of the Office of the District of Columbia Controller is authorized to organize the personnel and property transferred herein within any organizational unit as he or she deems appropriate to fulfill the functions transferred by this plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_VI.">
      <akn:num>VI.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Abolishment The existing Unclaimed Property Unit within the Department of Finance and Revenue is hereby abolished.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_VII.">
      <akn:num>VII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rescission All orders and parts of orders in conflict with any of the provisions of this plan are, to the extent of such conflict, hereby repealed, except that any rules or regulations adopted or promulgated by virtue of the authority granted by such orders, shall remain in force until properly revised, amended or rescinded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_01_VIII.">
      <akn:num>VIII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date This Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1992 shall become effective on a date to be specified by an executive order of the Mayor issued no later than 30 calendar days after this plan has been approved in accordance with the requirements of section 422(12) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-242(12) [ยง 1-204.22]), and section 5(c) of the Governmental Reorganization Procedures Act of 1981, effective October 17, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-42; D.C. Code, sec. 1-299.4(c) [ยง 1-315.04]).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
