<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1503.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1503.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1503_01">
        <akn:num>1-1503.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment There is established, in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia, the Department of Human Services headed by a Director of Human Services, who shall coordinate and direct the operations of the department through the Commissioners of Public Health and Social Services and subordinate organizational components established herein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The Department of Human Services is established to assure that public health and social service policy is developed and implemented in response to the needs of individuals and families in the District of Columbia, and to promote the health, mental health and well-being of District residents through the delivery of high quality and equitably distributed services and income assistance programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization There are hereby established in the Department of Human Services: (1) the Office of the Director, with such subordinate staff offices as are required to carry out overall management responsibility for the Department, planning and policy review, and assurance of compliance with statutes and regulations affecting the department; the state responsibility for education and veterans programs shall also be placed in the Director&#x27;s office; (2) the Office of Public Health, headed by a Commissioner of Public Health who shall be delegated responsibility for developing and implementing health programs through subordinate staff offices and administrations; and (3) the Office of Social Services, headed by a Commissioner of Social Services who shall be delegated responsibility for developing and implementing social service programs through subordinate staff offices and administrations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions The functions of the major organizational components of the Department shall be as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfers There is hereby transferred to the Director of Human Services all powers, duties, and functions assigned or delegated to the Director of the Department of Human Resources as of the date immediately prior to the effective date of this Reorganization Plan. All positions, property, allocations, and other funds, available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties and functions assigned herein are hereby transferred to the Department of Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_VI.">
      <akn:num>VI.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Realignment The Director of Human Services, in the performance of assigned duties and functions, is authorized to complete the realignment of the organizational components of the Department herein established by means of redelegations of functions among organizational units and reassignment of departmental positions among control and responsibility centers, or by the elimination or establishment of alternative responsibility centers, in order to accomplish the following specific objectives:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_VII.">
      <akn:num>VII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Abolishment The District of Columbia Department of Human Resources is hereby abolished.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1503_01_VIII.">
      <akn:num>VIII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date This Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979 shall become effective in accordance with Section 422(12) of P.L. 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
