<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1501.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1501.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1501_01">
        <akn:num>1-1501.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1975</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_ii.">
      <akn:num>ii.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>purpose The Department of Transportation is charged with assisting the Mayor to assure the provision of a safe and adequate transportation system for residents and visitors to the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_iii.">
      <akn:num>iii.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>functions The Director of the Department of Transportation shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_iv.">
      <akn:num>iv.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>transfer of functions The following are hereby transferred to the Department of Transportation:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_v.">
      <akn:num>v.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>delegations and redelegations of authority A. The Director of the Department of Transportation is the successor to all authority delegated to the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles, the Director of the Department of Highways and Traffic, and the Transportation Systems Coordinator, and is authorized to act, either personally or through a designated representative, as a member of whatever committees, commissions, boards, or other bodies which presently include as a member the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles, the Director of the Department of Highways and Traffic, and the Transportation Systems Coordinator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_vi.">
      <akn:num>vi.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>other transfers All positions, personnel, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the above functions, other than those resources and functions to be transferred to the Public Service Commission, are hereby transferred to the Director of the Department of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_vii.">
      <akn:num>vii.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>organization The Director of the Department of Transportation, in the performance of his duties and functions, is authorized to establish such organizational components thereunder with such specified functions, as he deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_viii.">
      <akn:num>viii.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>rescission A. All Orders and parts of Orders in conflict with any of the provisions of this plan are, to the extent of such conflict, hereby repealed except that any municipal regulation adopted or promulgated by virtue of the authority granted by such orders shall remain in force until otherwise amended or repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_01_ix.">
      <akn:num>ix.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>effective date The provisions of this plan shall become effective pursuant to the requirements of Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
