<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1514.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1514.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1514_01">
        <akn:num>1-1514.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1996</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>ESTABLISHMENT There is hereby established, in the Executive Branch of the government of the District of Columbia (&quot;District&quot;), under the supervision of the Director, a Department of Health (&quot;Department&quot;). The Director shall have full authority over the Department and all functions and personnel assigned thereto, including the power to re-delegate to other employees and officials of the Department such powers and authority as, in the Director&#x27;s judgment, are warranted in the interests of efficiency and sound administration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>PURPOSE The mission of the Department is to ensure the provision of high quality health services by establishing District-wide health policy and standards and guidelines for safe and quality health service delivery; foster and promote health education and disease prevention; structure an efficient and cost-effective health care financing system; implement, monitor and evaluate the Department&#x27;s strategic health plan and the District-wide health plan; and undertake activities that will support the highest quality of life achievable for District residents and visitors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>ORGANIZATION There are hereby established in the Department: (1) the Office of the Director, with such subordinate staff offices as are required to carry out overall management responsibility for the Department; (2) the Finance and Administration Offices, with such subordinate staff offices as are required to coordinate and manage the financial and administrative functions for the Department; (3) the Health Regulation Administration, to develop the District-wide health plan, assure quality management and compliance with applicable federal and District rules that govern public health systems, license health care and social service professionals; regulate occupational and professional conduct and standards, health care and social service facilities and ensure compliance with applicable federal and District rules that govern uses and practices that affect the physical environment; (4) the State Health Affairs Administration, to fulfill state agency functions in the areas of maternal and child health, ambulatory, long term and preventive health care; (5) the Health Care Finance Administration, to administer the Medicaid program, Medical Charities Program and develop service coverage, service delivery and reimbursement policies for the District government&#x27;s health care financing programs; (6) the Addiction, Prevention and Recovery Administration, to coordinate the administer drug and substance abuse prevention and treatment programs and services; and (7) the HIV/Aids Administration, to coordinate programs and support services for Human Immuno-deficiency Virus (HIV) and Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>ACTIONS</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>TRANSFER OF FUNCTIONS</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_VI.">
      <akn:num>VI.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>OTHER TRANSFERS All positions, personnel, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available that relate to the functions set forth under Section V. above, are hereby transferred to the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_VII.">
      <akn:num>VII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>REORGANIZATION The Director of the Department is authorized to organize the personnel and property transferred herein within any organizational unit of the Department as the Director deems appropriate. Until such establishment, existing Orders establishing the components of the Commission of Public Health remain in force, where they do not conflict with this Plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1514_01_VIII.">
      <akn:num>VIII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>EFFECTIVE DATE This Reorganization Plan No. 4 in all its parts shall become effective pursuant to the promulgation of an executive order of the Mayor establishing the same, which shall be issued no later than thirty (30) calendar days after this plan has been approved in accordance with the requirements of Section 422(12) of the Home Rule Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-242(12) [ยง 1-204.22(12)].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
