<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1501.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1501.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1501_02">
        <akn:num>1-1501.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1975</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_1.">
      <akn:num>1.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment There is established, in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia, the Department of Housing and Community Development headed by a Director who shall perform the functions herein transferred, delegated, or otherwise assigned to him, and who shall have the authority to redelegate such functions as he deems necessary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_2.">
      <akn:num>2.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The Department of Housing and Community Development is established to formulate, develop and recommend housing and community development policy, plans and programs, and to accomplish the promotion, coordination and execution of policy, plans and programs, and the administration of laws, pertaining to housing and community development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_3.">
      <akn:num>3.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions The Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_4.">
      <akn:num>4.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of functions and delegated authorities respecting the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency The powers, duties and functions of the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency, as set forth in D.C. Code 5-701 through 5-737, are transferred to the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development, except as herein provided.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_5.">
      <akn:num>5.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of functions and delegated authorities respecting the National Capital Housing Authority The powers, duties and functions of the National Capital Housing Authority, as set forth in the District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act, as amended (D.C. Code 5-103 through 5-117), are transferred to the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development, who shall serve as the Authority. In carrying out his functions as such Authority, the Director shall be known as the &quot;National Capital Housing Authority.&quot; Such Authority shall be deemed a continuation of the Authority designated under Presidential Executive Order 6868 of October 9, 1934, as amended. During the absence or disability of the Director, or in the event of a vacancy in the Office of the Director, such Acting Director as may be designated by the Mayor or such subordinate officer of the Department as may be designated by the Director, shall act as the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_6.">
      <akn:num>6.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of functions and delegated authorities relating to the Office of Housing and Community Development The powers, duties and functions of the Director of the Office of Housing and Community Development, as set forth in Commissioner&#x27;s Orders No. 74-143 of June 29, 1974, No. 74-182 of August 21, 1974, No. 74-189 of September 6, 1974, No. 74-201 of September 25, 1974, and No. 74-233 of November 12, 1974, are transferred to the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development. The Office of Housing and Community Development is abolished.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_7.">
      <akn:num>7.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of functions and delegated authorities relating to the Department of Economic Development The powers, duties and functions of the Director of the Department of Economic Development, as set forth in Commissioner&#x27;s Order No. 69-96 of March 7, 1969, as amended, relating to the administration and enforcement of the building and housing codes and the zoning laws and regulations are transferred to the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development, except as herein provided. The functions relating to the issuance of licenses, permits and certificates in connection with the administration of such codes, laws and regulations shall remain vested in the Director of the Department of Economic Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_8.">
      <akn:num>8.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Services to be provided by other agencies The Director of the Department of Economic Development shall provide automated data processing services to the Department of Housing and Community Development for the conduct of its building and housing code enforcement activities. The Corporation Counsel [now Attorney General for the District of Columbia] shall perform the functions of general counsel for the Redevelopment Land Agency and the National Capital Housing Authority, which functions are transferred to the Corporation Counsel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_9.">
      <akn:num>9.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization The Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development, in the performance of the functions assigned to him, is authorized to establish such organizational components with such specified functions as he deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_10.">
      <akn:num>10.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repeal of previous Orders</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_11.">
      <akn:num>11.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of funds and other resources All positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the above functions, other than the functions transferred to the Corporation Counsel, are transferred to the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development, except that real property titled in the name of the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency shall remain so vested. All positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be available relating to the functions of the General Counsel and legal staffs of the Redevelopment Land Agency and the National Capital Housing Authority are transferred to the Corporation Counsel, who is authorized to establish such organizational components within that Office with such specified functions as may be deemed appropriate. Pursuant to the provisions of Public Law 93-198, section 713, all positions and personnel transferred herein which are in the competitive service shall retain such status and continue to be subject to all rules and regulations governing the competitive service until such time as the D.C. Government merit system is established in accordance with section 422 of Public Law 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1501_02_12.">
      <akn:num>12.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date The provisions of this Plan shall become effective pursuant to the requirements of Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
