<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1512.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1512.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1512_01">
        <akn:num>1-1512.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1993</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1512_01_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment There is hereby established in the Executive Office of the Mayor, the &quot;Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development&quot; under the direction and control of an Assistant City Administrator who shall be appointed by the Mayor to a position in the Executive Service pursuant to Title X of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, D.C. Law 2-139, effective March 3, 1979, (D.C. Code former sections 1-611.1 to 1-611.2) [§§ 1-610.01 to 1-610.02].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1512_01_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The purpose of the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development is to coordinate the activities of the Human Resources Development Cluster to provide training and employment services for both District Government employees and residents to meet the technological demands of today&#x27;s and tomorrow&#x27;s workplace.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1512_01_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions The functions of the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development shall be to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1512_01_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfers All positions, personnel, records, unexpended balances of appropriation and functions of the Office of Human Resources Development in the Office of Personnel are hereby transferred to the Office of the Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1512_01_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization The Assistant City Administrator for Human Resources Development is authorized to organize personnel and property within the Office of the Assistant City Administrator as is deemed appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1512_01_VI.">
      <akn:num>VI.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date The provisions of this plan shall become effective pursuant to the requirements of Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198, or on a date thereafter to be designated pursuant to Executive Order of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
