<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1502.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1502.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1502_01">
        <akn:num>1-1502.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1978</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment There is established in the Executive Branch of the Government of the District of Columbia, the Department of Labor headed by a Director who shall perform the functions herein transferred, delegated, or otherwise assigned to him and who shall have the authority to redelegate such functions as he deems necessary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The Department of Labor is established to provide opportunities for citizens and other eligible individuals to prepare for, find, and maintain employment; to provide training and supportive services to the unemployed, under employed and disadvantaged; to provide income maintenance to mitigate the effects of unemployment; and to promote the working conditions of wage earners by protecting their health, safety, wages, rights, and benefits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions The Director shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of Functions The following powers, duties and functions are hereby transferred to the Director:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishments The following Boards are hereby established in the Department of Labor:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_VI.">
      <akn:num>VI.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Delegations of authority</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_VII.">
      <akn:num>VII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repeal of previous orders and abolishments</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_VIII.">
      <akn:num>VIII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization The Director, in the performance of the duties and functions assigned to him, is authorized to establish such organizational components with such specified functions as he deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_IX.">
      <akn:num>IX.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of functions, funds and other resources All positions, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations and other funds available or to be made available relating to the functions assigned to the Director are hereby transferred to the Department of Labor. Pursuant to the provisions of Public Law 93-198, Section 713, all positions and personnel transferred herein which are in the competitive service shall retain such status and continue to be subject to all rules and regulations governing the competitive service until such time as the D.C. Government merit system is established in accordance with Section 422 of Public Law 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1502_01_X.">
      <akn:num>X.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date The provisions of this Plan shall become effective pursuant to the requirements of Section 422(12) of Public Law 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
