<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1511.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1511.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1511_02">
        <akn:num>1-1511.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1992</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment The Office of Tourism and Promotions (&quot;Office&quot;) is hereby established in the Executive Branch of the Government under the Deputy Mayor for Economic Development (DMED). The Office shall be supervised and administered by a Director who shall be appointed by the Mayor to a position in the Executive Service pursuant to Title X of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, D.C. Law 2-139, effective March 3, 1979, (D.C. Code former sections 1-611.1 - 1.611.2, and subject to the advice and consent of the Council. The Mayor&#x27;s Special Assistant for Tourism shall be the Acting Director pending confirmation by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The purpose of the Office is to increase revenues generated by tourism and related promotional, leisure and entertainment activities. The Office of Tourism and Promotions will coordinate the economic development efforts of the city in the areas of tourism and conventions and will better serve local firms engaged in the tourism industry by providing a more efficient delivery of public services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization The Director shall be appointed by the Mayor and shall report to the Deputy Mayor for Economic Development. The Director shall have oversight responsibility for the D.C. Committee to Promote Washington and the Office of Motion Picture and Television Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfers All positions, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocation, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the duties and functions assigned herein are transferred to the Office of Tourism and Promotions. This includes all positions, budget and other available resources currently held in the Office of Business and Economic Development and allocated to the Office of Motion Picture and Television Development and to the D.C. Committee to Promote Washington.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_VI.">
      <akn:num>VI.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Abolishment The position of Mayor&#x27;s Special Assistant for Tourism is abolished.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_02_VII.">
      <akn:num>VII.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date This Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1992 shall become effective on October 1, 1992, following Council review, in accordance with Section 422(12) of P.L. 93-198.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
