<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1509.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1509.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1509_01">
        <akn:num>1-1509.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1988</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1509_01_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose This plan changes the name of the Educational Institution Licensure Commission to the Education Licensure Commission and transfers the function of licensing and otherwise regulating proprietary schools from the Director, Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs to the Education Licensure Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1509_01_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Change of Name The Education Institution Licensure Commission, established by § 3 of the D.C. Law 1-104, the Education Licensure Commission Act of 1976, D.C. Code § 31-1603 [§ 38-1303], is hereby renamed the Education Licensure Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1509_01_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of Functions The functions with respect to proprietary schools vested in the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs by Council Regulation No. 71-30, as amended, 16 DCMR § 1200 et seq., Commissioner&#x27;s Order 71-458 (December 28, 1971), Mayor&#x27;s Order 78-42 (February 17, 1978), Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1983, and Mayor&#x27;s Order 83-92 (April 7, 1983) are hereby transferred to the Education Licensure Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1509_01_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization The Mayor is authorized to organize the personnel and property of the Commission to fulfill the functions transferred by this plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1509_01_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Dates This Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1988 shall become effective pursuant to the promulgation of an executive order of the Mayor establishing the same no later than thirty (30) calendar days after this plan has been approved in accordance with § 422(12) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, Public Law 93-198, D.C. Code § 1-242(12) [§ 1-204.22].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
