<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1511.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-1511.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_1511_03">
        <akn:num>1-1511.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1992</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_03_I.">
      <akn:num>I.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of OBFI Control Center The D.C. Office of Banking and Financial Institutions (&quot;OBFI&quot;) is hereby transferred from the Deputy Mayor for Economic Development (&quot;DMED&quot;) control center to a separate OBFI control center/responsibility center. OBFI will continue to be administered by the Superintendent and will remain a part of the economic development cluster reporting to the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_03_II.">
      <akn:num>II.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purpose The purpose of this plan is to transfer the OBFI budget from the budget of the DMED to a separate OBFI responsibility/control center.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_03_III.">
      <akn:num>III.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organization There will be a transfer of OBFI&#x27;s budget to a separate control/responsibility center. No organizational staffing or funding changes will occur at OBFI as a consequence of this shift other than the transfer of the authorization for one full time employee from the Office of International Business, a transfer of $18,000 to fund that position from the Office of Business and Economic Development, plus an overall budget increase of $68,000, all of which was approved by the Council in the FY 93 budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_03_IV.">
      <akn:num>IV.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Functions OBFI&#x27;s functions are contained in the District of Columbia Regional Interstate Banking Act of 1985 Amendments Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-107, effective April 11, 1986, codified in chapters 1, 4, 5, and 8 of title 26 [chapters 1, 2, 7, 13 of title 26] of the D.C. Code. These statutory duties of OBFI will remain unchanged as a result of this transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-1511_03_V.">
      <akn:num>V.</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective Date This Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1992 becomes effective the later of the date of Council approval in accordance with ยง 128 of the Fiscal Year of 1993 Budget Request Act (D.C. Act 9-186), or on a date thereafter to be designated pursuant to Executive Order of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
