<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.75"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.75/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_75">
        <akn:num>1-204.75</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond anticipation notes.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_75_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Authorizing issuance. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_75_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Maximum annual debt service amount. — The act of the Council authorizing the issuance of bond anticipation notes shall set forth for the bonds anticipated by such notes an estimated maximum annual debt service amount based on an estimated schedule of annual principal payments and an estimated schedule of annual interest payments (based on an estimated maximum average annual interest rate for such bonds over a period of 30 years from the earlier of the date of issuance of the notes or the date of original issuance of prior notes in anticipation of those bonds). Such estimated maximum annual debt service amount as estimated at the time of issuance of the original bond anticipation notes shall be included in the calculation required by § 1-206.03(b) while such notes or renewal notes are outstanding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_75_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Permitted outstanding duration. — Any bond anticipation note, including any renewal note, shall be due and payable not later than the last day of the third fiscal year following the fiscal year during which the note was originally issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_75_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>General authority of Council. — If provided for in [an] Act of the Council authorizing such an issue of bond anticipation notes, bond anticipation notes may be issued in succession, in such amounts, at such times, and bearing interest rates within the permitted maximum authorized by such Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_75_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective date of authorization acts; payments not subject to appropriation. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
