<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.34"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.34/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_34">
        <akn:num>1-204.34</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_34_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established for the District of Columbia the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission (hereafter in this section referred to as the  “Commission”).  The Commission shall consist of seven members selected in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b).  Such members shall serve for terms of six years, except that the member selected in accordance with subsection (b)(4)(A) shall serve for five years;  of the members first selected in accordance with subsection (b)(4)(B), one member shall serve for three years and one member shall serve for six years;  of the members first selected in accordance with subsection (b)(4)(C), one member shall serve for a term of three years and one member shall serve for five years;  the member first selected in accordance with subsection (b)(4)(D) shall serve for six years;  and the member first appointed in accordance with subsection (b)(4)(E) shall serve for six years.  In making the respective first appointments according to subsections (b)(4)(B) and (b)(4)(C), the Mayor and the Board of Governors of the unified District of Columbia Bar shall designate, at the time of such appointments, which member shall serve for the shorter term and which member shall serve for the longer term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_34_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_34_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_34_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
