<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-207.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-207.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_207_13">
        <akn:num>1-207.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of personnel, property, and funds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-207_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In each case of the transfer, by any provision of this chapter, of functions to the Council, to the Mayor, or to any agency or officer, there are hereby authorized to be transferred (as of the time of such transfer of functions) to the Council, to the Mayor, to such agency, or to the agency of which such officer is the head, for use in the administration of the functions of the Council or such agency or officer, the personnel (except the Commissioner of the District of Columbia, the Assistant to the Commissioner, the Chairman of the District of Columbia Council, the Vice Chairman of the District of Columbia Council, the other members thereof, all of whose officers are abolished by this chapter), property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds which relate primarily to the functions so transferred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-207_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any question arises in connection with the carrying out of subsection (a) of this section, such questions shall be decided:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-207_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any of the personnel authorized to be transferred to the Council, the Mayor, or any agency by this section which the Council or the head of such agency shall find to be in excess of the personnel necessary for the administration of its or his function shall, in accordance with law, be retransferred to other positions in the District or Federal Government or be separated from the service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-207_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No officer or employee shall, by reason of his transfer to the District government under this chapter or his separation from service under this chapter, be deprived of any civil service rights, benefits, and privileges held by him prior to such transfer or any right of appeal or review he may have by reason of his separation from service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
