<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.24a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.24a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_24a">
        <akn:num>1-204.24a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>In general.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_24a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment. — There is hereby established within the executive branch of the government of the District of Columbia an Office of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (hereafter referred to as the “Office”), which shall be headed by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia (hereafter referred to as the “Chief Financial Officer”).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_24a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Organizational analysis. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_24a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfers. — Effective with the appointment of the first Chief Financial Officer under § 1-204.24b, the functions and personnel of the following offices are established as subordinate offices within the Office:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_24a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Supervisor. — The heads of the offices listed in subsection (c) of this section shall serve at the pleasure of the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_24a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appointment and removal of office employees. — The Chief Financial Officer shall appoint the heads of the subordinate offices designated in subsection (c) of this section, after consultation with the Mayor and the Council. The Chief Financial Officer may remove the heads of the offices designated in subsection (c) of this section, after consultation with the Mayor and the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_24a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Annual budget submission. — The Chief Financial Officer shall prepare and annually submit to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, for inclusion in the annual budget of the District of Columbia government for a fiscal year, annual estimates of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for the year for the operation of the Office and all other District of Columbia accounting, budget, and financial management personnel (including personnel of executive branch independent agencies) that report to the Office pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
