<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.46"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.46/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_46">
        <akn:num>1-204.46</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enactment of local budget by Council.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_46_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Adoption of budgets and supplements. — The Council, within 70 calendar days, or as otherwise provided by law, after receipt of the budget proposal from the Mayor, and after public hearing, and by a vote of a majority of the members present and voting, shall by act adopt the annual budget for the District of Columbia government. The federal portion of the annual budget shall be submitted by the Mayor to the President for transmission to Congress. The local portion of the annual budget shall be submitted by the Chairman of the Council to the Speaker of the House of Representatives pursuant to the procedure set forth in § 1-206.02(c). Any supplements to the annual budget shall also be adopted by act of the Council, after public hearing, by a vote of a majority of the members present and voting.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_46_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transmission to President during control years. — In the case of a budget for a fiscal year which is a control year, the budget so adopted shall be submitted by the Mayor to the President for transmission by the President to the Congress; except, that the Mayor shall not transmit any such budget, or amendments or supplements to the budget, to the President until the completion of the budget procedures contained in this chapter and the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995 [Pub. L. 104-8].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_46_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prohibiting obligations and expenditures not authorized under budget. — Except as provided in § 1-204.45a(b), § 1-204.46b, § 1-204.67(d), § 1-204.71(c), § 1-204.72(d)(2), § 1-204.75(e)(2), § 1-204.83(d), and subsections (f), (g), (h)(3), and (i)(3) of § 1-204.90, no amount may be obligated or expended by any officer or employee of the District of Columbia government unless —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
