<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-201.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-201.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_201_03">
        <akn:num>1-201.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia provided for by part A of subchapter IV of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the District of Columbia established under Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District of Columbia Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia established under Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Chairman” means, unless otherwise provided in this Act, the Chairman of the Council provided for by part A of subchapter IV of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor provided for by part B of subchapter IV of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “act” includes any legislation passed by the Council, except where the term “Act” is used to refer to this chapter or other Acts of Congress herein specified.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “capital project” means any physical public betterment or improvement, the acquisition of property of a permanent nature, or the purchase of equipment or furnishings, and includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “pending”, when applied to any capital project, means authorized but not yet completed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District revenues” means all funds derived from taxes, fees, charges, miscellaneous receipts, grants and other forms of financial assistance, or the sale of bonds, notes, or other obligations, and any funds administered by the District government under cost sharing arrangements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “election”, unless the context otherwise provides, means an election held pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The terms “publish” and “publication”, unless otherwise specifically provided herein, mean publication in a newspaper of general circulation in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District of Columbia Courts” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “resources” means revenues, balances, enterprise or other revolving funds, and funds realized from borrowing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-201_03_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “budget” means the entire request for appropriations or loan or spending authority for all activities of all departments or agencies of the District of Columbia financed from all existing, proposed, or anticipated resources, and shall include both operating and capital expenditures.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
