<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.22"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.22/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_22">
        <akn:num>1-204.22</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers and duties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may designate the officer or officers of the executive department of the District who may, during periods of disability or absence from the District of the Mayor, execute and perform the powers and duties of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall administer all laws relating to the appointment, promotion, discipline, separation, and other conditions of employment of personnel in the Office of the Mayor, personnel in executive departments of the District, and members of boards, commissions, and other agencies, who, under laws in effect on the date immediately preceding January 2, 1975, were subject to appointment and removal by the Commissioner of the District of Columbia. All actions affecting such personnel and such members shall, until such time as legislation is enacted by the Council superseding such laws and establishing a permanent District government merit system, pursuant to paragraph (3) of this section, continue to be subject to the provisions of acts of Congress relating to the appointment, promotion, discipline, separation, and other conditions of employment applicable to officers and employees of the District government, to § 1-207.13, and where applicable, to the provisions of the joint agreement between the Commissioners and the Civil Service Commission authorized by Executive Order No. 5491 of November 18, 1930, relating to the appointment of District personnel. He shall appoint or assign persons to positions formerly occupied, ex officio, by the Commissioner of the District of Columbia or by the Assistant to the Commissioner and shall have power to remove such persons from such positions. The officers and employees of each agency with respect to which legislative power is delegated by this chapter and which immediately prior to January 2, 1975, was not subject to the administrative control of the Commissioner of the District, shall continue to be appointed and removed in accordance with applicable laws until such time as such laws may be superseded by legislation passed by the Council establishing a permanent District government merit system pursuant to paragraph (3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall administer the personnel functions of the District covering employees of all District departments, boards, commissions, offices and agencies, except as otherwise provided by this chapter. Personnel legislation enacted by Congress prior to or after January 2, 1975, including, without limitation, legislation relating to appointments, promotions, discipline, separations, pay, unemployment compensation, health, disability and death benefits, leave, retirement, insurance, and veterans’ preference applicable to employees of the District government as set forth in § 1-207.14(c), shall continue to be applicable until such time as the Council shall, pursuant to this section, provide for coverage under a District government merit system. The District government merit system shall be established by act of the Council. The system shall apply with respect to the compensation of employees of the District government during fiscal year 2006 and each succeeding fiscal year, except that the system may provide for continued participation in all or part of the Federal Civil Service System and shall provide for persons employed by the District government immediately preceding the effective date of such system personnel benefits, including but not limited to pay, tenure, leave, residence, retirement, health and life insurance, and employee disability and death benefits, all at least equal to those provided by legislation enacted by Congress, or regulation adopted pursuant thereto, and applicable to such officers and employees immediately prior to the effective date of the system established pursuant to this chapter, except that nothing in this chapter shall prohibit the District from separating an officer or employee subject to such system in the implementation of a financial plan and budget for the District government approved under subpart B of subchapter VII of Chapter 3 of Title 47, and except that nothing in this section shall prohibit the District from paying an employee overtime pay in accordance with § 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. § 207). The District government merit system shall take effect not earlier than 1 year nor later than 5 years after January 2, 1975.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall, through the heads of administrative boards, offices, and agencies, supervise and direct the activities of such boards, offices, and agencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may submit drafts of acts to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may delegate any of his functions (other than the function of approving or disapproving acts passed by the Council or the function of approving contracts between the District and the federal government under § 1-207.31) to any officer, employee, or agency of the executive office of the Mayor, or to any director of an executive department who may, with the approval of the Mayor, make a further delegation of all or a part of such functions to subordinates under his jurisdiction. Nothing in the previous sentence may be construed to permit the Mayor to delegate any functions assigned to the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia under subchapter I-A of Chapter 3 of Title 47, without regard to whether such functions are assigned to the Chief Financial Officer under such section during a control year (as defined in § 47-393(4)) or during any other year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall appoint a City Administrator, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Mayor. The City Administrator shall be the chief administrative officer of the Mayor, and he shall assist the Mayor in carrying out his functions under this chapter, and shall perform such other duties as may be assigned to him by the Mayor. The City Administrator shall be paid at a rate established by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may propose to the executive or legislative branch of the United States government legislation or other action dealing with any subject, whether or not falling within the authority of the District government, as defined in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, as custodian thereof, shall use and authenticate the corporate seal of the District in accordance with law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall have the right, under rules to be adopted by the Council, to be heard by the Council or any of its committees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to issue and enforce administrative orders, not inconsistent with this or any other Act of the Congress or any act of the Council, as are necessary to carry out his functions and duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_22_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may reorganize the offices, agencies, and other entities within the executive branch of the government of the District by submitting to the Council a detailed plan of such reorganization. Such a reorganization plan shall be valid only if the Council does not adopt, within 60 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) after such reorganization plan is submitted to it by the Mayor, a resolution disapproving such reorganization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
