<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-206.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-206.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_206_03">
        <akn:num>1-206.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Budget process; limitations on borrowing and spending.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-206_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as making any change in existing law, regulation, or basic procedure and practice relating to the respective roles of the Congress, the President, the federal Office of Management and Budget, and the Comptroller General of the United States in the preparation, review, submission, examination, authorization, and appropriation of the total budget of the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-206_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-206_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the Council shall not approve any budget which would result in expenditures being made by the District government, during any fiscal year, in excess of all resources which the Mayor estimates will be available from all funds available to the District for such fiscal year. The budget shall identify any tax increases which shall be required in order to balance the budget as submitted. The Council shall be required to adopt such tax increases to the extent its budget is approved. For the purposes of this section, the Council shall use a federal payment amount not to exceed the amount authorized by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-206_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the Mayor shall not forward to the President for submission to Congress a budget which is not balanced according to the provision of subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-206_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as affecting the applicability to the District government of the provisions of §§ 1341, 1342, and 1349 to 1351 and subchapter II of Chapter 15 of Title 31, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-206_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of a fiscal year which is a control year (as defined in § 47-393(4)), the Council may not approve, and the Mayor may not forward to the President, any budget which is not consistent with the financial plan and budget established for the fiscal year under part B of subchapter VII of Chapter 3 of Title 47.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
