<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.31"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.31/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_31">
        <akn:num>1-204.31</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Judicial powers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The judicial power of the District is vested in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals and the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.  The Superior Court has jurisdiction of any civil action or other matter (at law or in equity) brought in the District and of any criminal case under any law applicable exclusively to the District.  The Superior Court has no jurisdiction over any civil or criminal matter over which a United States court has exclusive jurisdiction pursuant to an Act of Congress.  The Court of Appeals has jurisdiction of appeals from the Superior Court and, to the extent provided by law, to review orders and decisions of the Mayor, the Council, or any agency of the District.  The District of Columbia courts shall also have jurisdiction over any other matters granted to the District of Columbia courts by other provisions of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The chief judge of a District of Columbia court shall be designated by the District of Columbia Judicial Nominating [Nomination] Commission established by § 1-204.34 from among the judges of the court in regular active service, and shall serve as chief judge for a term of four years or until a successor is designated, except that the term as chief judge shall not extend beyond the chief judge’s term as a judge of a District of Columbia court.  An individual shall be eligible for redesignation as chief judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A judge of a District of Columbia court appointed on or after the date of enactment of the District of Columbia Court Reorganization Act of 1970 [July 29, 1970] shall be appointed for a term of fifteen years subject to mandatory retirement at age seventy-four or removal, suspension, or involuntary retirement pursuant to § 1-204.32 and upon completion of such term, such judge shall continue to serve until reappointed or a successor is appointed and qualifies.  A judge may be reappointed as provided in subsection (c) of § 1-204.33.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Tenure Commission shall serve without compensation for services rendered in connection with their official duties on the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_31_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Tenure Commission shall have the power to suspend, retire, or remove a judge of a District of Columbia court as provided in § 1-204.32 and to make recommendations regarding the appointment of senior judges of the District of Columbia courts as provided in § 11-1504.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
