<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.90"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-204.90/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_204_90">
        <akn:num>1-204.90</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Revenue bonds and other obligations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No property owned by the United States may be mortgaged or made subject to any security interest to secure any revenue bond, note, or other obligation issued under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any and all such revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations issued under subsection (a)(1) of this section shall not be general obligations of the District, shall not be a pledge of or involve the faith and credit or taxing power of the District (other than with respect to any dedicated taxes) and shall not constitute a debt of the District, and shall not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings for purposes of ยง 1-206.02(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any and all such bonds, notes, or other obligations shall be issued pursuant to an act of the Council without the necessity of submitting the question of such issuance to the registered qualified electors of the District for approval or disapproval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any act of the Council authorizing the issuance of revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-204.46(c) shall not apply to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations issued under subsection (a)(1) of this section are not general obligation bonds of the District government and shall not be included in determining the aggregate amount of all outstanding obligations subject to the limitation specified in ยง 1-206.03(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The issuance of revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations by the District where the ultimate obligation to repay such revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations is that of one or more nongovernmental persons or entities may be authorized by resolution of the Council. The issuance of all other revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations by the District shall be authorized by act of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During any control period (as defined in ยง 47-392.09), any act or resolution of the Council authorizing the issuance of revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations under subsection (a)(1) of this section shall be submitted to the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority for certification in accordance with ยง 47-392.04. Any certification issued by the Authority during a control period shall be effective for purposes of this subsection for revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations issued pursuant to such act or resolution of the Council whether the revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations are issued during or subsequent to that control period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following provisions of law shall not apply with respect to property acquired, held, and disposed of by the District in accordance with the terms of any lease-purchase financing authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-204_90_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
