<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-303.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-303.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_303_01">
        <akn:num>1-303.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Police regulations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For causing full inspection to be made, at any reasonable times, of the places where the business of pawnbroking, junk-dealing, or second-hand clothing business may be carried on.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To regulate the storage of highly inflammable substances in the thickly populated portions of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To establish and regulate the charges to be made by owners of hacks and hackney carriages of any kind whatsoever.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To prohibit conducting droves of animals upon such streets and avenues as it may deem needful to public safety and good order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To regulate the keeping of dogs and fowls.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To prohibit the deposit upon the street or sidewalks of fruit, or any part thereof, or other substance or articles that might litter the same, or cause injury to or impede pedestrians.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To regulate or prohibit loud noises with horns, gongs, or other instruments, or loud cries, upon the streets or public places, and to prohibit the use of any fireworks or explosives within such portions of the District as it may think necessary to public safety.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-303_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To prescribe reasonable penalties, including civil penalties, for the infraction of the regulations mentioned in §§ 1-303.01 and 1-303.02. The penalties may be enforced in any court or administrative tribunal of the District of Columbia having jurisdiction of minor offenses or civil infractions, and in the same manner that minor offenses or civil infractions are by law prosecuted or adjudicated and punished.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
