<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-309.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-309.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_309_12">
        <akn:num>1-309.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions — Joint meetings; involvement of neighborhood groups; service area coordinators; service area manager; citizen’s advisory mechanism.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Commissions may meet jointly either formally or informally to deal more effectively with or respond to common issues and concerns. A Commissioner of an individual Commission may represent and participate in a formal joint meeting only after the individual Commission has authorized the participation of the Commission in the joint meeting. For any official action taken in a formal joint meeting, the Commission shall specify in a resolution the scope of any individual Commissioner’s participation. Action taken by individual Commissioners in an informal joint meeting shall follow the general direction of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission may involve representatives of other neighborhood groups in the work of its standing or special committees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall appoint a service area coordinator for each ward who shall act as the chairperson of the service area committee in that ward and shall coordinate all District government services at the ward level to residents of the ward. The head of each District government department or agency that delivers services at the ward level shall appoint a service area manager who shall oversee the day-to-day operations of the department or agency within the ward and shall represent that department or agency on the service area committee of that ward. The service area coordinators and managers shall work closely with the Commissions in their service area ward and shall provide them with any technical assistance necessary to the performance of their duties and responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a District government entity is required to establish a citizen’s advisory mechanism, appointments to that mechanism shall be made in such a manner as to ensure as far as possible the equal representation on the mechanism of each electoral ward, provided that, members of the advisory mechanism possess skills relevant to the tasks for which the advisory mechanism was established and, in the event that the size of the advisory mechanism requires the appointment of more than one person per ward, ward appointments shall be made in such a manner so as to ensure as far as possible a fair representation of each Commission area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_12_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each executive and independent agency, board, and commission of the District of Columbia and the Council shall assign an individual to act as an Advisory Neighborhood Commission Liaison who will serve as the primary contact for all Commissioners conducting official business with said government entity. The Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions shall maintain a list of the Liaisons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
