<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-301.115a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-301.115a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_301_115a">
        <akn:num>1-301.115a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Creation and duties of Office of the Inspector General.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It is the purpose of the Office of the Inspector General to independently:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Inspector General shall not disclose the identity of any person who brings a complaint or provides information to the Inspector General, without the person’s consent, unless the Inspector General determines that disclosure is unavoidable or necessary to further the ends of an investigation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Inspector General may undertake reviews and investigations, and make determinations or render opinions as requested by the Authority. Any reports generated as a result of the requests shall be automatically transmitted to the Council within 10 days of publication.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Inspector General may conduct an annual inspection and independent fiscal and management audit of the District of Columbia Housing Authority, beginning the first fiscal year of the Authority. In addition, the Inspector General may undertake reviews and investigations of the District of Columbia Housing Authority, and make determinations or render opinions, as requested by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In carrying out the duties and responsibilities established under this section, the Inspector General shall report expeditiously to the Attorney General whenever the Inspector General has reasonable grounds to believe there has been a violation of Federal or District criminal law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee of the Office of the Inspector General who, as part of his or her official duties, conducts investigations of alleged felony violations, shall possess the following authority while engaged in the performance of official duties:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_f_2">
      <akn:num>(f-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Inspector General shall prepare an annual report not later than December 1st of each year, summarizing the activities of the Office of the Inspector General during the preceding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_f_3">
      <akn:num>(f-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure on the part of any District government employee or contractor to cooperate with the Inspector General by not providing requested documents or testimony needed for the performance of his or her duties in conducting an audit, inspection or investigation shall be cause for the Inspector General to recommend appropriate administrative actions to the personnel or procurement authority, and shall be grounds for adverse actions as administered by the personnel or procurement authority, including the loss of employment or the termination of an existing contractual relationship.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_f_4">
      <akn:num>(f-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Anyone who has the authority to take or direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action, shall not, with respect to this authority, take or threaten to take any action against another as a reprisal for making a complaint or disclosing information to the Inspector General, unless the complaint was made or the information disclosed with the knowledge that it was false or with willful disregard for its truth or falsity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_f_5">
      <akn:num>(f-5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A peer review of the Office of the Inspector General’s audit, inspection and investigation sections’ standards, policies, procedures, operations, and quality controls shall be performed no less than once every 3 years by an entity not affiliated with the Office of the Inspector General. Any final report shall be distributed to the Mayor, the Council and the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_115a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
