<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.81"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.81/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_307_81">
        <akn:num>1-307.81</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Advisory Council” means the advisory council established by § 1-307.85.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agency” means the Captive Insurance Agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Act of terrorism” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 22-3152(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Captive manager” means the person appointed by the Risk Officer pursuant to § 1-307.84(b) to run the day-to-day affairs of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District real property asset” means improved real property owned by the District and includes all structures of a permanent character erected on or affixed to the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fund” or “Captive Trust Fund” means the Captive Trust Fund established under § 1-307.91.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federally qualified health center” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 1861(aa)(4) of the Social Security Act, approved August 14, 1935 (79 Stat. 313; 42 U.S.C. § 1395x(aa)(4)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gap coverage” means coverage for medical malpractice risks of the District’s Federally Qualified Health Centers not covered through the Federal Tort Claims Act, approved August 2, 1946 (60 Stat. 847; 15 U.S.C. § 41 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health center” means a health center or service that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medical malpractice” means professional negligence by act or omission by a health care provider in which the treatment provided falls below the accepted standard of practice in the medical community and causes injury or death to the patient, with most cases involving medical error.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Operational” means that the Council has approved insurance policies for the health centers covered under part B of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_9A">
      <akn:num>(9A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property insurance” means an insurance policy that protects against most risks to property such as earthquakes, floods, acts of terrorism, fires, boiler or machinery failures, business interruptions, pollution, fidelity, builders risk, debris removal, and weather damage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Risk Officer” means the Chief Risk Officer, established by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 2003, effective December 15, 2003 [D.C. Official Code, subchapter XVIII, Chapter 15, Title 1].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tail coverage” means liability insurance purchased by an insured to extend the insurance coverage beyond the end of the policy period of a liability policy written on a claims-made basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_81_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Volunteer service provider” means any person licensed to practice in the District who provides health-care, rehabilitative, social, or related administrative services:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
