<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.42"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.42/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_307_42">
        <akn:num>1-307.42</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Employer obligations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Permit the parent to enroll under family coverage any child who is otherwise eligible for coverage without regard to any enrollment restrictions;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Enroll the child under family coverage upon application by the child’s other parent, or by the District of Columbia agency administering either the Medicaid program or the child support enforcement program pursuant to Title IV-D of the Social Security Act (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 through 669), if the parent is enrolled but fails to make application to obtain coverage of the child;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Enroll the child and the employed parent under family coverage upon application by the child’s other parent, or by the District of Columbia agency administering either the Medicaid program or the child support enforcement program pursuant to Part D of Title IV of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.), if the employed parent is not enrolled and the health insurance plan requires the employed parent’s enrollment for the child to be eligible;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not disenroll or eliminate coverage of any such child unless the employer is provided satisfactory written evidence that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to §§ 46-251.07 and 46-251.08, withhold from the employee’s compensation the employee’s share (if any) of premiums for health coverage and to pay this amount to the insurer, except that the maximum amount so withheld may not exceed the maximum amount to be withheld under § 303(b) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act (82 Stat. 163; 15 U.S.C. § 1673(b));</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a court or administrative order that has directed the parent to provide health insurance coverage for the child, provide the insurer with the order for health insurance coverage and inform the insurer that the order operates to enroll the child in the coverage; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_42_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a medical support notice issued by the IV-D agency under § 46-251.02, comply with the provisions of §§ 46-251.04, 46-251.07, and 46-251.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
