<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-301.110a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-301.110a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_301_110a">
        <akn:num>1-301.110a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Leasing authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement is authorized to enter into lease agreements with any person, copartnership, corporation, or other entity, which do not bind the government of the District of Columbia for periods in excess of 20 years for each such lease agreement, on such terms and conditions, including, without limitation, lease-purchase, as he deems to be in the interest of the District of Columbia and necessary for the accommodation of District of Columbia agencies and activities in buildings or other improvements which are in existence or are to be constructed by the lessor for such purposes, or on unimproved real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The estimated maximum cost of any project approved pursuant to this section may be increased by an amount equal to the increase, if any, as determined by the Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement, in construction or alteration costs, from the date of transmittal of the prospectus to the Council, not to exceed 10% of the estimated gross cost.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement shall not make any agreement or undertake any commitment that will result in the construction of any building that is to be constructed for lease to, and for predominant use by, the District until the Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement has established detailed specification requirements for the building and unless the proposal is consistent with the Public Facilities Plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_h_1">
      <akn:num>(h-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement may acquire a new leasehold interest in any building that is proposed to be leased for the predominant use of rentable space by, or constructed for lease to and for predominant use of rentable space by the District government without regard to §§ 2-354.02 and 2-354.03; provided that such leasehold interest is acquired pursuant to a lease negotiated on behalf of the District by a duly licensed commercial real estate broker pursuant to a tenant representative services contract then in effect between the District and the broker.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_110a_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement shall inspect every building to be constructed for lease to, and for predominant use by, the District government during the construction of the building in order to determine compliance with the specifications established for the building. Upon the completion of the building, the Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement shall evaluate the building to determine the extent, if any, of failure to comply with the specifications for the building. The Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement shall ensure that any contract entered into for a leasehold interest in a building shall contain a provision that permits a reduction in rent during any period that the building is not in compliance with the specifications for the building.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
