<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-309.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-309.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_309_10">
        <akn:num>1-309.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions — Duties and responsibilities; notice; great weight; access to documents; reports; contributions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Advisory Neighborhood Commission (“Commission”) may advise the Council of the District of Columbia, the Mayor and each executive agency, and all independent agencies, boards and commissions of the government of the District of Columbia with respect to all proposed matters of District government policy including, but not limited to, decisions regarding planning, streets, recreation, social services programs, education, health, safety, budget, and sanitation which affect that Commission area. For the purposes of this part, proposed actions of District government policy shall be the same as those for which prior notice of proposed rulemaking is required pursuant to § 2-505(a) or as pertains to the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Thirty days written notice, excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays of such District government actions or proposed actions, including (1) the intent to acquire an interest in real property, either through purchase or lease or (2) the intent to change the use of property owned or leased by or on behalf of the government, shall be given by first-class mail to the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, each affected Commission, the Commissioner representing a single-member district affected by said actions, and to each affected Ward Councilmember, except where shorter notice on good cause made and published with the notice may be provided or in the case of an emergency and such notice shall be published in the District of Columbia Register. In cases in which the 30-day written notice requirement is not satisfied, notification of such proposed government action or actions to the Commissioner representing the affected single-member district shall be made by mail. The Register shall be made available, without cost, to each Commission. A central record of all such notices shall be held by the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reserved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission may present its views to any federal or District agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall not have the power to initiate a legal action in the courts of the District of Columbia or in the federal courts, provided that this limitation does not apply to or prohibit any Commissioner from bringing suit as a citizen.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reserved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No Commission may solicit or receive funds unless specifically authorized to do so by the Council, except that receipt of individual contributions of $1,000 or less need not be approved by the Council. No person shall make any contribution, nor shall a Commission receive any contribution from any person which, when aggregated with all other contributions received from that person, exceeds $1,000 per calendar year. Each Commission shall file with its quarterly reports to the District of Columbia Auditor required pursuant to § 1-309.13(j) details of all contributions received during the relevant period of time.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission shall monitor complaints of Commission area residents with respect to the delivery of District government services and file comments on same with the appropriate District government entity and the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission shall develop an annual fiscal year spending plan budget for the upcoming fiscal year within 60 days of notification of the amount of the Commission’s annual allotment. Prior to adoption of the budget at a public meeting, the Commission shall present the budget at a public meeting of the Commission to elicit comments from the residents of the Commission area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission may, where appropriate, constitute the citizen advisory mechanism required by any federal statute (unless specifically prohibited by federal statute).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_10_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission that adopts recommendations regarding legislation pending before the Council shall forward a copy of the recommendations to the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions (“Office”) and to the Secretary to the Council within 14 days after adoption. The Office shall keep a publicly accessible file of all Commission recommendations submitted pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
