<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-309.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-309.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_309_11">
        <akn:num>1-309.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions — Meetings; bylaws governing operation and internal structure; officers; open meetings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reserved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission shall give notice of all meetings or convocations to each Commissioner, individuals with official business before the Commission, and residents of the Commission area no less than 7 days prior to the date of such meeting. Shorter notice may be given in the case of an emergency or for other good cause. Notice of regular and emergency meetings must include, but is not limited to, at least 2 of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission shall establish bylaws governing its operation and internal structure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No Commission shall be entitled to incorporation, provided that no member of the Commission may be liable for action taken as an elected representative from a single-member district.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Chairmanship of each Commission committee or task force shall be open to any resident of the Commission area. The chairperson of each such committee or task force shall be appointed by the Commission. Each Commission shall make a good faith effort to involve all segments of the Commission population in its deliberations regardless of race, sex, age, voting status, religion, economic status, sexual orientation, or gender identity or expression.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-309_11_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Commission, including each committee of a Commission, shall be subject to the open meetings provisions of § 1-207.42(a). No meeting may be closed to the public unless personnel or legal matters are discussed. Without limiting the scope of that section, the following categories of information are specifically made available to the public:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
