<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-301.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-301.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_301_01">
        <akn:num>1-301.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Additional powers of Mayor, Council, and Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Waiver of business license renewal fees for personnel of armed forces. — The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within its discretion, in accordance with such regulations as it may make, to provide for the waiver of payment by any person in the military service of the United States of any annual or other periodic fee required by law to be paid to the District of Columbia or to any District of Columbia board or commission as a condition to retaining or renewing any license or permit to engage in any business or calling or to practice any profession in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Bond requirements for certain businesses; amount; termination of surety’s liability; notification by surety of payment on bond; insolvency of surety; action on bond; amount of recovery; certified copy of bond; license examination. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Leasing powers. — The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within his discretion to rent any building or land belonging to the District of Columbia or under the jurisdiction of the Mayor, or any available space therein, whenever such building or land, or space therein, is not then required for the purpose for which it was acquired, and to rent any used personal property belonging to the District of Columbia which is not then needed for the purpose for which it was acquired: Provided, that nothing contained in this subsection shall have the effect of changing in any manner Public Law No. 732, 74th Congress, entitled “An Act to authorize the operation of stands in federal buildings by blind persons, to enlarge the economic opportunities of the blind, and for other purposes”, approved June 20, 1936 (20 U.S.C. §§ 107-107f).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Issuance of revocable permits for construction of tunnels, and laying of conduits and pipes. — The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within his discretion to grant revocable permits upon such terms, conditions, bonds, and rentals as the Mayor may impose for the construction of tunnels, and the laying of conduits and pipes in the alleys, streets, and avenues in the District of Columbia under the jurisdiction of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Suspension of officers and employees. — Except as otherwise provided, the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within his discretion to suspend, with or without pay, any officer or employee appointed by him and, under such rules or regulations as he may prescribe, to delegate this power to any officers or employees of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Name and rename highways, buildings, public places and property. — The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within its discretion to name or change the name of a highway, circle, bridge, building, park or other public place or property as provided in §§ 9-204.01 through 9-204.09:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Assess and collect fees for copies and transcripts of regulations, permits, certificates and records; disposition of moneys. — The Mayor of the District of Columbia may fix, assess, and collect fees for copies of orders, regulations, permits, certificates, and transcripts of records furnished by the District of Columbia, including, but not limited to, transcripts of records of births and deaths. Such fees shall not exceed the reasonably estimated cost of providing such copies, certificates, and transcripts, and shall be deposited into the General Fund of the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Penalties for violation of rules and regulations. — The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within its discretion, where not otherwise specifically provided, to prescribe a penalty upon conviction of a violation of any rule or regulation authorized by §§ 1-301.01 to 1-301.05 and 1-301.21 by a fine of not more than $300 or imprisonment of not more than 90 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Purchase and sale of maps and publications; issuance without charge; delegation of authority; payment of cost. — The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within his or her discretion:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Placement of orders with federal departments and agencies; payment of cost; obligations upon appropriations. — The Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement is authorized and empowered in his discretion to place orders, if he determines it to be in the best interest of the District of Columbia, with any federal department, establishment, bureau, or office for materials, supplies, equipment, work, or services of any kind that such federal agency may be in a position to supply or be equipped to render, by contract or otherwise, and shall pay promptly by check to such federal agency, upon its written request, either in advance or upon furnishing or performance thereof, all or part of the estimated or actual costs thereof as determined by such department, establishment, bureau, or office as may be requisitioned; but proper adjustments on the basis of the actual costs of the materials, supplies or equipment furnished or work or services performed, paid for in advance, shall be made as may be agreed upon by the departments, establishments, bureaus, or offices concerned. Orders placed as provided in this subsection shall be considered as obligations upon appropriations in the same manner as orders or contracts placed with private contractors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_j_1">
      <akn:num>(j-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Placement of orders with the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Placement of orders with departments, offices, or agencies of the District; payment of cost; obligations upon appropriations. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-301_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Leases or permits for use of public space over or under 9th Street Southwest. — The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered in his discretion to enter into leases of, or to grant revocable permits for the use of, the public space over or under 9th Street Southwest in the District of Columbia to an extent not inconsistent with the use of such street by the general public for the purpose of travel, and in connection with any such lease or permit to impose such terms, including but not limited to the deposit of bond or other security, and to provide for the payment of such rents or fees as the Mayor may, in his discretion, determine to be necessary or desirable, but the Mayor shall, in connection with entering into a lease for, or granting a permit for, the use of public space over said Street in the District of Columbia, provide as a condition of any such lease or permit that such space shall not be used by the lessee or permittee in such manner as to deprive any real property not owned by such lessee or permittee of its easements of light, air, and access.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
