<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.65"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.65/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_307_65">
        <akn:num>1-307.65</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Financial institution establishment of opportunity accounts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_65_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A financial institution shall not establish an opportunity account for an account holder unless the establishment of the account by the financial institution is approved by the Mayor. The Mayor may grant general approval to a financial institution to establish an opportunity account for any person meeting specified standards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_65_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A financial institution may establish an opportunity account reserve fund account if the establishment of the account by the financial institution is approved by the Mayor. The Mayor may grant general approval to a financial institution to establish an opportunity account reserve fund account for any organization meeting specified standards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_65_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A financial institution establishing an opportunity account shall certify to the Mayor, on a form to be prescribed by the Mayor and accompanied by any documentation required by the Mayor, that an opportunity account has been established and that funds have been deposited into the account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_65_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A financial institution establishing an opportunity account reserve fund account shall certify to the Mayor, on a form to be prescribed by the Mayor and accompanied by any documentation required by the Mayor, that an opportunity account reserve fund account has been established and that funds have been deposited into the account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_65_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A financial institution establishing an opportunity account shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
