<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.67"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-307.67/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_307_67">
        <akn:num>1-307.67</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Matching funds and return of matching funds; tax exemption.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_67_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The administering organization shall deposit into a matching funds account for the account holder matching funds of at least $2 for every dollar that the account holder deposits into the account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_67_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to annual available appropriations, the District of Columbia shall provide to an administering organization matching funds of $2, to be deposited into the matching funds account for the account holder, for every dollar that the account holder deposits into the opportunity account; provided that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_67_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There shall be no limit on federal or private matching funds made available to an account holder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_67_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to annual available appropriations, matching funds deposited into a matching funds account or withdrawn by an account holder from a matching funds account shall be exempt from taxation under District of Columbia law; provided, that any money withdrawn from a matching funds account by an account holder for an unapproved use shall be taxed as income to the account holder, unless the funds are reinstated in accordance with ยง 1-307.68(d).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_67_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The administering organization shall deposit matching funds in an account separate from the opportunity account. The separate account may be the opportunity account reserve fund account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-307_67_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except for matching funds used for an approved purpose under ยง 1-307.68(a) before 10 years after the establishment of the opportunity account, the matching funds shall be returned to the District of Columbia and administering organization in the same amounts as the matching funds were provided 10 years after the establishment of the opportunity account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
