<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-325.181"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-325.181/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_325_181">
        <akn:num>1-325.181</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>West End Library and Fire Station Maintenance Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_181_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the West End Library and Fire Station Maintenance Fund, which shall be used solely to pay the expenses of providing supplemental maintenance service, insurance, and capital replacement for the West End Library and West End Fire Station along with those regularly provided by the District of Columbia Public Library and the Mayor, respectively, and ensuring that both facilities are maintained in a manner that is consistent with the high-quality conditions of the larger buildings of which they are a part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_181_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall deposit into the Fund 85% of the Deed Transfer and Recordation Taxes attributable to the new buildings constructed on Lots 836, 837, and 855 in Square 37 (or such successor record or assessment and taxation lots as may be created through future subdivision or creation of condominium units).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_181_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_181_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_181_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Fund shall be audited annually by the Inspector General, who shall transmit the audit report to the Mayor and Council no later than 90 days after close of the fiscal year. The annual audit shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
