<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-325.172"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-325.172/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_325_172">
        <akn:num>1-325.172</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_172_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as a nonlapsing fund outside the General Fund of the District of Columbia a fund designated as the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund. The Chief Financial Officer shall pay upon April 8, 2011, an amount not to exceed $5 million annually, but not to exceed $25 million in the aggregate, of the H Street Real Property Tax Increment Revenue and the H Street Sales Tax Increment Revenue into the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_172_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds deposited into the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (c) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_172_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>DMPED shall use a portion of each of the $5 million annual allocations into the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_172_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall prepare and deliver an annual report to the Council each year on January 1st. The annual report shall contain a listing and description of each grant issued from the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund pursuant to this part. Each listing shall contain specific information about the nature of the grant, the grantee, the use of the grant funds, the projected number of new jobs created for District residents, the projected economic benefit to the District, and any other information the Council may request regarding each grant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
