<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-325.171"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-325.171/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_325_171">
        <akn:num>1-325.171</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chief Financial Officer” means the Chief Financial Officer established by § 1-204.24(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DMPED” means the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development established by Mayor’s Order 99-62 (April 9, 1999).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Developer Sponsor” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 47-4634(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“H Street Real Property Tax Increment Revenue” means the portion of the real property tax imposed by Chapter 8 of Title 47 on real property in the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area in any fiscal year that exceeds the amount of the real property tax imposed on the real property in the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area in the fiscal year ended September 30, 2007.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area” means the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area as defined in section 2(2) of the Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution of 2007, effective July 10, 2007(Res. 17-257; 54 DCR 7194).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“H Street Retail Developer” means a person or corporation that proposes to, or provides technical assistance to, engage in the business of sale of personal property or services for use or consumption by the purchasers at locations in the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-325_171_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“H Street Sales Tax Increment Revenue” means the portion of the sales tax imposed by Chapter 20 of Title 47 on goods and services sold in the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area in any fiscal year that exceeds the amount of the sales tax imposed in the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area in the fiscal year ended September 30, 2007.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
