<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-331.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-331.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_331_10">
        <akn:num>1-331.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Designation of Casey Mansion as Mayor’s Official Residence.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-331_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On June 5, 2001, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted the Mayor’s May 3, 2001 recommendation (PR 14-179) to accept and approve the proposal of the Eugene B. Casey Foundation, as set forth in a February 26, 2001 letter to the Mayor from Mrs. Eugene B. Casey, to designate the site at 1801 Foxhall Road, N.W., as the official residence of the Mayor of the District of Columbia (“Casey Mansion Proposal”). The Casey Mansion Proposal provides that the Casey Mansion Foundation, which has already acquired the property at 1801 Foxhall Road, N.W., would be endowed with sufficient private resources to build and maintain, in perpetuity, all operating costs for the buildings and grounds of the official Mayor’s residence, including furnishings, housekeeping, insurance, landscaping, maintenance, security, staffing, and utilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-331_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to the issuance of any building permit for an official Mayor’s residence at 1801 Foxhall Road, N.W., the Mayor shall require that the Casey Mansion Proposal is memorialized in a document signed by representatives of the Mayor and the Eugene B. Casey Foundation or other foundation established to own, build, or maintain the Casey Mansion, which is provided to the Council and made available to the public, and which sets forth the specific terms and any conditions of the Casey Mansion Proposal, including the rights and obligations of each party, and including but not limited to information on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
