<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-515.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-515.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_515_02">
        <akn:num>1-515.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District residency preference for employees; District residency requirement for agency heads.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-515_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all District subordinate agencies, independent agencies, and instrumentalities shall use a ranking system based on a scale of 100 points for all employment decisions for positions equivalent to Career Service, educational employee, Legal Service, and Management Supervisory Service positions, as defined under § 1-603.01(3), (6), (13A), and (13B), and shall award each District resident applicant a preference of 10 points unless the resident declines the preference points. The 10 preference points shall be in addition to any points awarded on the 100-point scale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-515_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant claiming a hiring preference shall submit no less than 8 proofs of bona fide residency in a manner determined by the Mayor. If hired, the employee shall agree in writing to maintain bona fide District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of hire and shall provide proof of such residency annually to the director of personnel for the agency or instrumentality for the first 7 years of employment. Failure to maintain District residency for the consecutive 7-year period shall result in forfeiture of employment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-515_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-515_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall conduct annual audits of each subordinate agency’s personnel records to ensure that all persons claiming a residency preference at time of hiring complies with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section. Audit reports shall be submitted annually to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-515_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each subordinate agency, independent agency, and instrumentality head shall be a resident of the District of Columbia throughout his or her tenure and shall forfeit his or her position if he or she fails to remain a resident of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-515_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may issue rules to implement the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
