<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-607.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-607.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_607_01">
        <akn:num>1-607.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Affirmative action; exercise of religion.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-607_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council reaffirms its intent that the objectives of the Affirmative Action in District Government Employment Act, as amended (D.C. Code, § 1-521.01) be carried out.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-607_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each agency shall make reasonable accommodations for the free exercise of religion by its employees, and may adjust work schedules unless such adjustment would result in a substantial disruption of District business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-607_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an employee’s religious beliefs require the employee to take time off from work during certain periods of the workday or workweek, the employee may elect to make up the time off, rather than to charge the time off to leave, in accordance with the procedures established under subsections (d) and (e) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-607_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee who makes an election pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall, if the need to take time off is foreseeable, request an adjustment of his or her work schedule and obtain supervisory approval of the adjustment at least 10 days before taking time off from work. A request to adjust a work schedule may be disapproved if it is demonstrated that the adjustment would clearly interfere with the efficient conduct of the activities of the entity of the District government for which the employee works.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-607_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of an employee’s opportunity to obtain a religious accommodation shall be provided to the employee at the time the employee accepts appointment with the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-607_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the use of other forms of leave authorized by the District government or to require a supervisor to allow an employee the opportunity to work more than 40 hours in a given week to make up for the time taken off for the religious accommodation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
