<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-609.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-609.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_609_03">
        <akn:num>1-609.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Number of Excepted Service employees; redelegation of authority to appoint; publication requirement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Under qualifications issued pursuant to § 1-609.01, each appropriate personnel authority may appoint persons to the Excepted Service as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The authority to appoint persons to the Excepted Service, which is vested in subsection (a) of this section, may be redelegated, in whole or in part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 45 days of actual appointment and within 45 days of any change in such appointment, the names, position titles, and agency placements of all persons appointed to Excepted Service positions under the authority of this section shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the discretion of the personnel authority, an individual appointed to the Excepted Service at grade level DS-11 or above pursuant to this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The personnel authority may authorize performance incentives for exceptional service for individuals appointed pursuant to this section not to exceed 10% of the rate of basic pay in any year.  Such exceptional service incentives may be paid only when the Excepted Service employee is bound by a performance contract that clearly identifies measurable goals and outcomes and the employee has exceeded contractual expectations in the year for which the incentive is paid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual appointed to the Excepted Service pursuant to this section or § 1-609.08 may be paid severance pay upon separation for non-disciplinary reasons according to the length of the individual’s employment with the District government as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 90 days of September 10, 1999, and notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Mayor shall submit to the Council for approval under the provisions of § 1-611.06, regulations establishing the Metropolitan Police Department Excepted Service Sworn Employees” Compensation System.  Such regulations shall establish policies and procedures governing the compensation, promotion, transfer, and demotion of Metropolitan Police Department excepted service sworn employees appointed pursuant to section § 1-609.03(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
