<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-608.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-608.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_608_01">
        <akn:num>1-608.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Creation of Career Service.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue rules and regulations governing employment, advancement, and retention in the Career Service which shall include all persons appointed to positions in the District government, except persons appointed to positions in the Excepted, Executive, Educational, Management Supervisory, or Legal Service. The Career Service shall also include, after January 1, 1980, all persons who are transferred into the Career Service pursuant to the provisions of subsection (c) of § 1-602.04. The rules and regulations governing Career Service employees shall be indexed and cross referenced to the incumbent classification system and shall provide for the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Selections to the Career Service shall be made in accordance with equal employment opportunity principles as set forth in subchapter VII of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may issue separate rules and regulations concerning the personnel system affecting members of the uniform services of the Police and Fire Departments which may provide for a probationary period of at least 1 year. Other such separate rules and regulations may only be issued to carry out provisions of this chapter which accord such member of the uniform services of the Police and Fire Departments separate treatment under this chapter. Such separate rules and regulations are not a bar to collective bargaining during the negotiation process between the Mayor and the recognized labor organizations for the Metropolitan Police and Fire Departments, but shall be within the parameters of § 1-617.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For members of the Metropolitan Police Department and notwithstanding § 1-632.03(a)(1)(B) or any other law or regulation, the Assistant Chiefs of Police, Deputy Chiefs of Police, and inspectors shall be selected from among the lieutenants and captains of the force and shall be returned to the same civil service rank when the Mayor so determines.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_d_2">
      <akn:num>(d-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_d_3">
      <akn:num>(d-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each subordinate agency head shall submit to the Mayor and the Council quarterly reports detailing the names of all new employees and their pay schedules, titles, and place of residence. The report shall explain the reasons for employment of non-District residents. The Mayor shall integrate into each subordinate agency’s yearly performance objectives the rate of success in hiring District residents. The Mayor shall conduct annual audits of each subordinate agency’s personnel records to ensure that all persons claiming a residency preference at time of hiring complies with the provisions of subsection (e)(2) of this section. Audit reports shall be submitted annually to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
