<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-608.62"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-608.62/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_608_62">
        <akn:num>1-608.62</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Applicability.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_62_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-608.52 shall include attorneys employed by the District of Columbia Board of Education as part of the new Legal Service only as long as there is no Congressional statutory requirement that attorneys employed by the District of Columbia public schools be classified as Educational Service employees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_62_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_62_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 90 days after April 20, 1999, the Mayor shall appoint to the new Legal Service any attorney who has been appointed to a position in the Office of the Corporation Counsel as of the effective date of this subchapter. Effective October 1, 1999, the appropriate personnel authority shall appoint to the new Legal Service any attorney who has been appointed to a position in any other subordinate agency or in any independent agency as of that date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_62_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of ยง 1-608.56 shall apply to individuals hired on or before December 31, 1979 as attorneys by the Mayor, an agency under the personnel authority of the Mayor, or any independent agency upon enactment of legislation by Congress that states the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_62_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective October 1, 2014, any attorney who is employed by the Office of the Attorney General and performs work primarily as or for the General Counsel of a subordinate agency shall become an attorney employed by the subordinate agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
