<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-608.01a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-608.01a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_608_01a">
        <akn:num>1-608.01a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Creation of the Educational Service.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of this subchapter, the term “Board” means the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia for educational employees of the University of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall issue rules and regulations governing employment, advancement, and retention in the Educational Service, which shall include all educational employees of the District of Columbia employed by the Board. The rules and regulations shall be indexed and cross referenced as to the incumbent classification and compensation system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-608_01a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall submit to the Council quarterly reports detailing the names of all new employees, their pay schedules, titles, and place of residence. The report shall explain the reasons for employment of non-District residents. The Board shall integrate into its yearly performance objectives the rate of success in hiring District residents. The Boards shall conduct annual audits of its personnel records to ensure that all persons claiming a residency preference at time of hiring complies with the provisions of subsection (d)(2) of this section. Audit reports shall be submitted annually to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
