<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-609.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-609.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_609_06">
        <akn:num>1-609.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Domicile.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An appointee to the Excepted Service shall be domiciled in the District of Columbia at the time of his or her appointment or within 180 days of their appointment and shall remain domiciled in the District of Columbia during the period of the appointment, to be considered a bona fide resident. The failure to become a District of Columbia domiciliary or to maintain a District of Columbia domicile shall result in the forfeiture of the position to which the person has been appointed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Domicile shall be proven by affirmative acts by an employee who is not a District of Columbia domiciliary and does not maintain a principal place of residence in the District of Columbia at the time of his or her appointment with the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An Excepted Service appointee shall establish and certify that the District of Columbia is his or her domicile and principal place of residence as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person hired in the Excepted Service prior to March 16, 1989, who was required to be or become a District of Columbia resident within 180 days of appointment and maintain that residency or forfeit employment, shall continue to be bound by this domicile requirement after March 16, 1989.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person hired in the Excepted or Executive Service prior to October 1, 2002, who was required to be or become a District of Columbia resident within 180 days of appointment and maintain that residency or forfeit employment, shall continue to be bound by the terms of the residency requirement in effect at the time of hiring, and any waivers of the residency requirement previously granted to the person shall continue in effect. The requirements of D.C. Law 14-185 shall only apply to persons hired after October 1, 2002.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-609_06_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
