<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-606.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-606.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_606_01">
        <akn:num>1-606.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Office of Employee Appeals; composition; qualifications; term of office; vacancies; Chairperson; quorum; appeal procedure; conflict of interest; compensation; appointment of employees; expenditures; removal; exclusivity of position.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established an Office of Employee Appeals (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “Office”). The Office shall be composed of 5 members to be appointed by the Mayor in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section within 60 days of the date this chapter becomes effective as provided in § 1-636.02. Members of the Office shall have demonstrated knowledge concerning personnel management or labor relations, and a reputation for impartiality and integrity in the discharge of their responsibilities. No member shall be eligible for reappointment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term of office of each member of the Office shall be 6 years: Except, that: (1) Of those members first appointed, 2 shall serve for 2 years and 3 shall serve for 4 years, respectively, from the date of appointment; and (2) any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his or her predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. No member may serve beyond the expiration of his or her term, except that a member serving a term of less than 6 years, who was appointed under clause (1) of this subsection, or a member who is appointed to serve the remainder of an unexpired term of three years or less, who was appointed under clause (2) of this subsection, may be reappointed for a full 6-year term. Appointments to fill vacancies shall be made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (a) of this section. The Mayor shall designate the term of each member at the time of his or her appointment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chairperson of the Office shall be designated by the Mayor. The Chairperson shall be the chief executive of the Office. The Mayor shall from time to time designate 1 member as Vice Chairperson of the Office. During the absence or disability of the Chairperson, the Vice Chairperson shall perform the duties of the Chairperson.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Three members of the Office shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of official business and the issuance of rules and regulations. The Office may hear appeals brought before it under this subchapter by a hearing examiner. An appeal from a decision of any such hearing examiner may be taken either to the full Office or to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia at the option of any adversely affected party. If an appeal is taken directly to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, the decision of a hearing examiner, for the purposes of such appeal, shall be considered as the final decision of the Office. If an appeal is taken from a decision of a hearing examiner to the full Office, the decision of the hearing examiner shall be stayed pending a final decision of the Office. Upon a vote of a majority of its members, the Office may hear de novo all issues of fact or law relating to an appeal of a decision of the hearing examiner, except the Office may decide to consider only the record made before such hearing examiner. A final decision of the full Office, relating to an appeal brought to it from a hearing examiner, shall be appealable to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Upon reviewing the final decision of the Office, the Court shall determine if it is supported by substantial evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If at any time any matter comes before the Office in which any member has any interest, directly or indirectly, other than as that of a taxpayer, the member shall publicly so state and this statement shall be recorded in the minutes of that meeting. The member thereafter is disqualified from participation in the consideration of the matter under deliberation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Office is entitled to compensation at the rate of $125 per diem or $15.62 per hour whichever provides less, while actually in the service of the Office. Should a member serve in excess of 8 hours on a particular day, such member may be paid additional compensation for such period of service, to a maximum of 2 per diem payments for any consecutive 24-hour period. Adjustment to such rates of compensation shall be made in accordance with § 1-611.08(b), not to exceed the sum of $20,000 per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall be considered an independent agency for budgetary and administrative purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any member of the Office who: (1) Violates the provisions of subsection (k) of this section; (2) engages in a conflict of interest in violation of the provisions of subchapter XVIII of this chapter; or (3) is convicted of a crime, which if committed in the District of Columbia would be a felony, which is by this or any other statute punishable by disqualification to hold office, in addition to the other punishment prescribed for such offense, shall be removed from office as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No member of the Office may hold any other position in the District government or any subordinate position in the Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-606_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2, each qualified District resident applicant shall receive an additional 10-point preference over a qualified non-District resident applicant for all positions within the Office unless the applicant declines the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to, and not instead of, qualifications established for the position. All persons hired after February 6, 2008, shall submit proof of residency upon employment in a manner determined by the Office. An applicant claiming the hiring preference under this section shall agree in writing to maintain bona fide District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of hire and shall provide proof of residency annually to the Director of Personnel for the first 7 years of employment. Failure to maintain District residency for the consecutive 7-year period shall result in forfeiture of employment. The Office of Employee Appeals shall submit to the Mayor and Council annual reports detailing the names of all new employees and their pay schedules, titles, and place of residence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
