<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-610.52a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-610.52a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_610_52a">
        <akn:num>1-610.52a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Public Safety Executive Service pay schedule.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Service Public Safety Schedule (“DX Public Safety Schedule”) shall be divided into 4 pay levels and shall be the basic pay schedule for subordinate agency heads within the public safety cluster who are required to hold a medical degree or another advanced health-related degree.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall designate the appropriate pay level for each subordinate agency head within the public safety cluster based on market analyses considering the qualifications and work experience of each individual appointee, and other relevant criteria.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person paid from the DX Public Safety Schedule shall not be entitled to premium pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each level within the schedule shall have a minimum and maximum salary range established by the Mayor, subject to Council review and approval by resolution. Initial salary ranges shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council for a 60-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove of the proposed changes to the salary ranges by resolution within this 60-day period, the proposed salary ranges shall be deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any changes to the salary ranges established pursuant to subsection (d) of this section shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council for a 15-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove of the proposed changes to the salary ranges by resolution within this 15-day period, the proposed salary ranges shall be deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Initial salary ranges and any changes to the salary ranges shall become effective upon approval and shall be published in the District of Columbia Register no later than 45 days after their approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-610_52a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “public safety cluster” means the following District agencies or any successor agencies:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
