<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-613.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-613.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_613_01">
        <akn:num>1-613.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Programs for employee development.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor and the District of Columbia Board of Education shall each install and maintain programs for the training and development of their respective employees through planned courses, systems, or other instruction or education in fields which are or will be related to the performance of official duties for the District, in order to increase their knowledge, proficiency, ability, skill and qualifications in the performance of these duties. This system of training shall be created to ensure that the principles of efficiency, economy and equitable treatment for all employees is carried out for the successful operation of the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When educational facilities under the control and direction of the District government are not the most economical available to carry out the provisions of this section, the Mayor and the District of Columbia Board of Education may make arrangements and agreements with colleges, universities, educational institutions, appropriate institutions or corporations. The appropriate personnel authority shall have the authority to enter into these arrangements and agreements for employee development. The Mayor and the District of Columbia Board of Education shall issue rules and regulations concerning what items must be included in agreements for employee development activities relying on non-District facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor and the District of Columbia Board of Education shall issue rules and regulations concerning the implementation of this subchapter, consistent with equal employment opportunities and standards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The head of each District agency shall prepare an annual employee development plan which identifies subject matter areas where training is needed, the types of programs and courses which could be used to meet those identified training needs and the types of training activities which will be carried out in the coming year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Programs developed under the authority of this subchapter are appropriate matters for collective bargaining with labor organizations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-613_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall maintain a record in each employee’s personnel file of the training and development programs in which the employee has participated. The Mayor may dictate the content of the record; provided, that it includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
