<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_611_04">
        <akn:num>1-611.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Compensation system for Career and Excepted Services — Established.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall develop, in consultation with the Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, a new compensation system for all employees in the Career, Legal, Excepted, and Management Supervisory Services. Any comments that the Board of Education or the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia wish to make on the proposed system shall be presented along with the proposed pay system submitted by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This new system shall include, but need not be limited to, provisions for basic pay, pay increases based on quality and length of service, premium pay, allowances, and severance pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide for appropriate consultations with employee organizations in the development of the new compensation system for Career Service employees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall submit any proposed new compensation system to the Council for approval under the provisions of § 1-611.06. The submission shall include proposed dates on which the new compensation system shall become effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Until such time as a new compensation system is approved, the compensation system, including the salary and pay schedules, in effect on December 31, 1979, shall continue in effect: Provided, that pay adjustments shall be made in accordance with the policy stated in § 1-611.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Until such time as the Metropolitan Police Department Excepted Service Sworn Employees’ Compensation System is established, the Mayor may develop a pay schedule, to be limited to no more than 10 excepted service sworn employees, for Metropolitan Police Department Excepted Service sworn employees and submit it to the Council for approval in accordance with § 1-611.06.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of subsections (a) through (d) of this section, the term compensation system shall not include salary or pay schedules.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee who is under indictment or who is charged by information with or who has been convicted of a felony related to his or her employment duties shall not be eligible for benefits under an Easy Out, Early Out, or similar Retirement Incentive Program; provided, that any employee who is ultimately acquitted or cleared of any charge which caused his ineligibility shall be eligible for all benefits as if that employee has never been indicted for or charged by information with a felony.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “felony” means an offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment that exceeds one year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
