<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_611_06">
        <akn:num>1-611.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Compensation system for Career and Excepted Services — Review by the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Council by resolution approves, without revision, the new compensation system or systems, or any later changes in such system or systems or in the salary or pay schedules under the system or systems proposed in accordance with § 1-611.04 or § 1-611.05, the schedules shall become effective on the dates specified in the schedule submitted by the Mayor as provided in subsection (d) of § 1-611.05. If the Council takes no action on the Mayor’s proposed change within 60 calendar days of the submission thereof, such change shall be deemed to have been approved by the Council on the day next following the expiration of this 60-day period. The 60 calendar days for Council review shall not include days that pass during a recess of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Council revises the proposal, it shall return the proposal with its revisions to the Mayor. If the Mayor concurs in the revisions, the provisions of the compensation plan as revised shall become effective on the dates specified by the Council in the resolution revising the compensation plan, as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor does not concur in any 1 or more of the revisions recommended by the Council, including the Council’s recommendation as to the dates on which the pay changes shall become effective, the Mayor shall return the revisions within 10 days to the Council, with a statement of the Mayor’s reasons for not concurring. If the Council, by a two-thirds vote of the members present and voting, adopts a resolution insisting upon any 1 or more of the original revisions, the Council shall return the proposal and the revisions upon which the Council insists to the Mayor within 10 days of the Council’s receipt of the Mayor’s statement of reasons for not concurring in the revisions recommended by the Council. If any revisions insisted upon by the Council, including the Council’s recommendation as to the dates on which the pay changes should become effective, shall result in a greater cost to the District government than the Mayor’s original proposal, the Council shall adopt an act to provide a source of funding to cover the increased cost. The pay provisions of the compensation plan so adopted shall become effective on the dates specified by the Council in the resolution revising the new compensation system. If the two-thirds vote does not prevail, or the Council does not act within 10 days of the Council’s receipt of the Mayor’s statement of reasons for not concurring in the revisions recommended by the Council, the Mayor’s original proposal, with the revisions proposed by the Council in which the Mayor has concurred, shall become effective. The 10 days for Council review shall not include Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Retroactive pay is payable by reason of an increase in the salary or pay schedules under this section only where:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
