<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-617.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-617.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_617_10">
        <akn:num>1-617.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Selection of exclusive representatives; elections.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Exclusive recognition shall be granted to a labor organization which has been selected by a majority of employees in an appropriate unit who participate in an election, conducted by secret ballot, or by any other method in conformity with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Representation elections shall be conducted by an impartial body selected by the mutual agreement of the parties or, in the absence of a mutual agreement, by the Board. The entity conducting the election shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter, those rules and regulations as may be issued by the Board, or any election agreement as may be reached which is not inconsistent with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall certify the results of each election within 10 working days after the final tally of votes, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Board has reason to believe that such allegations or challenges may be valid, the Board shall hold a hearing on the matter within 2 weeks after the date of receipt of the objection. The Board shall give due notice of the hearing to all parties. If the Board determines that the outcome of the election was affected, even by third-party interference, or if the Board determines that the number of challenged ballots was sufficient to affect the outcome of the election, it shall require corrective action and may order a new election. If the Board determines that the alleged conduct did not affect the outcome of the election, it shall immediately certify the election results.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A labor organization seeking exclusive recognition shall submit to the Board and the appropriate agency a roster of its officers and representatives, a copy of its constitution and bylaws, and a statement of its objectives.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
