<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-612.35"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-612.35/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_612_35">
        <akn:num>1-612.35</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Approval or disapproval of leave transfer.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-612_35_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before approving an application, the agency head or designee shall determine that the request to become a recipient employee has been necessitated by a prolonged absence due to the employee’s serious health condition or the employee’s responsibility to provide personal care to an immediate relative.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-612_35_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In approving or disapproving the application, the agency head or designee may consider the leave record of the potential receiving employee, the probability that the recipient employee will separate from service, and any exigency or disruption in service that the agency or independent agency may experience.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-612_35_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The agency head or designee shall approve or disapprove an application of a proposed recipient employee and, to the extent practicable, shall notify the proposed recipient employee or the employee acting on behalf of the proposed recipient employee within 15 calendar days of receipt of the application. Notwithstanding any other law, if the recipient employee is eligible for leave under the Family and Medical Leave provisions of 28 U.S.C. § 2601 et seq., the leave transfer shall be granted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
