<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_611_05">
        <akn:num>1-611.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Compensation system for Career and Excepted Services — Periodic review.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, in consultation with the Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, shall provide for a periodic review of the basic compensation system, in order to improve the system and provide continuing conformity with the policy established by § 1-611.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>These reviews of compensation shall include, but need not be limited to, review of the adequacy of the rates of basic pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide for appropriate consultations with employee organizations of employees under his or her jurisdiction in the periodic reviews of the compensation system(s).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, in consultation with the personnel authorities named in subsection (a) of this section, shall consider, on an annual basis, changes in the compensation system or systems and in the salary and pay schedules under such system or systems, and shall submit adjustments, if any, to the Council pursuant to § 1-611.06. The submission to the Council shall include proposed dates on which the adjustments shall become effective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, because of economic conditions, the pendency of collective bargaining, or budgetary constraints due to limited appropriations or revenues, the Mayor should, in any year, consider it inappropriate to submit a proposed change, or to make the adjustment in the salary or pay schedules pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, an alternative plan may be submitted with respect to such changes or adjustments as the Mayor considers appropriate with a statement of the reasons therefor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
