<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-617.17"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-617.17/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_617_17">
        <akn:num>1-617.17</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Collective bargaining concerning compensation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Collective bargaining concerning compensation is authorized as provided in §§ 1-602.06 and 1-617.16. Such compensation bargaining shall preempt other provisions of this subchapter except as provided in this section. The principles of § 1-611.03 shall apply to compensation set under the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As provided in this section, the Mayor, the Board of Education, the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, and each independent personnel authority, or any combination of the above (“management”) shall meet with labor organizations (“labor”) which have been authorized to negotiate compensation at reasonable times in advance of the District’s budget making process to negotiate in good faith with respect to salary, wages, health benefits, within-grade increases, overtime pay, education pay, shift differential, premium pay, hours, and any other compensation matters. No subordinate agency shall negotiate a collective bargaining agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Multi-year compensation agreements are encouraged. No compensation agreement shall be for a period of less than 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Compensation negotiations pursuant to this section shall be confidential among the parties; provided, however, that the Council may appoint observers from its membership and staff, or both, to the negotiations. Such Council observers will be responsible for informing the members of the Council of the progress of negotiations. All information concerning negotiations shall be considered confidential until impasse resolution proceedings have been concluded or upon settlement. Management shall give the Council the same prior notice of negotiation proceedings that it gives to all parties to the negotiations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, shall take effect on the 30th calendar day, excluding days of Council recess, after the Mayor and the Council enact the budget request act, the supplemental budget request act, or the budget amendment act, or approve the reprogramming, as appropriate, that contains the funded settlement, unless prior to the 30th calendar day, the Council accepts or rejects the settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, by resolution. In the case of a settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, submitted after the enactment of budget legislation or the approval of a reprogramming that fully funds the settlement, including arbitrator’s award, the settlement, including arbitrator’s award shall take effect on the 30th calendar day, excluding days of Council recess, after the Mayor transmits the settlement, including arbitrator’s award, to the Council with the Mayor’s certification that the settlement, including arbitrator’s award, has been fully funded in previously enacted budget legislation or an approved reprogramming, unless prior to the 30th calendar day, the Council accepts or rejects the settlement, including arbitrator’s award, by resolution. If the Council rejects a settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, then the settlement shall be returned to the parties for renegotiation, with specific reasons for the rejection appended to the document disclosing the rejection of the settlement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall fully fund in future fiscal year budget requests, any settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, for future fiscal years contained in a multi-year compensation agreement that has been approved pursuant to this section. Any settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, that has been approved pursuant to this section shall be included in either the District budget request or in any supplemental budget request and shall be fully supported by the District by every reasonable means before Congressional bodies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provisions of subchapters XXII, XXIII, or XXVII of this chapter to the contrary, the health, life, and retirement programs authorized by these subchapters are proper subjects of collective bargaining under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the Public Employee Relations Board makes a determination as to the appropriate bargaining unit for the purpose of compensation negotiations pursuant to § 1-617.16, negotiations for compensation between management and the exclusive representative of the appropriate bargaining unit shall commence as provided for in subsection (f) of this section. The Mayor shall negotiate agreements concerning working conditions at the same time as he or she negotiates compensation issues.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_17_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
