<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_611_01">
        <akn:num>1-611.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Classification policy; grade levels; publication required; public hearing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The classification of all positions in the Career, Educational, Legal, Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services will be accomplished in accordance with the following policy:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The grade levels of all positions in the Career, Educational, Legal, Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services shall be based on the consideration of applicable factors, such as knowledge and skills required by the positions; supervisory controls exercised over the work; guidelines used; complexity of the work; scope and effect of the work; personal contacts; purpose of contacts; physical demands of the positions; and work environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Classification systems or proposals developed under the authority of this subchapter shall be published in the District of Columbia Register at least 60 days prior to their proposed effective date. The Mayor or the Board of Education or the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall hold, as provided in this subchapter, a public hearing on all such proposals he, she, or it has published in the District of Columbia Register prior to his, her, or its adoption of a classification system or amendment to such system; provided, that the classification system or systems in effect on December 31, 1979, shall remain in effect until the adoption of a classification system or systems pursuant to ยง 1-611.02 or ยง 1-611.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
