<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-614.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-614.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_614_11">
        <akn:num>1-614.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agency” means any office, department, division, board, commission, or other agency of the District government, including both subordinate agency and independent agency, required by law or by the Mayor or Council to administer any law or any rule adopted under the authority of a law. The term “agency” does not include the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Performance measures” means the methods of gauging the outcomes and outputs of publicly funded activities through procedures and devices, including, but not limited to, existing agency records, citizen surveys, and trained observer ratings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Performance plan” means the strategic description of how an agency’s mission and goals will be accomplished and shall consist of functions, activities, operations, and projects and both qualitative and quantitative measures required for effective implementation. The performance plan shall also include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Performance report” means the annual device by which District agencies report to the Council on the progress of management employees and other personnel toward achieving the objectives and goals in the performance plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Management employee” means any person whose functions include responsibility for project management and supervision of staff and the achievement of the project’s overall goals and objectives.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonmanagement personnel” means any person whose functions do not include responsibility for project management or supervision of staff, and are subject to the control and supervision by management employees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Significant activities” means activities that are central to the functions, goals, and services of the agency, program, or project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-614_11_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Publicly funded” or “public funds” means support by any governmental source.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
