<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-616.54"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-616.54/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_616_54">
        <akn:num>1-616.54</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administrative leave; enforced leave.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, a personnel authority may authorize the placing of an employee on annual leave or leave without pay, as provided in this section, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to placing an employee on enforced leave pursuant to this section, an employee shall initially be placed on administrative leave for a period of 5 work days, followed by enforced annual leave or, if no annual leave is available, leave without pay.  The employee shall remain in this status until such time as an action in accordance with regulations issued pursuant to § 1-616.51, taken as a result of the event that caused this administrative action, is effected or a determination is made that no such action in accordance with regulations issued pursuant to § 1-616.51 will be taken.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee to be placed on enforced leave shall be provided with a written notice proposing that action during the 5-day period of administrative leave.  To ensure receipt within the 5-day period, the initial delivery of notice may be accomplished either in person or by reading the notice to the employee over the telephone prior to actual delivery of the written notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A written notice issued pursuant to this section shall inform the employee of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within the 5-day administrative leave period, the employee’s explanation, if any, and statements of any witnesses shall be considered and a written decision shall be issued by the personnel authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a determination is made to place the employee on annual leave or leave without pay, the decision letter shall inform him or her of the placement on enforced leave, the date the leave is to commence, his or her right to grieve the action within 10 days of receipt of the written decision letter, and if the enforced leave lasts 10 or more days, his or her right to file an appeal with the Office of Employee Appeals within 30 days of the effective date of the appealed agency action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-616_54_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the basis for placing an employee on enforced leave pursuant to this section does not result in the taking of a disciplinary action pursuant to § 1-616.52 (or, in the case of an incumbent of a statutory position, the employee is not disciplined or removed in accordance with the provisions of the statute establishing the position), any annual leave or pay lost as a result of this administrative action shall be restored retroactively.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
