<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-617.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-617.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_617_01">
        <akn:num>1-617.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Policy.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia government finds and declares that an effective collective bargaining process is in the general public interest and will improve the morale of public employees and the quality of service to the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employee of the District government has the right, freely and without fear of penalty or reprisal:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or appropriate personnel authority, including his or her or its duly designated representative(s), shall meet at reasonable times with exclusive representative(s) of bargaining unit employees to bargain collectively in good faith.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-617_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (b) of this section does not authorize participation in the management of a labor organization or activity as a representative of such an organization by a supervisor, or management official or by an employee when the participation or activity would result in a conflict of interest or otherwise be incompatible with law or with the official duties of the employee. Supervisor means an employee having authority, in the interest of an agency, to hire, transfer, suspend, lay off, recall, promote, discharge, assign, reward, or discipline other employees, or responsibility to direct them, or to evaluate their performance, or to adjust their grievances, or effectively to recommend such action, if in connection with the foregoing the exercise of authority is not of a merely routine or clerical nature, but requires the use of independent judgment. The definition of supervisor shall include an incumbent of a position which is classified at a level higher than it would have been had the incumbent not performed some or all of the above duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
