<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_611_02">
        <akn:num>1-611.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment and maintenance of classification system for Career, Legal, Excepted, and Management Supervisory Services employees.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to carry out the policies of ยง 1-611.01, the Mayor shall provide for the development of a classification system covering all positions in the Career, Legal, Excepted, and the Management Supervisory Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide that all positions covered by this classification system are properly described in writing in accordance with the principal duties and responsibilities officially assigned to those positions and shall provide that all positions are properly evaluated by application of official classification standards, in accordance with accepted classification principles and techniques and in accordance with applicable rules and regulations. The Mayor shall provide for meaningful consultation with the District of Columbia Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia in the classification of positions of persons in the Career Service employed by the educational Boards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Classification systems or proposals developed under the authority of this section shall be published in the District of Columbia Register at least 60 days prior to their proposed effective date. The Mayor shall hold a public hearing on all such proposals he or she publishes in the District of Columbia Register prior to his or her adoption of a classification system(s) or amendment to such system(s).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
