<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-611.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_611_08">
        <akn:num>1-611.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Compensation — Members of boards and commissions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of any board or commission who receives compensation or reimbursement of expenses on January 1, 1980, shall receive such rates of compensation or reimbursement of expenses as are provided in existing law, rule, regulation, or order, or in this chapter, except as may be modified from time to time by rules and regulations published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, members of boards and commissions shall not be compensated for time expended in the performance of official duties except as authorized by subsections (b), (c), (c-1), (c-2), and (c-3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to establish by rule and regulation the rates of compensation or reimbursement of expenses for members of any board or commission, including any board or commission established after January 1, 1980. Any such rules and regulations proposed by the Mayor shall be transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 30-day (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which the Council of the District of Columbia is on recess) review period. Such rules and regulations shall become effective only if the Council of the District of Columbia does not adopt, within 30 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days on which the Council of the District of Columbia is on recess) from the date of the Mayor’s submission, a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part. Notwithstanding the provisions of § 1-604.05, rules and regulations published under this subsection shall be effective no earlier than 30 days after their publication in the District of Columbia Register.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of a salary as currently authorized by law:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of an hourly rate of pay as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the following boards and commissions shall be entitled to compensation in the form of stipend as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_c_3">
      <akn:num>(c-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Chairpersons of the boards and commissions specified in subsections (c-1) and (c-2) of this section who are public members shall be entitled to an additional compensation of 20% above the annual maximum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of boards and commissions shall not be entitled to reimbursement for expenses unless specifically authorized by law; except, that transportation, parking, or mileage expenses incurred in the performance of official duties may be reimbursed, not to exceed $15 per meeting or currently authorized amounts, whichever is less.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-611_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall conduct a comprehensive study of the compensation and stipend levels of the District’s boards and commissions, recognizing the different characteristics of these entities, and examining the best practices in the compensation and stipend policies of surrounding and comparable jurisdictions. Based on this study, the Mayor shall provide a report to the Council by December 31, 2002, with recommendations for a rational compensation and stipend policy applicable to boards and commissions, including any recommendations for changes in specific compensation and stipend levels that could be addressed in the FY 2004 budget and financial plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
