<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.24"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.24/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_623_24">
        <akn:num>1-623.24</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Time for making claim; finding of facts; award; right to hearing; conduct of hearing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or his or her designee shall determine and make a finding of facts and an award for or against payment of compensation under this subchapter within 30 days after the claim was filed based on the following guidelines:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure of an employee’s immediate superior to report an injury shall not prejudice a claimant’s right to benefits, nor relieve the Mayor or his or her designee of the duty to make a finding of facts and an award for or against payment of compensation within 30 days after the date the claim was filed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure of the Mayor or his or her designee to complete an investigation under subsection (a) of this section shall not prejudice a claimant’s right to benefits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_a_4">
      <akn:num>(a-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide a claimant and his or her attorney with access to the claimant’s file within 5 business days after a request to review the file is made. The claimant shall be provided, upon request, with one set of copies of the documents in the file.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A claimant who is not satisfied with a decision under subsection (d) of this section may, within 30 days after the issuance of a decision, request a hearing on the claim before a Department of Employment Services Disability Compensation Administrative Law Judge under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_24_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor or his or her designee fails to make payments of the award for compensation as required by subsection (a-3)(1), (a-4)(2), or (b)(3) of this section, the award shall be increased by an amount equal to one month of the compensation for each 30-day period that payment is not made; provided, that the increase shall not exceed 12 months’ compensation. In addition, the claimant may file with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia a lien against the Disability Compensation Fund, the General Fund of the District of Columbia, or any other District fund or property to pay the compensation award. The Court shall fix the terms and manner of enforcement of the lien against the compensation award.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
