<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-624.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-624.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_624_02">
        <akn:num>1-624.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Procedures.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-624_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reduction-in-force procedures shall apply to the Career and Educational Services, except those persons separated pursuant to § 1-608.01a(b)(2), and to persons appointed to the Excepted and Legal Services as attorneys and shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-624_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-624_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this subchapter, each employee who is a bona fide resident of the District of Columbia shall have 3 years added to his or her creditable service for reduction-in-force purposes.  For purposes of this subsection only, a nonresident District employee who was hired by the District government prior to January 1, 1980, and has not had a break in service since that date, or a former employee of the United States Department of Health and Human Services at Saint Elizabeths Hospital who accepted employment with the District government effective October 1, 1987, and has not had a break in service since that date, shall be considered a District resident.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-624_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A reduction-in-force action may not be taken until the employee has been afforded at least 15 days advance notice of such an action.  The notification required by this subsection must be in writing and must include information pertaining to the employee’s retention standing and appeal rights.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-624_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board of Education shall not require or permit non-school-based personnel or school administrators to be assigned or reassigned to the same competitive level as classroom teachers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
