<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_623_03">
        <akn:num>1-623.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Medical services and initial medical and other benefits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District government shall furnish to an employee who is injured while in the performance of duty the services, appliances, and supplies prescribed or recommended by a qualified physician, who is approved by the Mayor or his or her designee pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, which the Mayor considers likely to cure, give relief, reduce the degree or period of disability, or aid in lessening the amount of the monthly compensation. These services, appliances, and supplies shall be furnished:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, under such limitations or conditions as he or she considers necessary, may authorize the employing agencies to provide for the initial furnishing of medical and other benefits under this section. The Mayor may certify vouchers for these expenses out of the Employees’ Compensation Fund when the immediate superior of the employee certifies that the expense was incurred in respect to an injury accepted by the employing agency as properly compensable under this subchapter. The Mayor shall prescribe the form and content of the certificate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District government shall furnish or authorize payment for services, appliances, supplies, and reasonable transportation and expenses incidental thereto, to the injured employee within 30 days after the Mayor or his or her designee receives notice that the employee has been injured while in the performance of duty.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or his or her designee shall provide a claimant with written authorization for payment for any treatment or procedure within 30 days after the treating physician makes a written request to the Mayor or his or her designee for this authorization. If the Mayor or his or her designee fails to provide written authorization to the claimant within 30 days of the request, the treatment or procedure shall be deemed authorized, unless the Mayor or his or her designee commences a utilization review pursuant to § 1-623.23(a-2) within 30 days of the request.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
