<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-620.31"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-620.31/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_620_31">
        <akn:num>1-620.31</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Applicant” means any person who has filed any written employment application forms to work as a District employee, or has been tentatively selected for employment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child” means an individual 12 years of age and under.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District employee” means a person employed by the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drug” means an unlawful drug and does not include over-the-counter prescription medications.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee” means any person employed in a position for which he or she is paid for services on any basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Post-accident employee” means an employee of the District of Columbia, who, while on duty, is involved in a vehicular or other type of accident resulting in personal injury or property damage, or both, in which the cause of the accident could reasonably be believed to have been the result, in whole or in part, from the use of drugs or alcohol on the part of the employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Probable cause” or “reasonable suspicion” means a reasonable belief by a supervisor that an employee in a safety-sensitive position is under the influence of an illegal drug or alcohol to the extent that the employee’s ability to perform his or her job is impaired.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Random testing” means drug or alcohol testing conducted on an District employee in a safety-sensitive position at an unspecified time for purposes of determining whether any District employee subject to drug or alcohol testing has used drugs or alcohol and, as a result, is unable to satisfactorily perform his or her employment duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reasonable suspicion referral” means referral of an employee in a safety-sensitive position for testing by the District for drug or alcohol use.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Safety-sensitive position” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-620_31_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Youth” means an individual between 13 and 17 years of age, inclusive.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
