<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-627.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-627.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_627_06">
        <akn:num>1-627.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Special rules governing the assignment of employees from private sector organizations to the District.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the requirements set forth in ยง 1-627.05, the requirements in this section shall apply to all written agreements in which an employee of a private sector organization is assigned to work for a District government agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to entering into an agreement to assign a private sector employee to a District agency, the head of the agency shall prepare a written determination and findings explaining why the agency cannot use other District government personnel or procurement policies or procedures to secure the professional services that would be provided through the agreement. The head of the District agency shall not enter into an agreement for interagency personnel exchange with a private sector organization unless the Director of Personnel (or the Chief Technology Officer, in the case of the Office of the Chief Technology Officer) or the independent personnel authority certifies in writing that the agency has exhausted every effort to recruit its human resource needs through standard recruitment practices or fill its professional needs through standard procurement procedures without success. The Director of Personnel (or the Chief Technology Officer, in the case of the Office of the Chief Technology Officer) or the independent personnel authority shall retain a copy of the determination and findings as part of the official file for the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The agreement which contains the terms and conditions for the payment or reimbursement of salary, benefits, and other expenses to the private sector organization shall provide that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The private sector organization shall certify the accuracy of the cost of the salary, fringe benefits, and general and administrative costs included in the reimbursement agreement. The District agency shall reserve the right to audit those costs under the circumstances and methods it deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A former District government employee shall be prohibited, for a period of 2 years after his or her separation from District government employment, from participating in a personnel exchange agreement between the District government and a private sector organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 45 days after the end of each fiscal year (beginning with fiscal year 2002), the Chief Technology Officer shall prepare and submit to the Council and to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate a report describing all agreements entered into by the Chief Technology Officer under this section which are in effect during the fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 90 days of April 28, 2001, the Director of Personnel shall issue regulations governing the allowable reimbursement of general and administrative costs for the employees of private sector organizations assigned to work for a District agency. In developing the regulations, the Director of Personnel shall review standards used to calculate general and administrative costs for off-site employees found in federal law and regulation, and District of Columbia procurement regulations, and shall incorporate those standards into the implementing regulations for this subchapter as the Director deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-627_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
