<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.37"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.37/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_623_37">
        <akn:num>1-623.37</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Compensation for noncitizens and nonresidents.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_37_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the Mayor finds that the amount of compensation payable to an employee who is neither a citizen nor resident of the United States or Canada, or payable to a dependent of such an employee, is substantially disproportionate to compensation for disability or death payable in similar cases under local statute, regulations, custom, or otherwise at the place outside the continental United States or Canada where the employee is working at the time of injury, he or she may provide for payment of compensation on a basis reasonably in accord with prevailing local payments in similar cases by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_37_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a case under this section, the Mayor or his or her designee may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_37_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may delegate to an employee or agency of the District of Columbia government, with such limitations and right of review as he or she considers advisable, authority to process, adjudicate, commute by lump-sum award, compromise and pay a claim or class of claims for compensation, and to provide other benefits, locally, under this section, in accordance with such rules, regulations, and instructions as the Mayor considers necessary. For this purpose, the Mayor may provide or transfer funds, including reimbursement of amounts paid under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_37_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may waive the application of this subchapter in whole or in part and for such period or periods as he or she may fix if the Mayor finds that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_37_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may apply this section retrospectively with adjustment of compensation and benefits as he or she considers necessary and proper.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
