<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.16"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.16/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_623_16">
        <akn:num>1-623.16</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Limitation of right to receive compensation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_16_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>While an employee is receiving compensation under this subchapter or if he or she has been paid a lump sum in commutation of installment payments until the expiration of the period during which the installment payments would have continued, he or she may not receive salary, pay, or remuneration of any type from the District of Columbia, except:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_16_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee shall not be eligible for compensation under this subchapter if he or she was employed by the District of Columbia or the federal government before October 1, 1987, and is receiving disability benefits from the federal government for the same injury.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_16_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual entitled to benefits under this subchapter because of his or her injury, or because of the death of an employee who also is entitled to receive from the District of Columbia government under a provision of a statute, other than this subchapter, payment or benefits for that injury or death (except proceeds of an insurance policy), because of service by him or her (or in the case of death, by the deceased) as an employee or in the armed forces, shall elect which benefits he or she will receive. The individual shall make the election within 1 year after the injury or death or within a further time allowed for good cause by the Mayor. The election when made is irrevocable, except as otherwise provided by statute.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_16_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The liability of the District of Columbia government or an instrumentality thereof, under this subchapter or any extension thereof with respect to the injury or death of an employee, is exclusive and instead of all other liability of the District of Columbia government or the instrumentality to the employee, his or her legal representative, spouse, dependents, next of kin, and any other person otherwise entitled to recover damages from the District of Columbia or the instrumentality because of the injury or death in a direct judicial proceeding, in a civil action, or in admiralty, or by an administrative or judicial proceeding under a workmen’s compensation statute or under a federal tort liability statute. This subchapter does not apply to a master or a member of a crew of a vessel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_16_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
