<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.23"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-623.23/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_623_23">
        <akn:num>1-623.23</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Physical examinations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee shall submit to examination by a medical officer of the District of Columbia government, or by a physician designated or approved by the Mayor, after the injury and as frequently and at the times and places as may be reasonably required. The employee may have a physician designated and paid by him or her present to participate in the examination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each person who provides medical care or service under this subchapter shall utilize a standard coding system for reports and bills pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any medical care or service furnished or scheduled to be furnished under this subchapter shall be subject to utilization review. Utilization review may be accomplished prospectively, concurrently, or retrospectively. A decision on the medical care or service to the employee shall be made by the utilization review organization or individual within 60 days after the utilization review is requested. If the utilization review is not completed within 120 days of the request, the care or service under review shall be deemed approved. If the Mayor denies medical care or service because the medical care provider or claimant has not provided enough information for the utilization review process, the provider or claimant may request approval for the medical care or service again by providing new information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Medical care providers shall not hold employees liable for services rendered in connection with a compensable injury under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An employee is entitled to be paid expenses incident to an examination required by the Mayor which, in the opinion of the Mayor, are necessary and reasonable, including transportation and loss of wages incurred in order to be examined. The expenses, when authorized or approved by the Mayor, are paid from the Employees’ Compensation Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall fix the fees for examinations under this section by physicians not employed by or under contract to the District of Columbia government to furnish medical services to employees. The fees, when authorized or approved by the Mayor, are paid from the Employees’ Compensation Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-623_23_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an employee refuses to submit to or obstructs an examination, his or her right to compensation under this subchapter is suspended until the refusal or obstruction stops. Compensation is not payable while a refusal or obstruction continues, and the period of the refusal or obstruction is deducted from the period for which compensation is payable to the employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
