<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-626.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-626.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_626_13">
        <akn:num>1-626.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties and liabilities of Trustee; exemptions; violations and sanctions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A fiduciary shall discharge his duties with respect to the Trust solely in the interest of the participants and beneficiaries and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any liability which he may have under any other provision of this section, a fiduciary with respect to the Trust shall be liable for a breach of fiduciary responsibility of another fiduciary with respect to the Trust:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (f), (g), and (h) of this section, a fiduciary with respect to the Trust shall not cause the Trust to engage in a transaction, if he knows or should know that the transaction constitutes a direct or indirect:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, a fiduciary with respect to the Trust shall not:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transfer of real or personal property by a party in interest shall be treated as a sale or exchange if the property is subject to a mortgage or similar lien which the Trust assumes or if it is subject to a mortgage or similar lien which a party in interest placed on the property within the 10-year period ending on the date of the transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The prohibitions provided in subsection (c) of this section shall not apply to any of the following transactions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in subsection (c) of this section shall be construed to prohibit any fiduciary from:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may submit to the Council for its approval by resolution proposed exemptions from all or part of the restrictions imposed by subsections (c) and (d) of this section. The Mayor shall only request exemptions that have been granted by the United States Secretary of Labor. Any proposed exemption submitted to the Council shall be accompanied by written findings by the Mayor that the proposed exemption is administratively feasible, in the best interests of the Trust and its participants and beneficiaries, and protective of the rights of participants and beneficiaries of the Trust.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-626_13_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
