<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-711"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-711/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_711">
        <akn:num>1-711</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Retirement Board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established, as an independent agency of the government of the District of Columbia, a board of trustees to be known as the District of Columbia Retirement Board which shall have exclusive authority and discretion (subject to the requirements of this chapter) to manage and control the Funds established by this chapter, and for implementation and administration of the retirement program and post employment benefit programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall from time to time, or when necessary, promulgate and adopt rules, regulations, and resolutions, and issue directives for the management and administration of the retirement program and for management and control of the Funds. To efficiently administer and implement the retirement program and manage the Funds, the Board may make reasonable interpretations of and implement all governing authorities. All governing authorities shall comply with necessary qualification requirements set forth by the Internal Revenue Code as amended for governmental retirement plans. Governing authorities may constitute the Trust Document for the retirement program and the Funds. Prior to the enactment or adoption of any governing authority, the Retirement Board shall submit a written analysis of the proposed governing authority to the appropriate person including the Mayor, the Council of the District of Columbia, the Chief Financial Officer, the Chairman of the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board, the President of the Board of Education, or their successors, for purposes of fulfilling its fiduciary duties and for continued compliance with Internal Revenue Code qualification requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not more than 90 days after all initial members of the Board have been selected in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the Board shall certify in writing to the Director of the Office of Budget and Financial Management of the District of Columbia that the Board is assuming responsibility for the Funds established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In accordance with ยง 1-809.01, after enactment of Chapter 8 of this title, the Board shall continue to discharge its duties and responsibilities under the retirement program and to the Funds (as the duties and responsibilities are modified by the Retirement Protection Act), including the responsibility for federal benefit payments provided in ยง 1-903.05, until the Secretary of the U.S. Treasury provides notification to the District government as required under the Retirement Protection Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Staff appointed by the Board pursuant to subsection (g)(2) of this section shall not be subject to the provisions of subchapter XI of Chapter 6 of this title.  The Board shall have exclusive authority to establish classification and compensation policy for staff appointed by the Board, provided that staff shall not be paid at a rate greater than the highest level authorized for nonunion workers in the District Service schedule.  The Board shall establish by regulation a new compensation system for staff appointed by the Board within one year of October 20, 1999.  Until a new compensation system is established by regulation, staff appointed by the Board shall be subject to the compensation policy applicable prior to October 20, 1999. The Board shall have exclusive authority to establish by regulation alternative benefits requirements for its employees to insure an efficient system of personnel administration and to recruit and retain highly qualified personnel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 30 days after December 7, 2004, the Board, in consultation with the Chief Financial Officer, shall determine the time and methodology for transferring the necessary functional responsibilities, as defined by rules and regulations issued by the Board from the Office of Payroll and Retirement Services of the Office of Financial Operations and Systems to the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-711_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may reasonably rely upon records, statements, and representations from the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, the District of Columbia Public Charter School Board, the Secretary of the Board of Education, or its successor, a participant or beneficiary sworn in or acknowledged before an individual authorized to administer oaths, or presenting an affidavit, certification, or other reasonably reliable proof regarding any matter affecting the rights and privileges of a participant or beneficiary under the retirement program and post employment benefit programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
