<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-736"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-736/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_736">
        <akn:num>1-736</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Public information.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-736_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the contents of the descriptions, annual reports, statements, and other documents filed with the Mayor, the Council, the Speaker, and the President pro tempore pursuant to this subchapter shall be public information, and the Mayor, the Council, the Speaker, and the President pro tempore shall each make such documents available for inspection in an appropriate location. The Mayor, the Council, the Speaker, and the President pro tempore may use the information and data in such documents for statistical and research purposes and may compile and publish such studies, analyses, reports, and surveys based thereon as may be considered appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-736_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Information described in § 1-735(a) with respect to a participant or beneficiary of a retirement program may be disclosed only to the extent that information respecting that participant’s or beneficiary’s benefits under Title II of the Social Security Act may be disclosed under such Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-736_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except to the extent that information which is protected from public disclosure under subsection (b) of this section, or which relates to personnel matters the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, is involved, all meetings of the Board shall be open to the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
