<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-911.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/1-911.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_1_911_01">
        <akn:num>1-911.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Civil enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-911_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A civil action may be brought:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-911_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Retirement Board fails or refuses to comply with a request for any information that the Retirement Board is required by this chapter to furnish to a participant or beneficiary (unless the failure or refusal results from matters reasonably beyond the control of the Board) by mailing the information requested to the last known address of the requesting participant or beneficiary within 30 days after the request, then the Retirement Board may, in the court’s discretion, be liable to the participant or beneficiary in an amount of up to $100 a day from the date of the failure or refusal, and the court may order the Retirement Board to provide the required information and may in its discretion order other relief as it considers proper.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-911_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Retirement Board may sue and be sued under this chapter as an entity.  Service of summons, subpoena, or other legal process of a court upon the Chairman of the Retirement Board in that capacity shall constitute service upon the Retirement Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1-911_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any action under this chapter by a participant, beneficiary, fiduciary, or the Retirement Board, the court in its discretion, may grant reasonable attorneys fees and costs of action to either party.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
