<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/20-403"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/20-403/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_20_403">
        <akn:num>20-403</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Supervised administration; changes and effect.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-403_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The filing of signed waivers by all interested persons in accordance with section 20-731 shall be treated for all purposes as a change to unsupervised administration, but the filing of a subsequent demand for the filing of inventories and accounts by any such interested person shall be treated as a change back to supervised administration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-403_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A petition for supervised administration may be filed by any interested person or by a personal representative at any time before the termination of a probate proceeding; similarly, the Court may initiate such a proceeding upon good cause shown. In either event, after notice to interested persons and a hearing (unless the hearing is waived by both the petitioner and the personal representative, or by the interested persons if petitioner is the personal representative), the Court may order supervised administration, applying the same standards as under section 20-402. In no event, however, shall any Court Order be deemed to convert the proceeding to a supervised administration unless the Order expressly so provides. The filing of such petition does not affect any powers and duties of the personal representative unless they are expressly restricted by the Court pending the hearing or final Order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-403_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event of a change from one form of administration to another pursuant to this title, such change shall be prospective only. Except in the case of fraud, no action of the personal representative shall be set aside by the Court solely by reason of a change from one form of administration to another.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
