<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/20-735"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/20-735/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_20_735">
        <akn:num>20-735</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Optional proceedings, terminating unsupervised administration; testate or intestate; Certificate of Completion.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-735_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise ordered by the Court for good cause shown in a particular matter, the personal representative in an unsupervised administration shall close the estate by filing with the Court a Certificate of Completion, which shall be verified and in a form prescribed by the Court. Such Certificate may be filed at any time, but in no event prior to the expiration of the time for filing creditors’ claims against the estate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-735_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Certificate of Completion shall include a statement that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-735_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Certificate of Completion shall also contain a list containing the name and address of each recipient of the copy of the account and the corresponding notice, as well as a certificate of service confirming that each of those individuals or entities also received a copy of the Certificate of Completion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20-735_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any interested person or other recipient of a copy of the account may object to the account by mailing or delivering to the personal representative or to the Court, within the 60-day period described above, a written statement of his or her objections to the account as stated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
