<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1092"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1092/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1092">
        <akn:num>47-1092</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>YMCA Community Investment Initiative, Lot 2010, Square 234.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1092_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The real property located at 1325 W Street, N.W., Washington, D.C., and described as Lot 2010, Square 234, shall be exempt from real property taxation, and interests in the property shall be exempt from possessory interest taxation so long as the real property continues to be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1092_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1092_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The exemptions set forth in this section shall apply to successor nonprofit entities formed by YMCA DC for purposes of meeting requirements under the New Market Tax Credit provided by section 45D of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, so long as the real property continues to be used and occupied by YMCA DC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1092_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council orders that all real property tax, penalties, interest, fees, and other related charges assessed against the real property described in subsection (a) of this section through the end of the month during which this act becomes effective be forgiven, and that any payments already made be refunded. The Council further orders that all recordation and transfer taxes, penalties, and interest collected with respect to the transfers described in subsection (b) of this section through the end of the month during which this act becomes effective be forgiven and payments already made be refunded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
