<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1374"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1374/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1374">
        <akn:num>47-1374</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Service of process.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1374_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plaintiff shall set forth in the caption of the complaint the last address known to the plaintiff or to the attorney filing the complaint of each defendant, as obtained from:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1374_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (a) of this section shall not require the plaintiff or the attorney for the plaintiff to make any investigations or to search any other records or sources of information other than those stated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1374_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This subsection applies only if a last known address for a defendant is obtained as provided under subsections (a) and (b) of this section. The plaintiff shall cause a copy of the order of publication to be mailed by first class, certified mail, postage prepaid, to each defendants address as determined by the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1374_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice to a defendant may be made in any other manner that results in actual notice of the pendency of the action to the defendant. If notice is given under this subsection, the plaintiff shall file an affidavit that fairly describes the method and time of service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1374_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
