<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1377"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1377/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1377">
        <akn:num>47-1377</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Purchaser reimbursed by redeeming party for expenses.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1377_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1377_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No purchaser of a certificate of sale shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred within 4 months after the date of the tax sale. A purchaser other than the District shall not be reimbursed for any expenses if the certificate becomes void under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1377_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The purchaser shall not be entitled to be reimbursed for any expenses or attorney’s fees not included in this section. Expenses or attorneys’ fees incurred by a purchaser who appeals the assessment or the vacant status of the property are not reimbursable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1377_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the purchaser fails to satisfy the requirements for posting under § 47-1353.01 or fails to provide proof of posting required under § 47-1370(c)(4), the purchaser shall not be entitled to collect the legal expenses set forth in subsection (a) of this section; provided, that upon a showing to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia of good cause for the failure to meet the posting requirements of § 47-1353.01 or § 47-1370(c) (4), the purchaser shall be entitled to collect those expenses, not to exceed the amounts set forth in subsection (a) of this section, that the Superior Court of the District of Columbia considers reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1377_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, if the tax sale is cancelled by the Mayor under § 47-1366, the purchaser shall not be entitled to reimbursement of the expenses permitted under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section if the purchaser fails to specifically disclose to the Mayor, at least 45 days before the filing of a complaint to foreclose the right of redemption, information that is obtained or should have been obtained from the pre-complaint investigation, including the title examination and review of bankruptcy records under § 47-1371(b)(2) and § 47-1371(b)(2A), that evidences a violation of § 47-1332(c), a violation of a bankruptcy stay, or errors, as prescribed by the Mayor through regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
