<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1303.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1303.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1303_02">
        <akn:num>47-1303.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Private sale of unimproved residential real property bid off in the name of the District.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mayor may sell at private sale real property that has been bid off in the name of the District at public tax sale for 2 consecutive years and that has not been redeemed by the owner within the redemption period provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before accepting offers on the bid off property for private sale, the Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners of adjoining property shall have the first opportunity to purchase bid off property at private sale. The Mayor shall notify the owners of adjoining property that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If only 1 adjoining property owner offers to purchase the bid off property and meets the requirements of subsection (c) of this section, the Mayor shall accept the offer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If more than 1 adjoining property owner offers to purchase the bid off property and meets the requirements of subsection (c) of this section, the Mayor shall accept the highest offer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If no acceptable offer is made by an adjoining property owner within the time period determined by the Mayor, the Mayor shall sell the bid off property to any interested purchaser in accordance with procedures established by the Mayor. The minimum sale price acceptable shall be an amount equal to all current year’s taxes and assessments, including penalties and interest, and costs charged against the property. Unsold bid off property shall not be returned to the public tax sale, but shall be retained by the Mayor until sold at private sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1303_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An offer to purchase bid off property at private sale shall be made in writing on a form and under such conditions as the Mayor shall by regulation prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
