<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1801.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1801.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1801_04">
        <akn:num>47-1801.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>General definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliated group” means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; provided, that the affiliated group shall not include any corporation that does not have gross income derived from sources within the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Aggregated effective tax rate” means the sum of the effective rates of tax imposed by the District of Columbia, states, or possessions of the United States, and foreign nations that have entered into comprehensive tax treaties with the United States government, where a related member receiving a payment of interest expense or intangible expense is subject to tax and where the measure of the tax imposed included the payment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apportioned net operating loss” means the net operating loss generated in the year of the loss multiplied by the District of Columbia’s apportionment formula for the loss year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Blind” means a taxpayer whose central visual acuity does not exceed 20/200 in the better eye with correcting lenses or whose visual acuity is greater than 20/200 but is accompanied by a limitation in the field of vision such that the widest diameter of the visual field subtends an angle no greater than 20 degrees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business income” means all income that is apportionable under the Constitution of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Combined group” means the group of all persons whose income and apportionment factors are required to be taken into account pursuant to § 47-1805.02a(a) and (b) and the pertinent regulations in determining the taxpayer’s share of the net business income or loss apportionable to the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial domicile” means the principal place from which the trade or business of the taxpayer is directed or managed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Compensation” means wages, salaries, commissions, and any other form of remuneration paid to an employee for personal services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Corporation” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Deficiency” with respect to any tax imposed by this chapter means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Dependent” means a dependent as defined in section 152 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Dividend” means any distribution made by a corporation or financial institution (domestic or foreign) to its stockholders or members, out of its earnings, profits, or surplus, other than paid-in surplus, whenever earned by the corporation or financial institution and whether made in cash or in any other property (other than stock of the same class in the corporation or financial institution, if the recipient of the stock dividend has neither received nor exercised an option to receive the dividend in cash or in property other than stock instead of stock) and whether distributed before, during, upon, or after liquidation or dissolution of the corporation or financial institution; except, that in the case of any such distribution, any part of which for purposes of the income tax imposed under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is deemed to constitute a capital gain, such part shall be deemed to constitute a capital gain for purposes of the tax imposed by this chapter; provided, that in the case of any dividend that is distributed other than in cash or stock in the same class in the corporation or financial institution and not exempted from tax under this chapter, the basis of tax to the recipient shall be the market value of the property at the time of the distribution; provided further, that a dividend shall not include any dividend paid by a mutual life insurance company to its shareholders.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Doing business” means any activity of a partnership, corporation, or financial institution that enjoys the benefits and protection of the government and laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic partners” means persons who have registered their relationship with the District pursuant to § 32-702.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee” means an individual having a place of abode or residing or domiciled within the District at the time the tax is required to be withheld in respect to the individual’s employment by another, and to every other individual who maintains a place of abode within the District for an aggregate of 183 days or more during the taxable year, whether domiciled in the District or not, including an officer of a corporation, but excluding any elective officer of the government of the United States or any officer or employee in the legislative branch of the government of the United States whose compensation is paid by the Secretary of the Senate or Clerk of the House of Representatives, any officer of the executive branch of the government of the United States whose appointment was made by the President of the United States, subject to confirmation by the Senate of the United States, and whose tenure of office is at the pleasure of the President of the United States, or any Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, unless the officer, employee, or justice is domiciled within the District of Columbia at any time during the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employer” means an employer as defined in section 3401(d) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fiduciary” means a guardian, trustee, executor, committee, administrator, receiver, conservator, or any other person acting in any fiduciary capacity for any person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial institution” means any bank or trust company incorporated or required to be incorporated and doing business under the laws of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any state, a substantial part of the business of which consists of receiving deposits and making loans and discounts or of exercising fiduciary powers similar to those permitted to national banks under authority of the Comptroller of the Currency and which is subject by law to supervision and examination by the District or by any state, territorial, or federal authority having supervision over the financial institution, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fiscal year” means an accounting period of 12 months ending on any day other than the last day of December and on the basis of which the taxpayer is required to report for federal income tax purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Head of household” shall have the same meaning as defined in section 2(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Individual” means all natural persons (other than fiduciaries), whether married, domestic partners, or unmarried.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intangible expense” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intangible property” means patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights, and similar types of intangible assets.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interest expense” means an amount directly or indirectly allowed as a deduction under section 163 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for purposes of determining taxable income under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Internal Revenue Code of 1954” means the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, approved April 6, 1954 (68A Stat. 3; 26 U.S.C. § 1 et seq.), as amended through May 24, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Internal Revenue Code of 1986” means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 1 et seq.); which provisions shall apply on the same dates that they are effective for federal tax purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International banking facility” or “IBF” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 204.8(a)(1) of Regulation D of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, effective December 3, 1981 (12 CFR § 204.8(a)(1)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International banking facility extension of credit” or “IBF loan” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 204.8(a)(3) of Regulation D of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, effective December 3, 1981 (12 CFR § 204.8(a)(3)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International banking facility time deposit” or “IBF time deposit” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 204.8(a)(2) of Regulation D of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, effective December 3, 1981 (12 CFR § 204.8(a)(2)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Net operating loss” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 172(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, subject to limitations and modifications provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Net operating loss deduction” means the aggregate of the apportioned net operating loss carryovers to the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonbusiness income” means all income other than business income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonresident” means every individual other than a resident.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Ownership” in determining the ownership of stock, assets, or net profits of any person, means the constructive ownership of section 318(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as modified by section 856(d)(5) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Partnership” means a general or limited partnership or organization of any kind that is treated as a partnership for tax purposes under the laws of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Payroll period” means a payroll period as defined in section 3401(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any individual, firm, partnership, general partner of a partnership, limited liability company, registered limited liability partnership, foreign limited liability partnership, association, corporation (whether or not the corporation is, or would be if doing business in the District, subject to this chapter), unincorporated business, company, syndicate, estate, trust, business trust, trustee, trustee in bankruptcy, receiver, executor, administrator, assignee, fiduciary, or organization of any kind. For purposes of combined reporting, The term “person” shall not include a Qualified High Technology Company as defined in § 47-1817.01(5)(A).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Related entity” means a person that under the attribution rules of section 318 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Related member” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident” means an individual domiciled in the District at any time during the taxable year, and every other individual who maintains a place of abode within the District for an aggregate of 183 days or more during the taxable year, whether or not the individual is domiciled in the District, excluding any elective officer of the government of the United States or any employee on the staff of an elected official in the legislative branch of the government of the United States if the employee is a bona fide resident of the state of residence of the elected officer, or any officer of the executive branch of the government whose appointment was made by the President of the United States and subject to confirmation by the Senate of the United States and whose tenure of office is at the pleasure of the President of the United States, or any Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, unless the officer, employee, or justice is domiciled within the District at any time during the taxable year. In determining whether an individual is a resident, an individual’s absence from the District for temporary or transitory purposes shall not be regarded as changing his domicile or place of abode.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sales” means all gross receipts of the taxpayer that are business income, as that term is defined in this section. The term “sales” does not include receipts of a taxpayer from hedging transactions and from the maturity, redemption, sales, exchange, loan, or other disposition of cash or securities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_44">
      <akn:num>(44)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Standard deduction” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_45">
      <akn:num>(45)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory, or possession of the United States and any foreign country or political subdivision thereof.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_46">
      <akn:num>(46)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subpart F income” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 952 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_47">
      <akn:num>(47)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Surviving spouse” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; except, that in applying section 2(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the term spouse shall be deemed to include a domestic partner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_48">
      <akn:num>(48)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tax” or “tax liability” includes the liability for all amounts owing by a taxpayer to the District under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_49">
      <akn:num>(49)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_50">
      <akn:num>(50)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Taxable income” means as required by the context set forth in § 47-1807.01(2) or § 47-1808.02(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_51">
      <akn:num>(51)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Taxable year” means the calendar year or the fiscal year, whichever is the basis upon which the net income of the taxpayer is computed under this section; if no fiscal year has been established by the taxpayer, it means the calendar year. The term “taxable year” includes, in the case of a return made for a fractional part of a calendar or fiscal year under the provisions of this section or under regulations prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer, the period for which the return is made; provided, that no taxpayer shall change from a calendar year to a fiscal year or from a fiscal year to a calendar year within any taxable year without the written authorization of the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_52">
      <akn:num>(52)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Taxpayer” means any person subject to the tax imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_53">
      <akn:num>(53)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Trade or business” means the engaging in or carrying on of any trade, business, profession, vocation, or calling, or commercial activity in the District of Columbia, including activities in the District that benefit a related entity of the taxpayer, the performance of functions of a public office, and the leasing of real or personal property in the District of Columbia by any person whether or not the property is leased directly by the person or through an agent, officer, or a representative, and whether or not the person, agent, officer, or representative performs any services in connection with the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_54">
      <akn:num>(54)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“United States” means the United States of America and includes all of the states of the United States, the District of Columbia, and United States’ territories and possessions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_55">
      <akn:num>(55)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unitary business” means a single economic enterprise that is made up either of separate parts of a single business entity or of a commonly controlled group of business entities that are sufficiently interdependent, integrated, and interrelated through their activities so as to provide synergy and mutual benefit that produces a sharing or exchange of value among them and a significant flow of value to the separate parts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_56">
      <akn:num>(56)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Wages” means wages as defined in section 3401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_57">
      <akn:num>(57)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Water’s-edge combined group” is comprised of all entities includible in the combined report, as determined pursuant to § 47-1810.07.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1801_04_58">
      <akn:num>(58)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Worldwide combined report” means the combination of the income and activities of all members of a unitary group irrespective of the country in which the corporations are incorporated or conduct business activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
