<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1810.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1810.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1810_02">
        <akn:num>47-1810.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Allocation and apportionment of District and non-District income.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Allocation and apportionment. — The entire net income of any corporation, financial institution, or unincorporated business, or the unrelated business income of an exempt organization, derived from any trade or business carried on or engaged wholly within the District shall, for the purposes of this chapter, be deemed to be from sources within the District and shall, along with other income from sources within the District, be allocated to the District. If the net income of a corporation, financial institution, or unincorporated business, or the unrelated business income of an exempt organization, is derived from sources within and without the District, the taxpayer shall apportion business income and allocate non-business income as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Taxation by another state. — For purposes of allocation and apportionment of income under this section, a taxpayer is taxable in another state if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Allocation of nonbusiness income. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Apportionment of business income. — Except as provided in subsection (d-1) or (d-2), whichever is applicable, all business income shall be apportioned to the District by multiplying the income by a fraction, the numerator of which is the property factor plus the payroll factor plus the sales factor, and the denominator of which is 3.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Apportionment of business income. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_d_2">
      <akn:num>(d-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Apportionment of business income. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Property factor. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payroll factor. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Sales factor. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Alternative methods. — If the allocation and apportionment provisions of this section do not fairly represent the extent of the taxpayer’s business activity in the District, the taxpayer may petition for or the Mayor may require, in respect to all or any part of the taxpayer’s business activity, if reasonable:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Definitions. — For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1810_02_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Construction. — This section shall be so construed as to effectuate its general purpose to make uniform the law of those states that enact it.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
