<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1807.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1807.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1807_12">
        <akn:num>47-1807.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax on corporations and financial institutions — Credits — Tax credit for farm to food donations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1807_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2015, any qualified incorporated business under § 6-1504 may claim a nonrefundable credit against taxes imposed by this subchapter equal to 50% of the value of food commodity donations made during the tax year to a District of Columbia food bank or shelter recognized as a tax-exempt organization pursuant to U.S.C. § 501(c)(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1807_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1807_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A donated food commodity shall not be damaged, out-of-condition, nor of a condition that would be considered unfit for human consumption under District or federal law or regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1807_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A corporation claiming the tax credit shall provide documentation supporting the tax credit claim in a form and manner prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1807_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “food commodity” means vegetables, fruits, grains, mushrooms, honey, herbs, nuts, seeds, or rootstock grown in the District by urban farming, as defined in § 48-401(5), or by a community garden, as defined in § 48-401(1), that are intended to be used as food in its perishable state and are approved by regulatory authorities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
