<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1818.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1818.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1818_01">
        <akn:num>47-1818.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Abatement period” means from the effective date of this subchapter through the date when an abatement provided for in this subchapter is exhausted or forfeited, or otherwise expires in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“BAS agreement” means a city-wide business activity strategy agreement between the District and a Qualified Social E-Commerce Company as specified in § 47-1818.03(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Disrupted corridor” means an area that is distressed due to the lack of amenities, transportation, or commerce, disrupted due to construction operations, or is otherwise determined by the Mayor to be a distressed or disrupted area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“New hire” or “newly hired” means an individual who was not employed by a Qualified Social E-Commerce Company before calendar year 2010 and was, or is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“New hire wage credit” means a credit equal to 10% of the wages paid during the first 24 calendar months of employment to a newly hired employee hired after December 31, 2009, and before January 1, 2016, accrued annually up to $5,000 per new hire per tax year, up to a maximum amount of the new hire wage credit cap.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“New hire wage credit cap” means a ceiling of $15 million.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Social E-Commerce Company” means a company that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified High Technology Company” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 47-1817.01(5).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified real property” means real property located in the District of Columbia on which a commercial office building totaling no less than 200,000 square feet is constructed, or substantially rehabilitated, and equipped after June 1, 2012, and which is owned or leased by a Qualified Social E-Commerce Company for use as a primary corporate headquarters.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Real property” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 47-802(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident” means an individual whose principal residence is located in the District of Columbia and who is subject to District of Columbia personal income tax, or is a new hire who becomes a resident within 180 days of his or her new hire start date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident hiring factor” means the applicable percentage contained in this paragraph if a Qualified Social E-Commerce Company achieves, or has achieved, the following annual resident new hire proportion goals during calendar years 2010 through 2015:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident employment credit” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“STEM” means the fields of study in the categories of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unrelated entity” means any person or entity that is not a related entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
