<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1005.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1005.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1005_01">
        <akn:num>47-1005.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Interests in real property belonging to government and international organizations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term “exempt purpose”, as applied to a lessee or user, shall mean an exempt purpose with specified use, operation, and other restrictions as set forth in § 47-1002(4) through (20) and § 47-1002(31).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If real property (or a portion thereof), which is exempt or immune from real property taxation under § 47-1002(1) through (3) or the law of the United States or the District of Columbia, is leased, loaned, or otherwise made available to any person in connection with a business or as a residence, or both, and the use is not for an exempt or immune purpose and the person is not exempt or immune from income taxation under the law of the United States or District of Columbia, the leasehold interest, possessory interest, beneficial interest, or beneficial use of the lessee or user of the real property shall be assessed and taxed. The Mayor shall determine the assessed value of the interest or use in accordance with § 47-820(a)(3) as if the lessee or user of the real property were the owner of the real property and the real property were not exempt or immune from taxation; provided, that the taxable value may be adjusted by the Mayor to reflect the duration of the interest or use remaining; provided further, that the Mayor may impute a duration of the interest or use based upon the intent, actions, and policies of the parties to the conveyance, the history of the real property, the perception of third parties, and written documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of § 47-831 shall apply in the case where a leasehold interest, possessory interest, beneficial interest, or beneficial use has escaped or been omitted from assessment and taxation, or the assessment has been made void.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The lessee or user shall be subject to the same application process, filing requirements for reports and income and expense statements, taxes, and penalties as an institution, organization, corporation, or association under § 47-1007.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1005_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The rate of tax under § 47-812, for the applicable classification under § 47-813 determined according to the use of the leased or loaned real property, shall be applied to the assessed value for purposes of the tax levy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
