<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1806.09b"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1806.09b/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1806_09b">
        <akn:num>47-1806.09b</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax on residents and nonresidents; credits; lower income, long-term homeowner credit — Application for credit.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_09b_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To receive the credit allowed by § 47-1806.09a, the eligible resident shall submit, with the resident’s District of Columbia income tax return, an application containing any forms and information prescribed by the Mayor. If the resident is not required to file a District of Columbia income tax return, the resident shall submit an application containing any forms and information in a manner that the Mayor shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_09b_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the resident does not submit the application required by subsection (a) of this section within 12 months after the last day of the tax year for which the credit may first be requested, the credit shall not be allowed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_09b_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An eligible resident may apply for the credit allowed by § 47-1806.09a or the credit allowed by § 47-1806.08a [repealed], but shall not be eligible for both tax credits. No person may apply for any of the credits if another person in the household has applied for any of the credits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_09b_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An eligible resident in a household may seek a pro rata contribution from the eligible resident who receives the credit. The eligible resident who does not receive the credit shall not have any right against the District of Columbia to claim or recover the credit or any portion thereof, whether at law or in equity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_09b_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an eligible resident shall not be required to submit an application with the eligible resident’s 2003 District of Columbia personal income tax return.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
