<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1812.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1812.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1812_08">
        <akn:num>47-1812.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Withholding of tax.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Income of foreign corporations or unincorporated business. — Whenever the Council of the District of Columbia shall deem it necessary in order to satisfy the District’s claim for a tax payable by any foreign corporation or unincorporated business, it may, by rules and regulations, require any person subject to the jurisdiction of the District to withhold and pay to the Mayor an amount not in excess of 5% of all income payable by such person to such foreign corporation or unincorporated business. After such foreign corporation or unincorporated business shall have filed all returns required under this subchapter, and the same shall have been audited, the Mayor shall refund any overpayment to the taxpayer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wages; method of determination. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Overlapping pay periods; multiple employers. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Included and excluded wages. — If the remuneration paid by an employer to an employee for services performed during one-half or more of any payroll period of not more than 31 consecutive days constitutes wages, all the remuneration paid by such employer to such employee for such period shall be deemed to be wages; but if the remuneration paid by an employer to an employee for services performed during more than one-half of any such payroll period does not constitute wages, then none of the remuneration paid by such employer to such employee for such period shall be deemed to be wages.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Exemptions. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure to withhold or pay amounts withheld. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Statement to be furnished employee. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Liability for tax withheld. — An employer shall be liable for the payment of tax required to be deducted and withheld under this section. Such tax shall be paid to the Mayor and shall not be paid to any other person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Declaration and payment of estimated tax. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Liability for 1956 tax. — One-half of the liability for the income tax imposed by this chapter for the calendar year 1956, or the fiscal year of a taxpayer beginning during such calendar year, upon any resident of the District (other than fiduciaries) shall be discharged. The remainder of the total amount of the income tax due as shown on the taxpayer’s return shall be paid to the Collector on the 15th of April, 1957, or if the return be made on the basis of a fiscal year the remainder of the total amount of such tax shall be paid on the 15th day of the 4th month following the close of the fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rate of interest. — Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, interest shall be assessed on deficiencies and late payments of income tax withheld or required to be withheld at source by an employer as provided for in this section at the rate of one and one half percent per month or fraction thereof from the date prescribed for payment of the tax until paid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Withholding from lottery winnings. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1812_08_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
