<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1270"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1270/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1270">
        <akn:num>47-1270</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Administrative costs” means the costs of DHCF to administer, manage, and monitor the Intermediate Care Facility for People with Intellectual Disabilities reimbursement program and the Stevie Sellows quality improvement funding support, including personnel costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DHCF” means the Department of Health Care Finance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_1B">
      <akn:num>(1B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fund” means the Stevie Sellows Quality Improvement Fund established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross revenue” means the sum of revenue for provisions of services to consumers with developmental disabilities. For purposes of this chapter, gross revenues does not include charitable contributions or interest income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“ICF/IID” means Intermediate Care Facility for People with Intellectual Disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intermediate care facility for persons with intellectual or developmental disabilities” and “ICF-IDD” have the same meaning as under 42 U.S.C. 1396d(d), but do not include a facility operated by the federal government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medicaid” means the medical assistance programs authorized by title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343;  42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.), and by  [§ 1-307.02], and administered by DHCF.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Quality of care improvements” means improving the quality of care for consumers with developmental disabilities by efforts to reduce turnover and increase the qualifications of the employees, excluding managers, administrators, and contract employees, such as an increase in salaries or benefits, or an increase in training and educational opportunities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Rebasing year” means the third year after the effective date of the State Plan Amendment governing the reimbursement of ICF/IID and every subsequent third year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident” means a person receiving services in an ICF-IDD.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1270_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reimbursement methodology” means the prospective Medicaid payment rate system for intermediate care facilities for persons with intellectual disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
