<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1806.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1806.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1806_04">
        <akn:num>47-1806.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax on residents and nonresidents — Credits — In general.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount of tax payable under this subchapter by a resident of the District in respect to the taxable year shall be reduced by a credit equal to the amount of individual income tax such individual is required to pay and, in fact, has paid to any state, territory or possession of the United States, or political subdivision thereof, upon income attributable to such state, territory or possession of the United States, or political subdivision thereof, for such taxable year or portion thereof while concurrently a resident of the District. The credit provided under this subsection shall not exceed the proportion of the tax otherwise due under this chapter that the amount of the individual’s adjusted gross income received by him, or accrued to him if on an accrual basis, subject to tax in the other jurisdiction bears to his entire adjusted gross income received by him, or accrued to him, while he was concurrently a resident of the District. The Mayor may require satisfactory proof of the payment of such income taxes to another jurisdiction. The credit provided by this subsection shall not be allowed against any tax imposed under §§ 47-1808.01 through 47-1808.06. Beginning with any taxable year after December 31, 1990, no franchise tax, license tax, excise tax, unincorporated business tax, occupation tax, or any tax characterized as such by the other taxing jurisdiction, even if applied to earned or business income, shall qualify as a credit under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount deducted and withheld as tax under this chapter during any calendar year upon the wages of any individual shall be allowed as a credit to the recipient of the income against the tax imposed by this chapter, for taxable years beginning in such calendar year. If more than 1 taxable year begins in such calendar year such amount shall be allowed as a credit against the tax for the last taxable year so beginning.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall take effect in accordance with the provisions of § 1-206.02(c)(1) and shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1806_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
