<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1363"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1363/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1363">
        <akn:num>47-1363</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rights of owners and purchasers during redemption period; appointment of receiver of real property.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1363_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a real property sold under this chapter shall have the right, during the period of redemption, to continue in possession of, and to exercise all rights of ownership over, the real property until the right of redemption has been finally foreclosed under the provisions of subchapter IV of this chapter; provided, that a purchaser may apply to the Superior Court for the appointment of a receiver of the real property covered by the certificate of sale or assignment of the certificate of sale in accordance with the provisions of laws and of rules and practice of the Superior Court that relate to receivers. If a certificate of sale is held by the District or instrumentality thereof, the Mayor or instrumentality of the District may make application by complaint to the Superior Court for the appointment of a receiver of the real property covered by the certificate of sale. The defendant, in an action brought by the Mayor or instrumentality of the District for the appointment of a receiver, shall be the owner of the real property whose name last appears as the owner on the Mayor’s tax roll. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the real property is vacant or abandoned, a certificate of sale has at any time been issued in the name of the District or instrumentality thereof, and the certificate of sale is presently held by the District or instrumentality thereof, the Mayor or instrumentality of the District shall have the right of immediate possession of the real property from the date of the tax sale without the necessity of receivership proceedings; provided, that the Mayor or instrumentality of the District shall make an accounting of all rents collected to the owner on redemption of the real property, and on redemption, shall remit the rents, less all remuneration for the maintenance and upkeep of the real property. The Mayor or an instrumentality of the District shall not be subject to the expiration of a waiting period or other period before making improvements to the real property. To redeem the vacant or abandoned real property, the person redeeming shall pay the District or instrumentality thereof for the reasonable value of all improvements made by the District or instrumentality thereof to the real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1363_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the purchaser of a real property at a tax sale shall not have:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
