<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1054"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1054/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1054">
        <akn:num>47-1054</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust; lot 30, square 1060.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1054_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council of the District of Columbia orders that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against real property located at square 1060, lot 30, for the period of tax years 1997 to 2003, be forgiven, and that any payment already made for this period, as of [April 5, 2005], be refunded; provided, that this property is owned and used by the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust as a community garden, which is available for use by the public, and not used for commercial purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1054_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The one-time transfer of the property specified in subsection (a) of this section to the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust shall not be subject to the recordation and transfer taxes and fees under Chapters 9 or 14 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1054_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the transfer of the property described in subsection (a) of this section to the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust, the property shall be exempt from all taxation so long as the same is used in carrying out the public purposes and activities of the Capitol Hill Community Garden Land Trust, and not used for commercial purposes and subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007 and 47-1009.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
