<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1052"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1052/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1052">
        <akn:num>47-1052</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payments in lieu of taxes, lots 878 and 880, square 456.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, during the PILOT period, no real property taxes shall be due and payable from the owner of a Parcel during the PILOT period. In lieu of real property taxes during the PILOT period, the owner of each Parcel shall pay a PILOT, in the amount that would be owed to the District if the Parcel were subject to real property taxation (including interest and penalties in the same amount that would be imposed on delinquent real property tax payments), to the Qualified Theater Company in the manner provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, during the PILOT period, the District shall, in lieu of any real property tax bills, send a PILOT bill to each owner of each Parcel, and shall send a copy of the PILOT bills to the Qualified Theater Company. The PILOT bills shall be sent out at the same time and in the same manner as real property tax bills would be sent for the Parcels and shall state the amount of the PILOT owed by the property owner. Except as otherwise provided for pursuant to subsection (g) of this section, the PILOT bill shall state that payments shall be made to the Qualified Theater Company, or at the Qualified Theater Company’s direction, within the same time period that real property tax payments are required to be made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, before the expiration of the Initial PILOT Period, on the date that a PILOT payment is made, the total amount of PILOT payments equals or exceeds $6 million and no building permit for a theater with a floor area of not less than 18,000 square feet to be used for theater and ancillary facilities on any Parcel has been issued, the collection of the PILOT shall be suspended and the imposition of real property taxes on the Site shall resume. If, after the suspension of the collection of the PILOT but during the Initial PILOT Period, the building permit is issued, then collection of the PILOT shall resume and PILOT bills shall be sent as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall constitute a prior lien on the applicable Parcels to the same extent as a real property tax lien.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Qualified Theater Company may pledge its interest in the PILOT as an account pursuant to Article 9 of Title 28.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the District issues Bonds, the District may, in financing documents that it enters into in connection with that transaction, provide for the PILOT to be made to the bond trustee for the benefit of the holders of the Bonds, to be used only to pay principal, premium, and interest on the Bonds and for any other payments set forth in the financing documents. If such provisions are included in the financing documents, the PILOT shall constitute a lien against the property on which the PILOT was assessed to the same extent as a real property tax lien and shall be deemed to be a tax within the meaning of 11 U.S.C. §§ 502(b), 505, and 507(a)(8)(B).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Qualified Theater Company, through its counsel, may file suit in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia against any owner of a Parcel whose PILOT is at least 60 days overdue. The Qualified Theater Company may recover as damages a delinquent PILOT, including interest and penalties, and the Qualified Theater Company’s attorneys’ fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any judgment obtained pursuant to subsection (h) of this section shall not be waived or reduced by the District and shall only be satisfied by the payment to the Qualified Theater Company of the full amount of the judgment, by waiver or compromise by the Qualified Theater Company, or by sale of the relevant Parcel pursuant to subsection (k) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Qualified Theater Company obtains a judgment in a suit filed pursuant to subsection (h) of this section, it may execute upon the judgment using any method authorized by District law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a PILOT shall remain unpaid for 180 days after it is due, upon the request of the Qualified Theater Company or its designee, and upon presentment of evidence in a form satisfactory to the District of the PILOT delinquency, the District shall sell the applicable Parcel in the same manner and under the same conditions as property sold for delinquent real property taxes, at the next ensuing tax sale for which proper notice may be given, if the PILOT, including interest and penalties thereon, shall not have been paid in full prior to the sale. The proceeds shall be applied towards the delinquent PILOT, including interest and penalties thereon; provided, that the proceeds from the sale shall be applied first toward any delinquent water and sewer charges, and then toward any delinquent litter control nuisance fines, in accordance, respectively with §§ 34-2407.02 and 34-2110, and § 8-807). The proceeds for the delinquent PILOT, including interest and penalties thereon, and the Qualified Theater Company’s costs associated with the sale shall be delivered to the Qualified Theater Company within 30 business days after their receipt by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Parcel owner may challenge the accuracy of any PILOT bill in the same manner as if it were a real property tax bill. If, after a Parcel owner pays a PILOT bill, the District determines that the amount of the PILOT bill was incorrect and resulted in an overpayment of some or all of that payment by the Parcel owner, the amount of the overpayment shall be credited against the next PILOT bill with respect to the Parcel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The remedies available to a Qualified Theater Company under subsections (h), (i), and (j) of this section shall be satisfied only by execution against the Site and no deficiency arising therefrom shall give rise to a personal obligation of the Owners. The penalties, interest, and legal fees provided for in subsections (h), (i), and (j) of this section shall be limited to those available to the District in connection with a tax sale for delinquent real property taxes under Chapter 13A.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1052_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall expire on the day after the date on which the District and the Qualified Theater Company have entered into a grant agreement for the making of the grant identified in subsection (a)(7)(B) of this section, and the funding of that grant. The Mayor shall notify the Council when the District and the Qualified Theater Company have entered into the grant agreement and the grant is funded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
