<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1271"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1271/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1271">
        <akn:num>47-1271</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>[Stevie Sellows] Quality Improvement Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1271_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a fund designated as the Stevie Sellows Quality Improvement Fund (“Fund”), which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used for the purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section. All assessments collected under this chapter, any and all interest earned on those assessments, and any and all interest and penalties collected under § 47-1274, shall be deposited into the Fund, and shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section, subject to authorization by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1271_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Fund shall be used to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1271_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, of the revenues deposited in the Fund in fiscal year 2011, at least $1 million shall be used to support quality of care improvements for those facilities that meet the requirements of § 47-1272, and up to $3.7 million may be used to support Medicaid services in the District of Columbia, including reimbursements for ICF/IIDs for the services that they provide.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1271_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall submit to the Council, as a part of the annual budget, a requested appropriation for expenditures from the Fund for a fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1271_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall audit all income and expenses of the Fund annually and provide the annual report to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
