<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1805.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1805.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1805_02">
        <akn:num>47-1805.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Returns — Persons required to file.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Residents and nonresidents. — Every nonresident of the District receiving income subject to tax pursuant to this chapter and every resident of the District, except a fiduciary, who is required to file a federal return under the provisions of § 6012 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. § 6012].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Fiduciaries. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Joint fiduciaries. — A return by one of 2 or more joint fiduciaries filed with the Mayor shall be sufficient compliance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any resident or nonresident or any fiduciary is unable to make his own return, the return shall be made by his duly authorized agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Corporations and financial institutions. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unincorporated businesses. — Every unincorporated business engaging in or carrying on any trade or business within the District or receiving income from sources within the District within the meaning of §§ 47-1810.01 to 47-1810.03 and having a gross income of more than $12,000, regardless of whether it has a net income. The return shall be made by the taxpayer or taxpayers liable for the payment of the tax.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Partnerships. — Every partnership, other than partnerships subject to the taxes imposed by §§ 47-1808.01 to 47-1808.06 on unincorporated businesses, engaged in any trade or business, or receiving income from sources within the District. There shall be included in such return the names and addresses of the individuals who would be entitled to share in the net income of the partnership, if distributed, and the amount of distributive share of each individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Exempt Organizations. — Every exempt organization exempt from tax that has unrelated business income subject to tax under section 511 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. § 511] or income subject to tax under section 527 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. § 527], as provided under § 47-1802.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Registration. — No person shall engage in or continue to engage in a trade, business or profession subject to taxes under the provisions of this chapter without first registering to do so. Such registration shall be made in such manner and on such forms as the Mayor shall prescribe and registration shall not be transferable. Whoever engages in a trade, business or profession which is subject to tax under the provisions of this chapter without first registering to do so, as required by this section, shall, upon conviction thereof be fined not more than $500. Such failure to register shall also be subject to a civil penalty of $50 a day for each day that such failure continues.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
