<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1803.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1803.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1803_03">
        <akn:num>47-1803.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Gross income — Deductions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Deductions allowed. — The following deductions shall be allowed from gross income in computing net income of corporations, financial institutions, unincorporated businesses and partnerships:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Deduction for domestic production activities disallowed. — In computing net income of corporations, financial institutions, unincorporated businesses, and partnerships, no deduction from gross income shall be allowed for the amount attributable to domestic production activities under section 199 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. § 199].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Deductions allowed — Generally. — In the case of an individual, estate, or trust, deductions allowed under this section shall be the same (and to the same extent) as the deductions allowed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 on federal individual or fiduciary income tax returns; provided, however, that no deduction may be allowed for the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Deductions allowed — Long-term care insurance]. — For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2015, an individual may deduct from gross income the amount the individual pays annually in premiums for long-term care insurance, as defined in § 31-3601(5); provided, that the deduction shall not exceed $500 per year, per individual, whether the individual files individually or jointly.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Deductions allowed — Teacher expenses]. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_b_3">
      <akn:num>(b-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Depreciation. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_b_4">
      <akn:num>(b-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Limitation on itemized deductions. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Standard deduction. — Every individual who claims the standard deduction on his or her federal income tax return shall claim the applicable standard deduction specified in § 47-1801.04(26). Every individual who itemizes deductions on his or her federal income tax return shall itemize the deductions permissible under this chapter. If spouses or domestic partners file separate returns, the applicable standard deduction shall be allowed to neither if the net income of one of the spouses or domestic partners is determined by itemizing deductions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Deductions not allowed. — In computing net income, no deductions shall be allowed in any case for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1803_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Lower income rental housing depreciation deduction. — An investor in a shared equity financing agreement may qualify for a depreciation deduction as provided in § 47-3507.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
