<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1818.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1818.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1818_02">
        <akn:num>47-1818.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax credits to Qualified Social E-Commerce Companies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (c) of this section and § 47-1818.04, the real property taxes imposed by Chapter 8 of this title with respect to qualified real property shall be abated up to the amount of the new hire wage credit, beginning in fiscal year 2016 and continuing until the new hire wage credit is exhausted or forfeited, or through fiscal year 2025, whichever occurs earlier; provided, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (c) of this section and § 47-1818.04, the corporate income tax imposed on a Qualified High Technology Company by § 47-1817.06 with respect to taxable income earned by a Qualified Social E-Commerce Company shall be abated up to the amount of the resident employment credit for 5 years commencing on the date that the Qualified Social E-Commerce Company occupies qualified real property (except, that in no instance shall such 5-year period begin before October 1, 2015), or until the resident employment credit is exhausted or forfeited as provided pursuant to this subchapter, or through fiscal year 2025, whichever occurs earlier. The resident employment credit amount available to be applied against the tax imposed by § 47-1817.06 shall be determined each tax year by applying the resident new hire proportions during the timeframe set forth in § 47-1818.01(14).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1818_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
