<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1805.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1805.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1805_03">
        <akn:num>47-1805.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Returns — Filing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Time and place. — All returns of income for the preceding taxable year required to be filed under the provisions of § 47-1805.01 shall be filed with the Mayor on or before the 15th day of April of each year, except that such returns, if made on the basis of a fiscal year, shall be filed on or before the 15th day of the 4th month following the close of such fiscal year; provided, however, that any return required to be filed, for the preceding year under the provisions of subchapter VII of this chapter shall be filed on or before the 15th day of March in each year, except that such returns, if made on the basis of a fiscal year, shall be filed on or before the 15th day of the 3rd month following the close of such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Extension of time. — The Mayor may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing the returns required by § 47-1805.02 whenever in his judgment good cause exists therefor, and he shall keep a record of every such extension. Except in case of a taxpayer who is not within the continental limits of the United States, no such extension shall be granted for more than 6 months, and in no case shall such extension be granted for more than 1 year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1805_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Exempt Organizations. — Notwithstanding the provisions of— subsection (a) of this section, unrelated business income tax returns of exempt organizations shall be filed on or before the 15th day of the 5th month following the close of the taxable year for the taxpayer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
