<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-143"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-143/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_143">
        <akn:num>47-143</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>United States Treasury offset program authorized; setoff of federal debts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may enter into an agreement with the United States Secretary of the Treasury to participate in the Treasury Offset Program. The offset agreement may provide for the collection of any delinquent debt owed to the District of Columbia from federal payments payable to the debtor. The offset agreement may also provide for the United States to submit requests to the District for delinquent nontax debts owed to federal agencies to be offset against District of Columbia payments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may authorize the Chief Financial Officer to reduce a District of Columbia payment by the amount of any federal nontax debt amount requested by the United States to be offset by the District in accordance with the offset agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The offset agreement may provide for the United States or the District to charge a fee for an offset implemented by either party and that the offset fee may be deducted from amounts remitted to the District of Columbia by the federal government. The amount of an offset fee charged by the United States shall be added to the nontax debt amount owed the District by the debtor and shall be considered an additional debt of the debtor, which shall be subject to offset. The amount of an offset fee charged by the District shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The offset agreement may provide that a federal official may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After receiving a certified offset request from a federal official, the Mayor may (or shall, if required by the offset agreement):</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-143_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
