<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1512"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1512/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1512">
        <akn:num>47-1512</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rolling stock.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1512_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The rolling stock of railroad companies, refrigerator-car companies, parlor-car companies, sleeping-car companies, tank-car companies, express companies, car-renting companies, and all other companies owning parlor, sleeping, dining, tank, freight, or any other cars which are operated or run over or upon the line or lines of any railroad or terminal company in the District of Columbia, shall be deemed to be located in said District for purposes of taxation, whether or not the individual units are continuously in the District or are constantly changing, and such property shall be reported, assessed, and taxed within the time, and at the rates prescribed by law, for the reporting and taxation of other personal property in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1512_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Such rolling stock as is primarily located in the District of Columbia shall be reported and taxed at its full and true value on the last day of the calendar year preceding the tax date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1512_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Such rolling stock as is not primarily located in the District of Columbia shall be reported and taxed in the manner following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1512_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All of the provisions of law relating to the filing of returns, assessment, payment, and collection of personal property taxes in the District of Columbia shall be applicable to the companies described in the foregoing subsections.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1512_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual, partnership, unincorporated association, or corporation aggrieved by any assessment of taxes made pursuant to the provisions of this section may appeal therefrom to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the same manner and to the same extent as set forth in §§ 47-3303, 47-3304, and 47-3306 to 47-3308.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1512_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall be applicable to the taxable year beginning July 1, 1945, and each taxable year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
