<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1261"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1261/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1261">
        <akn:num>47-1261</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Case mix reimbursement methodology” means a prospective Medicaid payment rate system for nursing facilities that includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fiscal year” means the 12-month accounting period of the District of Columbia beginning on October 1 and ending on September 30 of the next year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fund” means the Nursing Facility Quality of Care Fund established by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross resident revenue” means the sum of resident charges, ancillary service charges, and other charges related to the provision of services to residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medicaid” means the medical assistance programs authorized by title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.), and by [§ 1-307.02], and administered by the Department of Health.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Net resident revenue” means gross resident revenue less deductions resulting from a nursing facility’s inability to collect full payment of its established charges to residents. The deductions include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nursing facility” means a health care facility as defined in and codified at § 44-501(a)(3), but does not include a health care facility operated by the federal government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Quality of care initiatives” means initiatives that include a case mix reimbursement methodology, reimbursement of the costs of the audit required by § 47-1262(d), and, to the extent that amounts in the Fund remain, other programs designed to promote and foster the improved care, safety, and health of residents in Medicaid-certified nursing facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident” means a person receiving services in a nursing facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1261_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Superior Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
