<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1084"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-1084/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_1084">
        <akn:num>47-1084</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc. residential rental project; Lot 800, Square 5984, and Lot 916, Square 5730.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1084_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The real properties described as Lot 800, Square 5984, and Lot 916, Square 5730, owned by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., shall be exempt from real property taxation so long as the real properties continue to be owned by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or continue to be under applicable use restrictions during a federal low-income housing tax credit compliance period, and not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1084_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The conveyance of any of the properties described in subsection (a) of this section to Affordable housing [Housing] Opportunities, Inc. or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by it shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 11 of Title 42 of the District of Columbia Official Code, and the transfer of any of the properties described in subsection (a) of this section by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by it shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 9 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-1084_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All recordation and transfer taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc., or SOME, Inc. or an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Affordable Housing Opportunities, Inc. or SOME, Inc. with respect to real property located at Lot 800, Square 5984, or Lot 916, Square 5730, or any of the properties described in § 47-1078(a)(2), for any conveyance or transfer prior to [September 14, 2011], shall be forgiven, and any payments already made shall be refunded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
