<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.49"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.49/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_49">
        <akn:num>47-2853.49</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Substantial equivalency; practice privilege.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board, or its designee, shall make a determination of whether the education, examination, and experience requirements contained in the statutes and administrative rules of another jurisdiction are comparable to, or exceed, the education, examination, and experience requirements contained in the Uniform Accountancy Act, approved by the NASBA Board of Directors on July 7, 2007 (http://www.nasba.org/862571B900737CED/60C85E6667EE42F58   62573E6004F3E9D/$file/UAA%20Fifth%20Edition%20Final.pdf) (“UAA”) or that an individual certified public accountant’s (“CPA”) education, examination, and experience qualifications are comparable to or exceed the education, examination, and experience requirements contained in the UAA. In making its determination, the Board, or its designee, shall take into account the qualifications without regard to the sequence in which experience, education, or examination requirements were attained.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual whose principal place of business is not in the District shall be presumed to have qualifications substantially equivalent to the District’s qualifications and shall have all the privileges of licensees and permit holders of the District without the need to obtain a license under § 47-2853.42 or a permit under § 47-2853.47, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in this part, an individual granted practice privileges under this section, who offers or renders professional services, whether in person or by mail, telephone, or electronic means pursuant to this part, need not provide notice or other submission to any individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual licensee of another state exercising the privilege afforded under this section and the firm that employs the licensee shall simultaneously consent, as a condition of the grant of the privilege, to the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual who has been granted practice privileges under this section and who performs services for which a firm permit is required under subsection (e) of this section shall not be required to obtain a license under § 47-2853.42 or a permit under § 47-2953.47 [§ 47-2853.47].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_49_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A permit holder of the District offering or rendering services or using their CPA title in a state shall be subject to disciplinary action in the District for an act committed in the state for which the permit holder would be subject to discipline for the act committed in the state. The Board shall investigate any complaint made by a board of accountancy of a state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
