<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2837"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2837/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2837">
        <akn:num>47-2837</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Secondhand dealers; classification; licensing; stolen property.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2837_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered to classify dealers in secondhand personal property (referred to in this section as “dealers”) and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered to fix and collect a license fee for each such class of dealer, which fee, in the judgment of the Mayor, will be commensurate with the cost to the District of Columbia of inspection, supervision, and regulation of such class of dealer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2837_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In classifying dealers the Council may take into consideration the kind of property dealt in, whether the property is retained by the dealer for sale at retail, whether the property is disposed of by the dealer out of the District of Columbia, whether the property is disposed of by the dealer as junk or otherwise, and such other criteria as the Council may deem appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2837_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person engaging in the business of buying, selling, trading, exchanging, or dealing in secondhand personal property of any description, including the return of unused portion of any ticket, order, or token purporting to evidence the right of the holder or possessor thereof to be transported by any railroad or other common carrier, however operated, from one state or territory of the United States, or from the District of Columbia, to any other state or territory of the United States or to the District of Columbia, shall be regarded as a dealer, and shall obtain the appropriate license and pay the fee therefor fixed by the Mayor. For the purposes of this section, the term “secondhand personal property” shall not include any item of personal property:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2837_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2837_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section for Class A and Class C shall be issued as an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter. Any other license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a General Sales endorsement to a basic business license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
