<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2018"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2018/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2018">
        <akn:num>47-2018</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Secrecy of returns; reciprocity.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2018_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2018_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in subsection (a) of this section shall be construed to prohibit the publication of notices authorized in this chapter or the publication of statistics so classified as to prevent the identification of particular returns or reports and the items thereof, or the publication of delinquent lists showing the names of persons, vendors, or purchasers who have failed to pay the taxes imposed by this chapter within the time prescribed herein, together with any relevant information which in the opinion of the Mayor may assist in the collection of such delinquent taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2018_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in subsection (a) of this section shall be construed to prohibit the Mayor, in his discretion, from divulging or making known any information contained in any report, application, or return required under the provisions of this chapter other than such information as may be contained therein relating to the amount of gross proceeds or tax thereon or any particulars relating thereto or the computation thereof.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2018_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any violation of the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be punishable by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [ยง 22-3571.01], or imprisonment for 1 year, or both, in the discretion of the court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2018_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Mayor may permit the proper officer of the United States or of any state or territory of the United States or his authorized representative to inspect the returns filed under this chapter, or may furnish to such officer or representative a copy of any such return, provided the United States, state, or territory grants substantially similar privileges to the Mayor or his representative or to the proper officer of the District charged with the administration of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2018_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All reports, applications, and returns received by the Mayor under the provisions of this chapter shall be preserved for 3 years and thereafter until the Mayor orders them to be destroyed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
