<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_02">
        <akn:num>47-2853.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>License, certification, and registration criteria.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice an occupation or profession for which a license, certification, or registration is required under this subchapter without a current valid license, certificate, or registration in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A license, certification, or registration is not required for the practice of any occupation, trade or profession not covered by this subchapter or Chapter 12 of Title 3.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall relieve any person from the obligation to obtain a business license or endorsement or any other license or permit required by District law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Registration shall be required whenever the Mayor has determined that a person who seeks to practice a particular occupation or profession need not meet specified educational or training requirements nor demonstrate competence, but to protect the public should be identified as a practitioner of that occupation or profession.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each board established pursuant to ยง 47-2853.06 shall advise the Mayor as to whether the occupations or professions under its jurisdiction are appropriately regulated by licensure, certification, or registration in accordance with the criteria established in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
