<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2404"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2404/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2404">
        <akn:num>47-2404</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Licenses.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall manufacture for sale, keep for sale, offer for sale, display for sale in vending machines, or sell cigarettes or other tobacco product in the District without having first obtained a license or licenses for such purpose or purposes from the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may issue the following types of licenses, upon the filing of an application as prescribed by the Mayor:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall keep a complete record of applications made for licenses under this section and of the actions taken thereon.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may, by regulation, adjust the license fees imposed by subsection (b) of this section and may establish fees for duplicate licenses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Licenses issued under this section shall remain in effect for such periods of time as may be prescribed by the Mayor by regulation, not exceeding 1 year from the effective date of such licenses, or until such licenses are suspended or revoked by the Mayor under subsection (f) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may, after a hearing, suspend or revoke any license issued under this section for any violation of this chapter or of the regulations promulgated under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The licenses required by this section shall be in addition to the licenses required by any other law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may suspend any license issued under this section to any person convicted of a first or second violation of ยง 22-1320. The Mayor shall revoke the license for a third or subsequent violation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2404_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this chapter shall be issued as a General Sales endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
