<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.44"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.44/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_44">
        <akn:num>47-2853.44</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Registration of firms of certified public accountants.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A firm registering with the Board as a firm of certified public accountants under subsection (a) of this section shall meet the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (a)(4) of this section, a firm that is a corporation organized for the practice of certified public accounting shall also comply with Chapter 5 of Title 29, and any rules promulgated thereunder, governing the issuance, ownership, and transferability of shares and be in compliance with such regulations as may be issued for such corporations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A firm that is registered pursuant to this section and holds a permit issued by the Board, or that is exempt from holding a registration and permit under subsection (a)(2) and (3) of this section may use the words “certified public accountants” or the abbreviation “CPA” in connection with its firm name. A registered firm shall notify the Board within one month after the admission or withdrawal of a member or shareholder in practice in the District from any firm so registered. Firms shall not offer certified public accounting services unless registered pursuant to this section, except as provided in subsection (a)(2) and (3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant firm for initial issuance or renewal of a permit to practice under this section shall register each office of the firm within the District with the Board and demonstrate that all attest and compilation services rendered in the District are under the charge of a person licensed under this part, or the corresponding provision of prior law or some other state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant firm for initial issuance or renewal of permits under this section shall, in its application, list all states (including the District) in which the firm has applied for or has been issued permits as a CPA firm and list any past denial, revocation, or suspension of a permit by the District or any other state, and each licensee or applicant for a permit under this section shall notify the Board in writing, within 30 days after its occurrence, of any change in the identities of partners, officers, shareholders, members, or managers whose principal place of business is in the District, any change in the number or location of offices within the District, any change in the identity of the persons in charge of such offices, and any issuance, denial, revocation, or suspension of a permit by any other state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_44_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Firms that fall out of compliance with the provisions of this section due to changes in firm ownership or personnel shall take corrective action as quickly as possible. The Board may grant a reasonable period to take corrective action. Failure to bring the firm back into compliance within a reasonable period, as defined by the Board, shall result in the suspension or revocation of the firm permit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
