<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.17"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.17/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_17">
        <akn:num>47-2853.17</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Revocation, suspension, or denial of license or privilege; civil penalty; reprimand.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each board, subject to the right of a hearing as provided by this subchapter, on an affirmative vote of a majority of its members present and voting may take 1 or more of the disciplinary actions provided in subsection (c) of this section against any applicant or person permitted by this subchapter to practice an occupation or profession regulated by the board who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon determination by a board that an applicant, licensee, or person permitted by this subchapter to practice in the District has committed any of the acts described in subsection (a) of this section, the board may direct the Mayor to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant may be denied a license or certificate by reason of a conviction which bears directly on the fitness of the person to be licensed only after consideration by the Mayor of the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a conviction of a criminal offense which bears directly on the fitness of the person to be licensed is the basis for denial of an application for a license or certificate under subsection (c) of this section, the denial shall be in writing and specifically state the evidence presented and reasons for the denial. A copy of the denial shall be provided to the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subchapter shall preclude prosecution for a criminal violation of this subchapter regardless of whether the same violation has been or is the subject of one or more of the disciplinary actions provided by this subchapter. Criminal prosecution may proceed prior to, simultaneously with, or subsequent to administrative enforcement action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_17_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person licensed to practice an occupation or profession in the District is subject to the disciplinary authority of the relevant board on the basis of disciplinary action taken by another jurisdiction if the basis of the disciplinary action would have caused a similar result in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
