<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2407"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2407/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2407">
        <akn:num>47-2407</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Redemption of stamps.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2407_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may, upon receipt of satisfactory evidence of the facts, redeem any stamps, issued under this chapter, which have been spoiled, destroyed, or rendered useless or unfit for the purpose intended, or for which the owner may have no use. Such redemption may be made either by allowing the owner of such stamps a credit on the purchase of new stamps equal to the amount paid for the spoiled, destroyed, or useless stamps or by refunding such amount; provided, that no refund shall be made in those cases where the owner can be made whole by allowing a credit on the purchase of new stamps. No refund or allowance shall be made under this section unless the owner of such stamps has filed a written claim, under oath, for such refund or allowance with the Mayor within 6 months after the stamps were spoiled, destroyed, or rendered useless or unfit for the purposes intended, or, in the case of the stamps for which the owner has no use, within 6 months after the purchase of such stamps.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2407_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No refund or allowance shall be made until:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2407_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the time limitations specified in subsection (a) of this section for the redemption of stamps, a claim for the redemption of unused stamps which are owned by licensed retailers or vending machine operators on the effective date of this chapter, other than stamps which were spoiled, destroyed, or rendered useless or unfit prior to the effective date of this chapter, shall be filed within 6 months after the effective date of this chapter. Stamps owned by licensed retailers and vending machine operators which were spoiled, destroyed, or rendered useless or unfit prior to the effective date of this chapter shall be subject to the time limitation for the redemption of such stamps specified in subsection (a) of this section. If the Mayor authorizes the continued affixation of stamps after the effective date of this chapter, which stamps were purchased by licensed retailers and vending machine operators prior to the effective date of this chapter, a claim for the redemption of such stamps shall be filed within the time prescribed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
