<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2829"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2829/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2829">
        <akn:num>47-2829</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Vehicles for hire; identification tags on vehicles; vehicles for school children; ambulances, private vehicles for funeral purposes; issuance of licenses; payment of fees.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the District government shall not issue or reissue a license or permit to any applicant for a license or permit if the applicant:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person, partnership, association, trust, or corporation operating or proposing to operate any vehicle or vehicles not confined to rails or tracks for the transportation of passengers for hire over all or any portion of any defined route or routes in the District of Columbia, shall, on or before the first day of October in each year, or before commencing such operation, submit to the Mayor, in triplicate, an application for license, stating therein the name of such person, partnership, association, trust, or corporation, the number and kind of each type of vehicle to be used in such operation, the schedule or schedules and the total number of vehicle miles to be operated with such vehicles within the District of Columbia during the 12-month period beginning with the first day of November in the same year; provided, that the provisions of this subsection shall not apply to companies operating both street railroad and bus services in the District of Columbia which pay taxes to the District of Columbia on their gross receipts; provided, that the provisions of this subsection shall not apply to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. The Mayor shall thereupon verify and approve, or return to the applicant for correction and resubmission, each such statement. Upon receipt of the approved copy, and prior to the first day of November in the same year, or before commencing such operation, each such applicant shall pay to the Collector of Taxes, in lieu of any other personal or license tax, in connection with such operation, the sum of $.01 for each vehicle mile proposed to be operated in the District of Columbia in accordance with the application as approved. Upon presentation of the receipt for such payment, the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent shall issue a license authorizing the applicant to carry on the operations embodied in the approved application. No increase of operations shall be commenced or continued unless and until an application similar to the original and covering such increase in operation shall have been approved and forwarded in the same manner and the corresponding additional payment made and license issued. No license shall be issued under the terms of this subsection without the approval of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners of taxicabs shall pay an annual license tax of an amount set by the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission for each taxicab which is to be operated in the District. The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission is authorized to make all reasonable and usual regulations for the control of taxicabs, and the Mayor shall make and enforce all reasonable and usual regulations he or she may consider necessary for vehicles licensed under the preceding subsections and § 47-2831.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission may develop procedures to evaluate the record of a taxicab operator’s license under the terms of subsection (e) of this section, and the owners of taxicabs licensed under the terms of this subsection. The record maintained by the Office of Taxicabs for each licensee shall contain any violations associated with the license upon the final determination of liability by any governmental body charged with adjudicating violations. Any procedure shall clearly state the grounds for suspension or revocation of a license. If the license of a person licensed pursuant to subsection (e) of this section is revoked, the person must complete the requirements contained in subsections (e)(2)(A) and (B) of this section before the person may receive a new license. If the license of a person licensed pursuant to subsection (e) of this section is suspended, the licensee must complete the requirements contained in subsection (e)(2)(A) of this section and present to the Commission the certificate of completion of the required course before reinstatement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_e_2">
      <akn:num>(e-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After March 25, 1987, the Office of Taxicabs under the direction of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, and prior to March 25, 1987, the Department of Public Works shall make the following information available for public inspection: The name of each person licensed under the terms of subsections (c) and (d) of this section; the licensee’s annual license number; the name of the association, corporation, or organization that maintains the lease or membership agreement with the licensee; any monetary fine, suspension, or revocation action taken against the licensee; where applicable, a certificate of completion by the licensee of the training course established pursuant to subsection (e-1) of this section; a record of any criminal conviction of the licensee within the last 3 years; and, any points assessed against the licensee’s District of Columbia operators permit. The records shall be cross-referenced to the association, corporation, or organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_e_3">
      <akn:num>(e-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission may issue rules to implement the provisions of subsections (e) through (e-2) of this section pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_e_4">
      <akn:num>(e-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After March 25, 1987, the Office of Taxicabs under the direction of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, and prior to March 25, 1987, the Department of Public Works shall, by regular mail and within 5 business days of a final decision of suspension, revocation, or non-renewal of a taxicab operator license, notify the association, corporation, organization, or person that maintains a taxicab lease or taxicab association or company membership agreement with the operator that the operator’s privilege to operate a taxicab in the District of Columbia has been suspended, revoked, or not renewed. The association, corporation, organization, or person that maintains a lease with the operator shall upon receipt of the notice terminate any lease agreement, written or otherwise, with the operator, and shall take reasonable steps to assure the return to the owner of any vehicle leased to the operator. The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission shall promulgate regulations to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All vehicles licensed under this section shall bear such identification tags as the Council of the District of Columbia may from time to time direct; and nothing herein contained shall exempt such vehicles from compliance with the traffic and motor vehicle regulations of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the procuring of a license, or the payment of a tax, with respect to a vehicle owned or operated by a state or local government or a subdivision or instrumentality thereof which is being used to transport school children, their teachers, or escorts to the District of Columbia from the state in which their school is located.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, owners of motor vehicles for hire used for any purpose, including, but not limited to, owners of ambulances for hire, and owners of passenger vehicles which, when used for hire, are used exclusively for funeral purposes, and, owners of passenger vehicles used exclusively for contract livery services for which the rate is fixed solely by the hour, and owners of passenger vehicles for hire used for sightseeing purposes shall pay a license tax of an amount set by the Mayor for each vehicle having a seating capacity of 12 or less passengers exclusive of the driver used in the conduct of their business. License endorsements requested by this subsection, excluding that of ambulances, shall be issued by the Department of Public Works. Licenses requested by this subchapter for ambulances shall be issued by the Department of Health as an Inspected Sales and Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall engage in driving or operating any vehicle licensed under the terms of subsection (h) of this section without having procured from the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent a license which shall only be issued upon evidence satisfactory to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, that the applicant is a person of good moral character and is qualified to operate such vehicle, and upon payment of an annual license fee of an amount set by the Mayor. Such license shall be carried upon the person of the licensee or in the vehicle while engaged in driving such vehicle when such vehicle is being used for hire. Application for such license shall be made in such form as shall be prescribed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia. Each annual license issued under the provisions of this paragraph shall be numbered, and there shall be kept in the Office of Taxicabs a record containing the name of each person so licensed, his annual license number and all matters affecting his qualifications to be licensed hereunder. No license issued under the provisions of this subsection shall be assigned or transferred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who resides in the District of Columbia, the State of Maryland, or the Commonwealth of Virginia shall be eligible to apply for an operator and vehicle license to operate a public vehicle-for-hire.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2829_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to a private vehicle-for-hire operator affiliated with a private vehicle-for-hire company pursuant to [subchapter I of Chapter 3 of Title 50 [§ 50-531 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
