<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2844"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2844/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2844">
        <akn:num>47-2844</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Regulations; suspension or revocation of licenses; bonding of licensees authorized to collect moneys; exemptions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2844_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council of the District of Columbia and Mayor are further authorized and empowered to make any regulations that may be necessary in furtherance of the purpose of this chapter and the Mayor is further authorized and empowered to suspend or revoke any license issued hereunder when, in his judgment, such is deemed desirable in the interest of public decency or the protection of lives, limbs, health, comfort, and quiet of the citizens of the District of Columbia, or for any other reason he may deem sufficient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2844_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2844_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2844_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2844_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this chapter requiring an inspection as a prerequisite to the issuance of a license, the Mayor is authorized to provide by regulation that any such inspection shall be made either prior or subsequent to the issuance of a license, but any such license, whether issued prior or subsequent to a required inspection, may be suspended or revoked for failure of the licensee to comply with the laws or regulations applicable to the licensed business, trade, profession, or calling.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2844_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
