<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2409"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2409/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2409">
        <akn:num>47-2409</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Seizure and forfeiture of property.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2409_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following shall be subject to seizure by the Mayor or any law enforcement officer of the District and to forfeiture to the District:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2409_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following conveyances shall not be subject to forfeiture under this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2409_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All property which is seized under subsection (a) of this section shall be promptly delivered to the Mayor and placed under seal, or removed to a place designated by the Mayor. Such property shall be proceeded against in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by libel action brought in the name of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia or any of his assistants and shall, unless good cause be shown to the contrary, be forfeited to the District; provided, that such property shall not be subject to replevin, but is deemed to be in the custody of the Mayor subject only to the orders, decrees, and judgments of the court having jurisdiction over the forfeiture proceedings, and; provided, further, that notwithstanding the provisions of this section, whenever such property is subject to seizure and forfeiture on account of failure to comply with the provisions of this chapter and the Mayor determines that such failure was excusable, the Mayor may return the property to the owner or owners thereof. Whenever the Mayor determines that any property seized under subsection (a) of this section is liable to perish or become greatly reduced in price or value by keeping such property until the completion of forfeiture proceedings, the Mayor may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2409_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After the final order, decree, or judgment is made, forfeited property shall be made available for the official use of any agency of the District government, disposed of by public auction, or otherwise disposed of as the Mayor may prescribe. If there is a bona fide prior lien against such forfeited property, the Mayor may (1) make payment of such lien and retain the property for official use, or (2) dispose of such property by public auction, and the proceeds of the sale of such property shall be made available, first, for the payment of any tax due under this chapter and all expenses incident to the seizure, forfeiture, and sale of such property, and, second, for the payment of such lien, and the remainder shall be deposited with the Treasurer of the District of Columbia; provided, that no payment of a lien shall be made where the lienor was a consenting party or privy to the violation of this chapter on account of which the property was seized and forfeited. To the extent necessary, liens against forfeited property shall, on good cause shown by the lienor, be transferred from the property to the proceeds of the sale of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2409_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever any cigarettes or other tobacco product are found in any vending machine in violation of the provisions of ยง 47-2402(g), the Mayor shall seal the machine to prevent the sale or removal of any cigarettes or other tobacco product from the machine until such time as the violation is corrected in the presence of the Mayor. The operator of such vending machine shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than the amount set forth in [ยง 22-3571.01] or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both; provided, that if the vending machine contains cigarettes or other tobacco product described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section, the operator shall, in addition, be subject to the penalties imposed by the other provisions of this chapter. Any person, other than the Mayor, who removes or otherwise tampers with any seals placed on a vending machine by the Mayor shall be subject to the penalties imposed by ยง 47-2414 [repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2409_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person whose property has been seized and forfeited under this section shall not be relieved from any other penalty imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
