<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2887.15"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2887.15/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2887_15">
        <akn:num>47-2887.15</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Civil remedies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2887_15_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An educational institution has a right of action against an athlete agent or a former student-athlete for damages caused by a violation of this part. In an action under this section, the court may award to the prevailing party costs and reasonable attorney’s fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2887_15_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Damages of an educational institution under subsection (a) of this section include losses and expenses incurred because, as a result of the conduct of an athlete agent or former student-athlete, the educational institution was injured by a violation of this part or was penalized, disqualified, or suspended from participation in athletics by a national association for the promotion and regulation of athletics, by an athletic conference, or by reasonable self-imposed disciplinary action taken to mitigate sanctions likely to be imposed by such an organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2887_15_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A right of action under this section does not accrue until the educational institution discovers or by the exercise of reasonable diligence would have discovered the violation by the athlete agent or former student-athlete.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2887_15_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any liability of the athlete agent or the former student-athlete under this section is several and not joint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2887_15_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This part does not restrict rights, remedies, or defenses of any person under law or equity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
