<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2106"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2106/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2106">
        <akn:num>47-2106</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalty for conducting false “closing-out sales” and for violation of this chapter; prosecutions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2106_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who shall advertise, hold, conduct, or carry on any sale of goods, wares, or merchandise under the description of closing-out sale or a sale of goods, wares, or merchandise damaged by fire, smoke, water, or otherwise, contrary to the provision of this chapter, or who shall violate any of the provisions of this chapter shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or imprisonment for 90 days or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2106_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prosecutions for violations of this chapter and regulations promulgated under the authority of this chapter shall be conducted in the name of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia or any of his assistants.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2106_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this chapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
