<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2001"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2001/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2001">
        <akn:num>47-2001</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Additional charges” means the excess of the gross receipts from the sale of or charges for any room or accommodations received by a room remarketer over the net charges.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Armored car service” means picking up and delivering money, receipts, or other valuable items with personnel and equipment to protect the properties while in transit. The term “armored car service” shall not include coin rolling or change-room services; provided, that these charges are separately stated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business” includes any activity engaged in by any person or caused to be engaged in by him with the object of gain, benefit, or advantage, either direct or indirect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cigar” means any roll for smoking, other than a cigarette as defined in § 47-2401(1) [§ 47-2401(1A)], made wholly or in part of tobacco, and where the wrapper or cover of the roll is made of natural leaf tobacco or any substance containing tobacco.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Collector” means the Collector of Taxes of the District or his duly authorized representatives.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his duly authorized representative or representatives.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Engaging in business” means commencing, conducting, or continuing in business, as well as liquidating a business when the liquidator thereof holds himself out to the public as conducting such a business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Food or drink” means items sold for human or animal ingestion that are consumed for their taste or nutritional value. These items include, but are not limited to, baby foods and formula; baked goods; baking soda, baking powder, and baking mixes; bouillon; cereal and cereal products; cocoa and cocoa products; coffee and coffee substitutes; condiments; cooking wines; cough drops; edible cake decorations; egg and egg products; fish and fish products, including shellfish; fruit, fruit products, and fruit juices; gelatin; honey; ice cream; meat and meat products; milk and milk products; nondairy creamers; oleomargarine; pasta and pasta products; poultry and poultry products; powdered drinks, including health and diet drinks; salad dressings; salt and salt substitutes; sauces and gravies; snack foods; soups; spices and herbs; sugar and sugar products; syrup and syrup substitutes; tea and tea substitutes; vegetables, vegetable products, and vegetable juices; vitamins; water; yogurt; pet foods; flavored extracts; ice; and any combination of these items. The term “food or drink” does not include spirituous or malt liquors, beers, and wines; drugs, medicines or pharmaceuticals; chewing tobacco; toothpaste; or mouthwash.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_g_1">
      <akn:num>(g-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Food or drink prepared for immediate consumption” includes, but is not limited to, food or drink in a heated state (except heated baked goods whose heated state is solely a result of baking); sandwiches suitable for immediate consumption; prepared salads; salad bars; party platters; cold drinks dispensed in or with a cup or glass either by a retailer or on a self-service basis by the consumer; frozen yogurt, ice cream, or ice milk sold in quantities of less than one pint; and all food or drink, served by, or sold in or by, restaurants, lunch counters, cafeterias, hotels, caterers, boarding houses, carryout shops or like places of business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_g_2">
      <akn:num>(g-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross receipts” means the total amount of the sales prices of the retail sales of vendors, valued in money, whether received in money or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_h_1">
      <akn:num>(h-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Net charges” means the gross receipts from the sale of or charges for any room or accommodations received from a room remarketer by the operator of a hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients for a consideration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_h_2">
      <akn:num>(h-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nexus-vendor” means a vendor that has a physical presence within the District of Columbia, such as property or retail outlets, selling via the internet property or rendering services to a purchaser in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_h_3">
      <akn:num>(h-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” includes an individual, partnership, society, club, association, joint-stock company, corporation, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, or referee, and any other person acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity, whether appointed by a court or otherwise, and any combination of individuals acting as a unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_i_1">
      <akn:num>(i-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Premium cigar” means any cigar with a retail cost of $ 2.00 or more, or packaged units of cigars averaging $ 2.00 or more per packaged cigar at retail.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_i_2">
      <akn:num>(i-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Purchaser” includes a person who purchases property or to whom is rendered services, receipts from which are taxable under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Purchaser’s certificate” means a certificate signed by a purchaser and in such form as the Mayor shall prescribe, stating the purpose to which the purchaser intends to put the subject of the sale, or the status or character of the purchaser.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Retailer” includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Retail establishment” means any premises in which the business of selling tangible personal property is conducted or in or from which any retail sales are made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Return” includes any return filed or required to be filed as herein provided.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_o_1">
      <akn:num>(o-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Room remarketer” means any person, other than the operator of a hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients for a consideration, having any right, access, ability, or authority, through an internet transaction or any other means whatsoever, to offer, reserve, book, arrange for, remarket, distribute, broker, resell, or facilitate the transfer of rooms the occupancy of which is subject to tax under this chapter and also having any right, access, ability or authority to determine the sale or charge for the rooms, lodgings, or accommodations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sale” and “selling” mean any transaction whereby title or possession, or both, of tangible personal property is or is to be transferred by any means whatsoever, including rental, lease, license, or right to reproduce or use, for a consideration, by a vendor to a purchaser, or any transaction whereby services subject to tax under this chapter are rendered for consideration or are sold to any purchaser by any vendor, and shall include, but not be limited to, any “sale at retail” as defined in this chapter. Such consideration may be either in the form of a price in money, rights, or property, or by exchange or barter, and may be payable immediately, in the future, or by installments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_q_1">
      <akn:num>(q-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Semipublic institution” means any corporation, and any community chest, fund, or foundation, organized exclusively for religious, scientific, charitable, or educational purposes, including hospitals, no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_r_1">
      <akn:num>(r-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Soft drink” means a non-alcoholic beverage with natural or artificial sweeteners. The term “soft drink” shall not include a beverage that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tangible personal property” means corporeal personal property of any nature.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_t">
      <akn:num>(t)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tax” means the tax imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_u">
      <akn:num>(u)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Taxpayer” means any person required by this chapter to make returns or to pay the tax imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_v">
      <akn:num>(v)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tax year” means the calendar year, or the taxpayer’s fiscal year if it be other than the calendar year when such fiscal year is regularly used by the taxpayer for the purpose of reporting District income taxes as the tax period in lieu of the calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_[v_1]">
      <akn:num>[(v-1)]</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Transient” means any person who occupies, or has the right to occupy, any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations for a period of 90 days or less during any one continuous stay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_w">
      <akn:num>(w)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Vendor” includes a person or retailer, including a nexus-vendor, selling property or rendering services upon the receipts from which a tax is imposed under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_w_1">
      <akn:num>(w-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2001_x">
      <akn:num>(x)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The foregoing definitions shall be applicable whenever the words defined are used in this chapter unless otherwise required by the context.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
