<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.195"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.195/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_195">
        <akn:num>47-2853.195</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Fiduciary duties of a property manager.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_195_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensee engaged to manage real estate shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_195_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in the property management agreement, a licensee engaged to manage real estate does not breach any duty or obligation to the owner by representing other owners in the management of other properties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_195_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensee engage to manage real estate may also represent the owner as seller or landlord if he or she enters into a brokerage relationship that so provides; in which case, the licensee shall disclose such brokerage relationships pursuant to the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_195_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to entering into any brokerage relationship provided for in this section, a licensee shall advise the prospective client of the type of brokerage relationship proposed by the broker, and the broker’s compensation, and whether the broker will share such salary or compensation with another broker who may have a brokerage relationship with another party to the transaction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_195_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The brokerage relationships set forth in this section shall commence at the time that a client engages a licensee and shall continue until (1) completion of performance in accordance with the brokerage relationship; or (2) the earlier of (A) any date of expiration agreed upon by the parties as part of the brokerage relationship or in any amendments thereto; (B) any mutually agreed upon termination of the relationship; (C) a default by any party under the terms of the brokerage relationship; or (D) a termination as set forth in § 47-2853.197(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
