<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2885.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2885.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2885_08">
        <akn:num>47-2885.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Licensing of pharmacies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The application for a pharmacy license shall be made on a form to be prescribed by the Mayor and shall be accompanied by the required fee. The license shall be valid for a period of time to be determined by the Mayor. No license fee shall be required for the operation of a pharmacy by the United States government or by the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Application for renewal of a pharmacy license shall be made not later than 30 days before the expiration date of the license to avoid lapse. An additional fee for late filing not exceeding the amount of the renewal fee shall be established by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each pharmacy license issued shall apply only to the operation of the pharmacy at the location for which it is issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A pharmacy license is not transferable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whether or not the proprietor of a pharmacy is a pharmacist, the pharmacy license shall be issued in the name of the proprietor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a pharmacy changes proprietorship, the license shall become void and shall be promptly surrendered to the Mayor, and a license shall be obtained by the new proprietor whether or not there is any change in the name of the pharmacy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2885_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a Public Health: Pharmacy and Pharmaceuticals endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
