<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2002.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2002.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2002_05">
        <akn:num>47-2002.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Ballpark sales taxes.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2002_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2002_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter relating to the imposition of sales tax on either a retail sale or a sale at retail, there is hereby imposed an additional sales tax of 4.25% on the gross receipts of any person from the sale of tickets to any public event referred to in ยง 47-2001(n)(1)(H) sponsored by the person (or any affiliate of such person) and to be performed at the ballpark, regardless of whether the ticket is sold to a person who resells the ticket to another person or to a person who uses the ticket for admission to the event; provided, that with respect to tickets to events at Robert F. Kennedy Stadium, the tax shall apply only to professional baseball games or professional baseball-related events and exhibitions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2002_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, there is hereby imposed an additional sales tax of 4.25% on the gross receipts of any person from the sale at the ballpark during such times as shall reasonably relate to the performance of baseball games or baseball-related events and exhibitions at the ballpark of tangible personal property or services otherwise taxable under the provisions of this chapter, except the gross receipts from (1) sales of food and beverages subject to the tax imposed by ยง 47-2002(3), and (2) the sale of or charge for the service of parking motor vehicles; provided, that with respect to the sale of tangible personal property or services at Robert F. Kennedy Stadium, the additional tax shall apply only to professional baseball games or professional baseball-related events and exhibitions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2002_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following revenues shall be deposited into one or more accounts within the Ballpark Revenue Fund:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2002_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer or his delegate shall promulgate regulations as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section, including regulations relating to the determination of District gross receipts and electronic filing and payment of sales taxes and fees. Until such time as the Chief Financial Officer or his delegate shall promulgate the regulations, any promoter of any event at which gross receipts from the sale of tickets, tangible personal property, or services are potentially subject to the taxes imposed by this section shall comply with the requirements of ยง 47-2002.04 as if the event were a special event.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
