<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.154"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.154/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_154">
        <akn:num>47-2853.154</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Appraisal Education Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_154_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a fund designated as the Appraisal Education Fund (“Fund”), which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia. All funds obtained from an appraisal education fund fee to be established by the Mayor (which shall be in addition to licensing and renewal fees established by the Mayor) and civil penalties imposed by the Board or the Office of Administrative Hearings pursuant to this part, and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress and used solely to pay the costs of operating and maintaining the Fund. All funds, interest, and other amounts deposited into the Fund shall not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall continually be available for the uses and purposes set forth in this section, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_154_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_154_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may establish minimum and maximum balances for the Fund, procedures for continuing and discontinuing assessing licensees, and rules for the implementation and operation of the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_154_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a licensee fails to pay the appraisal education fee within the time prescribed by rule, his or her license shall be automatically suspended. The Board shall send a notice of the suspension, by certified mail, to the address of record within 5 days after the suspension. The license shall be restored only upon the actual receipt by the Mayor of the delinquent fee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
