<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2839.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2839.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2839_01">
        <akn:num>47-2839.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Security agencies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful for any person to engage in the business of operating, managing, or conducting a security agency, for profit or gain, or to advertise or represent his or her business to be that of a security agency, or that of conducting, managing, or operating a security agency, without first obtaining a license to do so.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who violates any provision of this section, or the provisions of Chapter 21 of Title 17 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations pertaining to security agencies, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be subject to a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [ยง 22-3571.01] or imprisonment of not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All license fees collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the Occupations and Professions Licensing Special Account established pursuant to ยง 47-2853.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
