<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2886.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2886.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2886_09">
        <akn:num>47-2886.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Board of Registration for Professional Engineers— Complaints; hearings; appeals.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may upon its own motion, and shall upon the sworn complaint in writing of any person setting forth charges which would constitute grounds for refusal, suspension, or revocation of a certificate, as set forth in § 47-2886.08(16), investigate the acts of any person holding or claiming to hold a certificate. All charges, unless dismissed by the Board as unfounded or trivial, shall be heard by the Board within 3 months after the date on which they shall have been filed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall, at least 30 days prior to the date set for the hearing, notify the accused in writing of any charges made, and shall afford him an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel in reference thereto. Such notice may be served by its delivery personally to the accused licensee by the United States Marshal in the manner prescribed for service of original process in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, or by mailing it by registered mail or by certified mail with return receipt demanded, to the place of business last theretofore specified by the accused in his last notification to the Board. At the time and place fixed in the notice, the Board shall proceed to hearing of the charges and both the accused and the complainant shall be accorded ample opportunity to present, in person or by counsel, such testimony, evidence, and argument as may be pertinent to the charges or to any defense thereto. The Board may continue such hearing from time to time and shall give notice in writing to all parties in interest of the date and hour to which the hearing has been continued, and the place at which it is to be held.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall preserve a complete record of all proceedings at the hearing of any case wherein a certificate is refused, revoked, or suspended. The notice of hearing, complaint, and all other documents in the nature of pleadings and written motions filed in the proceedings, the transcript of testimony, and the orders of the Board shall be the record of such proceedings. The Board shall furnish a transcript of such record at cost to any person interested in such hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, after completion of the hearing, the Board shall be of the opinion that the accused is guilty of the charges, or any of them, the Board shall issue an order refusing, suspending, or revoking the certificate. Such order shall be served upon the accused person either personally or by mailing it by registered mail to the address specified by the accused person in his last notification to the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person aggrieved by the action of the Board may appeal as provided in §§ 2-501 to 2-510.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
