<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2211"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2211/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2211">
        <akn:num>47-2211</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Monthly returns; content and form; payment of tax.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every purchaser who is required to pay the tax under this chapter shall file a return with the Mayor within 20 days after the end of each calendar month. Such returns shall show the total sales prices of all tangible personal property and services purchased at retail sale upon which the tax imposed has not been paid by the purchaser to vendors or retailers, the amount of tax for which the purchaser is liable, and such other information as the Council of the District of Columbia deems necessary for the computation and collection of the tax.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council of the District of Columbia may permit or require the returns of purchasers to be made for other periods and upon such other dates as the Mayor may specify.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The return filed by a purchaser shall include the sales prices of all tangible personal property and services purchased at taxable retail sale during the calendar month or other period for which the return is filed and upon which the tax imposed has not been reimbursed by the purchaser to vendors or retailers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The form of return shall be prescribed by the Mayor and shall contain such information as he may deem necessary for the proper administration of this chapter. The Mayor may require amended returns to be filed within 20 days after notice and to contain the information specified in the notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the time of filing his return as provided in this section, the purchaser shall pay to the Mayor the amount of tax for which he is liable as shown by such return.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The taxes for the period for which a return is required to be filed under this section shall be due by the taxpayer and payable to the Mayor on the date limited for the filing of the return for such period, without regard to whether a return is filed or whether the return which is filed correctly shows the amount of the total sales prices and taxes due thereon.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2211_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
