<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2820"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2820/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2820">
        <akn:num>47-2820</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Theaters, moving pictures, skating rinks, dances, exhibitions, lectures, entertainments; assignment of police and firemen and additional fees based thereon; hours minors are prohibited on premises.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners or managers of theaters in which moving pictures are displayed, for profit or gain, shall pay a license fee of $830 biennially.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners or managers of buildings in which skating rinks, fairs, carnivals, balls, dances, exhibitions, lectures, or entertainments of any description including theatrical or dramatic performances of any kind are conducted, for profit or gain, shall pay a license fee of $500 per annum; provided, that for entertainments, concerts, or performances of any kind where the proceeds are intended for church or charitable purposes, and where no rental is charged, no license shall be required; provided further, that when, in the opinion of the Chief of Police and the Fire Chief of the District of Columbia, or either of them, it is necessary to post policemen or firemen, or both, at, on, and about the licensed premises for the protection of the public safety, in addition to the license fee provided for above, such owners or managers shall pay a further monthly permit fee, to be determined monthly by the said Chief of Police and Fire Chief, or either of them, based upon a reasonable estimate of the number of hours to be spent by policemen and firemen at, on, and about the licensed premises, this fee to be payable in advance on the first day of the month for which the permit is sought. Policemen and firemen so assigned shall be charged for by the hour at the basic daily wage rate of policemen and firemen so assigned in effect the first day of the month for which the permit is sought.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any applicant who holds a valid class C or D license issued pursuant to Chapter 1 of Title 25 and who holds a certificate of occupancy for less than 401 persons shall be exempt from the provisions of subsection (b)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall suspend the license of any licensee determined to have violated the provisions of subsection (c) of this section. The period of suspension shall not exceed 1 year for each violation. A licensee alleged to be in violation shall be entitled to a hearing in accordance with ยง 1-1509.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2820_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as  an Entertainment endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
