<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2886.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2886.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2886_13">
        <akn:num>47-2886.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Fees; Professional Engineers’ Fund; expenses of Board; audit.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each application for registration as a professional engineer shall be accompanied by the appropriate prescribed application fee and the registration fee. A person desiring certification as an engineer-in-training shall pay the prescribed application fee for such certification with his application and shall pay the additional application fee and the registration fee upon filing his application for registration as a professional engineer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Should the Board deny the issuance of a certificate of registration to any applicant, the registration fee deposited with the application shall be refunded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount of the fees prescribed in this part is that fixed by the following schedule:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Secretary-Treasurer of the Board shall receive and account for all money derived from the provisions of this part and shall keep such money in a separate fund to be known as “Professional Engineers’ Fund,” such Fund to be disbursed only by the Secretary-Treasurer upon itemized vouchers approved by the Chairman and attested by the Secretary-Treasurer of the Board. The Secretary-Treasurer shall furnish bond for the faithful discharge of his duties, in such form and amount as the Council of the District of Columbia shall require. The premium on such bond shall be regarded as a proper and necessary expense of the Board. The Secretary-Treasurer of the Board shall receive such salary as the Mayor shall determine, in addition to the compensation provided for in § 47-2886.06 [omitted]. The Board may make expenditures from this Fund for any purpose which, in the opinion of the Board, is reasonably necessary for the proper performance of its duties under this part; provided, however, that such expenditures shall in no event exceed the total of receipts. For the purpose of any contemplated investigation or audit by the Inspector General, the Office of the Inspector General shall have free access to the books of account, records, and papers of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
