<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.161"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.161/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_161">
        <akn:num>47-2853.161</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Scope of practice for real estate brokers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_161_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a fee, commission, or other valuable consideration, lists for sale, or sells, exchanges, purchases, rents, or leases real property. A real estate broker may collect or offer to collect rent or income for the use of real estate, or negotiate a loan secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or other encumbrance upon the transfer of real estate. A real estate broker may also engage in the business of erecting housing for sale and may sell or offer to sell that housing, or who as owner may sell or, through solicitation or advertising, offer to sell or negotiate the sale of any lot in any subdivision of land comprising 5 lots or more. This definition shall not apply to the sale of space for the advertising of real estate in any newspaper, magazine, or other publication; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_161_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>May employ real estate brokers, associate real estate brokers, real estate salespersons, property managers and resident managers. The real estate broker shall be held accountable for the day-to-day job-related activities of his or her employees. These activities include, but are not limited to, property management, leasing or renting of property, listing for sale, buying or negotiating the purchase or sale, or exchanging real estate or negotiating a loan on real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
