<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_03">
        <akn:num>47-2853.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Scope of subchapter.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This subchapter does not limit the right of a person to practice an occupation or profession that he or she is licensed, certified, or registered to practice, except as provided in this subchapter or by any other law or regulation. A person may practice any other occupation or profession for which authorization is not required by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prohibit the practice of an occupation or profession by a person enrolled in a recognized training program, school, or college as a candidate for a degree or certificate in that occupation or profession, or enrolled in a recognized postgraduate training program, provided that the practice is performed:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prohibit the practice of an occupation or profession by a person who has filed an initial application for licensure or certification and is awaiting action on that initial application, provided that the practice is performed:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as expressly provided to the contrary in this subchapter, any person licensed, certified, or registered by any District agency established by any statute amended, repealed, or superseded by this subchapter is considered for all purposes to be licensed, registered, or certified by the appropriate board established under this subchapter for the duration of the term for which the license, certification, or registration was issued, and may renew that authorization in accordance with the appropriate renewal provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided to the contrary in this subchapter, any person who was originally licensed, certified, or registered under a provision of law that has been repealed by this subchapter is deemed to meet the education and experience requirements for licensure, certification, or registration as if that provision had not been repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this subchapter prohibiting the practice of an occupation or profession without a license, certificate, or registration shall not apply to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
