<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.202"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.202/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_202">
        <akn:num>47-2853.202</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Eligibility requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_202_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant to be an apprentice refrigeration and air conditioning mechanic shall be registered by the Mayor, without examination, upon providing such information as may be required by the Board of Industrial Trades and payment of appropriate fees. An apprentice refrigeration and air conditioning mechanic shall work only under the direct personal supervision and control of a licensed master mechanic.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_202_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for licensure as a master mechanic shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Industrial Trades that the applicant has been employed installing, maintaining, repairing and replacing refrigeration and air conditioning equipment systems larger than 25 compressor horsepower or the equivalent tons of refrigeration in the aggregate for a period of at least 5 consecutive years immediately preceding the date of application, as verified in writing by a master mechanic.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_202_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for licensure as a master mechanic limited shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Industrial Trades that the applicant:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_202_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
