<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2402"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2402/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2402">
        <akn:num>47-2402</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Imposition; payment of cigarette tax.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Cigarettes on which the taxes levied and imposed by this section have been paid shall not be subject to additional taxation under this section; provided, that the burden of proof that the taxes levied and imposed by this section have been paid shall be upon the person who sells or possesses cigarettes in the District, against whom a tax assessment has been made, who has submitted an application for a refund, or whose cigarettes have been seized. For the purposes of this section, the term “person” includes any officer or employee of a corporation responsible for payment of the tax, or any member of a partnership or association responsible for the payment of the tax.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The tax levied and imposed by this section shall be paid by the affixture of stamps, purchased from the Mayor, evidencing the payment of the amount of tax imposed by this section. Such stamps shall be affixed to the original packages of cigarettes included in the directory of Tobacco Product Manufacturers maintained pursuant to § 7-1803.03(b) and shall be cancelled in the manner prescribed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection and subsection (f) of this section, each licensed wholesaler shall affix a stamp or stamps, evidencing the payment of the amount of tax imposed by this section, to each original package of cigarettes to be kept for sale, offered for sale, displayed for sale, or sold within the District. Such stamps shall be affixed to each original package of such cigarettes within 72 hours after the receipt of such cigarettes and prior to the sale of such cigarettes unless such cigarettes are exempt from taxation under the provisions of this chapter. Whenever any cigarettes are found in the place of business of a licensed wholesaler without the stamps affixed as herein provided, or not segregated or marked as having been received within the preceding 72 hours, or not segregated or marked as being held for sale outside of the limits of the District, or not segregated or marked as being held for sale to the United States or the District government, or any instrumentalities thereof, or not segregated or marked for other exempt purposes under this chapter, a prima facie presumption shall arise that such cigarettes are subject to the tax levied and imposed by this section and are possessed in violation of the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Licensed retailers and vending machine operators shall not accept deliveries of unstamped or improperly stamped cigarettes. Such licensees shall examine all packages of cigarettes immediately upon their receipt and shall immediately return any and all unstamped or improperly stamped cigarettes to the licensed wholesaler. Unless substantial evidence to the contrary is shown, the possession of any unstamped or improperly stamped cigarettes by such licensees shall be prima facie evidence that such cigarettes are possessed in violation of the provisions of this chapter. The Mayor may, however, authorize licensed retailers and vending machine operators to acquire and have in their possession cigarettes bearing cigarette tax stamps issued by any other state or jurisdiction; provided, that such cigarettes are intended for sale in such other state or jurisdiction. Licensed retailers and vending machine operators shall not purchase, acquire, or have in their possession District tax stamps. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, licensed retailers or vending machine operators, other than licensed retailers or vending machine operators who are also licensed wholesalers, who either have in their possession unused cigarette tax stamps or unstamped cigarettes on the effective date of this chapter shall not be deemed in violation of this subsection; provided, that such licensed retailers and vending machine operators affix or redeem such unused cigarette tax stamps and pay the tax levied and imposed by this section on such unstamped cigarettes in the manner and within the time specified by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On sales of cigarettes to other licensed wholesalers, a licensed wholesaler may deliver such cigarettes without affixing stamps thereon, and such other licensed wholesalers shall be liable for the tax imposed by this section on such cigarettes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All packages of cigarettes placed in cigarette vending machines shall be placed in such manner that the District cigarette tax stamps are visible whenever the packages are within that area of the vending machine which permits visibility of the packages.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as authorized by this section or § 47-2403, no person shall willfully or knowingly sell, transfer, buy, receive, have in his possession, or offer to sell, transfer, buy, or receive any unstamped or improperly stamped cigarettes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall sell, transfer, or offer to sell or transfer any cigarette tax stamps to any person other than the Mayor; nor shall any person buy, receive or offer to buy or receive any cigarette tax stamps from any person other than the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may by regulation provide for the purchase of stamps at a discount not exceeding 10% of the face value of such stamps.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The taxes imposed under this section shall be deemed to be a part of the selling price of cigarettes and shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any taxes imposed by any other law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2402_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
