<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.92"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2853.92/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2853_92">
        <akn:num>47-2853.92</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Eligibility requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_92_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant to be an apprentice electrician shall be registered by the Mayor, without examination, upon providing such information as may be required by the Board of Industrial Trades and payment of appropriate fees. An apprentice electrician shall work only under the direct personal supervision and control of a licensed master electrician or licensed master electrician specialist.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_92_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (b-1) of this subsection, an applicant for licensure as a journeyman electrician or a master electrician limited (low voltage) shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Industrial Trades that he or she has satisfactorily completed a class on Title 12C of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations or equivalent code within 2 years prior to submittal of the application and has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_92_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2853_92_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for licensure as a master electrician shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant has met the requirements of subsection (b) of this section and in addition has worked as a journeyman electrician for at least 4 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
