<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2762"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2762/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2762">
        <akn:num>47-2762</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Ballpark fee.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2762_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2762_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount of the ballpark fee shall be computed according to the following schedule:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2762_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On or before December 1 of each year, the Chief Financial Officer shall certify to the Council the amount of revenue received by the District from imposition of the ballpark fee during the immediately preceding fiscal year and provide an estimate of the amount of revenue expected to be received from the ballpark fee in the then current fiscal year. If the amount estimated to be collected is less than $14 million plus any amount necessary to replenish any reserve funds in accordance with the financing documents and to avoid any projected shortfall in debt service on the bonds, the Chief Financial Officer shall compute the amount of the ballpark fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section needed to provide estimated revenue in the current fiscal year equal to $14 million plus any amount necessary to replenish any reserve funds in accordance with the financing documents and to avoid any projected shortfall in debt service on the bonds, by applying the same percentage increase to each amount of the then-current ballpark fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section. The Chief Financial Officer shall notify the Council, the Mayor, and the feepayers of the new schedule and, upon such notice, the amount of the ballpark fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section shall be increased as of October 1 of the current fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2762_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The revenues received by the District from the ballpark fee imposed by this section shall be deposited into the Ballpark Revenue Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2762_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except in the case of street vendors described in § 47-2002.01, the Chief Financial Officer may require taxpayers subject to the sales taxes and fees imposed by §§ 47-2002.05 and 47-2762 and all sales taxes described in [§ 2-1217.12], to make payments of those taxes electronically.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2762_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer or his delegate shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
