<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2851.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2851.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2851_13">
        <akn:num>47-2851.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Basic Business License Fund; disposition of license fees, penalties, and fines.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2851_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established the Basic Business License Fund (“Fund”) which shall be classified as a proprietary fund and a type of enterprise fund for the purposes of § 47-373(1). The Fund shall be credited with all fees that are identified in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2851_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All fees collected for the issuance of a basic business license and endorsements, including renewals, late renewal penalties, other penalties, and fines, shall be deposited in the Fund. Half of the total amount of penalties and fines collected as a result of notices of infractions issued for basic business license violations shall also be deposited in the Fund. The entire cost of the basic business licensing system shall be paid from the Fund and no other appropriated funds shall be used for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2851_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Revenue credited  to the Fund shall be expended by the Department as designated by an appropriations act of Congress, for the purposes of maintaining and upgrading the basic business licensing system, including copying fees, automation upgrades, personnel costs, and supplies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2851_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
