<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2827"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2827/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2827">
        <akn:num>47-2827</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Commission merchants in food; bakeries; bottling, candy-manufacturing, and ice cream manufacturers; groceries; markets; delicatessens; restaurants; private clubs; wholesale fish dealers; dairies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Commission merchants dealing in food or food products shall pay a license fee of $645 per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners or managers of delicatessens, ice cream parlors, soda fountains, or soft drink establishments shall pay a license fee of $133 per annum; provided, that if any licensee hereunder shall conduct upon the same premises more than 1 of the callings herein listed, or listed in subsection (b) of this section, no additional fee shall be required.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners or managers of ice cream manufacturing establishments shall pay a license fee of $1,050 per annum; provided, that if any licensee hereunder shall conduct upon the same premises more than 1 of the callings listed in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, no additional fee shall be required.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wholesale dealers in fish or other marine products shall pay a license fee of $429 per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners or managers of dairies shall pay a license fee of $3,300 per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All dealers in food or food products not listed herein, or elsewhere in this chapter shall pay a license fee of $111 per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Licenses for Candy Manufacturers, Commercial Merchant Food, Ice Cream Manufacturers, Marine Product suppliers, and other wholesale food establishments shall be issued under the master business license system as a Food Establishments: Wholesale endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Licenses for Bakeries, Delicatessens, Food Product suppliers, Groceries, Supermarkets, and other retail food establishments shall be issued under the master business license system as a Food Establishments: Retail endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2827_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may adjust, by rule, the fees established by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
