<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2839"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2839/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2839">
        <akn:num>47-2839</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Private detectives; “detective” defined; regulations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Private detectives, or detective agencies, by whatsoever name called, shall pay a license tax of $158 per annum; provided, that no license shall be issued under this section without the approval of the Chief of Police.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of this section, the term “detective” or “detective agency” means and includes any person, firm, or corporation engaged in the business of, or advertising, or representing himself, or itself, as being engaged in the business of detecting, discovering, or revealing crime or criminals, or securing information for evidence relating thereto, or discovering or revealing the identity, whereabouts, character, or actions of any person or persons, thing or things.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful for any person to engage in the business of detective, or operate, manage, or conduct a detective agency, for profit or gain, or to advertise or represent his business to be that of a detective, or that of conducting, managing, or operating a detective agency, without first obtaining a license so to do.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered to make such reasonable regulations as it deems advisable for the government and conduct of the business of private detectives licensed hereunder, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and empowered to revoke the license of a private detective when in his judgment such is deemed advisable in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All laws which govern the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia in the matters of persons, property, or money shall be applicable to all private detectives licensed hereunder, and such detectives shall make like returns and dispositions of such matters as is required by existing law and the rules of the Mayor of the District of Columbia governing the Metropolitan Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a Public Safety endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2839_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All license fees collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the Occupations and Professions Licensing Special Account established pursuant to § 47-2853.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
