<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2886.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-2886.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_2886_08">
        <akn:num>47-2886.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Board of Registration for Professional Engineers—Powers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To investigate and to approve those institutions that provide and maintain satisfactory standards for the education of students desiring to engage in the practice of engineering;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To provide for and to regulate the certification and to certify as an engineer-in-training any person of good character and repute who is a citizen of the United States, at least 18 years of age or has graduated from an institution, and who speaks and writes the English language, if such person:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To register as a professional engineer any person who is not a citizen of the United States, who is of good character and repute, at least 25 years of age, and speaks and writes the English language, if such person submits evidence, of a grade and character satisfactory to the Board, that he is an engineer of established and recognized standing in the profession of engineering in his own country, and who submits certification as to character and qualifications from at least 2 professional engineers of the District of Columbia. Such registration shall entitle the holder to engage in the practice of engineering only for the duration of and in connection with a specific project for which it was granted, and shall be subject to annual renewal and to suspension or revocation as registration granted as otherwise provided in this part. Engineers to whom such temporary registration has been granted shall be separately listed in the roster;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To require all candidates for registration as professional engineers to file with the Secretary-Treasurer of the Board a written application on a prescribed form and accompanied by the required fee. Such application shall contain statements made under oath, showing the applicant’s education, detailed summary of his experience in engineering work, and the general field or fields of engineering in which he has his principal activity, and shall contain not less than 5 references, of whom 3 or more shall be engineers having personal knowledge of his engineering training and experience;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To investigate the allegations contained in any application for registration as a professional engineer in order to determine the truth of such allegations, and to determine the competency of any person applying for a registration to assume responsible charge of the work involved in the practice of engineering, such competency to be determined by the grade and character of the engineering work actually performed. Any person having the necessary qualifications prescribed in this part to entitle him to registration or certification shall be eligible therefor, although he may not be practicing his profession at the time of making his application. Evaluation of experience in engineering shall be based upon the applicant’s knowledge of the fundamental engineering subjects, which shall be broad in scope and of a nature to develop and mature the applicant’s engineering knowledge and judgment. In considering the qualifications of an applicant who has graduated in engineering from an approved institution, each year, but not exceeding 2 years, of successful postgraduate study in engineering, and each scholastic year, in excess of 4, of an approved 5- or 6-year engineering curriculum, and each year of teaching engineering subjects, in an approved institution, may be considered as equivalent to 1 year of experience in engineering. In considering the qualifications of an applicant who is an undergraduate in engineering, or who has graduated in a curriculum other than engineering, from an approved institution, each equivalent year of approved engineering education, as determined by evaluation by the Board of the educational records submitted, may be considered as equivalent to 2 years of combined education and experience in engineering. Experience in engineering gained under the supervision of a professional engineer or similarly qualified engineer, and experience in engineering gained subsequent to the attaining of an equivalent to the minimum requirements for certification as an engineer-in-training, of a grade and character satisfactory to the Board, shall be given full credit. In any case when the evidence presented in the application does not appear to the Board conclusive nor warranting the issuance of a certificate of registration or a certificate as engineer-in-training without examination, the applicant may be required to present further evidence for the consideration of the Board, and may also be required to pass an oral or written examination, or both, as the Board may determine. Whenever the Board determines otherwise than by examination that an applicant has not produced sufficient evidence to show that he is competent to assume responsible charge of the work involved in the practice of engineering, and shall refuse to examine or to register such applicant, it shall set forth in writing its findings and the reasons for its conclusions, and furnish a copy thereof to the applicant;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To prescribe the scope, manner, time, and place for the examination of applicants for registration as professional engineers, to provide for the conduct of and to conduct such examinations, and to make written reports of such examinations. The prescribed examinations shall be written, or written and oral, and designed to permit an applicant for registration as a professional engineer to take the examination in 2 stages. The 1st stage of the examination shall be designed to test the applicant’s knowledge of fundamental engineering subjects, including mathematics, physical and applied sciences, properties of materials, and the principles of engineering design. Satisfactory passing of this portion of the examination shall constitute a credit for the life of the applicant or until he is registered as a professional engineer. The 2nd stage of the examination shall be designed to test the applicant’s ability to apply the principles of engineering to the actual practice of engineering in the field of engineering in which he has indicated his principal activity. An applicant failing to pass an examination may apply for reexamination at the expiration of 6 months and will be reexamined upon payment of the prescribed fee;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To issue a certificate of registration and a pocket registration card to each professional engineer granted registration under the provisions of this part. The certificate of registration shall authorize the registrant to practice as a professional engineer, show the full name of the registrant, have a serial number, and be signed by the members of the Board under the seal of the Board. The pocket registration card issued with the certificate shall show the full name and registration number of the registrant, state that the person named therein has been granted registration to practice as a professional engineer for the period ending on the 31st day of October in the 2nd year of the then current biennial registration renewal period, and be signed by the Chairman and Secretary-Treasurer of the Board; to provide for and regulate the renewal of registration of professional engineers registered under this part. On or before the 1st day of August 1952, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary-Treasurer of the Board shall mail to every professional engineer registered under this part a blank application for biennial renewal of registration, addressing such application to the last-known post-office address. Upon receipt of such application blank, a registrant shall execute and return the application for his biennial registration renewal card to the Board together with the biennial registration renewal fee of $2. Upon receipt of such application and renewal fee the Board shall issue a pocket registration renewal card which shall show the full name and registration number of the registrant, be signed by the Chairman and Secretary-Treasurer of the Board, and state that the person named therein has been granted registration to practice as a professional engineer for the period beginning November 1st in the year of issue and expiring on the 31st day of October in the 2nd year following. Application shall be made biennially on or before the 1st day of November and if not so made an additional fee of $1 for each 30 days delay beyond the 1st day of November, and up to the 1st day of March following shall be added to the current biennial registration renewal fee to be paid upon renewal; to issue a duplicate certificate of registration to replace a certificate lost, destroyed, or mutilated, subject to the rules of the Board, and upon payment of the prescribed fee. The issuance of a certificate of registration by the Board shall be presumptive evidence in all courts and places that the person named therein is entitled to all the rights and privileges of a registered professional engineer while said certificate remains unsuspended, unrevoked, or unexpired;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To issue a special certificate of registration and pocket registration card to every noncitizen professional engineer granted registration under the provisions of this part. The special certificate of registration shall authorize the registrant to practice as a professional engineer in connection with a specific project, show the full name of the registrant, have a registration number, and be signed by the members of the Board under the seal of the Board. The special pocket registration card issued with such certificate shall show the full name and registration number of the registrant, state that the person named therein has been granted temporary registration to practice as a professional engineer, state the specific project in connection with which the special registration is granted, the period for which it is granted, not to exceed 1 year from the date of issue, and be signed by the Chairman and Secretary-Treasurer of the Board. Temporary registration may be renewed at the discretion of the Board for periods not in excess of 1 year upon application therefor and payment of the annual renewal fee;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To prescribe and to issue a certificate, attested by its seal and signed by the members of the Board, to any applicant who in the opinion of the Board has satisfactorily met all the requirements of this part for certification as an engineer-in-training;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To keep a roster of all professional engineers registered under this part, showing the registrant’s name, place of business or employment, registration number, and the general field or fields of engineering in which registrant qualified to practice, and a roster of engineers-in-training certified under this part. These rosters, together with other information deemed to be of interest to the engineering profession, shall be published in booklet form by the Board on the 1st day of March of each even year, beginning with 1952, or as soon thereafter as practicable. The Board shall also, upon the 1st day of March of each odd year, beginning with 1953, or as soon thereafter as practicable, publish a supplemental roster of all registered professional engineers and certified engineers-in-training. Such published rosters shall contain at the beginning thereof the words: “Each professional engineer receiving this roster is requested to report to the Board the names and addresses of any persons known to be engaged in the practice of engineering in the District of Columbia whose names do not appear in this roster. The names of persons giving such information shall not be divulged.” Copies of these rosters shall be mailed or otherwise sent to each registered professional engineer and engineer-in-training and be furnished to other persons upon request;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To adopt and have an official seal, and to keep minutes and records of all its transactions and proceedings, and a complete record of the credentials of each applicant and registrant. A transcript of an entry in such minutes and records, certified by the Secretary-Treasurer under the seal of the Board, shall be prima facie evidence of the original entry in such minutes and records;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To become a member of the National Council of State Boards of Engineering Examiners and to pay such dues as said Council shall establish, and to send a delegate to the annual meeting of said Council and to defray his reasonable and necessary expenses;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To adopt, amend, rescind, promulgate, and enforce such administrative rules and regulations not inconsistent with this part, as are deemed necessary and proper by the Board to carry into effect the powers conferred by this part. To employ such clerical or other assistants as are necessary for the proper performance of its duties. The regular annual employees of the Board shall, for the purpose of laws relating to compensation, classification, retirement, and leave, be employees of the District of Columbia;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To enforce the provisions of this part, to investigate for unauthorized and unlawful practice, to employ such persons as it may deem necessary to assist in the investigations and prosecutions incident to enforcement, to require the attendance of witnesses and the production of books and papers, and to require such witnesses to testify as to any and all matters within its jurisdiction. The Chairman and Secretary-Treasurer of the Board shall have power to issue subpoenas, and each shall have authority to administer oaths. Upon the failure of any person to attend as a witness, when duly subpoenaed, or to produce documents when duly directed by said Board, the Board shall have power to refer the said matter to any justice of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, who may order the attendance of such witness, or the production of such documents, or require the said witness to testify, as the case may be, and upon the failure of the witness to attend, to testify, or to produce such documents, as the case may be, such witness may be punished for contempt of court as for failure to obey a subpoena issued or to testify in a case pending before said Court. Witnesses who have been subpoenaed by the Board, and who testify if called upon, shall be paid the same fees that are paid witnesses in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To refuse to issue a certificate to any person, or to suspend or revoke the certificate of registration of any professional engineer or the certification of any engineer-in-training issued hereunder if such person:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-2886_08_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To reconsider the application of any person whose application has been refused or to reissue a certificate of registration to any professional engineer or a certification to any engineer-in-training whose certificate has been revoked for reasons the Board deems sufficient, upon payment of the prescribed fee for such reissuance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
