<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-368.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-368.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_368_01">
        <akn:num>47-368.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of dedicated funds to the General Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-368_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “Other-Type Funds” means District revenues, as defined in § 1-201.03(10), generated from fees, fines, assessments, or reimbursements by District of Columbia or its agencies or instrumentalities (including independent agencies or instrumentalities), earmarked for special purposes and accounted for or placed in a fund for such purposes; provided, that the term “Other-Type Funds” shall not include funds of the Housing Finance Agency; National Capital Revitalization Corporation; Washington Convention and Sports Authority; Public Service Commission; Office of People’s Counsel; Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation; Department of Banking and Financial Institutions; District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority; and Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration; and Compliance and Real Property Tax Administration Fund, except to the extent that there are not sufficient Other-Type Funds available in other agencies from which the transfer of funds requested under subsection (c) of this section may be obtained.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-368_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the dedication of funds to a particular use, all or part of the balance in an Other-Type Fund may be transferred to the General Fund of the District of Columbia in accordance with the procedure set forth in subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-368_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-368_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in fiscal year 2005, the Chief Financial Officer shall submit to the Council a quarterly audit and accounting of the spending, revenue generation, and balances for all Other-Type Fund dedicated for use by the Department of Health. If the information for such an Other-Type Fund is not submitted to the Council within one month after the end of a fiscal quarter, revenue that accumulated in the Other-Type Fund during the fiscal quarter may not be transferred to the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
