<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-391.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-391.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_391_01">
        <akn:num>47-391.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establishment. — Pursuant to Article I, section 8, clause 17 of the Constitution of the United States, there is hereby established the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority, consisting of members appointed by the President in accordance with subsection (b) of this section. Subject to the conditions described in § 47-391.08 and except as otherwise provided in this Act, the Authority is established as an entity within the government of the District of Columbia, and is not established as a department, agency, establishment, or instrumentality of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Membership. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Qualifications for membership. — An individual meets the qualifications for membership on the Authority if the individual:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No compensation for service. — Members of the Authority shall serve without pay, but may receive reimbursement for any reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by reason of service on the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Adoption of by-laws for conducting business of Authority. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
