<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-361"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-361/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_361">
        <akn:num>47-361</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agency” means the highest organizational unit of the District of Columbia government at which budgeting data is aggregated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agency funding source” means the designated resource or fund to which expenditures shall be charged.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Budget” means the entire annual appropriation, including borrowing and spending authority, for all activities of all agencies of the District of Columbia government financed from all existing, proposed, or anticipated resources.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Budget category” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital budget” means that part of the budget that describes the annual element of the multiyear capital improvements plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital project” shall have the same meaning as provided in [§  1-201.03(8)].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Highway Trust Fund” means the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, established by [§ 9-111.01], and the Federal Highway Trust Fund, established pursuant to Title 23 of the United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intra-District transfer” means a budget modification that involves the movement of $50,000 or more in funds from one agency to another agency for the same purpose for which the funds were appropriated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Object category” means the 2 major types of expenditures, which are personal services and non-personal services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Object class” means the subdivision of specific types of expenditures in the operating budget, such as fringe benefits and supplies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Offsetting” means an increase that is matched by a decrease with no change occurring in budget authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Operating budget” means that part of the budget for the operation of the District government, excluding the capital budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Program” means the highest level of budgeting and expenditure control within an agency that is designated for a specific purpose in the operating budget, which may consist of multiple actions necessary to achieve the stated purpose and goals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-361_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reprogramming” means a budget modification of $500,000 or more for purposes other than those originally authorized that results in an offsetting reallocation of budget authority from one budget category to another budget category; provided, that with respect to a capital reprogramming, the term “reprogramming” means a cumulative adjustment to a project’s capital budget during a fiscal year of $500,000 or more.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
