<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-391.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-391.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_391_03">
        <akn:num>47-391.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers of Authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Hearings and sessions. — The Authority may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Authority considers appropriate. The Authority may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before it.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Powers of members and agents. — Any member or agent of the Authority may, if authorized by the Authority, take any action which the Authority is authorized to take by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Obtaining official data. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Gifts, bequests, and devises. — The Authority may accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of services or property, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Authority. Gifts, bequests, or devises of money and proceeds from sales of other property received as gifts, bequests, or devises shall be deposited in such account as the Authority may establish and shall be available for disbursement upon order of the Chair.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subpoena power. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Administrative support services. — Upon the request of the Authority, the Administrator of General Services shall promptly provide to the Authority, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Authority to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Authority to enter into contracts. — The Executive Director may enter into such contracts as the Executive Director considers appropriate (subject to the approval of the Chair) to carry out the Authority’s responsibilities under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Civil actions to enforce powers. — The Authority may seek judicial enforcement of its authority to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Penalties. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
