<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-340.29"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-340.29/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_340_29">
        <akn:num>47-340.29</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond details.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer may take any action reasonably necessary or appropriate in accordance with this subchapter in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, security for, and payment of the bonds of each series, including, determinations of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor, and attested by the Secretary of the District of Columbia by the Secretary’s manual or facsimile signature.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds of any series may be issued in accordance with the terms of a trust instrument to be entered into by the District and the trustee, and may be subject to the terms of one or more agreements entered into by the Mayor, through the Chief Financial Officer, pursuant to § 1-204.90.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time in one or more issues and in one or more series.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The bonds, the interest thereon, and the income therefrom shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District irrevocably pledges for and on behalf of the owners of the bonds as further security for the due and punctual payment of the principal and redemption price, if any, and interest on, the bonds as they shall become due and payable for any reason, all of its right, title, and interest now owned or later acquired in and to the Available Tax Revenues, whether received or to be received, or held at the time, by a Collection Agent, custodian, escrow agent, or District officials. This pledge creates and grants a security interest as contemplated in § 1-204.90, subject to the terms, conditions, and limitations in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-340_29_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consistent with § 1-204.90(a)(4)(B) and notwithstanding Article 9 of Title 28:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
