<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-381"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-381/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_381">
        <akn:num>47-381</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Findings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That there exists a public perception that the District budget approved by the Council, after considerable careful public examination, is the plan which determines the manner in which District funds will be spent;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the District’s new financial management system, which became operative in fiscal year 1980, provides the Council a new level of budget information;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That questions remain in regard to the role of the Council with respect to ongoing oversight and control of the District budget;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That a large portion of the District’s annual expenditures are funded by grants from the federal government and private sources. Although these grant funds are a major portion of the District’s program process, to a great extent, planning and allocation of these funds are without public participation through the legislative process;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That under the District’s new financial management system, the Council will be excluded from approval or review of federal grant funds to District agencies;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That the District does not have a legislative process to address and control all city expenditures from all revenue sources; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-381_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>That there is a need to clearly define the continuing role of the Council in the budget process in order to resolve those questions critical to the shaping of public policy and the prudent management of publicly entrusted tax dollars.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
