<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-351.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-351.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_351_08">
        <akn:num>47-351.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Collateral and reporting requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except for securities directly purchased without a repurchase agreement and money market funds, an eligible financial institution must at all times provide collateral equal to at least 102% of the District funds held by the eligible financial institution for deposits and investments that are not fully federally insured.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may accept as collateral any combination of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may at any time classify the use of a particular type of collateral as ineligible.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may at any time require that collateral exceed 102% of the District funds held for deposit or investment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), shall require the eligible financial institution to place required collateral in a joint custody account established for the benefit of the District at the Federal Reserve Bank under procedures of the Federal Reserve Bank, or in an independent third-party insured institution. Collateral for investments may be placed at a third-party insured institution customer account in a Federal Reserve Bank with the approval of the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon written approval of the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), an eligible financial institution may substitute collateral of greater or equivalent value from the various types listed in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An eligible financial institution may not withdraw collateral previously pledged without the prior approval of the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An eligible financial institution shall submit to the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), monthly verified reports that list all segregated collateral for District funds and its market value. The report shall also include the average daily balance of the amount of District funds on deposit or invested for the previous month. An insured institution shall submit copies of its quarterly call reports within 45 days after each fiscal quarter. A noninsured institution shall submit its Form 10K or annual financial statements within 60 days after each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
