<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-392.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-392.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_392_02">
        <akn:num>47-392.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Process for submission and approval of financial plan and annual District budget.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Submission of preliminary financial plan and budget by Mayor. — Not later than the February 1 preceding a fiscal year for which the District government is in a control period, the Mayor shall submit to the Authority and the Council a financial plan and budget for the fiscal year which meets the requirements of § 47-392.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Review by authority. — Upon receipt of the financial plan and budget for a fiscal year from the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section, the Authority shall promptly review the financial plan and budget. In conducting the review, the Authority may request any additional information it considers necessary and appropriate to carry out its duties under this part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Action upon approval of Mayor’s preliminary financial plan and budget. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Action upon disapproval of Mayor’s preliminary financial plan and budget. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Revisions to financial plan and budget. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Requirements for a Pay-as-you-go Capital Account. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Omitted]</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Omitted]</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Expedited submission and approval of consensus budget and financial plan. — Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the Mayor, the Council, and the Authority jointly develop a financial plan and budget for the fiscal year which meets the requirements applicable under § 47-392.01 and which the Mayor, Council, and Authority certify reflects a consensus among them:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reserve funds. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_j_1">
      <akn:num>(j-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_j_2">
      <akn:num>(j-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Cash Flow Reserve Account. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_j_3">
      <akn:num>(j-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Fund Balance Deposit Requirements. — If either of the Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account or the Cash Flow Reserve Account are below full funding, as specified in, respectively, subsections (j-1) and (j-2) of this section, immediately upon issue of the Comprehensive Annual Financial Report, the Chief Financial Officer shall deposit 50% of the undesignated end-of-year fund balance into each account, or 100% of the end-of-year fund balance into the remaining account that has not reached capacity, to fully fund these accounts to the extent that the undesignated end-of-year fund balance allows.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_j_4">
      <akn:num>(j-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Increase in Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account]. — If amounts required for the Emergency Cash Reserve Fund or the Contingency Reserve Fund pursuant to § 1-204.50a are reduced, the amount required to be deposited in Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account shall be increased by a like amount.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Positive fund balance. — [Repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_02_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[DC Streetcar and Integrated Premium Transit System defined]. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
