<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-308.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-308.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_308_01">
        <akn:num>47-308.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Performance-based budget.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning with the District of Columbia’s Fiscal Year 2004 budget and financial plan, any agency that has converted to a performance-based budget shall continue presenting its budget in such format, unless the Chief Financial Officer considers it appropriate to present an agency’s budget in a different format.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in Fiscal Year 2004 and continuing in subsequent fiscal years until all applicable agencies funded by the General Fund within the District of Columbia’s budget and financial plan are submitting performance-based budgets, the Mayor shall identify by executive order, no later than July 10, at least 15 additional agencies to submit performance-based budgets the following fiscal year. For the Fiscal Year 2006 budget and financial plan, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a performance-based budget for every operating agency in the District of Columbia, unless the Chief Financial Officer considers it inappropriate to do so.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in fiscal year 2006 and phasing in through fiscal year 2009 by appropriation title beginning with Public Safety and Justice and Public Works in fiscal year 2006, Governmental Direction and Support in fiscal year 2007, Public Education Systems and Economic Development and Regulation in fiscal year 2008, and Human Support Services and all other remaining agencies in fiscal year 2009, the Chief Financial Officer shall provide service level budgets for any operating agency where services are a part of an activity that has a minimum threshold of $5 million from the prior fiscal year’s appropriation or provides services determined by the Mayor or the Council to be a priority for the District of Columbia. By no later than August 15 of each year, beginning in fiscal year 2006 and continuing in subsequent fiscal years, the Chief Financial Officer shall provide to the Mayor and the Council a list of service costs for activities that have a minimum threshold of $10 million from the prior fiscal year’s appropriation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in Fiscal Year 2005 and continuing in subsequent fiscal years, the Office of Budget and Planning, in consultation with the Office of the City Administrator, shall identify 25 critical programs to benchmark with comparable jurisdictions and shall include those benchmarks in the budget and financial plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of Budget and Planning shall review all agency program expenditures, including program definitions, estimated program costs, program performance measures, and agency benchmarks, which expenditures shall be included in the District of Columbia’s budget and financial plan. For the Fiscal Year 2006 budget, no operating agency budget shall be forwarded to the Mayor for approval without the Office of Budget and Planning’s determination that it is a performance-based budget, except those agencies for which the Chief Financial Officer considers such a budget to be inappropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-308_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
