<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-351.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-351.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_351_09">
        <akn:num>47-351.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Linked deposits for community development lending.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may make a deposit in an insured financial institution in return for a commitment by that institution to make specific community development loans in a low-to-moderate income area. The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), shall determine the amount and scope of community development loans required to qualify for such linked deposits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When making a linked deposit, the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may accept a below-market interest rate that is within 3% of the market rate interest if the insured financial institution provides an equivalent reduction in the interest rate charged for the community development lending to which the deposit is linked.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may make deposits linked to either specific loans or loan types.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An insured financial institution may submit to the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), a linked deposit application that includes information about the proposed community development lending and any other information the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), requires.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), approves a linked deposit application, the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), and the insured financial institution shall enter into an agreement that includes each of the following terms and conditions and any others the Mayor, or the CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), may require:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The total amount of linked deposits and community development program deposits shall not exceed 7% of the average annual investment balance of the latest audited fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
