<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-355.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-355.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_355_05">
        <akn:num>47-355.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reporting requirements of the Chief Financial Officer and Agency Fiscal Officers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-355_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall submit reports to the Council and the Mayor on a quarterly basis indicating each agency’s actual expenditures, obligations, and commitments, each by source of funds, compared to their approved spending plan. This report shall be accompanied by the CFO’s observations regarding spending patterns and steps being taken to assure spending remains within the approved budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-355_05_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each Agency Financial Officer (“AGO”) shall submit quarterly reports to the Chairperson of the Council committee that has purview over the AGO’s agency. Each report shall include the agency’s actual expenditures, obligations, and commitments, organized by source of funds, and compared to their approved spending plan. The report shall be accompanied by the AGO’s analysis of spending patterns and of the steps taken to assure that spending remains within the approved budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-355_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall be required to develop the quarterly apportionment of funds, by source of funds, for each agency based on the spending plans submitted by agency heads and agency fiscal officers. The apportionment shall be binding on agencies unless otherwise modified by the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-355_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall determine when each agency will transition to the quarterly apportionment of funds, so long as all agencies transition to quarterly apportionment within 3 years of [April 4, 2003].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-355_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section is intended to interfere with the exclusive authority and discretion of the District of Columbia Retirement Board to manage and control retirement funds pursuant to [Chapter 7 of Title 1].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-355_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
