<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-3401.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-3401.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_3401_02">
        <akn:num>47-3401.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Short-term advances for seasonal cash-flow management.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In general. — If the conditions in subsection (b) of this section are satisfied, the Secretary shall make an advance of funds from time to time, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the purpose of assisting the District government in meeting its general expenditures, as authorized by Congress, at times of seasonal cash-flow deficiencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Conditions to making any short-term advance. — The Secretary shall make an advance under this section if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Amount of any short-term advance. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Maturity of any short-term advance. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Interest rate. — Each advance made under this section shall bear interest at an annual rate equal to a rate determined by the Secretary at the time that the Secretary makes such advance taking into consideration the prevailing yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the maturity of such advance, plus 1/8 of 1%.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Ten-business-day zero balance requirement. — After the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the first advance is made under this section, the Secretary shall not make any new advance under this section unless the District government has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-3401_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Deposit of advances. — As provided in § 47-392.04(b), advances made under this section for the account of the District government shall be deposited by the Secretary into an escrow account held by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
