<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-351.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-351.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_351_01">
        <akn:num>47-351.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bank” means an insured financial institution as defined in section 2 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, approved September 21, 1950 (64 Stat. 873; 12 U.S.C. § 1813), which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Banking business” means the deposit or investment of District funds or the use of District funds for the provision of financial services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Collateralized mortgage obligations” shall mean securities issued by a government or quasi-governmental agency and backed by a pool of underlying home mortgages packaged and sold in the secondary market.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community Reinvestment Act” means the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977, approved October 12, 1977 (91 Stat. 1147; 12 U.S.C. §§ 2901-2907).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Compensating balances” means collected balances held by the depository to compensate the depository for the cost of financial services rendered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Credit union” means an institution insured by the National Credit Union Administration, and either serving designated geographical areas within the District of Columbia or serving the employees of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Deposit” means District funds which are held by a financial institution subject to withdrawal upon demand by the District or upon a check or warrant of the District or the act of entrusting District funds into a financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the government of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District funds” means money, currency, notes, or drafts belonging to or under the control of the District, including, but not limited to, the federal payment, federal grants, taxes, fees, special assessments, all other funds received from the federal government, and funds paid to or received by a board, agency, commission, institution, committee, or office of the District or from any other source. This does not include any assets of a pension, assets held by the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority, an employee deferred compensation program of the District, or an irrevocable trust established pursuant to § 1-626.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible financial institution” means any bank or any brokerage firm registered with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission (“SEC”) or any savings and loan association, savings bank, credit union, or any subsidiary or affiliate thereof meeting the requirements to become eligible to submit a bid pursuant to § 47-351.04.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial services” means those services performed by a financial institution in connection with the retention of deposits, including check payment, check clearing, reconciliation of accounts, check printing, the collection and transfer of taxes and fees, night depository services, custodial services, and other services that may be necessary for the efficient management of District funds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home Mortgage Disclosure Act” means the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975, approved December 31, 1975 (89 Stat. 1124; 12 U.S.C. § 2801 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insured financial institution” or “insured institution” means a bank, savings and loan association, savings bank, credit union, or any subsidiary or affiliate thereof.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Invest” means to commit District funds in order to gain profit or interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment” means property acquired with District funds for future profit or interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment grade obligation” means securities that have a minimum rating of BBB, Baa, or BBB- from Standard and Poor’s, Moody’s Investor Service, or Fitch Investor Service rating agencies that rate the securities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Linked deposit” means limited deposits in an insured financial institution made pursuant to an authorization from the Mayor, or CFO pursuant to § 47-351.02(c), to waive the competitive bidding requirements of the act in order to make a deposit in return for that institution’s commitment to make community development loans in low-to-moderate income areas.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low-to-moderate income area” means a census tract in which more than 50% of the households have a median household income of less than 100% of the District’s median household income based on the most recent decennial census.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mortgage loan” means a loan that is secured by residential real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Noninsured financial institution” means an investment advisor, investment banker, investment company, investment trust, or any other company, subsidiary, or affiliate thereof designated by the Mayor, or the CFO during a control year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Quasi-governmental corporation” means United States government-sponsored enterprises that issue investment-grade obligations. This includes, but is not limited to, banks for cooperatives, federal land banks, federal intermediate credit banks, federal farm credit banks, federal home loan banks, the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, the Tennessee Valley District, the Small Business Administration, or any such agency or enterprise that may be created.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Savings and loan association” means an institution organized as a savings and loan association under the laws of the United States, a state, or the District, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Savings bank” means an institution organized as a savings bank under the laws of the United States, a state, or the District, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-351_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Small business” means a business with annual gross sales or revenues of $5 million or less.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
