<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-392.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-392.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_392_06">
        <akn:num>47-392.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Effect of finding of non-compliance with financial plan and budget.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Submission of reports. — Not later than 30 days after the expiration of each quarter of each fiscal year (beginning with Fiscal Year 1996), the Mayor shall submit reports to the Authority describing the actual revenues obtained and expenditures made by the District government during the quarter with its cash flows during the quarter, and comparing such actual revenues, expenditures, and cash flows with the most recent projections for these items.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Demand for additional information. — If the Authority determines, based on reports submitted by the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section, independent audits, or such other information as the Authority may obtain, that the revenues or expenditures of the District government during a control year are not consistent with the financial plan and budget for the year, the Authority shall require the Mayor to provide such additional information as the Authority determines to be necessary to explain the inconsistency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Certification of variance. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-392_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effect of certification. — If the Authority certifies to the Secretary of the Treasury that a variance exists:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
