<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-391.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-391.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_391_09">
        <akn:num>47-391.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Chief Management Officer.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may employ a Chief Management Officer of the District of Columbia, who shall be appointed by the Chair with the consent of the Authority. The Chief Management Officer shall assist the Authority in the fulfillment of its responsibilities under the District of Columbia Management Reform Act of 1997, subtitle B of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, title XI of Public Law 105-33, to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the District of Columbia Government. The Authority may delegate to the Chief Management Officer responsibility for oversight and supervision of departments and functions of the District of Columbia Government, or successor departments and functions, consistent with the District of Columbia Management Reform Act of 1997, subtitle B of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, title XI of Public Law 105-33. The Chief Management Officer shall report directly to the Authority, through the Chair of the Authority, and shall be directed in his or her performance by a majority of the Authority. The Chief Management Officer shall be paid at an annual rate determined by the Authority sufficient in the judgment of the Authority to obtain the services of an individual with the skills and experience required to discharge the duties of the office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-391_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Employment contract. — Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the employment agreement entered into as of January 15, 1998, between the Chief Management Officer and the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority shall be valid in all respects.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
