<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-318"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-318/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_318">
        <akn:num>47-318</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-318_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Budget gap” means the difference between estimated expenditures and estimated revenues.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-318_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Budget modification” means a reexamination of all major elements of the current year budget, and shall contain for the current year budget all elements of the multiyear plan listed in paragraph (4) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-318_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gap-closing action” means any action designed to eliminate the budget gap. Gap-closing actions include increases in current revenue bases and rates; new taxes, fees, charges, fines, and penalties; expenditure reductions associated with lower service levels; and productivity improvements that yield expenditure reductions without a decrease in service levels. Gap-closing actions must be proposed in the fiscal year prior to their implementation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-318_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Multiyear plan” means the costs and funding of services in the District over a 4-year period and shall be based on the actual experience of the immediately preceding 3 fiscal years, on the approved current fiscal year budget, and on estimates for at least the 4 succeeding fiscal years. Pursuant to § 1-204.43, the multiyear plan shall include provisions identifying:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-318_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Multiyear plan modification” means a reexamination of all major elements of the multiyear plan, and shall contain all elements of the multiyear plan listed in paragraph (4) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-318_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tax expenditures” means the revenue losses attributable to provisions of federal law and the laws of the District of Columbia that allow, in whole or in part, a special exclusion, exemption, or deduction from taxes authorized in this title, or which provide a special credit, a preferential rate of tax, or a deferral of tax liability.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
