<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4641"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4641/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4641">
        <akn:num>47-4641</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Allen Chapel A.M.E. Senior Residential Rental Project; Lots 0024, 0025, 0026, 0038, 0214, 0215, 0218, 0923, 0924, and 0925, Square 5730.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4641_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The real property described as Lots 0024, 0025, 0026, 0038, 0214, 0215, 0923, 0924, and 0925, Square 5730, owned by Allen Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Allen Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church, Inc., shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title as long as the real property is owned by Allen Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church, Inc., or by an entity controlled, directly or indirectly, by Allen Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church, Inc., and not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4641_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The real property described as Lot 0218, Square 5730, including any improvements on the property, which was consolidated from portions of Lots 0038, 0923, and 0924, Square 5730 and which has been transferred from Allen Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church, Inc., to the Alabama Ave. Affordable Housing, L.P., shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title so long as the real property is used as an affordable rental housing project and is not used for commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4641_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The exemption provided in subsection (b) of this section shall run with Lot 0218, Square 5730 and shall apply to any subsequent owner or assignee or successor in interest of the Alabama Ave. Affordable Housing, L.P.; provided, that the property is used as an affordable rental housing project and is not used for commercial purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4641_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
