<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4506"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4506/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4506">
        <akn:num>47-4506</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Implementation of the Program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall implement the Program through use of one or more financial organizations as account depositories and managers. Under the Program, individuals may establish accounts directly with an account depository.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall solicit proposals from financial organizations to act as account depositories or managers of the Program. The Chief Financial Officer shall promulgate regulations that establish a procedure to, from time to time, review the method by which financial organizations are selected. Financial organizations submitting proposals shall describe the investment instrument which will be used in accounts. The Chief Financial Officer may select as account depositories or managers one or more financial organizations that demonstrate the most advantageous combination, both to potential program participants and the District of Columbia, from among the following factors:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A management contract shall include terms requiring the financial organization to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer may provide that an audit may be conducted of the operations and financial positions of the program depository or manager at any time if the Chief Financial Officer has reason to be concerned about the financial position, the recordkeeping practices, or the status of accounts of the program depository and manager.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During the term of a contract with a program manager, the Chief Financial Officer shall conduct an examination of the manager and its handling of accounts. The examination shall be conducted at least biennially if the manager is not otherwise subject to periodic examination by the Mayor, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or other similar entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If selection of a financial organization as a program manager or depository is not renewed, after the end of its term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Chief Financial Officer terminates a financial organization as a program manager or depository, the Chief Financial Officer shall cause the accounts to be transferred to another financial organization that is selected as a program manager or depository and into investment instruments as similar to the original instruments as possible.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4506_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
