<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4616"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4616/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4616">
        <akn:num>47-4616</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payments in lieu of taxes, Southwest Waterfront PILOT/TIF Area.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During the PILOT period:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall determine the amount of PILOT due for each lot and shall generally administer the PILOT program established herein, in the same manner as provided for real property taxation under Chapter 8 of this title or in the case of PILOT due with respect to possessory interests under § 47-1005.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall be subject to the same penalty and interest provisions as unpaid real property taxes under Chapter 8 of this title or unpaid possessory interest taxes under § 47-1005.01(f)(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All PILOT shall be made to the District and shall be allocated as provided in the Southwest Waterfront Bond  Financing Act of 2008 [D.C. Law 17-252].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall be paid at the same time and in the same manner as real property taxes under Chapter 8 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A lien for unpaid PILOT, including penalty and interest, shall attach to the applicable lot within the Southwest Waterfront PILOT/TIF Area in the same manner and with the same priority as a lien for delinquent real property tax under Chapter 13A of this title. Unpaid PILOT shall be collected in accordance with Chapter 13A of this title. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if a possessory interest tax would be imposed with respect to a lease or right to use a lot pursuant to § 47-1005.01 but for this section, the failure to make payments in lieu of taxes with respect to the possessory interest shall be enforced against the owner of the possessory interest in the manner specified in § 47-1005.01(f)(3). The PILOT shall be deemed a tax within the meaning of 11 U.S.C. §§ 502(b), 505, and 507(a)(8)(B).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a lot or possessory interest within the Southwest Waterfront PILOT/TIF Area may challenge any assessment or reassessment of the lot or possessory interest in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 8 of this title and the applicable PILOT shall reflect the result of the challenge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4616_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall be an assessment for the purposes of §§ 47-832 through 47-835 relating to subdivisions of lots, parcels, or tracts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
