<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4111"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4111/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4111">
        <akn:num>47-4111</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rewards for informants.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the expenses are not otherwise provided for by law, the Mayor may pay the expenses which he considers necessary for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount payable under this section shall not exceed 10% of the proceeds, other than interest and penalties, collected by reason of the information obtained as a result of the payments. The proceeds collected shall be available for the payments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No present or former employee of the District whose job responsibilities include, or have included, tax administration or enforcement, or any person who is working, or has worked, for a contractor on a tax administration or enforcement project for the District government, shall be eligible for the rewards authorized in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may pay an amount which he or she may consider appropriate for information to achieve the purposes set forth in subsection (a)(1) or (a)(s) [sic] of this section. No person, in the absence of express authority from the Mayor, shall make an offer, promise, or contract, or otherwise bind the Mayor, with respect to such payments or the amount thereof.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_c_3">
      <akn:num>(c-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall be eligible to file a claim for any monetary payment authorized by this section who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4111_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may promulgate regulations to carry out the purpose of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
