<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4103"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4103/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4103">
        <akn:num>47-4103</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Failure to pay tax, make return, keep records, or supply information.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4103_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person required under this title to pay a tax or estimated tax, or required by this title, or by regulations made under authority thereof, to make a return, keep any records, or supply any information, who willfully fails to pay the tax, pay the estimated tax, make the return, keep the records, or supply the information, at the time required by law or regulations, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [ยง 22-3571.01], or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4103_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person required under this title to pay a tax or estimated tax, make a return, keep any records, or supply any information, who fails to pay the tax, pay the estimated tax, make the return, keep the records, or supply the information, at the time required by law or regulations, shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in [ยง 22-3571.01], or imprisoned not more than 180 days, or both, together with costs of prosecution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4103_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All prosecutions under this section shall be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia on information by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia in the name of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4103_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The fines set forth in this section shall not be limited by [ยง 22-3571.01].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
