<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4628"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4628/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4628">
        <akn:num>47-4628</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>The Heights on Georgia Avenue; Lots 98, 903, 904, 908, and 911, Square 2892.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning on the 1st day of the half tax year immediately following the date on which site preparation begins, as evidenced by either the issuance of a demolition permit, grading permit, or excavation permit, whichever is issued first, the Housing Element shall be exempt from real property taxation under Chapter 8 of this title; provided, that the following occurs:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For each deadline set forth in subsection (b) of this section, extensions may be granted at the discretion of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the deadlines set forth in subsection (b) of this section, as they may be extended by the Mayor as provided in subsection (c) of this section, are not met, The Heights on Georgia Avenue Developer shall pay to the District a sum equal to the amount of real property tax that would have been imposed on The Heights on Georgia Avenue Project in the absence of the exemption provided in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The exemption from real property taxation provided in subsection (b) of this section shall expire on the date that is the last day of the half tax year immediately following the earlier of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of ยง 47-831(b), the owner shall have a duty to inform the Office of Tax and Revenue when the Housing Element is no longer entitled to the exemption granted by subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4628_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no fees shall be charged to The Heights on Georgia Avenue Developer for any permits related to the construction of The Heights on Georgia Avenue Project, including private space or building permit fees or public space permit fees. The exemption provided by this subsection shall not include inspection fees for such permits, condominium registration application fees, or condominium conversion fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
