<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4505"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4505/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4505">
        <akn:num>47-4505</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administration and initial implementation of the Program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4505_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall take such action as may be necessary to effectuate the Trust, issue regulations with respect to the Program, and in connection therewith, the Trust, and otherwise initiate the implementation and administration of the Program consistent with this chapter. The Chief Financial Officer shall continue to administer and maintain the Program in a manner to ensure that the Program continues to qualify as a qualified tuition program under section 529 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. § 529].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4505_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall use the funds authorized in § 47-4503(c), § 47-4503(j) [(j) repealed], § 47-4503(r), and § 47-4506(b)(9) to pay for the staff and non-personal services needed to administer the Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4505_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief Financial Officer shall develop and implement the Program in a manner consistent with this chapter. To administer the Program, the Chief Financial Officer may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4505_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Delegate any and all duties, obligations, responsibilities, rights, and powers assigned and granted to the Chief Financial Officer under this chapter to the Trustee to be carried out and exercised in his or her capacity as Trustee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
