<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4630"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4630/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4630">
        <akn:num>47-4630</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax abatements for high technology commercial real estate database and service providers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsections (f), (g), and (h) of this section, the real property taxes imposed by Chapter 8 of this title with respect to real property purchased or leased and occupied by a high technology commercial real estate database and service provider shall be fully abated for 10 years, beginning the first day of the tax year following the purchase of the real property or the execution of the lease of the real property; provided, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the real property that is the subject of the abatement under section (b) of this section is a portion of a larger unit of real property that is assessed for real property tax under Chapter 8 of this title, the abatement shall be applied by reducing the assessment of the larger unit of real property by the ratio that the square footage of the occupied portion bears to the square footage of the larger unit of real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The abatement shall be deducted from the real property tax bill or by issuing a refund (in the same amount as what would have been the abatement) to the high technology commercial real estate database and service provider, notwithstanding § 47-811.02, at the discretion of the Office of Tax and Revenue. The Office of Tax and Revenue may apply the abatement to any half of the tax year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the high technology commercial real estate database and service provider shall cease to qualify for the abatement, the abatement shall cease on the first day of the month following the day when the Mayor certifies the disqualification to the Office of Tax and Revenue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall certify to the Office of Tax and Revenue the identity of each high technology commercial real estate database and service provider for which compliance under subsection (b) of this section has been verified by the Mayor, a description of each real property that is the subject of the abatement provided by this section, and the date on which the abatement shall begin.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The abatement pursuant to this section shall apply once the high technology commercial real estate database and service provider has certified to the Department of Employment Services that the provider has hired at least 100 employees residing in the District of Columbia beyond the number of employees residing in the District of Columbia as of January 5, 2010 (“baseline number”); provided, that the high technology commercial real estate database and service provider shall maintain the baseline number throughout the entire term of the abatement. The failure to maintain the baseline number shall result in the forfeiture of the abatement during any period in which the baseline number is not met.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4630_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funds shall be sufficient within an approved budget and financial plan to support the fiscal impact of a tax abatement under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
