<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4431"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4431/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4431">
        <akn:num>47-4431</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Refund offset.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, within the applicable period of limitations set forth in § 47-4302, may credit the amount of the overpayment of a tax, including interest allowed thereon, against the liability for a tax or an installment thereof (whether the tax was assessed as a deficiency or otherwise) of the person who made the overpayment and shall, subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section, refund any balance to the person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may credit the amount of the overpayment, including interest, in the following order of priority:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall credit the amount of the overpayment of an individual who has been determined:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon request, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall provide the Mayor with the names, and any other available identifying information, of individuals whom the Superior Court of the District of Columbia has determined are more than 60 days in arrears in court-ordered child support payments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of collecting an amount determined to be in default under federal student loan programs, the university shall provide the Mayor with the names, and any other available identifying information, of individuals whom the university has determined to be in default. A determination and notice of default under federal student loan programs shall be made as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of collecting an amount determined to be an overpayment of unemployment compensation, the Department of Employment Services, through its Director, shall provide the Mayor with the names, and any other identifying information, of individuals whom the Director has determined to have received benefit overpayments. Determination and notice of overpayment of unemployment compensation shall be made in accordance with the provisions of §§ 51-111, 51-112, and 51-119.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4431_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
