<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4632"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4632/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4632">
        <akn:num>47-4632</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Campbell Heights project; Lot 0207, Square 0204.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4632_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “covenants” means a restrictive covenant or regulatory agreements, or both, associated with the real property’s receipt of federal low-income housing tax credits or other assistance pursuant to section 42 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved Oct. 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2189; 26 U.S.C. § 42), or any other affordable housing program funded fully, or in part, by the District or its instrumentalities, including the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency, restricting the real property’s use to multifamily rental housing for low-income housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4632_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The real property, described as Lot 0207 (or any successor lot or lots), Square 0204, shall be exempt from taxation under Chapter 8 of this title, and District of Columbia permitting fees relating to construction or renovation of improvements on the real property, for a period commencing on the day after the transfer of real property to the Campbell Height Residents Association, or its assignee, and the recordation against the real property of the covenants and terminating when the last of the covenants terminates, but for no less than 15 years in accordance with the applicable low-income housing requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4632_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To claim the exemptions provided under subsection (b) of this section, including a refund of any real property taxes already paid, Campbell Height Residents Association, or its assignee, shall file a copy of the recorded deed of the real property to Campbell Height Residents Association, or its assignee, and the recorded covenants, with the Office of Tax and Revenue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
