<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4702"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4702/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4702">
        <akn:num>47-4702</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Annual certification of continuing eligibility for exemptions and abatements from real property tax.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4702_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To the extent allowable by law, on or before April 1 of each year, beginning in 2012, and every year thereafter, any nonprofit organization or business entity owning property receiving a real property tax exemption or abatement pursuant to Chapter 10 (other than property exempt under ยง 47-1002(1), (2), (3), or (21)) or Chapter 46 of this title, regardless of when the exemption or abatement was received, shall be required to file an annual report, under oath, with the Office of the Chief Financial Officer providing:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4702_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure to certify that the property was still eligible for the exemption or abatement based on the use of the property as required by subsection (a)(1) of this section shall result in a termination of the exemption or abatement as of the beginning of the tax year in which the report is required to be filed. If the report is not filed timely, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer shall assess a penalty of $250. This section shall not apply to a property owner that is required to file an annual report pursuant to ยง 47-1007.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4702_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon written application by the property owner filed on or before April 1 of any year, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing the report required under subsection (a) of this section. For reasonable cause, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer may abate the penalty provided under subsection (b) of this section as well as the tax, penalty, and interest resulting from the failure to file the report timely.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
