<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4658"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4658/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4658">
        <akn:num>47-4658</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments; Lot 808, Square 5041 and Lot 811, Square 5056.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4658_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the real property described as Lot 808, Square 5041 and Lot 811, Square 5056, which is owned by Parkside Residential, LLC, and known as the Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments, shall be allowed an annual real property tax abatement equal to the amount of the real property taxes assessed and imposed by Chapter 8 of this title of up to a total maximum amount for both lots of $600,000 per year for 10 property tax years commencing for Lot 808 and for Lot 811 at the beginning of the first month following the date the lot is issued a final certificate of occupancy (“commencement date”) and ending for each lot at the end of the 10th full real property tax year following the lot’s commencement date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4658_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The real property tax abatement authorized by this section shall expire for the lot, or lots, whichever the case may be, that has not been issued a final certificate of occupancy by September 20, 2018, and an abatement pursuant to this section shall not be allowed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4658_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and provided that the final certificate of occupancy is issued on or before September 20, 2018, upon the issuance of a final certificate for Lot 808 or Lot 811, any fees or deposits charged to and paid by Parkside Residential, LLC, related to that lot for the development of Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments, including private space or building permit fees or public space permit fees (“related fees”), shall be refunded and any prospective related fees forgiven.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4658_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The tax abatements and fees and deposits exemptions provided pursuant to this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
