<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4803"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4803/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4803">
        <akn:num>47-4803</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Eligibility.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4803_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A taxpayer may receive a District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit with respect to a qualified project; provided, that the Department issues an eligibility statement for that qualified project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4803_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The total District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit available to a qualified District of Columbia project shall be authorized and allocated by the Department based on the qualified project’s need for the credit for economic feasibility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4803_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia low-income housing tax credit shall be taken against the income, insurance premium, or franchise taxes imposed under this title, claimed equally for 10 years, subtracted from the amount of District of Columbia tax otherwise due for each taxable period and shall not be refundable; provided, that the credit may not be taken against any tax that is dedicated in whole or in part to the Healthy DC and Health Care Expansion Fund established by § 31-3514.02. Any amount of the low-income housing tax credit that exceeds the tax due for a taxable year may be carried forward to any of the 10 remaining subsequent taxable years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4803_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4803_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the recapture of District of Columbia low-income housing tax credits is required pursuant to § 47-4804(a) or (b), any statement submitted to the Chief Financial Officer as provided in this section shall include the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4803_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
