<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4640"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4640/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4640">
        <akn:num>47-4640</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payments in lieu of taxes, Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall be subject to the same penalty and interest provisions as unpaid real property taxes under Chapter 8 of Title 47.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning on October 1, 2014, the PILOT deferred under subsection (b)(1)(C) of this section shall be reduced by an amount not to exceed $2.4 million in consideration for the Owner agreeing to provide no less than 50 affordable housing units and an amount not to exceed $3 million for Owner’s conducting certain site preparation activities, including demolition of existing structures on the Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area and within F Street, N.W.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A lien for unpaid PILOT payments, including penalties and interest, shall attach to each tax lot in the Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area in the same manner and with the same priority as a lien for delinquent real property tax under Chapter 13A of this title. Unpaid PILOT payments may be collected in accordance with Chapter 13A of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a tax lot within the Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area shall not have the right to challenge the Mayor’s determination of the purchase price or adjusted purchase price under subsection (b)(2) of this section. The owner of a tax lot within the Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area shall have the right to challenge the assessed value of its tax lot in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 8 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not affect the calculation of the assessed value or payment of real property taxes with respect to any buildings or improvements constructed upon the deck upon the receipt of Certificate of Completion of Core and Shell of Building for such building or improvement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4640_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Land and improvements that are located in the Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area, and not otherwise exempt pursuant to § 47-1002, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title for the PILOT period; provided, that this exemption shall not apply to any improvements constructed upon the deck and the land and improvements on any lots that are removed from the Center Leg Freeway (Interstate 395) PILOT Area pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(D) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
