<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4610"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4610/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4610">
        <akn:num>47-4610</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Georgia Commons; Lots 848 and 849, Square 2906.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Housing Element shall be entitled to the exemption provided by subsection (c) of this section and the abatement provided by subsection (d) of this section so long as at least 57 of the units of the Housing Element are Affordable Units.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning on the date of the transfer of the ownership of Lots 848 and 849, Square 2906, from the District of Columbia to a private owner, the Housing Element shall be exempt from real property taxes imposed by Chapter 8 of this title until the first day of the half tax year immediately following the date on which the Housing Element passes the final inspection necessary for the certificate of occupancy to issue; provided, that the private owner shall diligently and expeditiously take all actions necessary to pass all inspections necessary for the certificate of occupancy to issue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of ยง 47-831(b), the private owner shall have a duty to inform the Office of Tax and Revenue when the Housing Element is no longer entitled to the exemption granted by subsection (c) of this section or the abatement granted by subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning on the date of the transfer of the ownership of Lots 848 and 849, Square 2906, from the District of Columbia to a private owner, the Retail Element shall be exempt from real property taxes imposed by Chapter 8 of this title until the first day of the half tax year immediately following the date on which the Retail Element passes the final inspection necessary for the certificate of occupancy to issue; provided, that the private owner shall diligently and expeditiously take all actions necessary to pass all inspections necessary for the certificate of occupancy to issue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of ยง 47-831(f), the private owner shall have a duty to inform the Office of Tax and Revenue when the Retail Element is no longer entitled to the exemption granted by subsection (f) of this section or the abatement granted by subsection (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4610_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The exemptions and abatements provided by this section shall run with Lots 848 and 849, Square 2906 and shall apply to any subsequent owner or assignee or successor in interest of Georgia Commons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
