<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4611"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4611/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4611">
        <akn:num>47-4611</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payments in lieu of taxes, Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During the PILOT period, the real property in the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area (other than the Improvement Parcels) shall be exempt from real property taxation. The improvements on the real property within the Improvement Parcels shall be exempt from real property taxation, but shall not be exempt from special tax provided for in ยง 1-204.81. The land within the Improvement Parcels shall not be exempt from real property taxation pursuant to this section. Real property and improvements within the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area which in the absence of this section would be subject to business improvement district assessments and other special assessments shall not be exempt from such assessments pursuant to this section or ยง 47-1002(30). Each owner of a parcel in the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area shall make a PILOT in an amount equal to the real estate taxes, if any, that the owner would be obligated to pay on such parcel in the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area in the absence of this section or in the case of the Improvement Parcels on the improvements on such parcel in the absence of this section. The PILOT shall be made in the same manner and at such times as annual real property taxes under Chapter 8 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall be subject to the same penalty and interest provisions as unpaid real property taxes under Chapter 8 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All PILOT shall be made to the District or its designee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The PILOT shall be paid on such dates that the annual real property taxes would have been due and payable on such parcel. An owner shall have at least 30 days from the date of issuance of a bill to pay any PILOT installment The owner shall deliver such PILOT to the address identified for delivery of such payment on the applicable bill.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A lien for unpaid PILOT, including penalty and interest, shall attach to the applicable lot within the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area in the same manner and with the same priority as a lien for delinquent real property tax under Chapter 13A of this title. An unpaid PILOT may be collected in accordance with Chapter 13A of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4611_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a lot within the Capper/Carrollsburg PILOT Area shall have the right to challenge any assessment or reassessment of such lot in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 8 of this title and the applicable PILOT shall reflect the result of such challenge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
