<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4002"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4002/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4002">
        <akn:num>47-4002</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk; duties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Children and Youth Investment Trust Corporation (“CYITC”) shall receive, as a grant, all monies that are generated by the tax check-off system established in § 47-1812.11b. The fund shall be administered by the CYITC and shall be used to support purposes consistent with the stated purpose of the fund. The CYITC shall submit an annual financial report to the Mayor and Council of the District of Columbia no later than March 1st of each year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CYITC shall publicize the availability of a tax check-off for drug prevention and children at risk. The Mayor shall assist the Fund to insure public education regarding the tax check-off and District taxpayer participation in the tax check-off.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CYITC shall take any necessary step to encourage the federal government to match the funds generated through the tax check-off.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CYITC may recommend other means to generate funds for drug prevention and children at risk.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CYITC shall encourage collaborative efforts and foster a public-private partnership in the development of drug prevention and children at risk programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CYITC shall advise the Mayor and the Council on action needed to insure effective programming for drug prevention and children at risk in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4002_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds generated through the tax check-off shall be invested by CYITC in bonds, treasury notes, other evidences of indebtedness of the United States, or federally insured commercial banks of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
