<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4301">
        <akn:num>47-4301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Periods of limitation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4301_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, the amount of a tax imposed under this title shall be assessed within 3 years after the return was filed (whether or not the return was filed after the date due) or, if the tax is payable by stamp, at any time after the tax became due and before the expiration of 3 years after the date on which a part of the tax was paid. A proceeding in court without assessment for the collection of the tax shall not commence after the expiration of such period. For purposes of this chapter, the term “return” means the return of tax required to be filed by the taxpayer (and does not include a return of tax of a person from whom the taxpayer has received an item of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4301_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, a return filed before the last day prescribed by this title, or by regulations promulgated under this title for filing, shall be considered as filed on the last day.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4301_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The execution of a return by the Mayor shall not start the running of the period of limitations on assessment and collection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4301_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4301_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, before the expiration of the time prescribed in this section for the assessment of a tax imposed by this title, both the Mayor and the taxpayer have consented in writing to its assessment after such time, the tax may be assessed at any time before the expiration of the extended period. The period may be extended further by subsequent agreement in writing made before the expiration of an extended period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4301_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the amount of taxable income for a taxable year (or portion of a taxable year) of a taxpayer as reported by the taxpayer, or his duly authorized agent, to the United States Department of Treasury for federal income tax purposes is changed or corrected by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, by a court of the United States, or by a court of the District of Columbia, or if the amount of taxable income for a taxable year (or portion of a taxable year) of a taxpayer as reported by the taxpayer or his duly authorized agent, to the District of Columbia for District of Columbia income or franchise tax purposes is changed or corrected by a court of the United States or the District of Columbia, the taxpayer, or his duly authorized agent, shall, within 90 days after the change or correction is finally determined, report in writing the changed or corrected taxable income to the District of Columbia. The Mayor may, within 180 days from the date of the receipt of written notice from the taxpayer of the changed or corrected taxable income as finally determined, assess or reassess the amount of a tax imposed by this title; provided, that if the date of receipt by the District of Columbia of a notice from the taxpayer is more than 180 days before the expiration of the applicable period of limitation, the Mayor shall have until the expiration of the applicable period of limitation to assess or reassess the amount of the tax. Failure to report the changed or corrected taxable income as finally determined within the 90-day period shall suspend the running of the period of limitation for a period of 180 days after the date that the report from the taxpayer, or his duly authorized agent, is received by the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
