<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4440"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-4440/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_4440">
        <akn:num>47-4440</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reciprocal refund offset.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4440_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The chief taxing official of a state, local, or municipal government may certify to the Mayor the existence of a tax debt and request that the Mayor withhold a refund due to a taxpayer to satisfy the debt owed by the taxpayer to the requesting state, local, or municipal government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4440_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A request under subsection (a) of this section shall not be honored unless the state, local, or municipal government provides a reciprocal right of credit to the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4440_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Certification of a tax debt shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4440_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a request under subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall notify the taxpayer (and in the case of a refund of a tax imposed upon the income of individuals, a spouse (or domestic partner) with whom the taxpayer filed a joint return). The notice shall include a copy of the certification by the chief taxing official of the requesting state, local, or municipal government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-4440_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may enter into agreements with the chief taxing official of a state, local or municipal government with respect to the operation of this section, including safeguards against the disclosure or inappropriate use of any information which personally identifies the taxpayer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
