<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-850.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-850.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_850_01">
        <akn:num>47-850.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Residential property tax relief — Homestead deduction for cooperative housing associations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-850_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of levying the real property tax during a tax year, the Mayor shall deduct from the assessed value of the real property owned by a cooperative housing association, as determined under § 47-820.01, $67,500, increased annually, beginning October 1, 2012, by the cost-of-living adjustment (if the adjustment does not result in a multiple of $50, rounded to the next lowest multiple of $50), for each homestead located therein. The deduction shall be apportioned equally between each installment during a tax year and shall not be carried forward or carried back.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-850_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The cooperative housing association shall only receive a deduction for one homestead of a shareholder or member, even though he or she may occupy more than one dwelling unit. The cooperative housing association shall not receive a deduction for a homestead if the basis of the deduction is another person in the household of the shareholder or member. Only one person in the household of the shareholder or member shall be entitled to claim a homestead in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-850_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order for the cooperative housing association to qualify a dwelling unit as a homestead and receive the deduction, the shareholder or member shall complete and file with the Mayor an application in a form prescribed by the Mayor. The shareholder or member shall certify, under penalty of perjury, the information provided on the application form and the application form shall be filed in the manner prescribed by the Mayor. The Mayor may require the shareholder or member to submit any information which the Mayor considers necessary, including the taxpayer identification numbers of the shareholder or member, any other person with an ownership or membership interest, and any person in the household of the shareholder or member. The Mayor may also require the shareholder or member, any other person with an ownership or membership interest, and any person in the household of the shareholder or member to submit information after the homestead has been qualified to determine whether the cooperative housing association remains entitled to the deduction for the homestead for the dwelling unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-850_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may require the officers or managers of the cooperative housing association to distribute the application forms to its shareholders or members and to collect the completed application forms from such shareholders or members for return to the Mayor. Officers and managers of a cooperative housing association shall supply such other information as the Mayor may require.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-850_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a properly completed and approved application is filed during the period October 1 through March 31 of the tax year, the cooperative housing association shall receive the deduction for the entire tax year. Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, if a properly completed and approved application is filed during the period April 1 through September 30 the cooperative housing association shall receive 1/2 of the deduction for the second installment only.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
