<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-857.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-857.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_857_04">
        <akn:num>47-857.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax abatements for new residential developments — Tax abatement for all new housing projects in Housing Priority Area.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-857_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to any project for which the owner or its designee satisfies § 47-857.02(a)(1) and (2) on or before September 30, 2004, and subject to § 47-857.02, there shall be allowed as an abatement of the real property tax imposed by § 47-811 on an eligible real property in eligible area #2 an amount computed as follows: $1.10 per residential FAR square foot, multiplied by the building’s total residential FAR square footage as certified by the project architect and the Mayor; provided, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-857_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-857_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall be deemed to have certified the groundbreaking if the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, or his or her successor, issues a letter certifying the groundbreaking or 20 business days pass after the date of the receipt of a request for the certification by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, or his or her successor, from the project developer; provided, that the request includes a certification by the project architect of the groundbreaking date of the residential project and the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, or his or her successor, does not reject the request or request further information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
