<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-893"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-893/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_893">
        <akn:num>47-893</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Levy of special assessment; protest; termination of levy.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in tax year 2008, there is levied a special assessment upon each real property located within the Southeast Water and Sewer Improvement Benefit District, except the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The special assessment applicable to a real property shall be equal to the sum of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Chief Financial Officer learns that a real property subject to the special assessment has been omitted from the special assessment for any previous tax year, the Chief Financial Officer shall provide notice under subsection (e) of this section to the owner for the succeeding, current, and prior tax years, and shall collect the special assessment amount in arrears, including penalty and interest from the date the special assessment should have been paid; provided, that no real property that has escaped the special assessment shall be liable under this section for a period of more than 3 prior tax years. No further notice shall be required for future tax years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a real property subject to special assessment under this subchapter, when first provided notice of a special assessment under this subchapter, may petition for administrative review, and appeal from a final determination made upon administrative review, of the amount of a special assessment, or the imposition of the special assessment, on the real property or interest therein in the same manner and to the same extent as set forth in ยง 47-825.01(f-1) as if the owner were a new property owner; provided, that for purposes of the new owner appeal, the date of transfer shall be deemed to be the date of the notice and the tax year shall be deemed to be the last tax year included in the notice; provided further, that notwithstanding the foregoing, the notice under subsection (c)(1) of this section shall be mailed on or before March 1, 2008 and the owner may petition for an administrative review on or before April 1, 2008 and appeal therefrom to the same extent and under the same conditions as a real property owner may appeal his tax year 2009 real property tax assessment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in tax year 2008, special assessments under this subchapter shall be levied annually and shall be due on June 30 of the tax year. The owner shall have 30 days to pay the special assessment bill before the bill is due.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The levy of special assessments under this subchapter shall terminate on the date on which the special assessment total collection amount has been received by the District, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A special assessment imposed under this subchapter shall not be required to be certified for the purposes of Chapter 13A of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each special assessment shall be made part of the public record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-893_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The total collection amount from the Southeast Water and Sewer Improvement Benefit District shall not exceed the amount required to pay the debt service on a total amount of $12.45 million of borrowing authority, which shall represent the special assessment total collection amount of the properties subject to the assessment under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
