<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-845.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-845.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_845_01">
        <akn:num>47-845.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax deferral — Bureau of National Affairs.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Mayor may enter into an agreement with The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. (“BNA”), and BNA Washington, Inc. (“BNAW”), to defer, up to 10 years, any real property tax liability on property located on Lot 109 and Lot 883 of Square 24, popularly known as 1227-1231 25th Street, N.W., Washington, D.C., or any property in the District of Columbia acquired for headquarters and principal operations as an addition to, or substitute for, the 25th Street address during the term of any deferral agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to enter into a written agreement (“Agreement”) with BNA and BNAW on such terms and conditions as the Mayor deems to be in the best interest of the District, the purpose of which is to provide BNA and BNAW with incentives to continue their current occupancy and usage of the real property specified in subsection (a) of this section, or any similar District property substituted therefor, for which real property tax relief is to be granted and in which BNA and BNAW maintain their headquarters and principal operations, including, but not limited to, production, editorial, home office sales, and home office operations, and to expand their business operation by committing to the lease or purchase of an additional 95,000 square feet of office space in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amount of real property tax owed during an approved deferment period shall not constitute delinquent taxes nor shall BNA and BNAW be assessed any interest or penalty for the deferment period. The deferral shall be prospective and shall apply only to the specified tax years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Taxes, including penalty and interest thereon, deferred under this section shall constitute a preferential lien upon the real property which shall be payable immediately by the seller, transferor, or conveyor whenever the real property is sold, transferred, or conveyed in any manner, to an entity other than BNAW or a wholly-owned subsidiary of BNA or whenever additional co-owners (other than BNA or a wholly-owned subsidiary of BNA) are added to the real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In no event shall the deferral granted pursuant to this section be transferable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As a condition to the grant of tax benefits under this section, BNA and BNAW shall submit to the Mayor by March 31st of each tax year an affidavit, signed under penalty of perjury. The affidavit shall contain the following averments or documentation of same establishing that after reasonable investigation, the undersigned have determined that BNA and BNAW:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall make an annual determination of the compliance by BNA and BNAW with the requirements of this section and the Agreement under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any assessment pursuant to a determination of noncompliance shall be due and payable by March 31st following the end of the tax year in which the certificate of noncompliance was issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-845_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to develop the necessary forms and procedures, and to promulgate regulations, necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
