<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-812"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-812/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_812">
        <akn:num>47-812</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of rates.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council, after public hearing, shall by October 15 of each year establish, by act, rates of taxation, by class, as provided in § 47-813, and the rates shall be applied, during the tax year, to the assessed value of all real property subject to taxation. The Council, acting by resolution, may extend the time for establishing the rates of taxation. If the Council does extend the time for establishing the rates of taxation on real property, it must establish those rates for the tax year by permanent legislation. If the Council does not establish the rates of taxation of real property by October 15, and does not extend the time for establishing rates, the rates of taxation applied for the prior year shall be the rates of taxation applied during the tax year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the real property tax rates for taxable property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 1994, and ending September 30, 1995, shall be the same rates in effect for the tax year beginning October 1, 1993, and ending September 30, 1994.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the real property tax rates for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 1995, and ending September 30, 1996, shall be the same rates in effect for the tax year beginning October 1, 1993, and ending September 30, 1994.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the following real property tax rates are established for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the real property tax year beginning October 1, 1995, and ending September 30, 1996:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 413 [Pub. L. 93-407, title IV, § 413], subsection (a) of this section, or any other law imposing requirements on the enactment of these tax rates, the following real property tax rates are established for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the real property tax year beginning October 1, 1996, and ending September 30, 1997:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the following real property tax rates are established for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 1997, and ending September 30, 1998:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_3">
      <akn:num>(b-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the sum of the real property tax rates and the special real property tax rates for taxable property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 1999, and ending September 30, 2000, shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_4">
      <akn:num>(b-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_5">
      <akn:num>(b-5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_6">
      <akn:num>(b-6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the sum of the real property tax rates and the special real property tax rates for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 2002, shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_7">
      <akn:num>(b-7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the sum of the real property tax rates and special real property tax rates for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 2005, shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_8">
      <akn:num>(b-8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_9">
      <akn:num>(b-9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_b_10">
      <akn:num>(b-10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to section 9 of the General Obligation Bond Act of 1994, effective May 3, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-116; 41 DCR 1224), the following real property special tax rates are established for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the real property tax year beginning October 1, 1995, and ending September 30, 1996:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 413, subsection (c) of this section, or any other law imposing requirements on the enactment of these tax rates, pursuant to section 9 of the General Obligation Bond Act of 1994, effective May 3, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-116; 41 DCR 1224), the following real property special tax rates are established for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the real property tax year that begins October 1, 1996, and ends September 30, 1997:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to section 9 of the General Obligation Bond Act of 1996, effective October 1, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-162; 43 DCR 5432), the following real property special tax rates are established for taxable real property in the District of Columbia for the tax year beginning October 1, 1997, and ending September 30, 1998:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the terms “Class 1 Property”, “Class 2 Property”, “Class 3 Property”, “Class 4 Property”, and “Class 5 Property” each has the same meaning as the terms have in § 47-813(c-2)(1), (2), (3), (4), and (5).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall issue rules necessary to implement subsections (b) through (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-812_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
