<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-883"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-883/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_883">
        <akn:num>47-883</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Levy of special assessment; protest; termination of levy.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days after [June 6, 2001], the CFO shall determine the total debt service projected to be paid on the initial General Obligation Bonds from their date of issuance through maturity, which amount shall constitute the Special Assessment Total Collection Amount; provided, that the Special Assessment Total Collection Amount shall be subject to adjustment after the initial determination if the CFO determines and certifies that the actual debt service payable on the initial General Obligation Bonds will be less than the amount projected. The Special Assessment Annual Collection Amount shall be 1/30 of the Special Assessment Total Collection Amount.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days after [June 6, 2001], the CFO shall determine the tax lots of real property which are subject to the special assessment under subsection (a) of this section, the total assessed value real property tax purposes of each tax lot, and the aggregate total assessed value for real property tax purposes of all tax lots. The valuation shall be determined as of the real property tax valuation date for tax year 2000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days after [June 6, 2001], the CFO shall determine the Special Assessment Factor, which shall be computed by dividing the Special Assessment Annual Collection Amount by the aggregate assessed value determined under subsection (c) of this section; provided, that the CFO may increase the Special Assessment Factor at any time by the amount that the CFO determines to be necessary to ensure that the special assessments under this section shall be at least equal to the Special Assessment Annual Collection Amount in each year. The special assessment applicable to each tax lot shall be determined by multiplying the Special Assessment Factor by the total assessed value of each tax lot as of [June 6, 2001], or, for any tax lot which becomes subject to the special assessment after [June 6, 2001], the date on which the tax lot becomes subject to the special assessment. Each special assessment shall be made part of the public record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a tax lot subject to special assessment under this subchapter may protest the amount of a special assessment levied by filing a protest with the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia (“Commission”), on a form prescribed by The Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia, within 30 days after notice of assessment. The protest shall be reviewed by the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia in accordance with § 47-825.1. Each decision of the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia shall be maintained by the Board and shall be made available for examination and photocopying at cost to any requestor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Special assessments levied under this subchapter shall be collected at the same time and in the same manner as real property taxes under this chapter are collected.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An unpaid special assessment shall be subject to the same penalty and interest provisions as a delinquent real property tax under this chapter. A lien for an unpaid special assessment, including penalty and interest, shall attach to the real property in the same manner and with the same priority as a lien for delinquent real property tax under Chapter 13A of this title. The unpaid special assessment shall be collected in accordance with Chapter 13A of the title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-883_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The levy of special assessments shall terminate on the date on which the Special Assessment Total Collection Amount has been received by the District, as certified by the CFO to the Mayor under § 47-884.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
