<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-863"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-863/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_863">
        <akn:num>47-863</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reduced tax liability for property owners over age 65 and for property owners with disabilities; rules.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a properly completed and approved application is filed during the period October 1 through March 31 of the tax year, the real property shall receive the deduction for the entire tax year. Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, if a properly completed and approved application is filed during the period April 1 through September 30, the real property shall receive ½ of the deduction, which shall be applied to the second installment only.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The application form filed by the individual, shareholder, or member shall apply to the initial tax year, or applicable installment, and to any succeeding tax year thereafter for which the deduction is allowed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A denial of the deduction shall be subject to the provisions of § 47-813(d-1)(3A) to the same extent as an appeal of a Class 3 classification.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_f_2">
      <akn:num>(f-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If real property tax is owing as a result of an erroneous or improper deduction, the following shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The eligibility of an eligible household for the deduction shall not be affected by the transfer of the eligible household into a revocable trust if the transfer is without consideration and the eligible household remains the residence of the applicant-grantor before and after the transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No other person in the household of the individual, shareholder, or member shall claim a deduction for an eligible household in the District. The cooperative housing association shall not receive a deduction for an eligible household if the basis of the deduction is another person in the household of the shareholder or member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an individual, shareholder, or member claims more than one eligible household in the same tax year, and has not timely notified the Mayor of all changes in eligibility, the Mayor shall disallow the deduction for all eligible households claimed by the individual, shareholder or member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-863_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of a house or a condominium, the real property tax bill shall indicate whether the real property is receiving the deduction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
