<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-805"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-805/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_805">
        <akn:num>47-805</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Office of Real Property Tax Ombudsman.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is created within the Office of the Mayor the Office of the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (“Office”), which shall be headed by the Real Property Tax Ombudsman (“Ombudsman”), who shall be appointed by the Mayor pursuant to § 1-523.01(a), as a statutory employee in the Excepted Service pursuant to § l-609.08. The Ombudsman shall serve for a term of 5 years. The Ombudsman shall serve at the pleasure of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman shall appoint staff and additional personnel as provided for in an approved budget and financial plan for the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman may assist an owner with matters concerning an abutting lot where the abutting lot and the Class 1 property are owned by the same owner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Ombudsman shall not appear on behalf of Class 1 real property owners in any court, administrative, or quasi-judicial proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of the Chief Financial Officer may share confidential tax information with the Ombudsman.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-805_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term “Class 1 real property owner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 47-813(c-3)(1); provided, that the term owner as used in § 47-813(c-3)(1) shall be construed broadly and include the persons defined as owners in § 47-802 as well as other persons with an equitable interest in the property, and any other persons the Ombudsman determines to be appropriate representatives of the property owner (or, if applicable, the property owner’s estate), or any other persons the Ombudsman determines to be consistent with the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
