<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-820"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/47-820/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_47_820">
        <akn:num>47-820</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Assessments — Estimated assessment roll; frequency of assessments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the real property tax year 1998 assessed value of all real property, subject to appeal pursuant to § 47-825.01 [repealed], shall be the real property tax year 1997 assessed value; provided, that for the purposes of appeal, the valuation date for real property tax year 1998 real property assessments shall be January 1, 1997. For purposes of determining the real property tax year 1998 assessment, the 1997 assessment with the latest date shall be the final 1997 assessment by the Mayor unless the assessment was otherwise revised by the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia or the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. In the case of a revision, the 1997 assessment shall be the assessment as determined by the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia or the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (a-1) of this section shall not affect the authority of the Mayor pursuant to § 47-829, to conduct a supplemental assessment of any property located in the District and shall not affect the right of a real property owner pursuant to § 47-830, to appeal from the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (b-1) and (b-2) of this section, all real property shall be assessed no less frequently than once every 2 years, and as soon as practicable such assessment shall be made annually. The Council may authorize and direct assessments to be made annually for some or all classes of real property, except that for fiscal year 1978, and for each fiscal year thereafter, all real property shall be assessed on an annual basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (b-1) of this section, for real property tax year 2002 and for each tax year thereafter, all real property which has completed its first 3-year cycle shall thereafter be revalued annually to determine its assessed value as of the valuation date. The assessed value of the real property revalued under this subsection shall not be phased in and the tax rate shall be applied to the assessed value for purposes of the tax year’s levy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47-820_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
