<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/35-235"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/35-235/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_35_235">
        <akn:num>35-235</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Metrorail discount cards; factors determining need in use of transit system.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_35-235_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Student Metrorail discount cards shall be issued by the Mayor of the District of Columbia only to those students who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_35-235_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Certifications of eligibility shall be issued only to those students who meet the eligibility requirements imposed by subsection (c) of § 35-233 and shall contain such additional information as the Mayor may require. The Mayor is authorized to verify information contained in certifications of eligibility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_35-235_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining need pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section, the Mayor shall consider appropriate indices of the student’s need to use the Metrorail Transit System for transportation to and from school and related educational activities in the District of Columbia, including the proximity of the student’s residence to his school, the proximity of the student’s residence and school to Metrorail stations and the student’s participation in city-wide education programs, work-study programs, inter-school extracurricular activities and other similar education and extracurricular activity programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_35-235_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Student Metrorail discount cards shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_35-235_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Metrorail student farecards shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_35-235_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person, other than the person for whose use such farecard is issued, shall use a student Metrorail farecard to ride on a Metrorail train and any such other use is hereby prohibited.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
