<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-117"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-117/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_117">
        <akn:num>25-117</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Brew pub permit requirements and qualifications.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-117_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A brew pub permit shall authorize the licensee to brew malt beverages at one location for consumption at a licensed restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub and for sale to licensed wholesalers for the purpose of resale to other licensees. The location used to brew malt beverages shall be on or immediately adjacent to the restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub licensed to the brew pub owner in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-117_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A brew pub permit shall authorize the licensee to sell beer in growlers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-117_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A brew pub permit shall be issued only to the licensee under an on-premises restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub retailer&#x27;s license, class C or D, or in conjunction with the issuance of an on-premises restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub retailer&#x27;s license, class C or D.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-117_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A brew pub permit shall be cancelled or revoked if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-117_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A brew pub permit shall be automatically suspended whenever and for the same period of time that the licensee’s retailer’s license, class C or D, is suspended.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
