<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-127"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-127/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_127">
        <akn:num>25-127</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Festival license.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A festival license shall authorize a licensee temporarily to sell, serve, and permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages at the specific premises described for consumption on the premises where sold; provided, that a festival license may be issued only for an event that includes the performance of sports or a cultural or tourism-related activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A festival license shall be issued for an event that is at least 5 consecutive days but no more than 15 consecutive days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The issuance of a festival license shall be solely at the discretion of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may deny the license application if the applicant had failed to control the environment of a previous event associated with either a festival license or a temporary license, or has sustained community complaints or police action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There shall be 2 classes of festival licenses:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The holder of a festival license shall be permitted to receive deliveries from a wholesaler for up to 48 hours before a Board-licensed event occurring on a Saturday, Sunday, or a legal District or federal holiday; provided, that the alcoholic beverages delivered pursuant to this subsection shall not be consumed until the date and time of the event and shall be stored at a secure location before the event.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The minimum annual fee for a class H license shall be $1,000. The minimum annual fee for a class I license shall be $2,000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-127_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Only one festival license shall be issued to an applicant in a 3-month period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
