<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-336"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-336/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_336">
        <akn:num>25-336</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Retail license prohibited in residential-use district.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-336_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No retailer’s license shall be issued for, or transferred to, a business operated in a residential-use district as defined in the zoning regulations and shown in the official atlases of the Zoning Commission for the District, except for a restaurant or tavern operated in a hotel or apartment house, if the entrance to the restaurant or tavern is entirely inside the hotel or apartment house and no sign or display is visible from the outside of the building.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-336_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nightclub license may be issued on the premises of a hotel that was legally located in a residential-use district and was operating a nightclub on the licensed premises on September 30, 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-336_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply if, at the time the application for a new license is submitted to the Board, a license of the same type and class is operating an establishment within 400 feet of the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-336_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-336_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-336_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the restriction in subsection (a) of this section, an off-premises retailer’s license may be applied for and approved by the Board in a residential-use district if an off-premises retailer’s license previously existed at the same location within the previous 2 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
