<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_301">
        <akn:num>25-301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>General qualifications for all applicants.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before issuing, transferring to a new owner, or renewing a license, the Board shall determine that the applicant meets all of the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To determine whether an applicant for a new license meets the criteria of subsection (a)(1) of this section, the Board shall examine records, covering the last 10 years from the date of application, maintained by ABRA regarding prior violations of the District’s alcohol laws and regulations by the applicant or establishments owned or controlled by the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding § 47-2861(1)(B), the Board shall not issue a license or permit to an applicant if the applicant has failed to file required District tax returns or owes more than $ 100 in outstanding debt to the District as a result of the items specified in § 47-2862(a)(1) through (9), subject to the exceptions specified in § 47-2862(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To determine whether an applicant for a new retailer or wholesaler license meets the criteria of subsection (a)(3) and (4) of this section, the Board may obtain criminal history records of criminal convictions maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Metropolitan Police Department. The Board shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall coordinate with the Metropolitan Police Department to adopt procedures necessary to facilitate this objective.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The fingerprint card shall not be maintained by the Board or by the Metropolitan Police Department and shall be returned to the applicant after the completion of the criminal background check.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Once notified, the Board shall seal, set aside, expunge, and otherwise maintain any record received pursuant to this section so that the record is in compliance with any order issued by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia pursuant to a sealing, set aside, or expungement statute, including Chapter 8 of Title 16 and Chapter 9 of Title 24. Once notified, the Board shall also seal, set aside, expunge, and otherwise maintain any record received pursuant to this section so that the record is in compliance with any court order or official government request or statement from the jurisdiction that is the source of that record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-301_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall maintain the confidentiality of any information returned from the Metropolitan Police Department and the Federal Bureau of Investigation and use such information only for the purpose of determining whether the applicant satisfies the criteria set forth in subsection (a)(3) and (4) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
