<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-423"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-423/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_423">
        <akn:num>25-423</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Posted notice required after submission of application and for the duration of the protest period.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-423_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The applicant shall post 2 notices, furnished by ABRA, of the application in conspicuous places on the outside of the establishment for the duration of the protest period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-423_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The notices shall state:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-423_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person wilfully removing, obliterating, or defacing the notices shall be guilty of a violation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-423_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant who fails to maintain the posted notices continuously during the protest period shall be guilty of a violation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-423_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Board determines that the notices posted at an applicant’s establishment have not remained visible to the public for a full 45 days, the Board shall require the reposting of the notices and shall reschedule the administrative review for a date at least 45 days after the originally scheduled review, unless the applicant has fully performed all other notice requirements and the Board determines that it is in the best interests, of the parties to proceed at an earlier date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-423_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The requirements of this section shall not apply to applicants for a solicitor’s license, manager’s license, caterer’s license, or a temporary license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
