<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-421"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-421/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_421">
        <akn:num>25-421</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice by Board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the receipt of an application for the issuance or renewal, for a substantial change in operation as determined by the Board under [§] 25-404, or for the transfer of a license to a new location, of a retailer’s license, the Board shall give notice of the application to the following parties:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The notice shall contain the legal name and trade name of the applicant, the street address of the establishment for which the license is sought, the class of license sought, and a description of the nature of the operation the applicant has proposed or the proposed change in operation. The description shall include the hours of sales or service of alcoholic beverages.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The notice to the Board of Education shall state the proximity of the establishment to the nearest public school of the District and the name of the nearest public school.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The notice shall state that persons objecting to approval of the application are entitled to be heard before the granting of the license, and shall inform the recipient of the final day of the protest period and the date, time, and place of the administrative review in accordance with subchapter III of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall give notice to the ANC by first-class mail, postmarked not more than 7 days after the date of submission, and addressed to the following persons:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall publish the notices required under this section in the District of Columbia Register.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 180 days after May 3, 2001, the Board shall implement a procedure by which it will provide additional notification, via electronic media, to the public and ANCs, of these notification requirements, and the publication of proposed and adopted regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-421_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The requirements of this section shall not apply to applicants for a caterer’s license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
