<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-772"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-772/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_772">
        <akn:num>25-772</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Unlawful importation of beverages.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-772_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Only a licensee under a manufacturer’s, wholesaler’s, or common carrier’s license, or retailer’s license under a validly issued import permit shall transport, import, bring, or ship or cause to be transported, imported, brought, or shipped into the District from outside the District any wines, spirits, or beer in a quantity in excess of one case at any one time.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-772_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No public or common carrier shall transport or bring into the District wine, spirits, or beer in a quantity in excess of one case per location in any one calendar month for delivery to any one person in the District other than the licensee under a manufacturer’s, wholesaler’s, or retailer’s license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-772_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to persons possessing old stocks who are moving into the District, to embassies or diplomatic representatives of foreign countries, to wines imported for religious or sacramental purposes, to wine, spirits, and beer to be delivered to the licensee under a manufacturer’s, wholesaler’s, or retailer’s license, or to any persons wishing to have liquor chocolates delivered to their residence. The term “liquor chocolates” may include other types of candies that have small amounts of liquor contained in the candy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-772_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The penalty for violation of this section shall consist of (1) the forfeiture of the beverages transported, imported, brought, or shipped, or caused to be transported, imported, brought, or shipped in violation of this section, and (2) a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or imprisonment for not more than 6 months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-772_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to other penalties provided in this section, any person who violates the provisions of this section shall be liable for any tax, penalties, and interest provided for in this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
