<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-911"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/25-911/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_25_911">
        <akn:num>25-911</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Seizure and forfeiture of alcoholic beverages and vehicles for which taxes have not been paid.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of ยง 25-803, if the taxes levied and imposed on alcoholic beverages by this chapter which have not been paid as required by this chapter, such alcoholic beverages shall be declared contraband goods and shall be forfeited to the District in accordance with the procedure set forth in this section. The Mayor may seize any such alcoholic beverages wherever they are found.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor has knowledge or reason to suspect that a vehicle is carrying alcoholic beverages or contains any alcoholic beverages in violation of the regulations contained in this title concerning the importation of alcoholic beverages, the Mayor may stop the vehicle and inspect it for alcoholic beverages on which the taxes levied and imposed by this chapter have not been paid. If such alcoholic beverages are found, the alcoholic beverages and the vehicle shall be declared contraband goods, shall be seized, and shall be forfeited to the District; provided, that the following vehicles shall not be subject to forfeiture under this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All property which is seized under subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be placed under seal or removed to a place designated by the Mayor. A libel action in the name of the District property shall be prosecuted against the property in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel. Unless good cause is shown to the contrary, the property shall be forfeited to the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The property shall not be subject to replevin, but shall be deemed to be in the custody of the Mayor, subject only to the orders, decrees, and judgments of the court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, if the property is subject to seizure and forfeiture on account of failure to comply with the provisions of this title and the Mayor determines that the failure was excusable, the Mayor may return the property to the owner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor determines that any property seized is liable to perish or become greatly reduced in price or value by keeping the property until the completion of forfeiture proceedings, the Mayor may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25-911_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After the final order, decree, or judgment is made, forfeited property shall be sold in the same manner as personal property seized for the payment of District taxes. The proceeds of the sale shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia. If there is a bona fide prior lien against the forfeited property, the proceeds of the sale of the property shall be applied in the following priority:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
