<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1202_04">
        <akn:num>10-1202.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Limitations on Authority’s powers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may not adopt an inducement resolution or a resolution authorizing a bond issuance, except for the purpose of refinancing, refunding, or reissuing bonds, unless the proposal has been submitted to the Council for a 30-day review period, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess. If, during the 30-day review period, the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving the submitted proposal, the Authority may take action to implement the proposal. In the event a proposal is disapproved, the Council shall state the reasons for disapproval in the disapproval resolution. The Authority may modify the proposal to address the concerns of the Council, and resubmit the proposal, as modified, for an additional 30-day review period excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in § 10-1202.13, no revenues collected on behalf of the Authority and transferred to or deposited in the Washington Convention Center Fund established pursuant to § 10-1202.08 shall be commingled with any funds of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With regard to the design of the new convention center:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall in no way interfere with or attempt to acquire site control or ownership of the existing convention center without submission of a resolution to the Council for its approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event that the Authority constructs the new convention center below ground, the District shall retain ownership of up to 15% of the developed air rights, for the purpose of providing economic development opportunities for community development corporations engaged in neighborhood economic development, with the ability to become a joint-venture partner on commercial or residential development over the New Convention Center, provided that the sale or lease of the air rights is not needed to finance the new convention center.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any and all reasonable, necessary, and verified preconstruction costs for the new convention center that are borne by the District government shall be reimbursed by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At least 51% of the Authority’s employees shall be District residents. At least 51% of every contractor’s employees hired after the contractor enters into a contract with the Authority, or with the developer or construction manager, to work on projects of the Authority shall be District residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority’s contract with the developer or construction manager selected pursuant to subsection (g)(1) of this section shall require the developer or construction manager to demonstrate that the developer or construction manager is able to furnish labor that can work in harmony with all other elements of labor employed or to be employed on the project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All operating costs of the existing convention center shall be the responsibility of the Authority after September 28, 1994.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All land and improvements acquired by the Authority to construct the new convention center shall be held in the name of the Authority, except that title to the property shall not be transferred by the Authority to any person or entity other than the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_04_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
