<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1221.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1221.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1221_04">
        <akn:num>10-1221.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Creation of the New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is created a TIF area designated as the New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area. The New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area is defined as the real property located in Lot 26 (formerly known as Lots 18, 21, 22, 24, 801 through 806, 830 through 839, 843, and 845), Square 370, bounded by 9th Street, N.W., 10th Street, N.W., L Street, N.W., and Massachusetts Avenue, N.W. As provided under ยง 10-1221.03, the Available Tax Increment from the New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area shall be deposited in the New Convention Center Hotel Fund and may be used as provided herein, including as security for the repayment of the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The base year for determination of Available Sales Tax Revenues from the New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area shall be the tax year preceding the year when this subchapter becomes effective and the base year for determination of Available Real Property Tax Revenues from the New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area shall be the fiscal year of the District when this subchapter becomes effective and the initial assessed value to be used in making such determination shall be the assessed value of each lot of taxable real property in the New Convention Center Hotel TIF Area on September 19, 2006.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
