<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1202_11">
        <akn:num>10-1202.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Terms for sale of bonds; additional bond and note provisions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may stipulate by resolution the terms for sale of its bonds in accordance with this chapter, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may sell its bonds at public or private sale and may determine the price for sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A resolution authorizing the sale of bonds may contain any of the following provisions, in which case these provisions shall be made part of the contract with holders of the bonds:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A pledge of the Authority is binding from the time it is made. Any funds, or property pledged, are subject to the lien of a pledge without physical delivery. The lien of a pledge is binding as against parties having any tort, contract, or other claim against the Authority regardless of notice. Neither the resolution nor any other instrument creating a pledge need be recorded.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The signature of any officer of the Authority which appears on a bond remains valid if that person ceases to hold office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may secure bonds by a trust indenture between the Authority and a corporate trustee which has trust company powers within the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A trust indenture of the Authority may contain provisions for protecting and enforcing the rights and remedies of holders of the bonds in accordance with the provisions of the resolution authorizing the sale of bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to preexisting agreements with the holders of the bonds or notes, the Authority may purchase its own bonds which may then be cancelled. The price the Authority pays in purchasing its own bonds cannot exceed the following limits:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority may establish special or reserve funds in furtherance of its authority under this chapter. Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, ยง 10-1202.13, and other applicable District law, and subject to agreements with holders of the bonds, the Authority shall manage its own funds, and may invest funds not required for disbursement in a manner the Authority determines to be prudent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds of the Authority are legal instruments in which public officers and public bodies of the District, insurance companies, insurance company associations, and other persons carrying on an insurance business, banks, bankers, banking institutions including savings and loan associations, building and loan associations, trust companies, savings banks, savings associations, investment companies, and other persons carrying on a banking business, administrators, guardians, executors, trustees, and other fiduciaries, and other persons authorized to invest in bonds or in other obligations of the District, may legally invest funds, including capital, in their control. The bonds are also securities which legally may be deposited with and received by public officers and public bodies of the District or any agency of the District for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or other obligations of the District is authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Obligations issued under the provisions of this chapter do not constitute an obligation of the District, but are payable solely from the revenues or assets of the Authority. Each obligation issued under this chapter must contain on its face a statement that the Authority is not obligated to pay principal or interest except from the revenues or assets pledged and that neither the faith and credit nor the taxing power of the District is pledged to the payment of the principal or interest on an obligation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All property, assets, and income of the Authority shall be exempt from District taxation and from any special assessments imposed by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_11_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Bonds issued by the Authority, their transfer, and the interest on the bonds shall be exempt from District taxation, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
