<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1601.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1601.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1601_03">
        <akn:num>10-1601.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond issuance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The bonds, the interest thereon, the income therefrom, and all monies pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of the bonds, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District hereby pledges and covenants and agrees with the holders of the bonds that, subject to the provisions of the financing documents, the District will not limit or alter the revenues pledged to secure the bonds or the basis on which the revenues are collected or allocated, will not impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the bonds, will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders of the bonds, and will not modify in any way, with respect to the bonds, the exemptions from taxation provided for in this subchapter, until the bonds, together with interest thereon, with interest on any unpaid installment of interest and all costs and expenses in connection with any suit, action, or proceeding by or on behalf of the holders of the bonds, are fully met and discharged. This pledge and agreement for the District may be included as part of the contract with the holders of the bonds. This subsection shall constitute a contract between the District and the holders of the bonds. To the extent that any acts or resolutions of the Council may be in conflict with this subchapter, this subchapter shall be controlling.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consistent with ยง 1-204.90(a)(4)(B), and notwithstanding Article 9 of Subtitle I of Title 28:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If there shall be a default in the payment of the principal of, or interest on, any bonds of a series after the principal or interest shall become due and payable, whether at maturity or upon call for redemption, or if the District shall fail or refuse to carry out and perform the terms of any agreement with the holders of any of the bonds, the holders of the bonds, or the trustee appointed to act on behalf of the holder of the bonds, may, subject to the provisions of the financing documents, do the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1601_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall select the underwriter for the bonds through a request for proposals and recommend to the underwriter a counsel that shall serve as counsel to the underwriter regarding the issuance of bonds. The bonds shall be sold to the underwriter through a negotiated process.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
