<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1221.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1221.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1221_03">
        <akn:num>10-1221.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Creation of the New Convention Center Hotel Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby established separate and apart from the General Fund of the District of Columbia a special nonlapsing fund designated as the New Convention Center Hotel Fund. The Chief Financial Officer shall deposit into the New Convention Center Hotel Fund the Available Tax Increment. The Chief Financial Officer shall create a sub-account within the New Convention Center Hotel Fund for Available Real Property Tax Revenues and Available Sales Tax Revenues and shall allocate the receipts from each to the appropriate sub-account. The Mayor may pledge and create a security interest in the funds in the New Convention Center Hotel Fund, or any sub-account or sub-accounts within the Fund, for the payment of the costs of carrying out any of the purposes described in subsection (b) of this section without further action by the Council as permitted by ยง 1-204.90(f). If bonds are issued, payment will be made in accordance with the provisions of the Financing Documents entered into by the District in connection with the issuance of the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, at the end of any fiscal year of the District, the balance of cash and investments in the New Convention Center Hotel Fund exceeds the amounts required under subsection (b) of this section, including the amount of debt service and reserves on the bonds, the excess shall be transferred to the General Fund of the District of Columbia, unless the District elects to use the excess to redeem the bonds prior to maturity, either in whole or in part.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
