<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.08a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.08a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1202_08a">
        <akn:num>10-1202.08a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Washington Convention Center Marketing Fund; marketing service contracts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established the Washington Convention Center Marketing Fund (“Marketing Fund”) to be maintained by the Authority to promote conventions, tourism, and leisure travel in the District and the hosting of sporting events, sports teams, recreational events, and entertainment events in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Monies in the Marketing Fund shall not be a part of, nor lapse into, the General Fund of the District. The Marketing Fund shall be audited at least once each year and a report of the audit shall be published by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The total dollar amount the Authority shall allocate to the Marketing Fund shall be based on, as nearly as practical, an amount equal to not less than 17.4% of the amount collected each year from the tax imposed by §§ 47-2002.02(1) and 47-2202.01(1). The Authority shall deposit monthly an amount equal to not less than 17.4% of the amount as collected from the tax imposed by §§ 47-2002.02(1) and 47-2202.01(1) into the Marketing Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where applicable, the marketing service contracts that the Authority may enter into shall include information on general and specific responsibilities, performance standards, pricing, financial reports and data, associated services, cooperative efforts with the Authority and the District, duration and termination of agreements, proprietary work product, notices, and remedies. All money received from the Authority under a marketing services contract shall be separately accounted for and subject to verification by audit. The Authority shall have the right at any time to terminate any marketing service contract for cause. In the event of termination for cause by the Authority, the services to be performed under the terms of the terminated marketing service contract shall be procured by request for proposals made pursuant to rules for the procurement of goods and services adopted by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The marketing service contracts shall include a contract with:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The marketing service contracts may include contracts with:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The obligation of the Authority to make any payment pursuant to any marketing service contract and the amount thereof shall be subject, and subordinate, in all respects, to the obligation of the Authority to apply any amount deposited or required to be deposited in any fund or account established or maintained pursuant to any resolution, indenture, or trust agreement adopted by the Authority relating to any bonds, notes, or other obligations issued by the Authority pursuant to § 10-1202.10 in accordance with the provisions of such resolution, indenture, or trust agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before entering into any marketing contract that is a multiyear contract or in excess of $1 million during a 12-month period, the Authority shall submit the contract to the Council for review and approval under § 2-352.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning in fiscal year 2013 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Chief Financial Officer shall transfer $3 million, as adjusted for inflation beginning in fiscal year 2015, as measured by the percentage increase, if any, from the preceding fiscal year in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor, from the General Fund of the District of Columbia to supplement the Marketing Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_08a_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
