<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1402"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1402/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1402">
        <akn:num>10-1402</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Property transfer.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1402_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of title. — In order to facilitate the construction, development, and operation of National Children’s Island, the Secretary shall, not later than six months after July 19, 1996 and subject to this subchapter, transfer by quitclaim deed, without consideration, to the District all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Islands. Unbudgeted actual costs incurred by the Secretary for such transfer shall be borne by the District. The District may seek reimbursement from any third party for such costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1402_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Grant of easements. — (1) The Secretary shall, not later than six months after July 19, 1996, grant, without consideration, to the District, permanent easements across the waterways and bed of the Anacostia River as described in the Survey as Leased Riverbed Areas A, B, C, and D, and across the shoreline of the Anacostia River as depicted on the plat map recorded in the Office of the Surveyor of the District as S.O. 92-252.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1402_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Development. — The development of National Children’s Island shall proceed as specified in paragraph 3 of the legend on the plat or as otherwise authorized by the District by agreement, lease, resolution, appropriate executive action, or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1402_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reversion. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
