<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1701"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1701/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1701">
        <akn:num>10-1701</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Taxation without representation federal tax pay-out message board installation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1701_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Council of the District of Columbia shall install, adjacent to the outside front wall of the John A. Wilson Building, a programmable electronic message board sign showing the dollar amount of federal taxes paid by the residents of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1701_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, the Mayor shall install, on public space within 200 feet of the baseball stadium, currently called Nationals Park, a programmable electronic message board sign showing the dollar amount of federal taxes paid by the residents of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1701_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The signs shall be large enough for the public to easily read and designed and placed in such a location so as not to deter from the architectural character of the exterior of the John A. Wilson Building or the exterior of Nationals Park.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1701_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Preference for the design, manufacture, installation, and maintenance of the signs shall be given to businesses certified as small, local, or disadvantaged business enterprises by the Department of Small and Local Business Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
