<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1202_05">
        <akn:num>10-1202.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Board of Directors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person appointed to fill a vacancy on the Board shall be appointed only for the unexpired term of the Board member whose vacancy is being filled. If any Board member is appointed to fill an unexpired term with more than 2 years remaining in the term, upon expiration of the term, that Board member shall be deemed to have served a full 4-year term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall appoint a chairperson of the Board from among the 9 public Board members with the advice and consent of the Council by resolution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each public Board member shall be a resident of the District or establish residency not later than 6 months after appointment to the Board. The Mayor shall remove any Board member for failure to establish or maintain residency or for misconduct or neglect of duty (as defined by the Board in its by-laws) after notice to the Board member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Should a Board member be indicted for the commission of a felony, the Board member shall be automatically suspended from serving on the Board. Upon a final determination of guilt or innocence, the term of the Board member shall, respectively, be automatically terminated or reinstated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall meet no less than once every 60 days and shall be subject to the provisions of ยง 1-207.42.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Seven Board members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and an affirmative vote of a majority shall be necessary for any valid Board action. For purposes of issuing bonds, and adopting budgets and financial plans, the Chief Financial Officer of the District with respect to the issuance of bonds and the adoption of budgets and financial plans, shall be a member of the majority. No vacancy in membership, except a vacancy of the Chief Financial Officer of the District, shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise all rights and perform all duties of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Board members shall serve without compensation, except that Board members may be reimbursed for all reasonable and necessary expenses incurred while engaged in official duties of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_05_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The powers of the Board shall not be limited by any articles of incorporation or by-laws adopted by the Interim Board established pursuant to ยง 10-1202.17.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
