<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-166"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-166/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_166">
        <akn:num>10-166</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfers and jurisdiction.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-166_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to § 1-204.04(b), jurisdiction over all public space park areas, maintained by the Department of Public Works before July 1, 1989, shall be transferred to and become the responsibility of the Department of Parks and Recreation. For purposes of this section, the phrase “all public space park areas” (“parks”) includes all parcels, lots, squares of land, green spaces, and monuments located within and owned or maintained by the District of Columbia government and not owned or maintained by the federal government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-166_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Public Works, Division of Roadside and Parks Maintenance, shall retain jurisdiction over, and responsibility for maintenance, landscaping, beautifying, promoting, and regulation of roadsides, interstate gateways, and cloverleafs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-166_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Facility Maintenance Administration within the Department of Parks and Recreation shall have jurisdiction over, and be responsible for the maintenance, landscaping, beautifying, promotion, and regulation of the parks transferred pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-166_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funds and existing continuing full-time employees and positions authorized for the Department of Public Works, Division of Roadside and Parks Maintenance (Responsibility Center 4044) within the Public Space Administration (Control Center 40) in the Fiscal Year 1989 Budget for the District of Columbia and allocated for the maintenance, landscaping, beautifying, promotion, and regulation of parks transferred pursuant to this section, shall be transferred to the Department of Recreation, Facility Maintenance Administration (Responsibility Center 2700) within Recreation Operations (Control Center 20).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-166_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Facility Maintenance Administration (Responsibility Center 2700) within Recreation Operations (Control Center 20) is renamed the Parks and Facility Maintenance Administration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-166_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Recreation and Parks is renamed the Department of Parks and Recreation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
