<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1221.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1221.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1221_02">
        <akn:num>10-1221.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Findings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A new hotel is required at the intersection of Ninth Street and Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., to support the operations of the Washington Convention Center and to enhance the economic benefits to the District of the Washington Convention Center. The construction and development of the New Convention Center Hotel would enable the Washington Convention Center to be more competitive in the convention market, enable it to attract increased business, and enhance the financial viability of the Washington Convention Center. The development of the New Convention Center Hotel is a municipal use that serves many public purposes and is in the interest of, and for the benefit of, the citizens of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-204.90 provides that the Council may, by act, authorize the issuance of District revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations, including refunding bonds, notes, or other obligations, to borrow money to finance, refinance, or reimburse and to assist in the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of undertakings in certain areas designated in ยง 1-204.90 where the ultimate obligation to repay such revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations is that of one or more governmental persons or entities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-204.90 provides that bonds may be issued to assist in undertakings in the area of economic development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1221_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The authorization, issuance, sale, and delivery of bonds for the payment of costs of the project are desirable, are in the public interest and will promote the purposes and intent of ยง 1-204.90.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
