<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.02c"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1202.02c/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1202_02c">
        <akn:num>10-1202.02c</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer of assets, rights, and obligations of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_02c_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_02c_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No existing lawful contract or other lawful legal obligation of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission transferred pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall be abrogated or impaired by the repeal of Chapter 14 of Title 3 [§ 3-1401 et seq.] or the superceding of Mayor’s Order 79-218, dated September 14, 1979, except for any obligation of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission to the District of Columbia related to personnel expenses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1202_02c_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Other than with respect to the rights and obligations of employment and employment-related contracts of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission not transferred pursuant to subsection (a)(4), nothing in § 10-1202.01 or § 10-1202.02 shall impair the obligations, commitments, pledges, or covenants, or the security made or provided by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission; provided, that the liability of the Authority with respect to any such obligation, commitment, pledge, covenant, or security made or provided by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission shall be limited to the assets and property of the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission transferred pursuant to this section and any income derived from such assets.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
