<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1141.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-1141.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_1141_04">
        <akn:num>10-1141.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rulemaking.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provide for a nonrefundable application fee to be paid by any party applying for a permit pursuant to this subchapter. The fee shall be set in an amount to recoup some or all of the costs to the District of Columbia for reviewing the application;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provide for the payment of a nondiscriminatory, fair, and equitable charge for any permit issued in accordance with this subchapter. The Mayor may allow a permittee to pay a fixed charge for a set period of time, pay an amount based upon the amount of the public right of way or public space used or occupied, pay an amount based upon a revenue sharing formula, or provide in-kind services to the District in lieu of a monetary payment, or the Mayor may require a permittee to pay a combination of these items. The regulations may also provide for interest to be charged on late payments of any charges imposed pursuant to this subchapter;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Generally establish categories of use and the extent to which public space, public rights of way, and public structures may be used;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Establish and regulate the process through which any impact, modification, or damage to the public space, public-rights-of-way, or public structures may be compensated, which may include the establishment of user fees, including impact and other direct-use fees, charges, and penalties. The regulations shall include provisions governing the appropriate bonding and insurance requirements which must be satisfied by any party who receives a permit issued pursuant to this subchapter, and shall provide for any permittee to provide comprehensive indemnification to the District for any costs or damages which it incurs as a result of actions taken by the permittee in connection with the exercise of any rights or privileges granted in any permit issued pursuant to this subchapter;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provide for the payment of a technology charge or other surcharge to be added to the fee for each permit issued under § 10-1141.03;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Treat the blockage of a sidewalk, bicycle lane, or other pedestrian or bicycle path the same as the closure of a lane of traffic, and in these cases apply similar regulations as that of a closure of a lane of traffic for each permit issued under § 10-1141.03;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Define “safe accommodation,” as it appears in paragraph (8) of this section and in § 10-1141.03, in consultation with the Bicycle Advisory Council and the Pedestrian Advisory Council, which definition shall apply to all permittees and shall ensure the safe and expedient passage of pedestrians and bicyclists; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-1141_04_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Require permittees to submit for approval by the Mayor a traffic management plan that addresses safe accommodation for pedestrians and bicyclists before the issuance of a permit by the Mayor under § 10-1141.03.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
