<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_301">
        <akn:num>10-301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “adopt” means to enter into a binding commitment to a program, site, or operation for not less than 1 year in duration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Parks and Recreation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department activity” means an activity, event, class, program, operation, service, or product for the benefit, enjoyment, education, amusement, or convenience of the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Designated Organizations” means entities designated by the Director pursuant to § 10-137.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fee-based use permit” means a permit issued by the Department to a person for a fee-based Department activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Friends Groups” means an organization, qualified under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3)), and registered under the park partner program, whose mission includes supporting an adopted park or recreation facility by advocating, fundraising, maintaining, and assisting in the planning process for the park or recreation facility adopted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Park Partner Agreement” means the agreement between the Department and the Friends Group explaining the duties, rights, and obligations of the Friends Group.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Planned Unit Development” means a plan for the development of residential, institutional, and commercial developments, industrial parks, urban renewal projects, or a combination of these as defined in the Zoning Regulations of the District of Columbia (11 DCMR § 199).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-301_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “sponsor” means to pledge or promise support to a program, site, or operation on an intermittent, short-term or one-time basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
