<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-509.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-509.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_509_01">
        <akn:num>10-509.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Designation of District employees to protect life and property outside the District; powers of arrest; weapons and uniforms.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-509_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia may designate any employee of the District to protect life and property in and on the buildings and grounds of any institution upon land outside the District acquired by the United States for the District of Columbia for the establishment or operation thereon of any sanitorium, hospital, training school, correctional institution, reformatory, workhouse, or jail; provided, that such employee shall be bonded for the faithful discharge of such duties, and the Council of the District of Columbia shall fix the penalty of any such bond. Whenever any employee is so designated he is hereby authorized and empowered:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-509_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual having the power to arrest as provided in subsection (a) of this section may carry firearms or other weapons and shall wear such uniform with such identification badge as the Mayor may direct or the Council by regulation may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
