<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-801"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-801/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_801">
        <akn:num>10-801</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authorization; description of property; submission and approval of resolution; reacquisition rights; notice.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Council determines that the real property is no longer required for public purposes pursuant to subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor shall attempt to dispose of the real property for a use with a direct public benefit as described in a specific government plan adopted by the Mayor or Council, including the Community Development Plan, the Comprehensive Plan, the Strategic Neighborhood Area Plan, or the Comprehensive Housing Strategy Plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, shall transmit to the Council a proposed resolution that contains the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A proposed resolution to provide for the disposition of real property transmitted to the Council pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be accompanied by the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proposed resolution to provide for the disposition of real property pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 90-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove of the proposed disposition of the property, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 90-day period, the proposed resolution shall be deemed disapproved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Approval of the disposition of the real property by the Council shall expire 2 years after the effective date of the resolution of approval. If the Mayor determines prior to the end of the 2-year period that the property cannot be disposed of within the 2-year period, the Mayor may submit to the Council, no later than 60 days prior to the end of the 2-year period, a resolution seeking additional time for the disposition of the property, and shall include with the resolution a detailed status report on efforts made toward disposition of the property as well as the reasons for the inability to dispose of the property within the 2-year period. If the Council does not take action to approve or disapprove the resolution within 30 days of receipt of the resolution, not including Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, or days of Council recess, the resolution shall be deemed disapproved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_d_2">
      <akn:num>(d-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_d_3">
      <akn:num>(d-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_d_4">
      <akn:num>(d-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_d_5">
      <akn:num>(d-5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of District-owned real property located at the northeast corner of Sixth and E Streets, S.W., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 0036 in Square 0494, for the construction of a mixed-use development, which was approved by the Council pursuant to the Fourth/Sixth and E Streets, S.W., Property Disposition Approval Resolution of 2009, effective November 3, 2009 (Res. 18-290; 56 DCR 8799), as extended by the Fourth/Sixth and E Streets, S.W., Property Disposition Extension Approval Resolution of 2011, effective July 12, 2011 (Res. 19-170; 58 DCR 6589), is extended to November 3, 2017.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall incorporate into the terms of the disposition of real property disposed of through a negotiated sale pursuant to this section, the right of the District to reacquire the property at the price originally conveyed plus any amounts secured by the property that have been approved by the Mayor, if the property is no longer used for the authorized purpose. For property located within the corporate boundaries of the District, if the District does not exercise its reacquisition option, the owner in fee simple shall be entitled to use the property or sell, convey, or otherwise dispose of the property for use in a manner that is consistent with the designation of the real property on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of any real property to be disposed under this section through a request for proposals or competitive sealed proposals, the Mayor shall include economic factors, including revenues, fees, and other payments to the District, as one of the criteria to evaluate the request for proposals or competitive sealed proposals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall take any steps necessary to ensure continuous community input in the disposition of any real property to be disposed of in accordance with this section, which shall include, for property located within the corporate boundaries of the District, providing notice to any affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission of the final terms and conditions for the sale of the property, for review and comment in accordance with § 1-309.10, prior to the disposition of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to any real property which is acquired under § 42-3171.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For real property that the Mayor has determined, after input from affected communities, to be no longer needed by the District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”), the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report on whether the Mayor intends to dispose of the real property to a public charter school under § 38-1802.09 or for use by another agency of the District government. The report shall be submitted to the Council by the Mayor within 90 days of the determination that the real property is no longer needed by the DCPS. If the report is not submitted by the Mayor to the Council within the 90-day period, the Mayor shall dispose of the real property in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter and shall transmit to the Council the resolutions required by subsection (a)(2) of this section within 180 days of the Mayor’s determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, or any rule of law, the Board is authorized to sell and convey the property located at 13th and K Streets, N.W., Lot 808, Square 285, commonly referred to as the Franklin School (“Franklin”) to the H Street Community Development Corporation (“H Street”), and to enter into and execute all agreements necessary to consummate this sale, provided that the Board and H Street have entered into a contract specifying that H Street shall resell and reconvey Franklin to the District of Columbia, for the use of the Board, for an amount equal to the price for which H Street purchased Franklin, once renovations have been completed and all of the Board’s outstanding debts to H Street related to the renovation of Franklin have been discharged. The Board is further authorized and directed to enter into and execute all agreements necessary to consummate the repurchase of Franklin within 90 days of the completion of the renovations and the discharge of the Board’s debts for said renovation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board is authorized to expend an amount not to exceed $4 million for the renovation of Rabaut and 2 other schools for District of Columbia Public Schools administrative offices, excluding Franklin; provided, however, that if these renovation costs are likely to exceed $4 million, the Board must come back to the Council for approval of additional expenditures of appropriated operating funds for these purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All District fees and taxes associated with the Board’s sale and repurchase of Franklin, and H Street’s ownership and renovation of Franklin, shall be waived.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The contractor hired by the Board shall provide an opportunity for students from the District of Columbia Public Schools to participate in vocational training programs with employment opportunities with this renovation project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall not expend any appropriated funds to pay for restoration costs but shall use funds to renovate the building to meet minimum occupancy requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this subchapter shall not apply to real property acquired by the District or an instrumentality of the District (or a subsidiary thereof) under § 47-1353(a)(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-801_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The net proceeds from the disposition of the McMillan Sand Filtration Site approved by the McMillan Residential Townhomes Parcel Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-705; 62 DCR 1091), the McMillan Residential Multifamily Parcels Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-706; 62 DCR 1094), and the McMillan Commercial Parcel Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-707; 62 DCR 1097), shall not be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia but instead shall be deposited into the capital fund account associated with the McMillan Site Redevelopment, EB0-AMS11C.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
