<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-803.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/10-803.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_10_803_01">
        <akn:num>10-803.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Unused and underutilized public school buildings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than one year after the effective date of this section, the Mayor shall report to the Council on the feasibility of selling, conveying, or leasing real property owned in fee simple or leased by the District of Columbia that is no longer required for public purposes to Qualified High Technology Companies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than one year after the effective of this section, the Superintendent of the District of Columbia Public Schools (“Superintendent”) shall conduct a study of unused or underutilized buildings within the public school system and report the results to the Mayor and Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may lease, directly or through a sponsor of a Qualified High Technology Company, real property, or portions thereof, which are not required for public purposes to a Qualified High Technology Company at reasonable below-market rates. The Mayor shall promulgate regulations setting forth the method of determining whether properties owned or leased by the District of Columbia are not required for public purposes and the terms on which such properties may be leased under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor and the Superintendent shall convene a summit to facilitate the internships and jobs described in subsection (e)(2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10-803_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall affect the preference for public charter schools in leasing or purchasing public school facilities, as set forth in § 38-1802.09.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
