<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1022"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1022/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1022">
        <akn:num>26-1022</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1022_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may institute an administrative cease and desist proceeding if the Superintendent [Commissioner] determines that a licensee or person required to have a license under this chapter or an authorized delegate has violated, is violating, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter or any rule, regulation or order imposed by the Superintendent [Commissioner], or written agreement entered into with the Superintendent [Commissioner] pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1022_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1022_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A cease and desist order may require the person licensed, or required to be licensed, or authorized delegate to cease and desist the violation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1022_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may issue and serve upon the licensee, or person required to be licensed, or authorized delegate a final cease and desist order if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1022_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A final cease and desist order shall become effective 10 days after the service of the order in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, except that a final cease and desist order which has been issued upon consent shall become effective upon the date specified in the order. A final cease and desist order shall remain in effect until it is stayed, modified, terminated, or set aside by the Superintendent [Commissioner] or a reviewing court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
