<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1018"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1018/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1018">
        <akn:num>26-1018</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Revocation or suspension of authorized delegates.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1018_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, after notice and a hearing, the Superintendent [Commissioner] finds that an authorized delegate of a licensee or any director, officer, employee, or controlling person of the authorized delegate (1) has violated any provision of this chapter or of any rule or regulation or order issued under this chapter, (2) has engaged or participated in any unsafe or unsound act with respect to the business of selling or issuing payment instruments of the licensee or the business of money transmission, (3) has willfully violated any provision of the regulations set forth in 31 C.F.R. Part 103, or (4) has made, or caused to be made in any application or report filed with the Superintendent [Commissioner] or in any proceeding before the Superintendent [Commissioner], any statement which was at the time and in the circumstances under which it was made, false or misleading with respect to any material fact, or has omitted to state in any such application or report any material fact which is required to be stated therein, the Superintendent [Commissioner] may issue an order suspending or barring the authorized delegate from continuing to be, or becoming, an authorized delegate of any licensee during the period for which the order is in effect. Upon issuance of the order, the licensee shall terminate its relationship with the authorized delegate according to the terms of the order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1018_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An authorized delegate to whom an order is issued under this section may apply to the Superintendent [Commissioner] to modify or rescind such order. The Superintendent [Commissioner] shall not grant such application unless the Superintendent [Commissioner] finds that it is in the public interest to do so and that it is reasonable to believe that such person will, if such person is permitted to resume being an authorized delegate of a licensee, comply with all applicable provisions of this chapter and of any regulation or order issued under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
