<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1112"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1112/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1112">
        <akn:num>26-1112</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Examinations and investigations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner], or his or her designated agent, shall examine the affairs, business, premises, and records of each licensee at least once in every 3 year period and at any other time the Superintendent [Commissioner] reasonably considers necessary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the course of any investigation or examination, the owners, member, officers, directors, partners, and any employees of such mortgage lender or mortgage broker being investigated or examined shall afford the Superintendent [Commissioner] full access to all premises, books, and records. For the foregoing purposes, the Superintendent [Commissioner], or his or her designated agent, shall have authority to administer oaths, examine under oath all the aforementioned persons, compel the production of papers and objects of all kinds, subpoena documents or other evidence, and summons and examine under oath any person whose testimony the Superintendent [Commissioner] requires.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When it becomes necessary to examine or investigate the books and records of a licensee required to be licensed under this chapter at a location outside the Washington, D.C. metropolitan region, the licensee shall be liable for, and shall pay to the Superintendent [Commissioner] within 30 days, the actual travel and reasonable living expenses incurred on account of its examination, supervision, and regulation, or shall pay a reasonable per diem rate approved by the Superintendent [Commissioner].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To carry out the purposes of this section, the Commissioner may do any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall remain in effect whether such licensee, or person subject to this chapter, acts or claims to act under any licensing or registration law of the District of Columbia, or claims to act without such authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No licensee, or person subject to investigation or examination under this section, shall knowingly withhold, abstract, remove, mutilate, destroy, or secrete any books, records, computer records, or other information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1112_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All examination fees shall be prescribed by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
