<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1118"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1118/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1118">
        <akn:num>26-1118</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Suspension, revocation, and enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1118_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may suspend or revoke the license of any licensee if the licensee or any owner, director, officer, member, partner, stockholder, employee, or agent of the licensee, while acting on behalf of the licensee:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1118_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1118_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may request the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia to take appropriate action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the enforcement of an order issued under this section. The Corporation Counsel may also seek, and the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may order or decree, damages and such other relief allowed by law, including restitution. Persons entitled to any relief as authorized by this section shall be identified by order of the court within 180 days after the date of the order permanently enjoining the unlawful act or practice. In any action brought by the Corporation Counsel by virtue of this provision, the Corporation Counsel shall be entitled to seek attorney’s fees and costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1118_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed under subsection (b) of this section, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall consider the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1118_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to preclude any individual or entity who suffers loss as a result of any violation of this chapter from maintaining an action to recover damages or restitution and, as provided by statute, attorney’s fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
