<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1201"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1201/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1201">
        <akn:num>26-1201</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Acquire” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Association” means a mutual or capital stock savings and loan association, building and loan association, or savings bank chartered under the laws of any 1 of the states or by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board pursuant to the federal act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Branch” or “branch office” means any office or other fixed location where an association has the authority to accept deposits and make loans, except:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Company” means “company” as defined in 12 U.S.C. § 1730a(a)(1)(C) [repealed] (“National Housing Act”).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Control” means “control” as defined in 12 U.S.C. § 1730a(a)(2) [repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Deposit” means any demand, time, or savings deposit, savings share account, withdrawable or repurchasable share, investment certificate, or other savings account or savings deposit account made by an individual, corporation, partnership, state or federal governmental unit, or any other organization, without regard to the location of the depositor. The term “deposit” shall not include a deposit by a foreign government, foreign official institution, or other associations. For purposes of this chapter, determination of deposits shall be made by reference to regulatory reports made by or to state or federal regulatory authorities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District association” means an association organized under the laws of the District or a federal association that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District savings and loan holding company” means a savings and loan holding company that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal act” means the Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933, approved June 13, 1933 (48 Stat. 128; 12 U.S.C. 1461 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal association” means an association chartered by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board pursuant to the federal act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low- and moderate-income area” means any area within the District that the Superintendent [Commissioner], by rule, designates as a low- and moderate-income area after consideration of the income levels of residents within the area and the mix and locations of the levels of income of residents within the area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonregional association” means any association that is neither a District association nor a regional association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonregional savings and loan holding company” means any savings and loan holding company that is neither a District savings and loan holding company nor a regional savings and loan holding company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual or a company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Principal place of business of an association” means the state in which the aggregate deposits of the association are the largest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Principal place of business of a savings and loan holding company” means the state where the total deposits held by the offices of the association subsidiaries of the savings and loan holding company are the largest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Region” means the states of Alabama, Arkansas, Delaware, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Maryland, Mississippi, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, South Carolina, Tennessee, Virginia, and West Virginia, and the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Regional association” means an association other than a District association, organized under the laws of 1 of the states in the region or under the laws of the United States that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Regional savings and loan holding company” means a savings and loan holding company other than a District savings and loan holding company that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Savings and loan holding company” means any company that directly or indirectly controls an association or any other company which is a savings and loan holding company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Service corporation” means any corporation, the majority of the capital stock of which is owned by 1 or more associations, that engages, directly or indirectly, in any activity which may be engaged in by a service corporation under the laws of 1 of the states or under the laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means any state of the United States or the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subsidiary” means “subsidiary” as defined in 12 U.S.C. § 1730a(a)(1)(H) [repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Superintendent” means the Superintendent of Banking and Financial Institutions [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Target development area” means any low- and moderate-income area within the District or any area which the Superintendent [Commissioner], by rule, designates as an underserved area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Target economic development project” means any commercial, industrial, residential real estate, business, or other economic development activity that the Superintendent [Commissioner], in consultation with the Council and the District of Columbia Office of Business and Economic Development (“OBED”), determines to be beneficial to residents in low- and moderate-income areas or small businesses in low- and moderate-income areas based on policies set forth in the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan of 1984, effective April 10, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-76; 31 DCR 1049), and placing special emphasis on economic development project activity in economically distressed areas which have been historically underserved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Underserved area” means any area which the Superintendent [Commissioner], in consultation with the Council and OBED designates as an “underserved area” based on the availability of deposit, loan, and credit services within the area to satisfy housing and small business needs or the availability and need for other financial services within the area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1201_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Women-owned” means that at least 51% of the savings and loan association is owned by a woman or women who make the policy decisions and actually manage day-to-day operations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
