<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1401.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1401.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1401_02">
        <akn:num>26-1401.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Appropriate federal financial institutions agency” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bank holding company” shall have the same meaning as set forth in section 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, approved May 9, 1956 (70 Stat. 133; 12 U.S.C. § 1841(a)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(6).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital accounts” means unimpaired capital stock, unimpaired surplus, and undivided profits or retained earnings of a financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital stock” means the aggregate of shares of nonwithdrawable capital stock issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(7).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community Reinvestment Act” means the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977, approved October 12, 1977 (91 Stat. 1147; 12 U.S.C. § 2901 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(9).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(10).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District of Columbia Banking Code” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.01(14).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District savings institution” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(15).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Equity securities” means a security representing an ownership interest in a corporation.or independent agency head</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal agency” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(17).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal financial institutions agency” means a federal government agency with regulatory authority over a financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federally chartered savings institutions” means a financial institution chartered by the Office of Thrift Supervision, or a successor agency to the Office of Thrift Supervision.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial institution” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(18).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment securities” means commercial paper, banker’s acceptances, marketable securities in the form of bonds, notes, and debentures, and similar instruments that are regarded as investment securities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Loan” includes a line of credit or other extension of credit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low-income” means an individual income that is less than 60% of the median individual income for the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area according to the statistics of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development or a median family income that is less than 60% of the median family income for the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area according to the statistics of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Moderate-income” means an individual income that is at least 60%, and less than 80%, of the median individual income for the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area according to the statistics of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, or a median family income that is at least 60%, and less than 80%, of the median family income for the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area according to the statistics of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“National bank” means a financial institution chartered and supervised by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, or a successor agency to the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(21).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Savings institution” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(23).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State bank” means a bank chartered and supervised by a financial institutions agency of a state of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State financial institutions agency” means a government agency of a state of the United States authorized to charter and supervise financial institutions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subsidiary” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(24).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Superior Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_02_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Universal bank” means a financial institution which is authorized by its articles of incorporation or other organizational documents to act as a financial institution and is certified under this chapter as a universal bank.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
