<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1204"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1204/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1204">
        <akn:num>26-1204</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Conditions for regional acquisitions and regional branches.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1204_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When not inconsistent with federal law, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall require each association or savings and loan holding company seeking to make an acquisition under § 26-1202 or seeking to branch under § 26-1203 to file information applicable to the nature of the application, a general plan of business, a proposed plan for capital investment in the District, and a community development program. In determining whether and to what extent the submissions are appropriate, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall consider the overall purposes and resources of the savings and loan industry. The community development program shall set forth the applicant’s plan to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1204_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To the extent considered appropriate by the Superintendent [Commissioner], the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall require that an applicant seeking to make an acquisition under § 26-1202 or seeking to branch under § 26-1203 provide the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1204_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of determining compliance with the requirements of this section, loans may include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1204_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1204_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] shall rule on any application submitted under §§ 26-1202 and 26-1203 no later than 90 days following the date of submission of a complete application, but the ruling may be conditioned upon approval by federal regulatory authorities or contain other appropriate conditions. The Superintendent [Commissioner] may extend the 90-day period for up to 30 days. If the Superintendent [Commissioner] fails to rule on the application within the 90-day period, or any extension, the application shall be deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1204_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of § 26-1202(a)(1) through (3) and § 26-1202(c)(1) and (2), a District association shall be treated as if it were a District savings and loan holding company if the laws of the state where the acquiring association or savings and loan holding company has its principal place of business would permit the regional association or a regional savings and loan holding company to be acquired by a District savings and loan holding company, but not by a District association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
