<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1205"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1205/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1205">
        <akn:num>26-1205</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authorization of nonregional acquisitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Ninety days after October 12, 1988, a nonregional association or a nonregional savings and loan holding company may acquire, on the approval of the Superintendent [Commissioner]:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before granting approval, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall determine that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Once an area has been designated as a “target development area” or once a project has been determined to be a “target economic development project” and identified by an applicant in an application that is approved pursuant to this section, that designation or determination is final for the applicant and any future revision in the designation of target development areas or target economic development projects shall have no effect on the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may reduce or extend the time within which an association or savings and loan holding company shall satisfy any commitment made in connection with an application filed pursuant to this section if the Superintendent [Commissioner] finds that the commitment was contingent upon certain action to be taken by the District that the District has not taken or the economic or financial conditions of the association or savings and loan holding company justify the action and the savings and loan holding company justifies the action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any District association or District savings and loan holding company may elect not to be acquired pursuant to this section by passing a resolution to that effect by its board of directors and shareholders or board of directors and members. The resolution shall be forwarded to the Superintendent [Commissioner] within 60 days after its adoption. No acquisition of an association or savings and loan holding company, which has timely filed a resolution, shall be allowed by the Superintendent [Commissioner], unless notice is given to the Superintendent [Commissioner], at the time an application is filed, that the resolution has been withdrawn or reversed by vote of the board of directors and shareholders or board of directors and members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the provisions of this section, a District association organized under the laws of the District may consolidate or merge with, transfer all or substantially all of its assets to, or effect a statutory merger with a nonregional association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1205_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] shall list applications for acquisitions pursuant to this section in the Superintendent’s [Commissioner’s] periodic bulletin published in the District of Columbia Register.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
