<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1103"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1103/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1103">
        <akn:num>26-1103</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>License requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To qualify for a license, an applicant shall satisfy the Superintendent [Commissioner] that the applicant, including its members, officers, directors, and principals is of good moral character and has sufficient financial responsibility, business experience, and general fitness to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for a mortgage loan originator’s license shall have a sponsor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may deny an application for a license to any person who has committed any act prior to the granting of the license that would be a ground for suspension or revocation of a license under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall deny an application if the applicant has:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To apply for a license an applicant shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The application shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With each application for licensure, the applicant shall pay the applicable fees prescribed by the Commissioner and any third-party fees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may, from time to time, increase or decrease the fees set forth in this section. The fees shall be fixed at such rates, and computed on such bases and in such manner as may, in the judgment of the Superintendent [Commissioner], be necessary to defray the approximate costs of carrying out the regulatory functions set forth in this chapter. These fees shall not be abated by surrender, suspension, or revocation of a license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For each license for which an applicant applies, the applicant shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_h_1">
      <akn:num>(h-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_h_2">
      <akn:num>(h-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may waive or defer any licensing requirement, other than requirements mandated by 12 U.S.C. § 5105, 5106, and 5108(d), for good cause shown in writing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for an original license or for the renewal of a license shall file a surety bond with each original application and any renewal application for the license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1103_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a Financial Services endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
