<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1401.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1401.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1401_12">
        <akn:num>26-1401.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Limitations on loan power of universal banks.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A universal bank shall not make loans under § 26-1401.09(a)(2) through the universal bank, or a subsidiary of the universal bank, in an aggregate amount that exceeds 20% of the universal bank’s capital; provided, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A loan made under § 26-1401.09(a)(2) shall require the prior approval of the board of directors or other governing board of the universal bank or its subsidiary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An equity interest or other form of interest taken as security in a project funded through a loan made under § 26-1401.09(a)(3) shall require the prior approval of the board of directors or other governing board of the universal bank or its subsidiary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may suspend a universal bank’s authority under § 26-1401.09(a)(2) or (3) if the Commissioner determines that the universal bank is not exercising, or will not exercise, authority under § 26-1401.09(a)(2) or (3) in a safe and sound manner or that the condition of the universal bank is not, or will not be, safe and sound. In making a determination to suspend a universal bank’s authority under this subsection, the Commissioner shall consider the universal bank’s capital adequacy, asset quality, earnings quantity, earnings quality, adequacy of liquidity, and sensitivity to market risk; the ability of the management of the universal bank; and any other factor the Commissioner determines is appropriate. If the Commissioner suspends the authority of a universal bank under this subsection, the Commissioner may specify how the universal bank or its subsidiary shall treat an outstanding loan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A universal bank shall not purchase foreign bonds unless the Commissioner promulgates a rule authorizing the purchase of foreign bonds by universal banks; provided, that a universal bank may purchase a general obligation bond issued by a foreign national government if the bond is payable in United States funds. The Commissioner shall not promulgate a rule under this subsection authorizing a universal bank to invest in foreign bonds issued by a single issuer in an aggregate amount that exceeds 10% of the universal bank’s capital.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A universal bank shall not consider any health information obtained from the records of an affiliate of the universal bank that is engaged in the business of insurance in the universal bank’s determination of whether to make a loan under § 26-1401.09(a)(2) or in the determination of whether to make any other loan, unless the person to whom the health information relates consents to the consideration of the health information in the universal bank’s determination of whether to make the loan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A universal bank shall not loan any part of its capital, surplus, or deposits on its own capital stock, notes, or debentures as collateral security; provided, that a universal bank may make a loan secured by its own capital stock, notes, or debentures to the same extent that the universal bank may make a loan secured by the capital stock, notes, and debentures of a holding company for the universal bank.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1401_12_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The restrictions and limits in subsections (a), (e), and (f) of this section shall not apply to a liability:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
