<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1151.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-1151.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_1151_01">
        <akn:num>26-1151.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Annual percentage rate” means the annual percentage rate for the mortgage loan calculated according to the provisions of the Truth in Lending Act, the regulations promulgated thereunder by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the official staff commentary thereto.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Assessed value” means the full market value of real property for assessment and taxation purposes as determined by the Office of Tax and Revenue and in effect on the applicable date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bona fide loan discount points” means loan discount points which are knowingly paid by the borrower for the express purpose of reducing, and which reduce, the annual percentage rate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Borrower” means each accommodation party, borrower, co-borrower, cosigner, co-maker, obligor, mortgagor, or guarantor obligated to repay a loan that is secured by a lien instrument.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bridge loan” means a loan that has a term of less than one year and that only requires that payments of interest be made until the entire unpaid balance becomes due.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(7).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(9).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gross income” means a borrower’s gross income as set forth in a mortgage loan application and by a borrower, the borrower’s financial statement, a credit report, financial information provided to the lender on behalf of the borrower, or as determined by any other reasonable means available to a lender, including a signed statement of the borrower; provided, that the borrower certifies the accuracy of the statement of his or her income and provides documentation that evidences such gross income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Lender” means any person to whom the obligation is initially payable, either under the terms of the note or contract, or by agreement if there is no note or contract. The term “lender” shall include a mortgage broker, obligee, or mortgagee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Lien instrument” means a deed of trust; mortgage; security agreement; trust deed; land installment contract; contract for a deed; assignment of lease, rent, or profit; or any other conveyance or retention of an interest in real property or personal property related to real property, including cooperative housing units and garage spaces, which secures the performance of a note or other obligation and creates a lien on real property or security interest in personal property. The term “lien instrument” shall include an amendment, modification, supplement, replacement, or restatement of a lien instrument.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mortgage broker” shall have the same meaning as in § 26-1101(10).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Note” means a promissory note secured by a deed of trust, a promissory note or mortgage bond secured by a mortgage, or any other written evidence of indebtedness or obligation secured by a lien instrument.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Notice” means a written notice that describes with reasonable clarity the specific act, event, or default and the response that the notice sender is seeking from the addressee or other party obligated to the sender of the notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Origination/discount points and fees” means points and fees as defined in 12 C.F.R. § 226.32(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, governmental subdivision or agency, business trust, estate, trustee for a trust, partnership, association, limited liability company, joint venture, government, or any other legal or commercial entity or agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Point” means, when referring to a fee, one percent applied to a portion of a loan amount.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Principal balance” means the principal amount of a note.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Real property” means real property in the District and interests in real property located in the District, including the stock of a cooperative housing corporation and associated residential lease of a cooperative housing unit or garage space.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Red Flag Warning Disclosure Notice” means the notice provided for by § 26-1152.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential real property” means real property in the District improved by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Servicer” shall have the same meaning as in section 6(i)(2) of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974, approved November 28, 1990 (104 Stat. 4405; 12 U.S.C. § 2605(i)(2)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subsidiary”, with respect to a specified bank holding company, means a company:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Supervising federal agency” means the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Federal Reserve Board, or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-1151_01_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Truth in Lending Act” means the Truth in Lending Act, approved May 29, 1968 (82 Stat. 146; 15 U.S.C. § 1601 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
