<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-431.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-431.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_431_02">
        <akn:num>26-431.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“CFO” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, established by § 1-204.24a.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community development” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_1B">
      <akn:num>(1B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community development loan” means a loan that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community Reinvestment Act” shall mean the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977, approved October 12, 1977 (91 Stat. 1147; 12 U.S.C. § 2901 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(7).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(9).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Deposit-receiving institution” means a federal, state, or District chartered bank, savings institution, or credit union that receives after March 11, 2015, District contracts pursuant to §§ 47-351.02(c) and 47-351.03, including any chartered bank, savings institution, or credit union that has applied to be or is regulated, supervised, examined, or licensed by the Department or a District chartered bank that is engaged in activity covered by §§ 47-351.02(c) and 47- 351.03; except, that the provision of services provided for and deposits made with regard to District debt transactions does not create a deposit-receiving institution, notwithstanding that deposit receiving institutions may provide those services or receive those deposits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Designated development areas” means any of the following located in the District:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Elderly resident” means a District resident 55 years of age or older.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal financial supervisory agency” means the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of Thrift Supervision and any successor to any of the foregoing agencies, as applicable to the specific type of bank.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial institution” shall have the same meaning as in § 26-551.02(18).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low-income” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-1401.02(21).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low-income area” means a census tract or block numbering area in which the median individual or family income does not exceed 65% of the median income of the Washington, D.C., metropolitan area as determined by the statistics of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Moderate-income” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-1401.02(22).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Moderate-income area” means a census tract or block numbering area in which the median individual or family income does not exceed 80% of the median income for the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area as determined by the statistics of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Minority group” means African-Americans, Hispanic-Americans, Latinos, Asian-Americans, Pacific Islander-Americans, American Indians, Native Americans, or Alaskan-Natives.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Minority-owned business” means a business in which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mortgage loan” means a loan that is secured by residential real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_14A">
      <akn:num>(14A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified investments” means a lawful investment, deposit, membership share, or grant that has as its primary purpose community development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Small business loan” means a small business loan as defined in Federal Reserve System Regulation BB, 12 C.F.R. Part 228.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-431_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Women-owned business” means a business in which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
