<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-551.17"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-551.17/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_551_17">
        <akn:num>26-551.17</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Temporary cease and desist order.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_17_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Along with a notice of charges, or after the issuance of a notice of charges, the Commissioner may issue a temporary cease and desist order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_17_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may issue a temporary cease and desist order if the Commissioner determines that a violation or unsafe or unsound practice is likely to cause:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_17_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The temporary cease and desist order may require a financial institution or its affiliate or subsidiary to immediately cease and desist from a violation or unsafe or unsound practice and to take affirmative action to prevent an occurrence set forth in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (b) of this section pending completion of investigatory proceedings under this chapter. If a notice of charges issued under ยง 26-551.13 states that the books and records of a financial institution are so incomplete or inaccurate that the Commissioner is unable to determine the financial condition of the institution or to ascertain the details or purpose of a transaction, the Commissioner may issue a temporary cease and desist order that requires the financial institution to cease an activity or practice which caused or contributed to the incomplete or inaccurate state of the books or records or take affirmative action to restore the books or records to a complete and accurate state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_17_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A temporary cease and desist order shall be effective upon service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_17_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A temporary cease and desist order shall remain in effect until:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
