<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-551.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-551.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_551_02">
        <akn:num>26-551.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means a financial institution holding company under federal law or a subsidiary or service corporation of a financial institution holding company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Appropriate federal financial institutions agency” means the federal agency with statutory authority over the financial institution activities of a financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bank” means an institution that engages in the business of banking, including a trust company, savings bank, savings and loan association, and credit union.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bank holding company” shall have the same meaning as set forth in section 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, approved May 9, 1956 (70 Stat. 133; 12 U.S.C. § 1841(a)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business of banking” means activities and transactions involving banking, including: (A) receiving deposits, paying checks, and lending money; (B) activities of a bank which are supervised by the Commissioner; and (C) activities incidental, necessary, or convenient to banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital” means capital deposits, surplus, and undivided earnings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Controlling interest” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Credit union” means a financial institution organized as a cooperative association with a limited membership and operating with insurance provided by the National Credit Union Administration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means a director or trustee of an organization or a person with functions similar to the functions of a director or trustee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District bank” means a bank chartered or organized under the District of Columbia Banking Code and under the authority and supervision of the Commissioner or a bank authorized to do business under the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District credit union” means a credit union chartered or organized under the District of Columbia Banking Code and under the authority and supervision of the Commissioner or a credit union authorized to do business under the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District of Columbia Banking Code” means the statutory provisions concerning banking and financial institutions which are codified in Title 26 of the District of Columbia Official Code, laws administered by the Commissioner, and rules and regulations promulgated under those statutory provisions and laws.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District savings institution” means a savings institution chartered or organized under the District of Columbia Banking Code and under the authority and supervision of the Commissioner or a savings institution authorized to do business under the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Executive officer” means a person who participates or has authority to participate, other than in the capacity of a director, in major policymaking functions of a financial institution, whether or not the person has an official title or receives compensation from the financial institution. The term “executive officer” shall not include a person who may exercise discretion in the performance of duties and functions, including discretion in the making of loans, if the person’s exercise of discretion is limited by policy standards adopted by the board of directors of the financial institution and the person does not participate in major policymaking functions of the financial institution. The chair of the board, the president, chief executive officer, chief operating officer, chief financial officer, every executive vice president of a financial institution, and the senior trust officer of a trust company shall be presumed to be executive officers unless the person is excluded, by resolution of the board of directors or by the bylaws of the financial institution, from participating, other than in the capacity of a director, in major policymaking functions of the financial institution and the person does not actually participate in major policymaking functions of the financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal agency” means an agency of the United States of America.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial institution” means a bank, savings institution, credit union, foreign bank, trust company, non-depository financial institution, or any other person which is regulated, supervised, examined, or licensed by the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking; which has applied to be regulated, supervised, examined, or licensed by the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking; which is subject to the regulation, supervision, examination, or licensure by the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking; or which is engaged in an activity covered by the District of Columbia Banking Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Non-depository financial institution” means a financial institution that is engaged in a regulated activity and that is not a bank or credit union.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Order” means an approval, consent, authorization, exemption, denial, prohibition, requirement, or other administrative action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, trust, joint venture, company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, pool syndicate, sole proprietorship, unincorporated organization, fiduciary business, or any other similar entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Regulated activity” means an activity authorized and regulated under the District of Columbia Banking Code and under the authority and supervision of the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Savings institution” means a savings and loan association or savings bank.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subsidiary” means a company in which a person owns at least a majority of the shares or equity interest or which the person controls.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
