<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-551.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-551.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_551_05">
        <akn:num>26-551.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>General powers and responsibilities of the Commissioner.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall be responsible for the performance of all duties, the exercise of all powers and jurisdiction, and the assumption and discharge of all responsibilities vested by law in the Department or the Commissioner. The Commissioner shall have all powers necessary or convenient for the administration and enforcement of the District of Columbia Banking Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may promulgate rules and regulations necessary or appropriate to the execution of the Commissioner’s powers, duties, and responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may enter into agreements that the Commissioner considers necessary or appropriate to the exercise of his or her powers, including agreements with agencies or instrumentalities of the District, states and territories of the United States of America, or the federal government, for the examination of banks, savings institutions, credit unions, trust companies, and other financial institutions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner, in the performance of the duties and responsibilities of the Department, may enter into contracts with the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Office of Thrift Supervision, the National Credit Union Administration, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, District agencies, other state or federal banking agencies, or any other entity, for those services necessary to carry out the duties and responsibilities of the Commissioner and the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-551_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission may establish and modify fees to implement the District of Columbia Banking Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
