<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-640"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-640/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_640">
        <akn:num>26-640</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Reports and records.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international banking corporation that maintains one or more international banking corporation offices or an international financing corporation under this chapter shall, at the times and in the form prescribed by the Commissioner, file written reports in the English language for such offices or corporation with the Commissioner under the oath of one of its officers, managers, or agents transacting business in the District of Columbia, showing the amount of its assets and liabilities and containing any other matters required by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international banking corporation that maintains 2 or more international banking corporation offices may consolidate the information in one report unless the Commissioner requires otherwise for purposes of the Commissioner’s supervision of the condition and operations of each office. The late filing of the reports shall be subject to the imposition of an administrative penalty prescribed by regulation. If an international banking corporation shall fail to file a report as directed by the Commissioner, or if a report shall contain any false statement knowingly made, it shall be grounds for revocation of the license of the international banking corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall, by regulation, prescribe the circumstances under which the Commissioner may require an international banking corporation to use internal or external auditors to address significant supervisory concerns with respect to the operations of an international branch or agency licensed in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international banking corporation which operates an agency or branch licensed under this chapter shall maintain, at a location accepted by the Commissioner:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other reports it may be required to file, an international banking corporation which maintains an international agency or international branch in the District of Columbia shall file reports with the Commissioner in form and at such times as the Commissioner prescribes, by regulation, concerning the management, asset quality, capital adequacy, and liquidity of the international banking corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international banking corporation that maintains a representative office in the District of Columbia licensed under this chapter shall make, maintain, and preserve at the office or at such other place as determined by the Commissioner, such books, accounts, and other records relating to the activities conducted at the office as the Commissioner may require. An international banking corporation which is licensed to establish and maintain a representative office shall file the reports accompanied by a reasonable fee, as required and determined by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may require such regular or special reports as the Commissioner considers necessary for the proper supervision of licensees. The additional reports shall be in the form prescribed by the Commissioner and shall be subscribed and affirmed as true under penalty of perjury.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-640_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an international banking corporation shall fail to make a report as directed by the Commissioner, it shall be subject to the penalties prescribed by regulation. A false statement contained in a report, in any other sworn statement made to the Commissioner by such report, or in any other sworn statement made to the Commissioner by the international banking corporation under the provisions of this chapter shall constitute perjury.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
