<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-635"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-635/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_635">
        <akn:num>26-635</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Scope of license; permissible activities of international banking corporations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the provisions of this chapter, an international representative office may act in the District of Columbia in a liaison capacity with existing and potential customers of an international banking corporation and its subsidiaries and affiliates. It may, through its employees or agents, solicit loans; assemble credit information; make proprietary inspections and appraisals; assist in completing loan applications and other preliminary paperwork in preparation for making a loan; administer personnel and operations; engage in data processing or recordkeeping activities; provide information to customers concerning their accounts; answer questions; receive applications for extensions of credit and other banking services; transmit documents on behalf of customers; make arrangements for customers to transact business on their accounts; service loans or extensions of credit and investments; solicit, but not accept, deposits; and engage in such other activities as the Commissioner may approve by order or regulation. An international representative office may not conduct any banking business, or part of a banking business, in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international banking corporation may, with the approval of the Commissioner under the District of Columbia Banking Code, acquire control over or organize a bank organized under the laws of the District of Columbia. For the purposes of this section, the term “bank” shall have the same meaning as set forth in section 2(c) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, approved May 9, 1956 (70 Stat. 133; 12 U.S.C. § 1841(c)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A bank established by an international banking corporation and chartered outside the District of Columbia may establish a branch in the District of Columbia; provided, that the branch shall be subject to the same laws, rules, regulations, and oversight as a bank branch of a domestic financial institution chartered outside the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international banking corporation that has established a branch, agency, or representative office outside the District of Columbia may establish and operate, directly or indirectly, an international branch, an international agency, or an international representative office in the District of Columbia in accordance with applicable District of Columbia law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An international financing corporation established under this chapter shall directly engage only in those activities permissible for corporations organized under the Edge Act. Subject to the prior approval of the Commissioner and to such limitations as the Commissioner shall prescribe by regulation, the fact that an international financing corporation invests in shares of, and owns or controls, an Edge Act corporation, an international banking corporation, or a company engaged in financial activities outside the United States, or establishes and operates branches, representative offices, and similar banking facilities in foreign countries, shall not prohibit their operation in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-635_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not be construed to prohibit an international banking corporation which does not maintain an office in the District of Columbia from transacting the following business:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
