<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-631"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-631/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_631">
        <akn:num>26-631</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Banking business” means activities and transactions involving banking, including receiving deposits, paying checks, lending money, and any activity which is determined by the Commissioner to be incidental to the business of banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(7).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § 26-551.02(9).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District of Columbia Banking Code” means the statutory provisions concerning banking and financial institutions which are codified in Title 26 of the District of Columbia Official Code, any law administered by the Commissioner, and rules and regulations promulgated under those statutory provisions and laws.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Edge Act” means the Federal Reserve Act, approved December 23, 1913 (38 Stat. 351; 12 U.S.C. § 221  et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal agency” means an agency of an international banking corporation established and operating under the Federal International Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal branch” means a branch of an international banking corporation established and operating under the Federal International Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal International Act” means the International Banking Act of 1978, approved September 17, 1978 (92 Stat. 607; 12 U.S.C. § 3101 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal international bank office” means a branch or agency of an international banking corporation established and operating under the Federal International “ct.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign country” means a country other than the United States, including a dependency or possession of such country, and any territory of the United States, including Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International agency” means an office located in the District of Columbia, other than a federal international bank office, which exercises powers, as set forth in § 26-635, on behalf of an international banking corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International banking corporation” means a banking corporation organized and licensed under the laws of a foreign country. The term “international banking corporation” shall include an international commercial bank, foreign merchant bank, foreign mortgage bank, or other foreign institution that engages in banking activities in connection with the business of banking in the country where the foreign institution is organized or operating.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International banking corporation office” means, unless otherwise specified, an office established in the District of Columbia under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International branch” means an office located in the District of Columbia, other than a federal international bank office, which exercises powers, as set forth in § 26-635, on behalf of an international banking corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International financing corporation” means a corporation organized under the laws of the District of Columbia for the purpose of engaging in the activities described in § 26-635.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International representative office” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Representative” means a person or entity located in an office in the District of Columbia that engages in any activity in the District of Columbia for or on behalf of an international banking corporation, which activity is not otherwise prohibited by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-631_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States or the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
