<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-712"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-712/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_712">
        <akn:num>26-712</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administrative procedure; cease and desist orders.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-712_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-712_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Notice of Charges shall set forth the basis for the administrative action and shall set a time and place for a hearing to determine whether a cease and desist order shall issue based on the Notice of Charges. The hearing shall be held within 60 days after the service of the Notice of Charges unless another date is set by the hearing officer at the request of 1 of the parties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-712_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event of a consent or default or if, upon the record at the hearing, the Superintendent [Commissioner] finds that any violation or practice alleged in the Notice of Charges is established by a preponderance of the evidence, the Superintendent [Commissioner] may issue an order to cease and desist from the violation or practice. The order may require the bank or person or director, officer, employee, agent, or other person who participates in the conduct of the affairs of the bank or person to cease and desist from the violation or practice, and take affirmative action to correct the violation or practice or any condition that results from the violation or practice. The affirmative action may include indemnification, reimbursement, restitution, or any other relief that the Superintendent [Commissioner] deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-712_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The cease and desist order shall become effective 30 days after service or, in the case of consent, shall become effective immediately. The order shall remain effective and enforceable unless the order is stayed, modified, terminated, or set aside by the Superintendent [Commissioner] or a reviewing court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-712_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, in the opinion of the Superintendent [Commissioner], a violation or practice or threatened violation or practice of this subchapter or ยง 26-103 is likely to cause insolvency, substantial dissipation of the assets or earnings of the bank or person, or serious prejudice to the interests of the depositors or customers of the bank or person, the Superintendent [Commissioner], through the Office of the Corporation Counsel, may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
