<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-706.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/26-706.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_26_706_01">
        <akn:num>26-706.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Alternative entry by acquisition.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-706_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subchapter, 90 days after April 11, 1986, any nonregional bank holding company may make application to the Superintendent [Commissioner] for approval to acquire:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-706_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant under this section shall be required to demonstrate to the Superintendent [Commissioner] that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-706_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-706_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may reduce or extend the time within which a bank holding company shall satisfy any commitment made in connection with an application filed pursuant to this section, if the Superintendent [Commissioner] finds that the commitment was contingent upon certain action to be taken by the District and the District does not take the action, or, upon good cause shown, the economic or financial conditions of the bank holding company justifies the action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-706_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any District bank holding company or District bank may choose not to be acquired pursuant to this section by having a resolution to that effect passed by its board of directors and shareholders. The resolution shall be forwarded to the Superintendent [Commissioner] within 60 days after its adoption. No acquisition of a bank or bank holding company which has timely filed such a resolution shall be allowed by the Superintendent [Commissioner] unless notice is given to the Superintendent [Commissioner], at the time an application is filed, that the resolution has been withdrawn or reversed by vote of the board of directors and shareholders.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26-706_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
