<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-1005"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-1005/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_1005">
        <akn:num>16-1005</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Hearing; evidence; protection order.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Individuals served with notice in accordance with § 16-1004 shall appear at the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding section 14-306, in a hearing under this section, one spouse shall be a competent and compellable witness against the other and may testify as to confidential communications, but testimony compelled over a claim of a privilege conferred by such section shall be inadmissible in evidence in a criminal trial over the objection of a spouse entitled to claim that privilege.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, after hearing, the judicial officer finds that there is good cause to believe the respondent has committed or threatened to commit a criminal offense against the petitioner or against petitioner’s animal or an animal in petitioner’s household, the judicial officer may issue a protection order that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of subsection (c)(6) and (7) of this section, if the judicial officer finds by a preponderance of evidence that a contestant for custody has committed an intrafamily offense, any determination that custody or visitation is to be granted to the abusive parent shall be supported by a written statement by the judicial officer specifying factors and findings which support that determination. In determining visitation arrangements, if the judicial officer finds that an intrafamily offense has occurred, the judicial officer shall only award visitation if the judicial officer finds that the child and custodial parent can be adequately protected from harm inflicted by the other party. The party found to have committed an intrafamily offense has the burden of proving that visitation will not endanger the child or significantly impair the child’s emotional development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A protection order issued pursuant to this section shall be effective for such period up to one year as the judicial officer may specify, but the judicial officer may, upon motion of any party to the original proceeding, extend, rescind, or modify the order for good cause shown.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any final order issued pursuant to this section and any order granting or denying extension, modification, or rescission of such order shall be appealable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Violation of any temporary or final order issued under this subchapter, or violation in the District of Columbia of any valid foreign protection order, as that term is defined in subchapter IV of this chapter, or respondent’s failure to appear as required by subsection (a) of this section, shall be punishable as contempt. Upon conviction, criminal contempt shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates any protection order issued under this subchapter, or any person who violates in the District of Columbia any valid foreign protection order, as that term is defined in subchapter IV of this chapter, shall be chargeable with a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in [§ 22-3571.01] or by imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_g_1">
      <akn:num>(g-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Enforcement proceedings under subsections (f) and (g) of this section in which the respondent is a child as defined by § 16-2301(3) shall be governed by subchapter I of Chapter 23 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of establishing a violation under subsections (f) and (g) of this section, an oral or written statement made by a person located outside the District of Columbia to a person located in the District of Columbia by means of telecommunication, mail, or any other method of communication shall be deemed to be made in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1005_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Orders entered with the consent of the respondent but without an admission that the conduct occurred shall be punishable under subsection (f), (g), or (g-1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
