<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-1114"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-1114/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_1114">
        <akn:num>16-1114</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Verdict; judgment; costs; future actions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1114_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In an action of ejectment, if the plaintiff’s title is established by proof, the verdict of the jury shall be generally for the plaintiff as to the whole or part of the property or interest claimed in the complaint, as the case may be. If the plaintiff fails to make satisfactory proof of title, the verdict shall be for the defendant as to the whole or part of the property, as the case may be. The verdict may be for the plaintiff as to part and for the defendant as to other part thereof. Except as provided by this chapter, judgment shall be rendered according to the verdict.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-1114_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When it appears on the trial that the defendant did not wrongfully enter into possession of the property sued for, or exercise acts of ownership over the same adversely to the plaintiff, the verdict of the jury shall be that the defendant is not guilty. Thereupon, judgment shall be rendered in favor of the defendant against the plaintiff for the costs of the action, but the judgment is not a bar to a future action by the plaintiff against the defendant for the recovery of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
