<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2305"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2305/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2305">
        <akn:num>16-2305</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Petition; contents; amendment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Complaints alleging delinquency or need of supervision shall be referred to the Director of Social Services, and complaints alleging neglect shall be referred to the Director of the Child and Family Services Agency, each of whom shall conduct a preliminary inquiry to determine whether the best interests of the child or the public require that a petition be filed. If judicial action appears warranted, under intake criteria established by rule of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, the Director of Social Services, or the Director of the Agency shall recommend that a petition be filed. If the Director of Social Services, in the case of a complaint alleging delinquency or need of supervision, decides not to recommend the filing of a petition, the complainant shall have a right to have that decision reviewed by the Corporation Counsel. The Director of Social Services, in the case of a complaint alleging delinquency or need of supervision, shall notify the complainant of such right of review. Complaints alleging neglect submitted by the Agency shall be referred directly to the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Petitions initiating judicial action may be signed by any person who has knowledge of the facts alleged or, being informed of them, believes they are true, except that petitions alleging need of supervision may only be signed by the Director of Social Services, a representative of a public agency or a nongovernmental agency licensed and authorized to care for children, a representative of a public or private agency providing social service for families, a school official, or a law enforcement officer. Petitions shall be verified and verification may be upon information or belief.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A petition shall be filed by the Corporation Counsel within seven days (excluding Sundays and legal holidays) after the complaint has been referred to the Director of Social Services, except as otherwise provided in section 16-2312. A petition shall set forth plainly and concisely the facts which give the Division jurisdiction of the child under section 11-1101(13). In delinquency cases the petition shall also state the specific statute or ordinance on which the charge is based. If delinquency or need of supervision is alleged, a statement shall be included in the petition that the child appears to be in need of care or rehabilitation. The petition shall contain such other facts and information as may be required by rules of the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A petition may be amended by leave of the Division on motion of the Corporation Counsel or counsel for the child, at any time prior to the conclusion of the factfinding hearing. The Division shall grant the Corporation Counsel, the child, and his parent, guardian, or custodian notice of the amendment and, where necessary, additional time to prepare.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia shall be a party to all proceedings under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
