<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2305.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2305.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2305_02">
        <akn:num>16-2305.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Preliminary probation conferences; adjustment process.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where the Director of Social Services recommends, after a preliminary inquiry is conducted pursuant to D.C. Official Code ยง 16-2305(a), that it is not in the best interests of the child or public to recommend the filing of a delinquency or persons in need of supervision petition, the Director of Social Services shall so recommend to the Office of the Corporation Counsel, and the Corporation Counsel shall make a determination of the suitability of the case for adjustment, which may include diversion. The Director of Social Services shall permit any participant who is represented by a lawyer to be accompanied by the lawyer at any preliminary conference.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to determine whether the case is suitable for adjustment, the Director of Social Services, in consultation with the Office of the Corporation Counsel, shall consider the following circumstances, among others:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2305_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the preliminary inquiry, the Director of Social Services shall inform each person entitled to be present of the function and limitations of, and the alternatives to, the adjustment process, and that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
