<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2310"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2310/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2310">
        <akn:num>16-2310</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Criteria for detaining children.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A child shall not be placed in detention prior to a factfinding hearing or a dispositional hearing unless he is alleged to be delinquent or in need of supervision and unless it appears from available information that detention is required —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A child shall not be placed in shelter care prior to a factfinding hearing or a dispositional hearing unless it appears from available information that shelter care is required —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The criteria for detention and shelter care provided in this section, as implemented by rules of the Superior Court, shall govern the decisions of all persons responsible for determining whether detention or shelter care is warranted prior to the factfinding hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a child has been placed in shelter care, the child’s parent, guardian or custodian shall be permitted visitation at least weekly unless it appears to the judge that such visitation rights would create an imminent danger to or be detrimental to the well-being of the child, in which case, the judge shall either prescribe a schedule of visitation rights or order that visitation rights not be allowed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Fact finding hearings for children ordered into secure detention or ordered into shelter care shall be held within the time limits provided in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2310_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No provision of this section shall be construed as a bar to any claim of denial of speedy trial as required by the Sixth Amendment of the United States Constitution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
