<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2331"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2331/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2331">
        <akn:num>16-2331</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Juvenile case records; confidentiality; inspection and disclosure.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “juvenile case records” means the following records of a case over which the Family Court has jurisdiction under section 11-1101(13):</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this section and in section 16-2333.01, juvenile case records shall be kept confidential and shall not be open to inspection, nor shall information from records inspected be divulged to unauthorized persons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the limitations of subsection (f) of this section, the following entities and persons may inspect juvenile case records:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The prosecuting attorney inspecting records pursuant to subsection (c)(3)(A) of this section may divulge the contents to the extent required in the prosecution of a criminal case, and the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia and his assistants may inspect a transcript of the testimony of any witness and divulge the contents to the extent required by the prosecution of the witness for perjury, without, wherever possible, naming or otherwise revealing the identity of a child under the jurisdiction of the Family Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the Family Court, upon application of the Attorney General, may order the release of certain information contained in the case record if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Superior Court may by rule or special order provide that particular items or classes of items in juvenile case records shall not be open to inspection except pursuant to rule or special order; but, in dispositional proceedings after an adjudication, no item considered by the judge (other than identification of the sources of confidential information) shall be withheld from inspection:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court may by rule or special order provide procedures for the inspection or copying of juvenile case records by persons entitled to inspect them. No person receiving any record or information pursuant to this section may publish or use it for any purpose other than that for which it was received without a special order of the court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2331_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall disclose, inspect, or use records in violation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
