<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2372"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2372/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2372">
        <akn:num>16-2372</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Court-appointed special advocate program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a court-appointed special advocate program to provide trained volunteers whose primary purpose is to ensure that children who are the subject of certain family division proceedings of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia are provided with appropriate service and case planning that is in their best interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court, in any appropriate action, may appoint an individual provided by the court-appointed special advocate program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The program shall be administered by the Family Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Family Division shall report annually to the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, who shall report to the Council of the District of Columbia regarding the operation of the program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Judges of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may adopt rules governing the implementation and operation of the program, including, but not limited to, training, selection, and supervision of volunteers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An advocate or a member of the administrative staff of the program is not liable for acts or omissions in providing services or performing duties on behalf of the program, unless the act or omission constitutes reckless, willful, or wanton misconduct or intentionally tortious conduct.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2372_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A court-appointed special advocate shall have access to and the use of the court record in a proceeding in which the advocate has been appointed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
