<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2307"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2307/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2307">
        <akn:num>16-2307</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfer for criminal prosecution.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within twenty-one days (excluding Sundays and legal holidays) of the filing of a delinquency petition, or later for good cause shown, and prior to a factfinding hearing on the petition, the Corporation Counsel may file a motion, supported by a statement of facts, requesting transfer of the child for criminal prosecution, if  —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Following the filing of the motion by the Corporation Counsel, summonses shall be issued and served in conformity with the provisions of section 16-2306.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When there are grounds to believe that the child is incompetent to proceed, the Division shall stay the proceedings for the purpose of obtaining an examination pursuant to Chapter 5A of Title 24 [§ 24-531.01 et seq.]. If the Division determines, pursuant to Chapter 5A of Title 24 [§ 24-531.01 et seq.], that the child is incompetent to proceed, the Division shall not proceed to a determination under subsection (d) of this section unless it subsequently has determined that the competency of the child has been restored.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Evidence of the following factors shall be considered in determining whether there are reasonable prospects for rehabilitating a child prior to his majority and whether it is in the interest of the public welfare to transfer for criminal prosecution:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of the transfer hearing the Division shall assume that the child committed the delinquent act alleged.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_e_2">
      <akn:num>(e-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is a rebuttable presumption that a child 15 through 18 years of age who has been charged with any of the following offenses, should be transferred for criminal prosecution in the interest of public welfare and the protection of the public security:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to a transfer hearing, a study and report, in writing, relevant to the factors in subsection (e), shall be made by the Director of Social Services. This report and all social records that are to be made available to the judge at the transfer hearing shall be made available to counsel for the child and to the Corporation Counsel at least three days prior to the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A judge who conducts a hearing pursuant to this section shall not, over the objection of the child for whom a motion to transfer was filed, participate in any subsequent factfinding proceedings relating to the offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2307_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transfer of a child for criminal prosecution terminates the jurisdiction of the Division over the child with respect to any subsequent delinquent act; except that jurisdiction of the Division over the child is restored if (1) the criminal prosecution is terminated other than by a plea of guilty, a verdict of guilty, or a verdict of not guilty by reason of insanity, and (2) at the time of the termination of the criminal prosecution no indictment or information has been filed for criminal prosecution for an offense alleged to have been committed by the child subsequent to transfer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
