<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2340"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2340/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2340">
        <akn:num>16-2340</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rights of victims or eyewitnesses in delinquency proceedings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2340_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A victim or a eyewitness of a delinquent act should:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2340_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A victim and the victim’s immediate family members have the right to submit a victim impact statement in all cases and have the victim impact statement considered in the disposition of the case. The Corporation Counsel and the Director of Social Services shall inform the victim and the victim’s immediate family members or caretaker, or their duly authorized attorney, of such right.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2340_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before, during, and immediately after any court proceeding, the court shall provide appropriate safeguards to minimize the contact that may occur between the respondent, or respondent’s family and witnesses for respondent, and the victim, eyewitnesses for the Corporation Counsel, and the family of the victim or the Corporation Counsel’s eyewitnesses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2340_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise mandated by law, the District government shall not be required to disclose the names or addresses of its witnesses prior to a hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2340_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The respondent, the respondent’s attorney or another person acting on behalf of the respondent shall clearly identify himself or herself as being, representing, or acting on behalf of the respondent at the beginning of any contact with the victim, the victim’s family, or other persons believed to be eyewitnesses to the offenses charged.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2340_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed as creating a cause of action against the District of Columbia, any public official, employee, or public agency responsible for implementing or carrying out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
