<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2312"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2312/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2312">
        <akn:num>16-2312</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Detention or shelter care hearing; intermediate disposition.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prompt notice of the detention or shelter care hearing shall be given, if delinquency or need of supervision is alleged, to the child, and to his spouse (if any), parent, guardian, or custodian, if he can be found, or, if neglect is alleged, to the child, and to the parent, guardian, or custodian named in the petition if he can be found. Counsel for the child, and in neglect cases counsel for the parent, guardian, or custodian, shall be entitled to a copy of the petition prior to the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the commencement of the hearing the judge shall advise the parties of the right to counsel, as provided in section 16-2304, and shall appoint counsel if required. He shall also inform them of the contents of the petition and shall afford the child, or in a neglect case, the parent, guardian, or custodian, an opportunity to admit or deny the allegations in the petition. He shall then hear from the Corporation Counsel to determine whether the child should be placed or continued in detention or shelter care under the criteria in section 16-2310. The child and his parent, guardian, or custodian shall have a right to be heard in their own behalf.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a judge finds that a child’s detention or shelter care is required under the criteria of section 16-2310, he shall then hear evidence presented by the Corporation Counsel to determine whether there is probable cause to believe the allegations in the petition are true. The child, his parent, guardian or custodian may present evidence on the issues and be heard in their own behalf.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a judge finds there is probable cause to believe the allegations in the petition are true, he shall order the child to be placed or continued in detention or shelter care and set forth is reasons. When a judge finds that there is not probable cause to believe the allegations in the petition are true, he shall order the child to be released.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Division at a detention or shelter care hearing may not postpone the determination of whether detention or shelter care is required. For good cause shown, however, the Division may grant a continuance of any other part of the hearing (including the filing of a petition) for a period not to exceed five days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On motion by or on behalf of the child, a child in custody shall be released from custody if his detention or shelter care hearing is not commenced within the time set herein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a child is not released after his detention or shelter care hearing and the parent, guardian or custodian did not receive notice thereof, the Division may, in the interest of justice, conduct a new hearing in accordance with rules prescribed by the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon objection of the child or his parent, guardian or custodian, a judge who conducted a detention or shelter care hearing shall not conduct a factfinding hearing on the petition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2312_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A presumption shall exist that a child will attend the same school that he or she would have attended but for the child’s entry into shelter care, unless it is determined that it is not in the child’s best interest to do so.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
