<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2335.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2335.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2335_02">
        <akn:num>16-2335.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sealing of records on ground of actual innocence.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding section 16-2335, a person who has been arrested for violation of the District of Columbia Official Code or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, or has been the subject of a petition filed pursuant to section 16-2305 and whose prosecution has been terminated without adjudication may file a motion with the Family Court at any time to seal all of the records of the arrest and related court proceedings on grounds of actual innocence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The burden is on the movant to establish that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the motion is filed within 4 years after the prosecution has been terminated, the movant must satisfy the burden described in subsection (b) of this section by a preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the motion is filed more than 4 years after the prosecution has been terminated, the movant must satisfy the burden described in subsection (b) of this section by clear and convincing evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining such motions, the Family Court may, but is not required to, employ a rebuttable presumption that the movant is not entitled to relief if the court finds that the government has been substantially prejudiced in its ability to respond to the motion by the delay in its filing, unless the movant shows that the motion is based on grounds which the person could not have raised by the exercise of reasonable diligence before the circumstances prejudicial to the government occurred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An acquittal does not establish a presumption that the movant is innocent or entitled to relief pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person whose adjudication has been vacated pursuant to section 16-2335.01(g)(2), and whose subsequent prosecution is terminated without adjudication, may file a motion with the Family Court pursuant to subsection (a) of this section or any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who is found to be actually innocent pursuant to this section or section 16-2335.01(g)(3) shall be entitled to the following relief with respect to such count or counts:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The effect of relief pursuant to this section shall be to restore the movant, in the contemplation of the law, to the status he or she occupied before being arrested or charged. No person as to whom such relief has been granted shall be held thereafter under any provision of law to be guilty of perjury or otherwise giving a false statement by reason of failure to recite or acknowledge his or her arrest, or charge, or trial in response to any inquiry made of him or her for any purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A motion to seal filed with the Family Court pursuant to this chapter shall state grounds upon which eligibility for sealing is based and facts in support of the person’s claim. It shall be accompanied by a statement of points and authorities in support of the motion, and any appropriate exhibits, affidavits, and supporting documents. A copy of the motion shall be served upon the prosecutor. The prosecutor shall not be required to respond to the motion unless ordered to do so by the Family Court pursuant to subsection (l) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If it plainly appears from the face of the motion, any accompanying exhibits, affidavits, and documents, and the record of any prior proceedings in the case, that the movant is not eligible for relief or is not entitled to relief, the Family Court may dismiss or deny the motion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the motion is not dismissed or denied after initial review, the Family Court shall order the prosecutor to file a response to the motion. The prosecutor shall file the response within 60 days of the issuance of the order except where the arrest was not presented to the prosecutor for a charging decision, in which case the prosecutor shall file the response within 90 days of the issuance of the order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the filing of the prosecutor’s response, the Family Court shall determine whether a hearing is required.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Family Court determines that a hearing is required, the hearing shall be scheduled promptly.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the hearing, the movant and the prosecutor may present witnesses and information by proffer or otherwise. Hearsay evidence shall be admissible.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order dismissing, granting, or denying the motion shall be in writing and include reasons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Family Court shall not be required to entertain a second or successive motion for similar relief on behalf of the same movant regarding the same offenses or arrests unless the previous motion was dismissed or denied without prejudice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order dismissing, granting, or denying a motion for sealing is a final order for purposes of appeal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Records sealed pursuant to this section shall be opened only on order of the Family Court upon a showing of compelling need, except that, upon request, the movant shall be entitled to a copy of the sealed records to the extent that such records would have been available to the movant before relief under this section was granted. A request for access to sealed court records may be made ex parte.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2335_02_t">
      <akn:num>(t)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person, upon making inquiry of the Family Court concerning the existence of records of arrest, court proceedings, or adjudications involving an individual, shall be entitled to rely, for any purpose under the law, upon the clerk’s response that no records are available under subsection (h)(7) of this section with respect to any issue about that person’s knowledge of the individual’s record.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
