<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2329"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2329/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2329">
        <akn:num>16-2329</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Finality of judgments; appeals; transcripts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2329_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, in all hearings and cases tried before the Division pursuant to this subchapter, the judgment of the Division is final.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2329_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In all appeals from decisions of the Division with respect to a child alleged to be neglected, delinquent, or in need of supervision, the child shall be identified only by initials in all transcripts, briefs, and other papers filed, and all necessary steps, as prescribed by rule of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, shall be taken to protect the identity of the child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2329_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the filing of a motion and supporting affidavit stating that he is financially unable to purchase a transcript, a party who has filed notice of appeal or of interlocutory appeal shall be furnished, at no cost or at such part of cost as he is able to pay, so much of the transcript as is necessary adequately to prepare and support the appeal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2329_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An appeal does not operate to stay the order, judgment, or decree appealed from, but on application and hearing whenever the case is properly before the appellate court, that court may order otherwise if suitable provision is made for the care and custody of the child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
