<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2320"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2320/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2320">
        <akn:num>16-2320</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Disposition of child who is neglected, delinquent, or in need of supervision.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a child is found to be neglected, the Division exercising juvenile jurisdiction shall also have jurisdiction over any natural person who is a parent or caretaker of the child to secure the parent or caretaker’s full cooperation and assistance in the entire rehabilitative process and may order any of the following dispositions which will be in the best interest of the child:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless a child found neglected is also found to be delinquent, he shall not be committed to, or confined in, an institution for delinquent children.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a child is found to be delinquent or in need of supervision, the Division exercising juvenile jurisdiction shall also have jurisdiction over any natural person who is a parent or caretaker of the child to secure the parent or caretaker’s full cooperation and assistance in the entire rehabilitative process and may order any of the following dispositions which will be in the best interest of the child:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Division shall order any child between the ages of 14 and 18 years who is found to be delinquent or in need of supervision to perform a minimum of 90 hours of community service with an agency of the District government or a non-profit or community service organization in accordance with section 24-904(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When determining what disposition shall be ordered under subsection (c) of this section, the Division shall consider any victim impact statement submitted to the Division and the victim, or the immediate family members of the victim when the victim is a child or when the victim is deceased or incapacitated, shall have the right to make a statement at the disposition hearing. The absence of the victim at disposition shall not preclude the court from holding the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_c_3">
      <akn:num>(c-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When determining what disposition shall be ordered under subsection (a) of this section, the Division may consider a child’s failure to appear at a scheduled hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No child found in need of supervision, as defined by section 16-2301(8), unless also found delinquent, shall be committed to or placed in an institution or facility for delinquent children, but shall be released to the child’s parent, guardian, or custodian, unless the return of the child will result in placement in, or return to, an abusive situation, or the child’s parent, guardian, or custodian is unwilling or unable to care for or supervise the child. If the return of the child will result in placement in, or return to, an abusive situation, or if the child’s parent, guardian, or custodian is unwilling or unable to care for or supervise the child, the Child and Family Services Agency shall open a neglect investigation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No child who is found to be delinquent, in need of supervision, or neglected shall be committed to a penal or correctional institution for adult offenders.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In its dispositional order for a child adjudicated neglected, the Division shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The department or agency to whom the legal custody of a child has been transferred pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall give notice, which may be oral, of any change in the placement of the child to the child’s parent, the child’s guardian ad litem and the child’s foster parent at least ten (10) days prior to the change in placement, except that in the case of an emergency notice shall be given no later than twenty-four (24) hours (excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays) after the change. Notice of a change in placement need not be given to the parent when the judge has determined that visitation would be detrimental to the child or the judge has determined that the parent should not be apprised of the child’s location. Upon the request of any person entitled to notice under this subsection the department or agency having legal custody of the child shall afford an opportunity for an administrative hearing to review the proposed change in the placement of the child. Except in the case of an emergency, the hearing shall be held and a decision rendered prior to a change in the placement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any child who is found to be delinquent for violation of the provisions of the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981 may, in addition to any other disposition ordered by the court for his supervision, care, and rehabilitation, be ordered to attend classes conducted by the Mayor pursuant to section 48-905.04(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
