<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2317"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2317/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2317">
        <akn:num>16-2317</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Hearings, findings; dismissal.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2317_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided by statute or court rule, all motions shall be heard at the time of the factfinding hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2317_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After a factfinding hearing on the allegations in the petition, the Division shall make and file written findings in all cases as to the truth of the allegations, and in neglect cases, he shall also make and file written findings as to whether the child is neglected. The Court may not make a finding of neglect based solely on a finding that a child is born addicted or dependent on a controlled substance or has a significant presence of a controlled substance in his or her system at birth. If the Division finds that —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2317_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Division finds in a factfinding hearing that —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2317_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2317_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Division shall give prompt notice of any dispositional hearing as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2317_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Corporation Counsel shall give prompt notice, if practicable, of any disposition and post-disposition hearings to the victim, or the immediate family members or caretakers of the victim, or their duly authorized attorney, when the victim is a child or when the victim is deceased or incapacitated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
