<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2320.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-2320.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_2320_01">
        <akn:num>16-2320.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Restitution.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Division may order the child to make restitution directly to the victim, governmental entity, or third-party payor after consideration of the age, circumstances, and financial ability of the child to pay. The Division may order the parent or guardian to make restitution directly to the victim, governmental entity, or third-party payor after consideration of the parent or guardian’s financial ability to pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A restitution hearing to determine the liability of a parent or guardian, a child, or both, shall be held within 30 days after the disposition hearing and may be extended by the Division for good cause. A hearing under this section may be held as part of a factfinding or disposition hearing for the child. A judgment of restitution against a parent or guardian may not be entered unless the parent or guardian has been afforded a reasonable opportunity to be heard and to present appropriate evidence in the parent or guardian’s behalf.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a restitution hearing, a written statement or bill for medical, dental, hospital, funeral, or burial expenses, or repair and replacement of property shall be prima facie evidence that the amount indicated on the written statement or bill represents a fair and reasonable charge for the services or materials provided. The burden of proving that the amount indicated on the written statement or bill is not fair and reasonable shall be on the person challenging the fairness and reasonableness of the amount.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon request of the Corporation Counsel or the recipient of a judgment of restitution, the Division may enforce the judgment for restitution under this section in the same manner that a monetary judgment is enforced by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia under Title 15 and applicable court rules.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director of Social Services shall be responsible for monitoring the collection and disbursement of restitution payments when the judgment of restitution provides that restitution is to be made in periodic or installment payments. The Director of Social Services shall inform the Division of the progress or status of the restitution payments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A judgment of restitution under this section shall not preclude a civil action to recover damages from the child, parent, or guardian. A civil verdict shall be reduced by the amount paid under the judgment of restitution. A judgment of restitution may be filed under seal in any civil case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If at the restitution hearing the Division finds that a child is financially unable to pay restitution pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, the Division may order the child to perform community service or some other non-monetary service of equivalent value in lieu thereof. If at the restitution hearing the Division finds that a parent or guardian is financially unable to pay restitution pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, the Division may order the parent or guardian to perform community service or some other non-monetary service of equivalent value in lieu thereof.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When entering a restitution order, the court shall include the restitution conditions both in the disposition order and in a separate judgement [sic] of restitution which shall be filed in a special proceedings case. An order requiring an adult to pay a judgment for restitution shall be filed in a special proceedings case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order of restitution requiring a parent or guardian, a child, or both to pay restitution constitutes a judgment and lien against all property of the person or persons required to pay for the amount they are obligated to pay under the order and may be recorded in any office for the filing of liens against real or personal property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A judgment of restitution may be enforced by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, a victim entitled under the order to receive restitution, a deceased victim’s estate, or any other beneficiary of the judgment in the same manner as a civil judgment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A judgment for restitution that is filed in a special proceedings case shall contain the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court shall provide each victim in a juvenile case with a notarized and sealed copy of the Order of Restitution or Reparation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the information that is included in a judgment for restitution filed in a special proceedings case, the Division shall provide the following information in a supplemental information form attached to the order. This information shall be kept confidential except by order of the Division:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All restitution payments shall be paid to the Superior Court. The payer shall receive a receipt for the payment. If the restitution payment is mailed, a receipt will be returned only if the payer encloses a self-addressed stamped envelope.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-2320_01_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court shall disburse the restitution payments to the recipient and make appropriate court records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
