<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-3902"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-3902/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_3902">
        <akn:num>16-3902</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Commencement of action; form of statement; preparation by clerk; notice and service; costs; default; memorandum to plaintiff.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Actions shall be commenced in the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch by the filing of a statement of claim, in concise form and free of technicalities. The plaintiff or his agent shall verify the statement of claim by oath or affirmation in the form herein provided, or its equivalent, and shall affix his signature thereto. The clerk of the Branch shall, at the request of an individual, prepare the statement of claim and other papers required to be filed in an action in the Branch, but his services are not available to a corporation, partnership, or association, in the preparation of the statements or other papers. A copy of the statement of claim and verification shall be made a part of the notice to be served upon the defendant named therein. The mode of service shall be by the United States marshal, as provided by law, or by registered mail or by certified mail with return receipt, or by a person not a party to or otherwise interested in the action especially authorized by the Clerk of the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch or appointed by the judge for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When notice is to be served by registered mail or by certified mail, the clerk shall inclose a copy of the statement of claim, verification, and notice in an envelope addressed to the defendant, prepay the postage with funds obtained from plaintiff, and mail the papers forthwith, noting on the records the day and hour of mailing. When the receipt is returned, the clerk shall attach it to the original statement of claim, and it constitutes prima facie evidence of service upon the defendant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When notice is served by a private individual, as provided by subsection (a) of this section, he shall make proof of service by affidavit before the clerk, showing the time and place of the service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When notice is served by the marshal, or by registered mail or by certified mail, the actual cost of service is taxable as costs. When notice is served by an individual, the cost of service, if any, is not taxable as costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The statement of claim, verification, and notice shall be in the following or equivalent form:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The foregoing verification entitles the plaintiff to a judgment by default, without further proof, upon failure of defendant to appear, if the claim of the plaintiff is for a liquidated amount. If the amount is unliquidated, the plaintiff shall be required to present proof of his claim.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The clerk shall furnish the plaintiff with a memorandum of the day and hour set for the hearing, not less than 5 nor more than 30 days from the date of the filing of the action. Where, in a case controlled by another statute, a greater or lesser time for hearing is specified by the other statute, that specified time is controlling. All actions filed in the Branch shall be made returnable therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-3902_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where the defendant is the District of Columbia or an officer or agency thereof, the Clerk shall schedule the hearing for a day that is not less than 30 days from the date of the filing of the action, service of a copy of the action on the Corporation Counsel to be completed within 15 days of filing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
