<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4430"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4430/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_4430">
        <akn:num>16-4430</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Regulation of arbitration organizations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any arbitration organization that administers or otherwise is involved in 50 or more consumer arbitrations a year shall collect, publish at least quarterly, and make available to the public in a computer-searchable database that permits searching with multiple search terms in the same search, and is accessible at the Internet website of the arbitration organization, if any, and on paper, upon request, all of the following information regarding each consumer arbitration it has administered or otherwise been involved in within the preceding 5 years:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the information required by subsection (a) of this section is provided by the arbitration organization in a computer-searchable format at the company’s Internet website and may be downloaded without any fee, the company may charge the actual cost of copying to any person who requests the information on paper. If the required information is not accessible by the Internet, the company shall provide that information without charge to any person who requests the information on paper.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No arbitration organization shall have any liability for collecting, publishing, or distributing the information in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in the section shall affect the ability of an arbitration organization to shift fees that would otherwise be charged or assessed upon a consumer party to another party.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before requesting or obtaining any fee, an arbitration organization shall provide written notice of the right to obtain a waiver of fees in a manner calculated to bring the matter to the attention of a reasonable consumer, including, but not limited to, prominently placing a notice in its first written communication to a consumer and in any invoice, bill, submission form, fee schedule, rules, or code of procedure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No neutral arbitrator or arbitration organization shall administer a consumer arbitration under any agreement or rule requiring that a consumer who is a party to the arbitration pay the fees and costs incurred by any opposing party if the consumer does not prevail in the arbitration, including, but not limited to, the fees and costs of the arbitrator, provider organization, attorney, or witnesses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No arbitration organization may administer a consumer arbitration to be conducted in the District of Columbia, or provide any other services related to such a consumer arbitration, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4430_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where this section is violated, any affected person or entity, including the Attorney General of the District of Columbia, can request a court to enjoin the arbitration organization from violating the section and order such restitution as appropriate. The arbitration organization shall be liable for that person or entity’s reasonable attorney fees and costs where that person or entity prevails or where, after the action is commenced, the arbitration organization voluntarily complies with the section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
