<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4603.11"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4603.11/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_4603_11">
        <akn:num>16-4603.11</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Warrant to take physical custody of child.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_11_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the filing of a petition seeking enforcement of a child-custody determination, the petitioner may file a verified application for the issuance of a warrant to take physical custody of the child if the child is imminently likely to suffer serious physical harm or be removed from the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_11_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the court, upon the testimony of the petitioner or other witness, finds that the child is imminently likely to suffer serious physical harm or be removed from the District, it may issue a warrant to take physical custody of the child. The petition must be heard on the next judicial day after the warrant is executed unless that date is impossible. In that event, the court shall hold the hearing on the first judicial day possible. The application for the warrant must include the statements required by section 16-4603.08(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_11_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A warrant to take physical custody of a child must:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_11_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The respondent must be served with the petition, warrant, and order immediately after the child is taken into physical custody.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_11_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A warrant to take physical custody of a child is enforceable throughout the District. If the court finds on the basis of the testimony of the petitioner or other witness that a less intrusive remedy is not effective, it may authorize law enforcement officers to enter private property to take physical custody of the child. If required by exigent circumstances of the case, the court may authorize law enforcement officers to make a forcible entry at any hour.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_11_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court may impose conditions upon placement of a child to ensure the appearance of the child and the child’s custodian.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
