<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4601.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4601.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_4601_01">
        <akn:num>16-4601.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Abandoned” means left without provision for reasonable and necessary care or supervision.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child” means an individual who has not attained 18 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-custody determination” means a judgment, decree, or other order of a court providing for the legal custody, physical custody, or visitation with respect to a child. The term includes a permanent, temporary, initial, and modification order. The term does not include an order relating to child support or other monetary obligation of an individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-custody proceeding” means a proceeding in which legal custody, physical custody, or visitation with respect to a child is an issue. The term includes a proceeding for divorce, separation, neglect, abuse, dependency, guardianship, adoption, paternity, termination of parental rights, and protection from domestic violence, in which the issue may appear. The term does not include a proceeding involving juvenile delinquency, contractual emancipation, or enforcement under subchapter III of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commencement” means the filing of the first pleading in a proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Court” means an entity authorized under the law of a state to establish, enforce, or modify a child-custody determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home state” means the state in which a child lived with a parent or a person acting as a parent for at least 6 consecutive months immediately before the commencement of a child-custody proceeding. In the case of a child less than 6 months of age, the term means the state in which the child lived from birth with any of the persons mentioned. A period of temporary absence of any of the mentioned persons is part of the period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Initial determination” means the first child-custody determination concerning a particular child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuing court” means the court that makes a child-custody determination for which enforcement is sought under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuing state” means the state in which a child-custody determination is made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Modification” means a child-custody determination that changes, replaces, supersedes, or is otherwise made after a previous determination concerning the same child, whether or not it is made by the court that made the previous determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, government, governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, public corporation, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person acting as a parent” means a person, other than a parent, who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Physical custody” means the physical care and supervision of a child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4601_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Warrant” means an order issued by a court authorizing law enforcement officers to take physical custody of a child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
