<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4603.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4603.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_4603_08">
        <akn:num>16-4603.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Expedited enforcement of child-custody determination.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A petition under this subchapter must be verified. Certified copies of all orders sought to be enforced and of any order confirming registration must be attached to the petition. A copy of a certified copy of an order may be attached instead of the original.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A petition for enforcement of a child-custody determination must state:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the filing of a petition, the court shall issue an order directing the respondent to appear in person, with or without the child, at a hearing and may enter any order necessary to ensure the safety of the parties and the child. The hearing must be held on the next judicial day after service of the order unless that date is impossible. In that event, the court shall hold the hearing on the first judicial day possible. The court may extend the date of hearing at the request of the petitioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4603_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order issued under subsection (c) of this section must state the time and place of the hearing and advise the respondent that at the hearing the court will order that the petitioner may take immediate physical custody of the child and the payment of fees, costs, and expenses under ยง 16-4603.12, and may schedule a hearing to determine whether further relief is appropriate, unless the respondent appears and establishes that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
