<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4803"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4803/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_4803">
        <akn:num>16-4803</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Designation of a standby guardian.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4803_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A designator may designate a standby guardian at any time.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4803_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The designation of a standby guardian shall be in writing and shall contain the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4803_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The designation shall be signed by the designator. Another adult may sign the designation on behalf of the designator if the designator is physically unable to do so, the designator expressly requests that the adult sign the designation, and the adult signs the designation in the presence of the designator. The designated standby guardian or alternate standby guardian may not sign on behalf of the designator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4803_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The designation shall be signed and dated by the designator or the designator’s proxy in the presence of 2 witnesses who shall be over 18 years of age and who cannot be the standby guardian or the alternate standby guardian. The witnesses shall indicate their witnessing of the signing of the designation by signing the designation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4803_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The designation shall include a statement that the designation is not valid until it is signed and witnessed as required by subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4803_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The standby guardian, and the alternate standby guardian, if one is designated, shall sign the executed designation to indicate acceptance of the standby guardianship.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
