<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4009"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-4009/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_4009">
        <akn:num>16-4009</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Disqualification of collaborative lawyer and lawyers in associated law firm.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4009_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, a collaborative lawyer is disqualified from appearing before the tribunal to represent a party in a proceeding related to the collaborative matter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4009_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section and §§ 16-4010 and 16-4011, a lawyer in a law firm with which the collaborative lawyer is associated is disqualified from appearing before the tribunal to represent a party in a proceeding related to the collaborative matter if the collaborative lawyer is disqualified from doing so under subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4009_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A collaborative lawyer or a lawyer in a law firm with which the collaborative lawyer is associated may represent a party:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-4009_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If subsection (c)(2) of this section applies, a collaborative lawyer, or lawyer in a law firm with which the collaborative lawyer is associated, may represent a party or family member only until that person is represented by a successor lawyer or reasonable measures are taken to protect the health, safety, welfare, or interest of the person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
