<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-803"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-803/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_803">
        <akn:num>16-803</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sealing of public criminal records in other cases.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who has been convicted of an eligible misdemeanor or an eligible felony pursuant to the District of Columbia Official Code or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations may file a motion to seal the publicly available records of the arrest, related court proceedings, and conviction if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person to whom a District of Columbia arrest has been attributed, who attests under oath that he or she was incorrectly identified or named, may file a motion to seal publicly available records of the arrest if the law enforcement agency did not take fingerprints at the time of the arrest and no other form of reliable identification was presented by the person who was arrested.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The waiting periods in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, before which a motion to seal cannot be filed, must be satisfied with respect to all of the movant’s arrests and convictions unless the movant waives in writing the right to seek sealing of an arrest or conviction as to which the prescribed waiting period has not elapsed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The waiting periods in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section may be waived by the prosecutor in writing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a motion filed under subsections (a), (b), or (c) of this section, the movant must seek to seal all eligible arrests and convictions in the same proceeding unless the movant waives in writing the right to seek sealing with respect to a particular conviction or arrest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining whether a movant is eligible to file a motion to seal because of a conviction, arrest, or pending charge, minor offenses shall not be considered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A motion to seal made pursuant to this section may be dismissed without prejudice to permit the movant to renew the motion after further passage of time. The Court may set a waiting period before a renewed motion can be filed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A motion to seal made pursuant to this section may be dismissed if it appears that the movant has unreasonably delayed filing the motion and that the government has been prejudiced in its ability to respond to the motion by the delay in its filing, unless the movant shows that the motion is based on grounds which the person could not have raised by the exercise of reasonable diligence before the circumstances prejudicial to the government occurred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Court grants the motion to seal:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-803_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person as to whom such relief has been granted shall be held thereafter under any provision of law to be guilty of perjury or otherwise giving a false statement by reason of failure to recite or acknowledge his or her arrest, charge, trial, or conviction in response to any inquiry made of him or her for any purpose except that the sealing of records under this provision does not relieve a person of the obligation to disclose the sealed arrest or conviction in response to any direct question asked in connection with jury service or in response to any direct question contained in any questionnaire or application for a position with any person, agency, organization, or entity defined in § 16-801(11).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
