<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-916.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-916.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_916_01">
        <akn:num>16-916.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Child Support Guideline.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any case that involves the establishment of child support, or in any case that seeks to modify an existing support order, if the judicial officer finds that there is an existing duty of child support, the judicial officer shall conduct a hearing on child support, make a finding, and enter a judgment in accordance with the child support guideline (“guideline”) established in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In every action for divorce or custody, and in every proceeding for protection involving an intrafamily offense, instituted pursuant to Chapter 10 of Title 16, where a party has a legal duty to pay support to another party, the judicial officer shall inquire into the parties’ child support arrangements. If the party entitled to child support has not requested support, or if the parties have agreed against the entry of a support order, the judicial officer shall advise the parties, regardless of whether they are represented by counsel, of the parties’ entitlement to receive and obligation to pay child support under the guideline.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The guideline shall be based on the following principles:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The judicial officer shall determine each parent’s adjusted gross income by making the additions to and deductions from gross income specified in subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_g_1">
      <akn:num>(g-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_g_2">
      <akn:num>(g-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A modified self-support reserve shall be calculated at 100% of the United States Department of Health and Human Services poverty guideline per year for a single individual to be used to determine support pursuant to subsection (g-1) of this section.  The modified self-support reserve shall be updated by the Mayor every 2 years with the updated amount to be published in the District of Columbia Register and made effective as of April 1.  As of April 1, 2015, the modified self-support reserve shall be $11,770.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The guideline shall not apply presumptively in cases where the parents’ combined adjusted gross income exceeds $240,000 per year. In these cases, the child support obligation shall not be less than the amount that the parent with a legal duty to pay support would have been ordered to pay if the guideline had been applied to combined adjusted gross income of $240,000. The judicial officer may exercise discretion to order more child support, after determining the reasonable needs of the child based on actual family experience. The judicial officer shall issue written factual findings stating the reasons for an award of additional child support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Reasonable child care expenses incurred for a child subject to the support order due to the employment or education of either parent shall be divided between the parents in proportion to their adjusted gross incomes and added to their respective shares of the basic child support obligation. Child care expenses shall be determined by actual family experience, unless the judicial officer determines that the actual family experience is not in the best interest of the child. If there is no actual family experience, or if the actual family experience is not in the best interest of the child, the judicial officer shall determine a reasonable child care expense based on the cost of child care from a licensed source. If the primary residential parent chooses child care with an actual cost that is less than the level required to provide child care from a licensed source, the judicial officer shall use the actual child care expense to calculate the child support obligation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a child subject to the support order receives SSDI derivative benefits from the parent with a legal duty to pay support, the following adjustment to the child support obligation shall be made:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As the last calculation in the determination of child support, the judicial officer shall calculate a low-income adjustment to ensure that the parent with a legal duty to pay support is able to satisfy personal subsistence needs after the payment of child support. The judicial officer shall apply this low-income adjustment after additions to and deductions from the parent’s share of the basic child support obligation have been made pursuant to subsections (i) through (l) of this section. The low-income adjustment shall be calculated as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The child support obligation, including additions for health insurance premiums, extraordinary medical expenses, and child care expenses, shall not exceed 35% of the adjusted gross income of the parent with a legal duty to pay support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Application of the guideline shall be presumptive. The guideline shall be applied unless its application would be unjust or inappropriate in the circumstances of the particular case. The propriety of any departure from the guideline under this subsection shall be justified in writing with a statement of the factors that form the basis for the judicial officer’s finding that the guideline amount is unjust or inappropriate. A transcript filed in the jacket shall suffice as a writing. The factors that may be considered to overcome the presumption are:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A support order issued under this section or section 46-204, shall be subject to modification by application of the guideline subject to the following conditions or limitations:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A support order shall not be deemed invalid on the sole basis that the support order was issued pursuant to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia Child Support Guideline and prior to the effective date of the Child Support Guideline Amendment Emergency Act of 1989, effective December 21, 1989 (D.C. Act 8-127; 37 DCR 3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_t">
      <akn:num>(t)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the occurrence of a substantial and material change in circumstances sufficient to warrant the modification of a child support obligation pursuant to the guideline, the judicial officer may modify any provision of an agreement or settlement relating to child support, without regard to whether the agreement or settlement is entered as a consent order or is incorporated or merged in a court order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_u">
      <akn:num>(u)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an order or agreement providing for child support does not set forth a date on which the child support commences, the child support shall be deemed to commence on the first day of the first month following the date the order was entered or the date the agreement was executed, whichever is later in time. If the relevant date falls on the first day of a month, the order shall be deemed to commence on that day.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_v">
      <akn:num>(v)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_w">
      <akn:num>(w)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Schedule of Basic Child Support Obligations contained in Appendix I shall be used to determine child support under the guideline.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_x">
      <akn:num>(x)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The worksheets contained in Appendices II and III may be used to calculate child support obligations under the guideline. Refer to Worksheet B in Appendix III to calculate child support in cases involving shared physical custody pursuant to subsection (q) of this section. Refer to Worksheet A in Appendix II to calculate child support in all other cases.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_01_y">
      <akn:num>(y)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall recommend to the Council every 4 years whether the dollar values in subsections (g)(3), (h), (j)(1), (m)(2), and (m)(3) of this section should adjusted for inflation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
