<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-914.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-914.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_914_02">
        <akn:num>16-914.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Child custody and visitation rights of parents during deployment for military service.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court shall not issue a permanent order modifying the terms of an existing custody or visitation order until 90 days after the termination of the deployment of a military parent. The court shall not consider the activation or deployment of a deploying parent as the sole factor in the court’s decision of whether or not to grant or deny a petition for custody or visitation, and neither deployment nor the potential for future deployment of a military parent shall, by itself, be regarded as a material change in the circumstances of any existing custody or visitation order, or against the best interests of the child, for the court to issue a permanent order modifying the terms of an existing custody or visitation order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court, in any child custody or visitation proceeding between either 2 deploying parents or a deploying parent and a non-deploying parent, shall allow any deploying parent to present testimony or evidence relevant to the custody or visitation proceedings either by affidavit or electronically when deployment precludes the personal appearance of the deploying parent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
