<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-914"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-914/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_914">
        <akn:num>16-914</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Custody of children.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, if the judicial officer finds by a preponderance of evidence that a contestant for custody has committed an intrafamily offense, any determination that custody or visitation is to be granted to the abusive parent shall be supported by a written statement by the judicial officer specifying factors and findings which support that determination. In determining visitation arrangements, if the judicial officer finds that an intrafamily offense has occurred, the judicial officer shall only award visitation if the judicial officer finds that the child and custodial parent can be adequately protected from harm inflicted by the other party. The party found to have committed an intrafamily offense has the burden of proving that visitation will not endanger the child or significantly impair the child’s emotional development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of a custody proceeding shall be given to the child’s parents, guardian, or other custodian. The court, upon a showing of good cause, may permit intervention by any interested party.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any custody proceeding under this chapter, the Court may order each parent to submit a detailed parenting plan which shall delineate each parent’s position with respect to the scheduling and allocation of rights and responsibilities that will best serve the interest of the minor child or children. The parenting plan may include, but shall not be limited to, provisions for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In making its custody determination, the Court:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Joint custody shall not eliminate the responsibility for child support in accordance with the applicable child support guideline as set forth in § 16-916.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Court, for good cause and upon its own motion, may appoint a guardian ad litem or an attorney, or both, to represent the minor child’s interests.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Court shall enter an order for any custody arrangement that is agreed to by both parents unless clear and convincing evidence indicates that the arrangement is not in the best interest of the minor child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An objection by one parent to any custody arrangement shall not be the sole basis for refusing the entry of an order that the Court determines is in the best interest of the minor child.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Court shall place on the record the specific factors and findings which justify any custody arrangement not agreed to by both parents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-914_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, no person shall be granted legal custody or physical custody of, or visitation with, a child if the person has been convicted of first degree sexual abuse, second degree sexual abuse, or child sexual abuse, and the child was conceived as a result of that violation. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as abrogating or limiting the responsibility of a person described herein to pay child support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
