<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-916.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-916.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_916_02">
        <akn:num>16-916.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Child Support Guideline Commission.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established a Child Support Guideline Commission (“Commission”). The Commission shall study and make recommendations on the child support guidelines to the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall consist of a chairperson and 8 members who are District of Columbia residents. The Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may appoint 2 members. The Mayor shall appoint the chairperson as well as 2 members, one of whom shall be a member of the District of Columbia Bar (“Bar”) and an expert in the fields of family law and child support. The Mayor shall also appoint one member to represent the Child Support Enforcement Division of the Office of the Corporation Counsel (“CSED”). The Council shall designate one Councilmember to serve on the Commission and shall appoint 2 additional members, one of whom shall be a member of the Bar and an expert in the fields of family law and child support.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The functions of the Commission shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission, as restructured pursuant to the Child Support Guideline Commission Restructuring Act [this section], shall convene no later than December 31, 2002, and shall issue initial recommendations no later than December 31, 2003.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for any reasonable expense associated with service on the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall provide sufficient space for the Commission to operate and may detail personnel to assist the Commission. The Mayor shall also direct any agency contacted by the Commission to give full cooperation to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
