<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-911"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-911/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_911">
        <akn:num>16-911</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Pendente lite relief.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-911_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During the pendency of an action for legal separation, divorce, the termination of a domestic partnership pursuant to ยง 32-702(d) or ยง 16-904(e), where one of the domestic partners has filed a petition for relief available under this section, or an action by a spouse to declare the marriage null and void, where the nullity is denied by the other spouse, the court may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-911_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-911_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-911_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The attachment, garnishment, or assignment under paragraphs (1) and (4) of subsection (a) is binding on the employer, trustee, or other payor of salary, wages, earnings, or other income. No employer shall discharge or otherwise discipline an employee because of such attachment, garnishment, or assignment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-911_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court may order, at any time, that maintenance or support payments be made to the Collection and Disbursement Unit, as defined in section 46-201(2A) [now ยง 46-201(3)], for remittance to the person entitled to receive the payments, and shall order that such payments be made to the Collection and Disbursement Unit when the Collection and Disbursement Unit is responsible for collecting and disbursing these payments under section 46-202.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-911_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Court may order any other appropriate pendente lite relief.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
