<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-916"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/16-916/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_16_916">
        <akn:num>16-916</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Maintenance of spouse [or domestic partner] and minor children; maintenance of former spouse [or domestic partner]; maintenance of minor children; enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a spouse or domestic partner shall fail or refuse to maintain his or her needy spouse, domestic partner, minor children, or both, although able to do so, or whenever any parent shall fail or refuse to maintain his or her children by a marriage since dissolved, although able to do so, the court, upon proper application and upon a showing of genuine need of a spouse or domestic partner, may decree, pendente lite and permanently, that such spouse or domestic partner shall pay reasonable sums periodically for the  support of such needy spouse or domestic partner and of the children, or such children, as the case may be, and the court may decree that he or she pay suit money, including counsel fees, pendente lite and permanently, to enable plaintiff to conduct the case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a former spouse or domestic partner has obtained a foreign ex parte divorce or termination of the domestic partnership, in accordance with § 32-702(d) or § 16-904(e), the court thereafter, on application of the other former spouse or domestic partner and with personal service of process upon such former spouse or domestic partner in the District of Columbia, may decree that he or she shall pay him or her reasonable sums periodically for his or her maintenance and for suit money, including counsel fees, pendente lite and permanently, to enable plaintiff to conduct the case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a father or mother fails to maintain his or her minor child, the Court may decree that the father or mother pay reasonable sums periodically for the support and maintenance of the child, including health insurance coverage and cash medical support, and may decree that the father or mother pay Court costs, including counsel fees, to enable plaintiff to conduct the cases.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A support order entered under this section shall contain terms providing for the payment of medical expenses for each child included in the support order, whether or not health insurance coverage is available to pay for those expenses. The court may order either or both parents to provide health insurance coverage, cash medical support, or both, consistent with § 16-916.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In all cases where accessible health insurance coverage is available to either or both parents at reasonable cost, the court shall order either or both parents to provide the health insurance coverage, consistent with § 16-916.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_3">
      <akn:num>(c-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In selecting among health insurance coverage options, the court shall consider, at a minimum, the cost, comprehensiveness, and accessibility of all health insurance coverage options available to either parent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_3A">
      <akn:num>(c-3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In cases where accessible health insurance coverage is not available to either parent at reasonable cost, or where the medical expenses of a child are not fully covered by health insurance, the court shall order either or both parents to pay cash medical support consistent with § 16-916.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_3B">
      <akn:num>(c-3B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, health insurance coverage shall be considered reasonable in cost if the cost to the obligated parent of providing coverage for the children subject to the support order pursuant to § 16-916.01(i)(3) does not exceed 5% of the parent’s gross income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_3C">
      <akn:num>(c-3C)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, health insurance coverage shall be considered accessible if, based on the work history of the parent providing the coverage, it will be available for at least one year, and if the child lives within the geographic area covered by the plan or within 30 minutes or 30 miles of primary care services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_c_4">
      <akn:num>(c-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All support orders subject to enforcement by the IV-D agency pursuant to title IV, part D of the Social Security Act, approved January 4, 1975 (88 Stat. 2351; 42 U.S.C. § 651 et seq.), shall require the payment of support in equal monthly amounts on the first day of each month. If a support order does not require the payment of support in this manner and the support order is or becomes subject to enforcement by the IV-D agency, the IV-D agency may direct the payor, upon notice to both parents, to pay the support in equal monthly amounts on the first day of each month; provided, that the total of the monthly amounts required to be paid in one year cumulatively equals the total support required to be paid annually under the support order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court may enforce any decree entered under this section in the same manner as is provided in section 16-911.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16-916_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
