<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1207"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1207/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_1207">
        <akn:num>42-1207</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice of pendency of action (lis pendens).</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The pendency of an action or proceeding in either state or federal court in the District of Columbia, or in any other state, federal, or territorial court, affecting the title to or tenancy interest in, or asserting a mortgage, lien, security interest, or other ownership interest in real property situated in the District of Columbia, does not constitute notice to, and shall not affect a party not a party thereto, unless a notice of the pendency of the action or proceeding is filed for recordation, as required by subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The notice referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall be effective only if the underlying action or proceeding directly affects the title to or tenancy interest in, or asserts a mortgage, lien, security interest, right of first offer, right of first refusal, or other ownership interest in real property situated in the District of Columbia, and the notice is in writing, signed by the plaintiff, defendant, other party to the action or proceeding, or by a counsel of record for such party, desiring to have the notice filed for recordation, and notarized, stating the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Recorder of Deeds shall admit for filing and recordation all notices that meet the requirements of subsection (b) of this section. Such notices shall have effect from the time of the filing for recordation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a notice of the pendency of an action or proceeding is filed for recordation and the debt or other relief for which the action or proceeding was brought is satisfied, it shall be the duty of the party who filed the notice of pendency to file for recordation a release of the notice of pendency of the action or proceeding within 30 days after the satisfaction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The party who filed the notice of pendency shall have the duty to cancel the notice by filing a release with the Recorder of Deeds if the underlying action or proceeding has been dismissed or terminated without entry of a judgment, and the filing of the release is not required under subsection (e) of this section. The release shall be filed within 30 days of the date the underlying action or proceeding was dismissed or terminated or of the applicable time period set forth in subsection (d)(1)(A),(B), or (C) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_e_2">
      <akn:num>(e-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall have the authority to file with the Recorder of Deeds a release of a notice of pendency if a cancellation or release of that notice has not been filed as required by subsection (d), (e), or (e-1) of this section and one year has elapsed since the date the cancellation or release should have been filed under subsection (d), (e), or (e-1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_e_3">
      <akn:num>(e-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall promulgate regulations to implement the provisions of this section. The Mayor may, by regulation, establish reasonable fees for recordation of notices of lis pendens and may, by regulation, establish reasonable fees for releases of notices of lis pendens.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person with an ownership interest in real property upon which a notice of pendency of action has been filed under this section may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A court in which a motion is filed or an action is brought under subsection (g) of this section may issue an order canceling the notice of pendency of action prior to the entry of judgment in the underlying action or proceeding if the court finds any one of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of the Lis Pendens Amendment Act of 2010 [D.C. Law 18-180], shall apply to any notice of pendency recorded before May 27, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall not be construed to apply where the title to or interest in the real property affected by the notice is not directly at issue in the underlying action or proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1207_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term “tenancy interest” means the rights of a tenant or tenants as set forth under Chapter 34 of this title [§ 42-3401.01 et seq.], regarding the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
