<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1103"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1103/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_1103">
        <akn:num>42-1103</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Imposition of tax; rate; return; contents; liability for tax; extension of period for filing, and waiver of, return.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_a_4">
      <akn:num>(a-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning October 1, 2006, except for residential properties transferred by deed of title for a consideration less than $400,000, an additional tax of .35% is imposed upon a deed that is subject to the tax under subsection (a)(1) of this section. Of the funds collected under this subsection, 15% shall be deposited in the Housing Production Trust Fund established by ยง 42-2802, and the remainder shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The parties to a deed which is submitted to the Mayor for recordation shall be jointly and severally liable for payment of the taxes imposed by this section; provided, that neither the United States nor the District of Columbia shall be jointly and severally liable with the transferee; provided further, that, beginning October 1, 2009, in the case of a deed that evidences a transfer of an economic interest in a cooperative housing association, the cooperative housing association shall be jointly and severally liable with the parties to the deed for the payment of taxes imposed by this section regardless of whether the cooperative housing association itself is a party to the deed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1103_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The deed and accompanying return shall be due as prescribed in ยง 47-1431(a) for the recordation of a deed; provided, that if the deed and return are submitted to the Recorder of Deeds before the due date, the return shall be due and taxes shall be due and owing at the time of submission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
