<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1902.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1902.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_1902_13">
        <akn:num>42-1902.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Assignments of limited common elements; method of reassignment; amendment of instruments and recordation thereof.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1902_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All assignments and reassignments of limited common elements shall be reflected by the condominium instruments. No limited common element shall be assigned or reassigned except in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. No amendment to any condominium instrument shall alter any rights or obligations with respect to any limited common elements without the consent of all unit owners adversely affected thereby as evidenced by their execution of such amendment, except to the extent that the condominium instrument expressly provided otherwise prior to the first assignment of that limited common element.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1902_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless expressly prohibited by the condominium instruments, a limited common element may be reassigned upon written application of the condominium unit owners concerned to the principal officer of the unit owners’ association or to any officer the condominium instruments may specify. The officer to whom the application is made shall prepare and execute an amendment to the condominium instruments that reassigns any right or obligation with respect to the limited common element involved. The amendment shall be executed by the unit owners of the condominium units concerned and shall be recorded by the unit owners’ association upon payment by the unit owners of reasonable costs for preparation and acknowledgment of the amendment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1902_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A common element not previously assigned as a limited common element shall be assigned only pursuant to § 42-1902.10(a)(5). The assignment shall be made as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
