<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1903.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-1903.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_1903_09">
        <akn:num>42-1903.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tort and contract liability of association and declarant; judgment liens against common property and individual units.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1903_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An action for tort alleging a wrong done: (1) by any agent or employee of the declarant or of the unit owners’ association; or (2) in connection with the condition of any portion of the condominium which the declarant or the association has the responsibility to maintain, shall be brought against the declarant or the association, as the case may be. No unit owner shall be precluded from bringing such an action by virtue of ownership of an undivided interest in the common elements or by reason of membership in the association or status as an officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1903_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unit owners other than the declarant shall not be liable for torts caused by agents or employees of the declarant within any convertible land or using any easement reserved in the declaration or created by § 42-1902.21 and 42-1902.22.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1903_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An action arising from a contract made by or on behalf of the unit owners’ association, its executive board, or the unit owners as a group, shall be brought against the association, or against the declarant if the cause of action arose during the exercise by the declarant of control reserved pursuant to § 42-1903.02(a). No unit owner shall be precluded from bringing such an action by reason of membership in the association or status as an officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-1903_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A judgment for money against the unit owners’ association shall be a lien against any property owned by the unit owners’ association, and against each of the condominium units in proportion to the liability of each unit owner for common expenses as established pursuant to § 42-1903.12(c), but no unit owner shall be otherwise liable on account of a judgment and, after payment by the unit owner of his or her proportionate share, the association shall not assess or have a lien against the unit owner’s condominium unit for any portion of the common expenses incurred in connection with the lien. If after payment by a unit owner of a proportionate share, the unit owners’ association elects to pay the balance of the judgment from common funds, the unit owners’ association shall reimburse the unit owner for the amount the unit owner paid separately. Any judgment shall be satisfied first out of the property of the unit owners’ association. The judgment shall be otherwise subject to the provisions of Title 15.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
