<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2801"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2801/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_2801">
        <akn:num>42-2801</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Board” means the Housing Production Trust Fund Board established under § 42-2802.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_1B">
      <akn:num>(1B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child development facility” means a facility where a child development program is provided for infants and children, away from home, for less than 24 hours a day for each infant or child, and which is to be located on a proposed housing or commercial project under a linked development agreement. The term “child development facility” shall include a child development center, child development home, or infant care center, but does not include a public or private elementary school engaged in legally required education and related functions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_1C">
      <akn:num>(1C)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_1D">
      <akn:num>(1D)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_1E">
      <akn:num>(1E)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Distressed neighborhood” means a United States Census Tract that the Mayor has determined to be distressed pursuant to § 42-2802.02(e), after considering the median sales price, median home appreciation rate, poverty rate, homeownership rate, and other factors the Mayor deems reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible household” means a household that, at the time of its purchase of a qualified housing unit, had total annual income at or below 120% of the area median income; provided, that the annual incomes of eligible households assisted through an allocation of proceeds from the Housing Production Trust Fund shall not exceed 80% of the area median income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Extremely low income” means a household income equal to 30% or less of the area median income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fund” means the Housing Production Trust Fund established pursuant to § 42-2802.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Future sales price” means the greater of any contract sales price or a value equal to 90% of the fair market appraised value determined within 6 months of the date of resale by a licensed appraiser of an affordable for-sale unit produced pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing production” means the construction, rehabilitation, or preservation of decent, safe, and affordable housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Land Trust Plan” means the District of Columbia Workforce Housing Land Trust Design and Implementation Plan, as amended and approved by subchapter III-A of Chapter 10 of Title 6 [§ 6-1061.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low income” means a household income equal to, or less than, 80% of the area median income and greater than 50% of the area median income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Moderate income” means a total income equal to between 50% and 80% of the Standard Metropolitan Statistical Area median as certified by the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonprofit housing developer” means a housing developer who qualifies as a nonprofit organization under 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Preexisting equity” means the discounted price determined as the difference between an initial contract sales price and the fair market appraised value at the time of the initial sale or the amount of public subsidy provided pursuant to this chapter that was invested in the creation of the affordable housing unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_8B">
      <akn:num>(8B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resale restrictions” means the parameters that govern the allowable sale of an affordable for-sale unit produced pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Targeted population” means low and moderate income families and individuals, including the elderly, people with disabilities, and single parent families.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_9A">
      <akn:num>(9A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Very low income” means a household income equal to, or less than, 50% of the area median income and greater than 30% of the area median income.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“WMATA” means Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Workforce Housing Land Trust” means the tax-exempt organization selected by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development to administer the pilot program pursuant to § 6-1061.02(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2801_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Workforce Housing Production Program Approval Act” means subchapter III-A of Chapter 10 of Title 6 [§ 6-1061.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
