<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2812.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2812.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_2812_02">
        <akn:num>42-2812.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Findings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-204.90 provides that the Council may, by resolution, authorize the issuance of District revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, or other obligations) to borrow money to finance, refinance, or reimburse and to assist in the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of undertakings in certain areas designated in ยง 1-204.90 where the ultimate obligation to repay the revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations is that of one or more governmental persons or entities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Under ยง 42-2802, the Council established the Housing Production Trust Fund as a permanent proprietary revolving fund to be administered by the Department to provide assistance in housing production for targeted populations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor wishes to issue bonds for the benefit of the Fund and to pledge to repayment of the bonds a portion of the monies deposited into the Fund and to use the proceeds of the bonds to accomplish certain of the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-204.90 provides that bonds may be issued to assist in undertakings in the area of housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The authorization, issuance, sale, and delivery of the bonds are desirable, are in the public interest, and will promote the purposes and intent of ยง 1-204.90 and of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
