<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2503"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2503/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_2503">
        <akn:num>42-2503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Eligibility.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2503_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant shall be eligible for the Program if the applicant is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2503_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No more than one member of a household shall be eligible for the Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2503_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not limit the eligibility of an applicant to participate in the Program based on the length of employment of the applicant or the length of time that the applicant has resided in the District of Columbia if the applicant is a District of Columbia police officer, firefighter, emergency medical technician, public school teacher, or a teacher at a District of Columbia public charter school; provided, that the Mayor may limit the eligibility of an applicant to receive a District of Columbia contribution toward a down payment based on the length of employment of the applicant with the District of Columbia or a District of Columbia public charter school or the length of time the applicant has resided in the District of Columbia. The Mayor shall not limit the eligibility of an applicant to participate in the Program based on the place of residence of the applicant at the time of his or her application. A rule, or a portion of a rule, inconsistent with this subsection shall be void.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
