<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2812.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2812.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_2812_04">
        <akn:num>42-2812.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond details.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to take any action reasonably necessary or appropriate in accordance with this subchapter in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, security for, and payment of the bonds of each series, including, but not limited to, determinations of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall contain a legend, which shall provide that the bonds are special obligations of the District, are without recourse to the District, are not a pledge of, and do not involve the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than real property transfer taxes and deed recordation taxes allocated to the Allocated Fund), do not constitute a debt of the District, and do not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in § 1-206.02(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor, and attested by the Secretary of the District of Columbia by the Secretary’s manual or facsimile signature. The Mayor’s execution and delivery of the bonds shall constitute conclusive evidence of the Mayor’s approval, on behalf of the District, of the final form and content of the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds of any series may be issued in accordance with the terms of a trust instrument to be entered into by the District and a trustee to be selected by the Mayor, and may be subject to the terms of one or more agreements entered into by the Mayor pursuant to § 1-204.90(a)(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time in one or more issues and in one or more series.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
