<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2812.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-2812.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_2812_03">
        <akn:num>42-2812.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond authorization for New Community Initiative neighborhoods, including Sursum Corda.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to § 1-204.90 and this subchapter, the Mayor is authorized to issue bonds to assist in financing, refinancing, or reimbursing costs of undertakings by the District to accomplish the purposes of the New Communities Initiative. Subject to Council approval by resolution submitted by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, the Mayor is authorized to issue bonds to assist in financing, refinancing, or reimbursing costs of developing mixed income and mixed use projects situated in:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds, which may be issued from time to time, in one or more series, which shall be tax-exempt or taxable as the Mayor shall determine, shall be payable solely from and secured by monies deposited in the Allocated Fund; provided, that the total amount of funds allocated annually to pay debt service on the bonds shall not exceed $16 million.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to pay from the proceeds of the bonds the costs and expenses of issuing and delivering the bonds, including, but not limited to, underwriting, legal, accounting, financial advisory, bond insurance or other credit enhancement, marketing and selling the bonds, and printing costs and expenses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall submit and the Council shall approve, by resolution, the amount of bonds that shall be issued at any one time for a project authorized by subsection (a) of this section. Each approval resolution shall state the aggregate principal amount of bonds to be issued, and shall be accompanied by a preliminary development plan that describes the projected construction plan, and includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After May 1, 2013, all new bonds or notes for the New Communities Initiative shall be issued, secured, and paid pursuant to Subchapter II-D of Chapter 3 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code; provided, that the new bonds or notes issued for the New Communities Initiative shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-2812_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>By April 1, 2014, the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development and the District of Columbia Housing Authority shall submit a written report to the Chairperson of the Council’s Committee on Economic Development, which shall address the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
