<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3508.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3508.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3508_06">
        <akn:num>42-3508.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Incentives for development of single-room-occupancy housing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3508_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may provide tax abatements and deferral or forgiveness of water and sewer fees and other indebtedness to the District as incentives for the development of single-room-occupancy housing for low- and moderate-income tenants. These incentives shall be provided pursuant to negotiations and written agreements between the Mayor and housing providers engaged in the development or operation of single-room-occupancy housing accommodations. In these negotiations and written agreements, the Mayor may establish a formula for abating property tax liability for properties developed pursuant to this section for a period of not more than 10 years beginning during the first year that newly-constructed or rehabilitated single-room-occupancy housing becomes available for occupancy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3508_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The incentives provided by this section shall be available for new construction, renovation of any vacant rental housing accommodation, or renovation of any non-housing property, whether vacant or not, for single-room-occupancy housing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3508_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To qualify for the incentives provided by this section, the housing provider shall demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Mayor that the single-room-occupancy housing meets the following minimum standards:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3508_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 180 days from August 25, 1994, the Mayor shall compile, provide to the Council, and publish in the District of Columbia Register an initial list of District-owned and privately-owned properties in the District that are available and suitable for the development of single-room-occupancy housing in accordance with this section. At least annually thereafter, the Mayor shall publish a revised list and provide a written report to the Council regarding the status of single-room-occupancy housing development at these and other sites.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
