<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3101"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3101/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3101">
        <akn:num>42-3101</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adverse impact” means the presence of any one or more of the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community-based organization” means any group, whether unincorporated or incorporated, affiliated with or organized for the benefit of one or more communities or neighborhoods, of defined geographic boundaries, containing the drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance, or any group organized to benefit the quality of life in a residential area containing the alleged drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Controlled substance” means any of the controlled substances as defined in § 48-901.02(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drug paraphernalia” means drug paraphernalia, as defined in § 48-1101(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Firearm” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 7-2501.01(9), except that it shall not include the lawful possession of a firearm by a person who is licensed or otherwise permitted by law to possess the weapon.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Manufacturing” means the production, preparation, propagation, compounding, conversion, or processing of a controlled substance, either directly or indirectly, by extraction from substances of natural origin or independent means of chemical synthesis, including the packaging or repackaging of the drug or labeling or relabeling of its container.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means the individual, corporation, partnership, trust association, joint venture, or any other business entity, and the respective agents of such individuals or entities, in whom is vested all or any part of the title to the property alleged to be a drug-, firearm-, or prostitution-related nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property” means tangible real property, or any interest in real property, including an interest in any leasehold, license or real estate, such as any house, apartment building, condominium, cooperative, office building, storage, restaurant, tavern, nightclub, warehouse, park, median, and the land extending to the boundaries of the lot upon which such structure is situated, and anything growing on, affixed to, or found on the land.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prostitution” means prostitution as defined in § 22-2701.01(1) [now § 22-2701.01(3)], or any act that violates any provision of §§ 22-2701, 22-2703, and 22-2723, § 22-2704, §§ 22-2705 to 22-2712, and § 22-2722.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3101_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tenant” means a person who resides in or occupies real property owned by another person pursuant to a lease agreement, whether written or oral, or pursuant to a tenancy at will or sufferance at common law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
