<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3401.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3401.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3401_03">
        <akn:num>42-3401.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Appraised value” means the value of a housing accommodation as of the date of the appraisal, based on an objective, independent property valuation, performed according to professional appraisal industry standards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bona fide offer of sale” means an offer of sale for a housing accommodation or the interest in the housing accommodation that is either:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_2A">
      <akn:num>(2A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Condominium” has the same meaning as in § 42-1901.02(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_2B">
      <akn:num>(2B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Condominium Act” means the Condominium Act of 1976 (§ 42-1901.01 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Condominium conversion” is the issuance of notice of filing pursuant to § 42-1904.06(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Conversion” shall include cooperative conversions and condominium conversions as defined in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cooperative” means a cooperative legally incorporated pursuant to the District of Columbia Cooperative Association Act (§ 29-901 et seq.) or a cooperative corporation incorporated in another jurisdiction for the primary purpose of owning and operating real property in which its members reside.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cooperative Act” means the District of Columbia Cooperative Association Act (§ 29-901 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cooperative conversion” is the filing of articles of incorporation pursuant to the Cooperative Act, or the comparable act of another jurisdiction and compliance with the requirements of this chapter, in either order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Division” means the Rental Accommodations Division established by § 42-3502.03 or the Rental Conversion and Sale Division established by § 42-3502.04a.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Head of household” means a tenant who maintains the affected rental unit as the tenant’s principal place of residence, is a resident and domiciliary of the District of Columbia, and contributes more than one-half of the cost of maintaining the rental unit. If no member of a household contributes more than one-half of the cost of maintaining the rental unit, the members of the household who maintain the affected rental unit as their principal place of residence are residents and domiciliaries of the District of Columbia, and contribute to the cost of maintaining the rental unit, may designate one of themselves as the head of household. An individual may be considered a head of household for the purposes of this chapter without regard to whether the individual would qualify as a head of household for the purpose of any other law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_10A">
      <akn:num>(10A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Highest and best use” means the reasonably probable legal use of a property that is physically possible, appropriately supported, and financially feasible and that results in the highest value of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Housing accommodation” or “accommodation” means a structure in the District of Columbia containing 1 or more rental units and the appurtenant land. The term does not include a hotel, motel, or other structure used primarily for transient occupancy and in which at least 60 percent of the rooms devoted to living quarters for tenants or guests are used for transient occupancy if the owner or other person or entity entitled to receive rents is subject to the sales tax imposed by § 47-2001(n)(1)(C) and the occupant of the rental unit has been in occupancy for less than 15 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low-income” means a household with a combined annual income, in a manner to be determined by the Mayor, which may include federal income tax returns where applicable, totaling less than the following percentages of the lower income guidelines established pursuant to § 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (42 U.S.C. § 1437f) for a family of 4 for the Washington Standard Metropolitan Statistical Area (SMSA), as the median is determined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development and adjusted yearly by historic trends of that median, and as may be further adjusted by an interim census of District of Columbia incomes by local or regional government agencies:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_12A">
      <akn:num>(12A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Matter-of-right” means a land use, development density, or structural dimension to which a property owner is entitled by current zoning regulations or law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the designated representative of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means an individual, corporation, association, joint venture, business entity and its respective agents, who hold title to the housing accommodation unit or cooperative share.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Rental Housing Act” means the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; § 42-3501.01 et seq.), or any successor rent control act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Rental unit” or “unit” means only that part of a housing accommodation which is rented or offered for rent for residential occupancy and includes an apartment, efficiency apartment, room, suite of rooms, and single-family home or duplex, and the appurtenant land to such rental unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tenant” means a tenant, subtenant, lessee, sublessee, or other person entitled to the possession, occupancy or benefits of a rental unit within a housing accommodation. If the names of 2 or more persons appear on a rental agreement, those persons shall determine which person may exercise a vote under this chapter. The singular term “tenant” includes the plural.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3401_03_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tenant organization” means an organization that represents at least a majority of the heads of household in the housing accommodation excluding those households in which no member has resided in the housing accommodation for at least 90 days and those households in which any member has been an employee of the owner during the preceding 120 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
