<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3405.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3405.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3405_05">
        <akn:num>42-3405.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Investigations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may make necessary public or private investigations in accordance with law within or without of the District of Columbia to determine compliance with the requirements of this chapter or to determine whether any person has violated or is about to violate this chapter or any rule or order hereunder, or to aid in the enforcement of this chapter or in the prescribing of rules and forms hereunder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of any investigation under this chapter, the Mayor or any officer designated by rule may administer oaths or affirmations, subpoena witnesses and compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any matter which is relevant to the investigation, including the existence, description, nature, custody, condition, and location of any books, documents or other tangible things and the identity and location of persons having knowledge or relevant facts or any other matter reasonably calculated to lead to the discovery of material evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon failure to obey a subpoena or to answer questions propounded by the investigating officer and upon reasonable notice to all persons affected thereby, the Mayor may apply to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order compelling compliance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
