<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3502.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3502.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3502_05">
        <akn:num>42-3502.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Registration and coverage.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Sections 42-3502.05(f) through 42-3502.19, except ยง 42-3502.17, shall apply to each rental unit in the District except:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rent may not be increased under subsections (a)(9) and (a)(10) of this section if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsections (b)(1) and (b)(2) of this section the housing provider shall be entitled to an exemption whenever the unit is next vacated in accordance with subsections (a)(9) and (a)(10)(A) of this section after an intervening loss of the exemption.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to the execution of a lease or other rental agreement after July 17, 1985, a prospective tenant of any unit exempted under subsection (a) of this section shall receive a notice in writing advising the prospective tenant that rent increases for the accommodation are not regulated by the rent stabilization program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not apply to the following units:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days of July 17, 1985, each housing provider of any rental unit not exempted by this chapter and not registered under the Rental Housing Act of 1980, shall file with the Rent Administrator, on a form approved by the Rent Administrator, a new registration statement for each housing accommodation in the District for which the housing provider is receiving rent or is entitled to receive rent. Any person who becomes a housing provider of such a rental unit after July 17, 1985 shall have 30 days within which to file a registration statement with the Rent Administrator. No penalties shall be assessed against any housing provider who, during the 120-day period, registers any units under this chapter, for the failure to have previously registered the units. The registration form shall contain, but not be limited to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3502_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each registration statement filed under this section shall be available for public inspection at the Division, and each housing provider shall keep a duplicate of the registration statement posted in a public place on the premises of the housing accommodation to which the registration statement applies. Each housing provider may, instead of posting in each housing accommodation comprised of a single rental unit, mail to each tenant of the housing accommodation a duplicate of the registration statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
