<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3404.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3404.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3404_02">
        <akn:num>42-3404.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tenant opportunity to purchase; “sale” defined.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3404_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before an owner of a housing accommodation may sell the housing accommodation or issue a notice to vacate for purposes of demolition or discontinuance of housing use, the owner shall give the tenant an opportunity to purchase the housing accommodation at a price and terms that represent a bona fide offer of sale.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3404_02_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever an offer of sale is made to tenants for a housing accommodation with 5 or more units that is required by subsection (a) of this section before the owner may issue a notice to vacate for purposes of demolition or discontinuance of housing use, and the offer is made in the absence of an arm’s-length third-party contract, the following shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3404_02_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a-1) of this section, for a tenant organization that before February 26, 2016 has registered the tenant organization with the Mayor pursuant to § 42-3404.11(1) and pursuant to either § 42-3405.03 or § 42-3405.03a has filed a complaint concerning this section, the following shall apply, beginning January 1, 2014:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3404_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of subchapters IV and V of this chapter, the terms “sell” or “sale” include, but are not limited to, the execution of any agreement pursuant to which the owner of the housing accommodation agrees to some, but not all, of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3404_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3404_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
