<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3503.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3503.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3503_03">
        <akn:num>42-3503.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authorization to enter into contracts for tenant assistance payments; determination of eligibility; procedure upon determination of eligibility.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may enter into contracts to make rental assistance payments to housing providers of rental dwelling units on behalf of eligible families in accordance with this section. Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2 shall not apply to the contracts authorized by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the fair market rents applicable to the Tenant Assistance Program shall be the fair market rents established annually by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (“HUD”) for new construction and substantial rehabilitation in the Washington, D.C., market. The Department, by rule, may establish the fair market rents for units in sizes for which there is no fair market rent established by HUD. If the Department, after reviewing the fair market rents established by HUD for the Washington, D.C., market, determines that the amounts do not accurately reflect fair market rents in the District, the Department may, by rule, adjust the amounts. If the proposed fair market rents vary from the fair market rents established by HUD, the Department shall submit a resolution for approval of the proposed fair market rents to the Council of the District of Columbia (“Council”) for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed resolution, in whole or in part, within this 45-day review period, the proposed resolution shall be deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Applications to participate in the Tenant Assistance Program shall be submitted to the Department and shall be in a form designated by the Department. The Department shall be responsible for verifying the sources of the family’s income and gathering information necessary for determining eligibility and the amount of the assistance payment. Priority shall be given to the elderly, individuals with disabilities, single-parent households, and applicants who have completed any employment training course provided by any District agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an applicant is determined by the Department to be eligible and is selected for participation, the applicant shall be given a certificate of eligibility. At the same time, the family shall be given a certificate holder’s packet which contains a request for lease approval, a list of properties for rent, information concerning recently completed housing, if any, including the location, and other items the Department determines should be included. In addition, the Department shall provide a full explanation of the following to assist the family in finding a suitable rental unit and to apprise the family and the housing provider of their respective responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon determination of eligibility the Department shall enter on each certificate the smallest unit-size appropriate for the eligible family consistent with the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3503_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Owners of rental accommodations in the District shall notify tenants of the existence of the Tenant Assistance Program and shall refer interested parties to the Department for further information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
