<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3405.10a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/42-3405.10a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_42_3405_10a">
        <akn:num>42-3405.10a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act Task Force.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_10a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall establish a Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act Task Force (“Task Force”) within 30 days after July 22, 2005.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_10a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The general mandate of the Task Force shall be to examine all aspects of subchapters IV and V of this chapter, including its implementation and compliance with its requirements, and to determine the best means for preserving rental housing, preventing the deterioration of the housing stock, and preventing the displacement of tenants.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_10a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall establish the methodology for achieving the purposes of the Task Force in consultation with the members. The Task Force shall issue a report and recommendations proposing policy initiatives and revisions to the statute designed to improve subchapters IV and V of this chapter, which shall be distributed to all members of the Council and the Mayor and made available to the general public within 30 days after its issuance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_10a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As part of its review, the Task Force shall consider:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_10a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Task Force shall be composed of 7 members, 5 of whom shall be appointed by the Mayor and 2 of whom shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Council. Members of the Task Force shall represent the interests affected by this chapter, including tenants, owners, the District government, title insurers, and other industry representatives.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42-3405_10a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Task Force shall continue in existence for 6 months and shall issue its report and recommendations before disbanding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
