<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1202"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1202/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1202">
        <akn:num>31-1202</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund; funding; uses; budget.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1202_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a trust fund designated as the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund, to which shall be credited all funds obtained pursuant to this chapter and Chapter 52A of this title without regard to fiscal year limitation. All monies and interest earned on monies deposited in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund shall be credited to the Fund and used solely for the purpose of this chapter and Chapter 52A of this title. Insurers and health maintenance organizations will be assessed separately. The funds obtained from assessments on insurance companies and health maintenance organizations will not be commingled within the Trust Fund, and separate accounts will be maintained within the Trust Fund in order to properly allocate assessment revenue and expenditures to insurers and health maintenance organizations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1202_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the applicable laws relating to the appropriation of District funds, monies received and deposited in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund or a division thereof, shall be used to defray the expenses of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking in the discharge of its administrative and regulatory duties as prescribed by law. These monies shall be deemed to include all administrative costs for regulating insurers and health maintenance organizations doing business in the District of Columbia, and no other assessments shall be charged for such purpose after the effective date of this chapter. The Mayor shall be responsible for the deposit and expenditure of these monies as provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1202_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1202_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1202_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1202_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council of the District of Columbia shall approve and establish the budget of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund in the same manner and at the same level of detail as approved and established for departments and agencies under the administrative control of the Mayor as provided in ยง 1-204.04(f).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
