<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1003"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1003/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1003">
        <akn:num>31-1003</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1003_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements need be reported pursuant to § 31-1001 if the nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions are not material.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1003_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this chapter, a material nonrenewal, cancellation, or revision is one that affects:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1003_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As respects either property and casualty or life, annuity, and accident and health business, either of the following events shall constitute a material revision which must be reported:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1003_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No filing shall be required if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1003_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following information is required to be disclosed in any report of a material nonrenewal, cancellation, or revision of ceded reinsurance agreements:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1003_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Insurers are required to report all material nonrenewals, cancellations, or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements on a nonconsolidated basis unless the insurer is part of a consolidated group of insurers which utilizes a pooling arrangement or 100% reinsurance agreement that affects the solvency and integrity of the insurer’s reserves and the insurer ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to the pool. An insurer is deemed to have ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to a pool if the insurer has less than $1,000,000 total direct plus assumed written premiums during a calendar year that $1,000,000 total direct plus assumed written premiums during a calendar year that are not subject to a pooling arrangement and the net income of the business not subject to the pooling arrangement represents less than 5% of the insurer’s capital and surplus.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
