<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1801"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1801/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1801">
        <akn:num>31-1801</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Actuary” means a person who is a member in good standing of the American Academy of Actuaries.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Controlling person” means any person, firm, association, or corporation who directly or indirectly has the power to direct, or cause to be directed, the management, control, or activities of the reinsurance intermediary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Holding Company Act” means the Holding Company System Act of 1993, Chapter 7 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurer” means any person, firm, association, or corporation duly licensed in the District pursuant to the applicable provisions of District insurance law as an insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Licensed producer” means an agent, broker, or reinsurance intermediary licensed pursuant to the applicable provision of insurance law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reinsurance intermediary” means a reinsurance intermediary-broker or a reinsurance intermediary-manager as these terms are defined in paragraphs (8) and (9) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reinsurance intermediary-broker” (“RB”) means any person, other than an officer or employee of the ceding insurer, firm, association, or corporation who solicits, negotiates, or places reinsurance cessions or retrocessions on behalf of a ceding insurer without the authority or power to bind reinsurance on behalf of the insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reinsurance intermediary-manager” (“RM”) means any person, firm, association, or corporation that has authority to bind or manages all or part of the assumed reinsurance business of a reinsurer, including the management of a separate division, department, or underwriting office, and acts as an agent for the reinsurer whether known as a RM, manager, or other similar term. Notwithstanding the above, for the purposes of this chapter, the following persons shall not be considered a RM, with respect to such a reinsurer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reinsurer” means any person, firm, association, or corporation duly licensed in the District pursuant to the applicable provisions of insurance law of the District as an insurer with the authority to assume reinsurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“ To be in violation” means that the reinsurance intermediary, insurer, or reinsurer for whom the reinsurance intermediary was acting failed to substantially comply with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1801_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified United States financial institution” means an institution that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
