<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1332"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1332/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1332">
        <akn:num>31-1332</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Domiciliary liquidator’s proposal to distribute assets.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1332_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days of a final determination of insolvency of an insurer by a court of competent jurisdiction of the District of Columbia, the liquidator shall make application to the court for approval of a proposal to disburse assets out of marshalled assets, from time to time as the assets become available, to a guaranty association or foreign guaranty association having obligations because of the insolvency. If the liquidator determines that there are insufficient assets to disburse, the application required by this section shall be considered satisfied by a filing by the liquidator stating the reasons for this determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1332_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proposal required by subsection (a) of this section shall at least include provisions for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1332_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The liquidator’s proposal shall provide for disbursements to the associations in amounts estimated at least equal to the claim payments made or to be made thereby for which the associations could assert a claim against the liquidator, and shall further provide that if the assets available for disbursement from time to time do not equal or exceed the amount of the claim payments made or to be made by the association, then disbursements shall be in the amount of available assets.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1332_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The liquidator’s proposal shall, with respect to an insolvent insurer writing life or health insurance or annuities, provide for disbursements of assets to any guaranty association or any foreign guaranty association covering life or health insurance or annuities, or to any other entity or organization reinsuring, assuming, or guaranteeing policies or contracts of insurance under the acts creating the associations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1332_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of the application shall be given to the association in and to the commissioners of insurance of each of the states. Such a notice shall be deemed to have been given when deposited in the United States certified mails, first class postage prepaid, at least 30 days prior to submission of the application to the court. Action on the application may be taken by the court provided the above required notice has been given, and, provided further, that the liquidator’s proposal complies with subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
