<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1503"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1503/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1503">
        <akn:num>31-1503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Required contract provisions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The insurer may terminate the contract for cause upon written notice to the managing general agent. The insurer may suspend the underwriting authority of the managing general agent during the pendency of any dispute regarding the cause for termination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The managing general agent will render accounts to the insurer detailing all transactions and remit all funds due under the contract to the insurer on not less than a monthly basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds collected for the account of an insurer will be held in a separate account by the managing general agent in a fiduciary capacity in a bank which is a member of the Federal Reserve System. This account shall be used for all payments on behalf of the insurer. The managing general agent may retain no more than 3 months estimated claims payments and allocated loss adjustment expenses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Separate records of business written by the managing general agent will be maintained. The insurer shall have access and right to copy all accounts and records related to its business in a form usable by the insurer, and the Mayor shall have access to all books, bank accounts, and records of the managing general agent in a form usable to the Mayor. These records shall be retained according to Chapter 14 of this title, and §§ 31-4440 and 31-5204.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The contract may not be assigned in whole or part by the managing general agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appropriate underwriting guidelines are required, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The insurer shall have the right to cancel or not renew any policy of insurance subject to the applicable laws and regulations of the District governing the cancellation and nonrenewal of insurance policies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the contract permits the managing general agent to settle claims on behalf of the insurer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where electronic claims files are in existence, the contract must address the timely transmission of the data.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the contract provides for a sharing of interim profits by the managing general agent, and the managing general agent has the authority to determine the amount of the interim profits by establishing loss reserves or controlling claim payments, or in any other manner, interim profits will not be paid to the managing general agent until 1 year after they are earned for property insurance business and 5 years after they are earned on casualty business and not until the profits have been verified pursuant to § 31-1504.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1503_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The managing general agent shall not:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
