<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1131.08a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1131.08a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1131_08a">
        <akn:num>31-1131.08a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Changes of name, residency, or address.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_08a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensee shall inform the Commissioner of a change of the licensee’s residential or business address within 30 days of the change of address. A nonresident insurance producer who moves from one state to another state or a resident insurance producer who moves from the District to another state shall file a change of address and provide certification from the new resident state within 30 days after the change of residence. No fee or license application shall be required.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_08a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A licensee shall inform the Commissioner of a change of the licensee’s legal or corporate name within 30 days after the change of name.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_08a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Failure to timely inform the Commissioner of a change in legal name or address shall result in a penalty as prescribed by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_08a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person licensed as an insurance producer in another state who moves to the District shall make application within 90 days of establishing legal residence to become a resident licensee under § 31-1131.06 unless the person maintains his principal place of business in another state and the person has a resident insurance producer license in that state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
