<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1371.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1371.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1371_04">
        <akn:num>31-1371.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authorization of investments by the board of directors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An insurer’s board of directors shall adopt a written plan for acquiring and holding investments and for engaging in investment practices that specifies guidelines as to the quality, maturity, and diversification of investments and other specifications, including investment strategies intended to assure that the investments and investment practices are appropriate for the business conducted by the insurer, its liquidity needs, and its capital and surplus. The board of directors shall review and assess the insurer’s technical investment and administrative capabilities and expertise before adopting a written plan concerning an investment strategy or investment practice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Investments acquired and held under this chapter shall be acquired and held under the supervision and direction of the board of directors of the insurer. The board of directors shall evidence by formal resolution, at least annually, that it has determined whether all investments have been made in accordance with delegations, standards, limitations, and investment objectives prescribed by the board of directors or a committee of the board of directors charged with the responsibility to direct its investments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On no less than a quarterly basis, and more often if considered appropriate, an insurer’s board of directors, or committee of the board of directors, shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In discharging its duties under this section, the board of directors shall require that records of an authorization or approval, other documentation as the board of directors may require, and the report of an action taken under authority delegated under the plan referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall be made available on a regular basis to the board of directors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In discharging their duties under this section, the directors of an insurer shall perform their duties in good faith and with that degree of care that ordinarily prudent individuals in like positions would use under similar circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an insurer does not have a board of directors, all references to the board of directors in this chapter shall refer to the governing body of the insurer having authority equivalent to that of a board of directors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
