<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1131.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1131.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1131_12">
        <akn:num>31-1131.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>License denial, nonrenewal, suspension, or revocation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may refuse to issue an insurance producer license; place an insurance producer on probation; suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew an insurance producer’s license; levy a civil penalty in accordance with subsection (d) of this section; issue subpoenas and administer oaths; or take any combination of these actions if an insurance producer or an applicant for an insurance producer license:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the reasons set forth in subsection (a) of this section, the Commissioner may place a business entity insurance producer on probation; suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew a business entity insurance producer’s license; or levy a civil penalty against a business entity insurance producer if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to or in lieu of any applicable denial of renewal, suspension, or revocation of a license, the Commissioner may, after a hearing, take any of the following actions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person affected or aggrieved by an order, ruling, proceeding, or action of the Commissioner, or any person acting on behalf of the Commissioner, under this section may contest the validity of the same in any court of competent jurisdiction by appeal or through any other appropriate proceedings. In any proceeding or appeal, the Commissioner shall not be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1131_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the revocation, surrender, or lapse of a license, the Commissioner may enforce the provisions of, and impose any penalty or remedy authorized by, this chapter or any other District law relating to insurance against any person who is under investigation for or charged with a violation of this chapter or any other District law relating to insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
