<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1316"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1316/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1316">
        <akn:num>31-1316</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Liquidation orders.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1316_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order to liquidate the business of a domestic insurer shall appoint the Commissioner and his or her successors in office liquidator and shall direct the liquidator to take possession of the assets of the insurer and to administer them under the general supervision of the court. The liquidator shall be vested by operation of law with the title to all of the property, contracts, and rights of action, and all of the books and records of the insurer ordered liquidated, wherever located, as of the entry of the final order of liquidation. The filing or recording of the order with the Clerk of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, or, in the case of real estate, with the recorder of deeds of the county where the property is located, shall impart the same notice as a deed, bill of sale, or other evidence of title duly filed or recorded with that recorder of deeds would have imparted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1316_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon issuance of the order, the rights and liabilities of any insurer and of its creditors, policyholders, shareholders, members, and all other persons interested in its estate shall become fixed as of the date of entry of the order of liquidation, except as provided in §§ 31-1317 and 31-1335.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1316_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order to liquidate the business of an alien insurer domiciled in the District shall be in the same terms and have the same legal effect as an order to liquidate a domestic insurer, except that the assets and the business in the United States shall be the only assets and business included therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1316_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the time of petitioning for an order of liquidation, or at any time thereafter, the Commissioner, after making appropriate findings of an insurer’s insolvency, may petition the court for a judicial declaration of insolvency. After providing notice and hearing it deems proper, the court may make the declaration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1316_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any order issued under this section shall require financial reports to the court by the liquidator. Financial reports shall include, at a minimum, the assets and liabilities of the insurer and all funds received or disbursed by the liquidator during the current period. Financial reports shall be filed within 1 year of the liquidation order and at least annually thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1316_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
