<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1326"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1326/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1326">
        <akn:num>31-1326</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Voidable preferences and liens.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transfer of property for or on account of a new and contemporaneous consideration which is deemed under subsection (b) of this section to be made or suffered after the transfer because of delay in perfecting it does not thereby become a transfer for or on account of an antecedent debt if any acts required by the applicable law to be performed in order to perfect the transfer as against liens or bona fide purchasers’ rights are performed within 21 days or any period expressly allowed by the law, whichever is less. A transfer to secure a future loan, if such a loan is actually made, or a transfer which becomes security for a future loan, shall have the same effect as a transfer for or on account of a new and contemporaneous consideration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any lien deemed voidable under subsection (a)(2) of this section has been dissolved by the furnishing of a bond or other obligation, the surety on which has been indemnified directly or indirectly by the transfer of or the creation of a lien upon any property of an insurer before the filing of a petition under this chapter which results in a liquidation order, the indemnifying transfer or lien shall also be deemed voidable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The property affected by any lien deemed voidable under subsections (a) and (e) of this section shall be discharged from the lien, and that property and any of the indemnifying property transferred to or for the benefit of a surety shall pass to the liquidator, except that the court may on due notice order such a lien to be preserved for the benefit of the estate and the court may direct that such a conveyance be executed as may be proper or adequate to evidence the title of the liquidator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall have summary jurisdiction of any proceeding by the liquidator to hear and determine the rights of any parties under this section. Reasonable notice of any hearing in the proceeding shall be given to all parties in interest, including the obligee of a releasing bond or other like obligation. Where an order is entered for the recovery of indemnifying property in kind or for the avoidance of an indemnifying lien, the court, upon application of any party in interest, shall in the same proceeding ascertain the value of the property or lien, and if the value is less than the amount for which the property is indemnified or than the amount of the lien, the transferee or lienholder may elect to retain the property or lien upon payment of its value, as ascertained by the court, to the liquidator, within a reasonable time as the court shall fix.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The liability of the surety under a releasing bond or other like obligation shall be discharged to the extent of the value of the indemnifying property recovered or the indemnifying lien nullified and avoided by the liquidator, or, where the property is retained under subsection (g) of this section, to the extent of the amount paid to the liquidator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a creditor has been preferred, and afterward in good faith gives the insurer further credit without security of any kind, for property which becomes a part of the insurer’s estate, the amount of the new credit remaining unpaid at the time of the petition may be set off against the preference which would otherwise be recoverable from him.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an insurer, directly or indirectly, within 4 months before the filing of a successful petition for liquidation under this chapter, or at any time in contemplation of a proceeding to liquidate it, pays money or transfers property to an attorney-at-law for services rendered or to be rendered, the transactions may be examined by the court on its own motion or shall be examined by the court on petition of the liquidator and shall be held valid only to the extent of a reasonable amount to be determined by the court, and the excess may be recovered by the liquidator for the benefit of the estate provided that where the attorney is in a position of influence in the insurer or an affiliate payment of any money or the transfer of any property to the attorney-at-law for services rendered or to be rendered shall be governed by the provisions of subsection (a)(2)(D) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1326_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
