<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1371.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-1371.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_1371_02">
        <akn:num>31-1371.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Acceptable collateral” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Acceptable private mortgage insurance” means insurance written by a private insurer protecting a mortgage lender against loss occasioned by a mortgage loan default and issued by a licensed mortgage insurance company, with an SVO 1 designation or a rating issued by a nationally recognized statistical rating organization equivalent to an SVO 1 designation, that covers losses to an 80% loan-to-value ratio.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Accident and health insurance” means protection which provides payment of benefits for covered sickness or accidental injury, excluding credit insurance, disability insurance, accidental death and dismemberment insurance, and long-term care insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Accident and health insurer” means a licensed life or health insurer or health service corporation whose insurance premiums and required statutory reserves for accident and health insurance constitute at least 95% of total premium considerations or total statutory required reserves, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Admitted assets” means assets having economic value which can be used to fulfill policy obligations and permitted, as allowed in the National Association of Insurance Commissioners Accounting Practices and Procedures Manual, to be reported as admitted assets on the statutory financial statement of the insurer most recently required to be filed with the Commissioner, but excluding assets of separate accounts, the investments of which are not subject to the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means, as to any person, another person that, directly or indirectly through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with the person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Asset-backed security” means a security or other instrument, excluding a mutual fund, evidencing an interest in, providing the right to receive payments from, or payable from distributions on, an asset, a pool of assets, or specifically divisible cash flows which are legally transferred to a trust or another special purpose bankruptcy-remote business entity, under the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business entity” includes a sole proprietorship, corporation, limited liability company, association, partnership, joint stock company, joint venture, mutual fund, trust, joint tenancy or other similar form of business organization, whether organized for profit or not for profit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cap” means an agreement obligating the seller to make payments to the buyer, with each payment based on the amount by which a reference price or level or the performance or value of one or more underlying interests exceeds a predetermined number, sometimes called the strike rate or strike price.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Capital and surplus” means the sum of the capital and surplus of the insurer required to be shown on the statutory financial statement of the insurer most recently required to be filed with the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Cash equivalents” means short-term, highly rated, and highly liquid investments or securities readily convertible to known amounts of cash without penalty. Cash equivalents shall include government money market mutual funds and class one money market mutual funds. For the purposes of this definition:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Class one bond mutual fund” means a bond mutual fund that at all times qualifies for investment using the bond class one reserve factor under the Purposes and Procedures of the Securities Valuation Office of the Securities Valuation Office or any successor publication.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Class one money market mutual fund” means a money market mutual fund that at all times qualifies for investment using the bond class one reserve factor under the Purposes and Procedures of the Securities Valuation Office of the Securities Valuation Office or any successor publication.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Code” means the laws relating to insurance which are codified in this title of the D.C. Official Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Collar” means an agreement to receive payments as the buyer of an option, cap, or floor and to make payments as the seller of a different option, cap, or floor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial mortgage loan” means a loan secured by a mortgage other than a residential mortgage loan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Construction loan” means a loan with a term of less than 3 years made for financing the cost of construction of a building or other improvement to real estate and secured by the real estate to be improved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Control” means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of a person, whether through the ownership of voting securities, by contract (other than a commercial contract for goods or non-management services), or otherwise, unless the power is the result of an official position with or corporate office held by the person. Control shall be presumed to exist if a person, directly or indirectly, owns, controls, holds with the power to vote, or holds proxies representing, 10% or more of the voting securities of another person. This presumption may be rebutted by a showing that control does not exist in fact. The Commissioner may determine, after furnishing all interested persons notice and an opportunity to be heard and making specific findings of fact to support the determination, that control exists in fact, notwithstanding the absence of a presumption to that effect.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Covered” means that, in an income generation transaction, an insurer owns or can immediately acquire, through the exercise of options, warrants, or conversion rights already owned, the underlying interest to fulfill or secure its obligations under a call option, cap, or floor it has written, or has set aside under a custodial or escrow agreement cash or cash equivalents with a market value equal to the amount required to fulfill its obligations under a put option it has written.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Credit tenant loan” means a mortgage loan which is made primarily in reliance on the credit standing of a major tenant, structured with an assignment of the rental payments to the lender, and is secured by a first lien on the real estate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Derivative transaction” means a transaction involving the use of one or more derivative instruments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Direct” or “directly”, when used in connection with an obligation, means that the designated obligor is primarily liable on the instrument representing the obligation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Dollar roll transaction” means 2 simultaneous transactions with different settlement dates no more than 96 days apart, where, in the first transaction, an insurer sells to a business entity and, in the second transaction, the insurer is obligated to purchase from the same business entity, substantially similar securities of the following types:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic jurisdiction” means the United States, Canada, the District of Columbia, any state, any province of Canada, or any political subdivision of any of the foregoing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Equity interest” means any of the following that are not rated credit instruments:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Equivalent securities” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Floor” means an agreement obligating the seller to make payments to the buyer in which each payment is based on the amount by which a predetermined number, sometimes called the floor rate or price, exceeds a reference price, level, performance, or value of one or more underlying interests.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign currency” means a currency other than that of a domestic jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Foreign jurisdiction” means a jurisdiction other than a domestic jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Forward” means an agreement (other than a future) to make or take delivery of, or effect a cash settlement based on the actual or expected price, level, performance, or value of, one or more underlying interests.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Future” means an agreement, traded on a qualified exchange or qualified foreign exchange, to make or take delivery of, or effect a cash settlement based on the actual or expected price, level, performance or value of, one or more underlying interests.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Government money market mutual fund” means a money market mutual fund that at all times:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Government-sponsored enterprise” means a:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Guaranteed or insured”, when used in connection with an obligation acquired under this chapter, means that the guarantor or insurer has agreed to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hedging transaction” means a derivative transaction which is entered into and maintained to reduce:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“High grade investment” means a rated credit instrument rated 1 or 2 by the SVO.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Income” means, as to a security, interest, accrual of discount, dividends, or other distributions, such as rights, tax or assessment credits, warrants, and distributions in kind.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Income generation transaction” means a derivative transaction involving the writing of covered call option, covered put options, covered caps, or covered floors that is intended to generate income or enhance return.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Initial margin” means the amount of cash, securities, or other consideration initially required to be deposited to establish a futures position.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurance future” means a future relating to an index or pool that is based on insurance-related items.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_44">
      <akn:num>(44)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurance futures option” means an option on an insurance futures contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_45">
      <akn:num>(45)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment company” means an investment company as defined in section 3(a)(1) of the Investment Company Act of 1940, approved August 20, 1940 (56 Stat. 867; 15 U.S.C. § 80a-3(a)(1)), and a person described in section 3(c) of the Investment Company Act of 1940, approved August 20, 1940 (56 Stat. 867; 15 U.S.C.§ 80a-3(c)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_46">
      <akn:num>(46)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment company series” means an investment portfolio of an investment company that is organized as a series company and to which assets of the investment company have been specifically allocated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_47">
      <akn:num>(47)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment practices” means transactions of the types described in § 31-1372.08, § 31-1372.10, § 31-1373.09, or § 31-1373.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_48">
      <akn:num>(48)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment subsidiary” means a subsidiary of an insurer engaged or organized to engage exclusively in the ownership and management of assets authorized as investments for the insurer if each subsidiary agrees to limit its investment in any asset so that its investments will not cause the amount of the total investment of the insurer to exceed any of the investment limitations or avoid any other provisions of this chapter applicable to the insurer. For the purposes of this paragraph, the total investment of the insurer shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_49">
      <akn:num>(49)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment strategy” means the techniques and methods used by an insurer to meet its investment objectives, such as active bond portfolio management, passive bond portfolio management, interest rate anticipation, growth investment, and value investing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_50">
      <akn:num>(50)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Letter of credit” means a clean, irrevocable, and unconditional letter of credit issued or confirmed by, and payable and presentable at, a financial institution on the list of financial institutions meeting the standards for issuing letters of credit under the Purposes and Procedures of the Securities Valuation Office of the Securities Valuation Office of the Securities Valuation Office, or any successor publication. To constitute acceptable collateral for the purposes of § 31-1372.08 and § 31-1373.02, a letter of credit shall have an expiration date beyond the term of the subject transaction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_51">
      <akn:num>(51)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Limited liability company” means an entity that is an unincorporated association, having perpetual duration, having one or more members that is organized and existing under Chapter 8 of Title 29, or under the laws of the United States or any state thereof that limits the personal liability of each member to the equity investment of the member in the business entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_52">
      <akn:num>(52)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Lower grade investment” means a rated credit instrument rated 4, 5, or 6 by the SVO.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_53">
      <akn:num>(53)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Market value” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_54">
      <akn:num>(54)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medium grade investment” means a rated credit instrument rated 3 by the SVO.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_55">
      <akn:num>(55)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Modified guaranteed contracts” means a modified guaranteed annuity or modified guaranteed life insurance policy or contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_56">
      <akn:num>(56)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Money market mutual fund” means a mutual fund that meets the conditions of 17 C.F.R. § 270.2a-7.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_57">
      <akn:num>(57)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mortgage loan” means an obligation secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, trust deed, or other consensual lien on real estate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_58">
      <akn:num>(58)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Multilateral development bank” means an international development organization of which the United States is a member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_59">
      <akn:num>(59)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mutual fund” means an investment company or, in the case of an investment company that is organized as a series company, an investment company series, that is registered with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission under the Investment Company Act of 1940, approved August 20, 1940 (56 Stat. 789; 15 U.S.C. § 80a-1 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_60">
      <akn:num>(60)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“NAIC” means the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_61">
      <akn:num>(61)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Obligation” means a bond, note, debenture, trust certificate, including an equipment certificate, production payment, negotiable bank certificate of deposit, bankers’ acceptance, credit tenant loan, loan secured by financing, net leases and other evidence of indebtedness for the payment of money (or participations, certificates, or other evidences of an interest in any of the foregoing), whether constituting a general obligation of the issuer or payable only out of certain revenues or certain funds pledged or otherwise dedicated for payment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_62">
      <akn:num>(62)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_63">
      <akn:num>(63)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, a business entity, a multilateral development bank, or a government or quasi-governmental body, such as a political subdivision or a government-sponsored enterprise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_64">
      <akn:num>(64)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Potential exposure” means the amount determined in accordance with the NAIC Annual Statement Instructions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_65">
      <akn:num>(65)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Preferred stock” means stock of a business entity, which stock has a preference in liquidation over the common stock of the business entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_66">
      <akn:num>(66)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified bank” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_67">
      <akn:num>(67)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified business entity” means a business entity that is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_68">
      <akn:num>(68)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified clearinghouse” means a clearinghouse for, and subject to the rules of, a qualified exchange or a qualified foreign exchange, which provides clearing services, including acting as a counterparty to each of the parties to a transaction such that the parties no longer have credit risk as to each other.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_69">
      <akn:num>(69)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified exchange” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_70">
      <akn:num>(70)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified foreign exchange” means a foreign exchange, board of trade, or contract market located outside the United States, its territories, or possessions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_71">
      <akn:num>(71)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_72">
      <akn:num>(72)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_73">
      <akn:num>(73)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Replication transaction” means a derivative transaction that is intended to replicate the performance of one or more assets that an insurer may acquire under this chapter. A derivative transaction that is entered into as a hedging transaction shall not be considered a replication transaction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_74">
      <akn:num>(74)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Repurchase transaction” means a transaction in which an insurer purchases securities from a business entity that is obligated to repurchase the purchased securities or equivalent securities from the insurer at a specified price, either within a specified period of time or upon demand.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_75">
      <akn:num>(75)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Required liabilities” means total liabilities required to be reported on the statutory financial statement of the insurer most recently required to be filed with the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_76">
      <akn:num>(76)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential mortgage loan” means a loan primarily secured by a mortgage on real estate improved with a residence for up to 4 families.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_77">
      <akn:num>(77)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reverse repurchase transaction” means a transaction in which an insurer sells securities to a business entity and is obligated to repurchase the sold securities or equivalent securities from the business entity at a specified price, either within a specified period of time or upon demand.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_78">
      <akn:num>(78)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Secured location” means the contiguous real estate owned by one person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_79">
      <akn:num>(79)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Securities lending transaction” means a transaction in which securities are loaned by an insurer to a business entity that is obligated to return the loaned securities or equivalent securities to the insurer, either within a specified period of time or upon demand.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_80">
      <akn:num>(80)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Series company” means an investment company that is organized as a series company, as defined in SEC Rule 18f-2(a), 17 C.F.R. § 270.18f-2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_81">
      <akn:num>(81)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sinking fund stock” means preferred stock that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_82">
      <akn:num>(82)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Special rated credit instrument” means a rated credit instrument that is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_83">
      <akn:num>(83)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means any of the several states, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_84">
      <akn:num>(84)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Substantially similar securities” means securities that meet all criteria for substantially similar specified in the NAIC Accounting Practices and Procedures Manual, and in an amount that constitutes good delivery form as determined from time to time by the Public Securities Administration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_85">
      <akn:num>(85)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“SVO” means the Securities Valuation Office of the NAIC, or any successor office established by the NAIC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_86">
      <akn:num>(86)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Swap” means an agreement to exchange or to net payments at one or more times based on the actual or expected price, level, performance, or value of one or more underlying interests.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_87">
      <akn:num>(87)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Variable contracts” means a variable annuity or a variable life insurance policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_88">
      <akn:num>(88)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Underlying interest” means the assets, liabilities, other interests or a combination thereof underlying a derivative instrument, such as any one or more securities, currencies, rates, indices, commodities, or derivative instruments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_89">
      <akn:num>(89)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unrestricted surplus” means the amount by which total admitted assets exceed 125% of the insurer’s required liabilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-1371_02_90">
      <akn:num>(90)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Warrant” means an instrument that gives the holder the right to purchase an underlying financial instrument at a given price and time or at a series of prices and times outlined in the warrant agreement. Warrants may be issued alone or in connection with the sale of other securities or to facilitate divestiture of the securities of another business entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
