<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2231_12">
        <akn:num>31-2231.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rebates: life, health, and annuities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall knowingly:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall directly or indirectly give, sell, purchase, or offer, or agree to give, sell, purchase, or offer as inducement to the policy or contract specified in subsection (a) of this section, or in connection therewith:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall receive or accept as inducement to a policy or contract:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 31-2231.11 or this section shall not be construed to include within the definition of discrimination or rebates any of the following practices:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 31-2231.11 or this section shall not be construed to include within the definition of securities an inducement to purchase insurance, the selling or offering for sale, contemporaneously with life insurance, mutual fund shares or face amount certificates of regulated investment companies under offerings registered with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission where the shares, the face amount certificates, or the insurance may be purchased independently of, and not contingent upon, purchase of the other, at the same price and upon similar terms and conditions as where purchased independently.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_12_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of § 31-2231.11 or this section, the term “valuable consideration” shall not include any educational materials, promotional materials, or articles of merchandise that cost less than $10, regardless of whether a policy or contract is purchased.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
