<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.22"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.22/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2231_22">
        <akn:num>31-2231.22</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers of the Commissioner; cease and desist orders.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_22_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may examine and investigate the affairs of a person engaged in the business of insurance in the District of Columbia to determine whether the person has been or is engaged in an unfair trade practice, an unfair method of competition, or an unfair or deceptive action practice under this chapter. The Commissioner may suspend or revoke the license or certificate of authority for a person that violates this chapter or a rule or regulation adopted under this chapter, or fails to comply with an order of the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_22_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_22_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may request the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia [Attorney General for the District of Columbia] (“Corporation Counsel”) take appropriate action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia (“Superior Court”) for the enforcement of an order issued under this section. The Corporation Counsel may also seek, and the Superior Court may order or decree, damages and other relief allowed by law, including restitution. In an action brought by the Corporation Counsel under this section, the Corporation Counsel may be awarded attorney’s fees and costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_22_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed under subsection (b) of this section, the Commissioner shall consider the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
