<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.20"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.20/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2231_20">
        <akn:num>31-2231.20</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Favored agent or insurer; coercion of debtors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_20_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall require, as a condition to the lending of money or extension of credit, or a renewal thereof, that the person to whom the money or credit is extended, or whose obligation a creditor is to acquire or finance, negotiate an insurance policy or renewal thereof through a particular insurer or group of insurers or agent, broker, or group of agents or brokers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_20_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person who lends money or extends credit shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_20_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who lends money or extends credit and who solicits insurance on real and personal property shall explain to the borrower in writing that the insurance related to the credit extension may be purchased from an insurer or agent of the borrower’s choice, subject only to the lender’s right to reject a given insurer or agent as provided in subsection (b)(2) of this section. Compliance with disclosures as to insurance required by truth-in-lending laws or comparable state laws shall constitute compliance with this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_20_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may examine and investigate those insurance-related activities of a person or insurer that the Commissioner believes may be in violation of this section. A affected person may submit to the Commissioner a complaint or material pertinent to the enforcement of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_20_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing herein shall prevent a person who lends money or extends credit from placing insurance on real or personal property if the mortgagor, borrower, or purchaser has failed to provide required insurance in accordance with the terms of the loan or credit document.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_20_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in this section shall apply to credit life or credit accident and health insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
