<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2407.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2407.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2407_01">
        <akn:num>31-2407.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice of proposed settlement for policy limits to underinsured motorist coverage carrier; waiver of subrogation; time limits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2407_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a tortfeasor’s insurer offers to pay its full policy limits of coverage for bodily injury or death to a claimant, conditioned upon the claimant’s insurer waiving its rights of subrogation against the tortfeasor, the claimant or the tortfeasor’s insurer shall give to the claimant’s insurer notice in writing that an offer to settle for policy limits has been made by the tortfeasor’s insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2407_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The written notice shall be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the claimant’s insurer, and shall include the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2407_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2407_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the claimant’s insurer gives notice and tenders payment to the claimant as provided for in subsection (c) of this section, the claimant’s insurer is and remains subrogated to the rights of the claimant as to the tortfeasor to the extent of any and all sums paid by the claimant’s insurer to the claimant. The payment by the claimant’s insurer of the amount equal to the policy limits offered by the tortfeasor’s insurer shall not serve in any way to waive, change, or increase the amount of the claimant’s underinsured motorist coverage beyond the underlying underinsured motorist coverage policy limits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2407_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
