<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2204"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2204/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2204">
        <akn:num>31-2204</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Requirements for trust agreement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The deed of trust and all amendments thereto shall be authenticated in such form and manner as the Commissioner may prescribe and shall not be effective unless approved by the Commissioner upon a finding that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If at any time the Commissioner finds, after reasonable notice and hearing, that the requisites for the approval no longer exist, the Commissioner may withdraw approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may from time to time approve modifications of, or variations in any deed of trust, which in the Commissioner’s judgment are not prejudicial to the interest of the people of the District or the United States policyholders and creditors of the U.S. Branch.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The deed of trust shall contain provisions which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The deed of trust may provide that income, earnings, dividends, or interest accumulations of the assets of the fund may be paid over to the United States manager of the U.S. branch upon request, provided that the total trusteed assets shall not thereby be less than the amount required to be maintained pursuant to § 31-2203.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon withdrawal of trusteed assets deposited in another state in which the insurer is authorized to do business, it shall be sufficient if the deed of trust requires similar written approval of the insurance supervising official of that state in lieu of approval of the Commissioner provided that the total trusteed assets shall not thereby be less than the amount required to be maintained pursuant to § 31-2203. In all such cases, the U.S. Branch shall notify the Commissioner in writing of the nature and extent of the withdrawal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may from time to time:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2204_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Refusal or neglect of any trustee to comply with the requirements of this section shall be grounds for the revocation of the insurer’s license or the liquidation of its United States Branch.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
