<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.16"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.16/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2231_16">
        <akn:num>31-2231.16</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Failure to provide claims history.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_16_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A property and casualty insurer shall provide the following loss information for the 3 previous policy years to the first named insured within 30 days of receipt of the first named insured’s written request:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_16_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the first named insured is requested by a prospective insurer to provide detailed loss information other than that required under subsection (a) of this section, the first named insured may mail or deliver a written request to the insurer for the additional information. No prospective insurer shall request more detailed loss information than is reasonably required to underwrite the same line or class of insurance. The insurer shall provide the information under subsection (a) of this section to the first named insured as soon as possible, but not later than 20 days after the receipt of the written request. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, no insurer shall be required to provide loss reserve information, and no prospective insurer may refuse to insure an applicant, solely because the prospective insurer is unable to obtain loss reserve information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_16_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may promulgate regulations to exclude the provision of the loss information as set forth in subsection (a) of this section for any line or class of insurance if it can be shown that the information is not needed for that line or class of insurance or if the provision of loss information is otherwise required by law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_16_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Information provided under subsection (a) of this section shall not be subject to discovery by a party other than the insured, the insurer, and the prospective insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
