<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2408.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2408.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2408_01">
        <akn:num>31-2408.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Uninsured Motorist Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A fund is established in the District, to be known as the Uninsured Motorist Fund (“Fund”), for the purpose of awarding compensation to a victim of an accident who sustains injury therefrom and would not otherwise be compensated for his or her loss. Assessment shall be made, on a fair and equitable basis, among all insurers in accordance with projections of the District government as to costs required for reasonable funding and administration of the Fund. The Fund shall be classified by the Mayor pursuant to § 47-375. The Fund shall be administered by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A victim is eligible for compensation under this section subject to the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The victim shall not be eligible if the victim is at fault, is an insured, owns a registered motor vehicle, or operated a motor vehicle in the accident upon which the claim is based.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Claims shall be processed and maintained in the order of their filing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The amounts of compensation awarded shall be equal to the amount of the victim’s loss, decreased by all amounts received by or available to the victim from collateral sources. No compensation shall be awarded pursuant to this section in an amount exceeding $100,000 in medical and rehabilitative expenses, $24,000 in wage loss, and $4,000 in funeral expenses. No final award of compensation shall be made unless the Fund contains sufficient monies to pay the award.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the amount of compensation awarded to a successful claimant, a reasonable fee may be awarded for any professional assistance required in connection with any claim under this section. The fee may not exceed 10% of the amount of the claimant’s award or $1,000, whichever is less.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any agreement by a person to waive, release, or commute his or her rights under this section is void. Compensation awarded under this section is exempt from execution, attachment, or other remedy for recovery or collection of debt, except for expenses resulting from injury or death which is the basis for the claim.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who knowingly submits false information in support of a claim under this section or knowingly suppresses relevant information concerning a claim under this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $2,000 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both. A person convicted of an offense under this subsection shall forfeit any compensation under this section and shall reimburse and repay to the District of Columbia any compensation received pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2408_01_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
