<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2231.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2231_01">
        <akn:num>31-2231.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agent” or “Broker” means a person who solicits, negotiates, effects, procures, delivers, renews, continues, or binds policies of insurance for persons or risks residing, located, or to be performed in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Annuity contract” means an agreement to make periodic payments in fixed dollar amounts under the terms of a contract for a stated period of time or for the life of the person specified in the contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gender identity or expression” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 2-1401.02(12A).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurance business” means the transaction of all matters pertaining to a contract of insurance, both before and after the effectuation of the contract, and all matters arising out of the contract or a claim thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurance policy” or “insurance contract” means a contract of insurance, indemnity, medical, health, or hospital service; a health maintenance organization plan or coverage; a suretyship; or an annuity that is issued, proposed for issuance, or intended for issuance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insured” means the party named on a policy or contract as the individual with legal rights to the benefits provided by the policy or contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurer” means a person, interinsurer, Lloyd’s insurer, fraternal benefit society, health maintenance organization, or any other legal entity engaged in the business of insurance, including agents, brokers, and third-party administrators. Insurer shall also mean medical service plans and hospital service plans.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any natural or artificial entity, including individuals, partnerships, associations, trusts, or corporations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2231_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unfair trade practices” means the commission of any one or more of the acts prohibited by §§ 31-2231.02 through 31-2231.21, or regulations promulgated hereunder, with such frequency to indicate a general business practice to engage in the proscribed conduct.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
