<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2409"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2409/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2409">
        <akn:num>31-2409</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Consumer protection.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Grounds for cancellation of policy. — No insurer shall cancel a policy except:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice required of cancellation of or refusal to renew policy. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Proof of mailing notice. — Proof of mailing of the notice of cancellation, or of intention not to renew, to the named insured by post office receipt secured or certified mail at the address shown in the policy or to the named insured’s last known address, shall be sufficient proof of notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consequences of failure to provide required notice. — Despite failure of the named insured to make timely payment of the renewal premium, failure by the insurer to provide the notice required by this section shall result in the insurer being required:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prohibited discrimination. — No insurer, other than a self-insurer, shall fail or refuse to issue a policy of motor vehicle insurance to an applicant, fail or refuse to renew a policy of motor vehicle insurance, or cancel a policy of motor vehicle insurance for any reason provided in Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prohibited inquiries concerning prior cancellation or nonrenewals. — No applicant for a policy of motor vehicle insurance, as a condition precedent to obtaining a policy or renewing a policy, shall be required to disclose whether he, she, or any person reasonably expected to operate the applicant’s motor vehicle has ever had an insurance policy cancelled or nonrenewed; provided, however, that at the time of application an applicant may be required to disclose his or her experience as an operator of a motor vehicle for a past period of not more than 3 years, and that of any person reasonably expected to operate the motor vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Refusal to accept brokerage business. — An insurer or agent that accepts brokerage business and rejects the business of a broker shall provide the Mayor and the broker, upon the request of the broker, the reasons in writing for such rejection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Policies in effect less than 60 days. — The restrictions on cancellation contained in this section shall not be effective with respect to any policy which shall have been in force for 60 days or less if the policy is not a renewal policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appeal procedure. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Immunity. — There shall be no liability on the part of and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against any employee of the District government, any insurer, its authorized representatives, its agents, its employees, or any firm, person, or corporation who, in good faith:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Other rights. — The rights provided by this chapter shall be in addition to and shall not prejudice any other rights the named insured may have at common law or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Terms more favorable; prohibition of waiving rights. — A policy may provide terms more favorable to named insureds than are required by this chapter, but no policy shall contain any provisions which waives any of the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consumer’s right to information. — A copy of the provisions of this section shall be provided, in writing, by the insurer to the named insured at the time of the initial purchase of insurance, or in the case of insurance renewal, provided, in writing, to the named insured by the insurer at the time of the 1st renewal after September 18, 1982.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nondiscrimination against persons not previously insured. — No insurer shall refuse to insure, refuse to continue to insure, limit coverage available to, or charge a disadvantageous rate to any person seeking to obtain insurance required by this chapter because that person had not been previously insured. This provision shall not apply if the applicant was required by law to maintain automobile insurance coverage and failed to do so. An insurer may require reasonable proof that the applicant did not fail to maintain this coverage. The insurer is not required to accept the mere lack of a conviction or citation for failure to maintain this coverage as proof of maintenance of coverage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2409_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Insurer to provide settlement. — Each insurer shall, at the time of renewal or denial of a motor vehicle insurance policy, provide to an applicant a statement which provides the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
