<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2703"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2703/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2703">
        <akn:num>31-2703</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Making of rates.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rates for insurance within the scope of this chapter shall not be excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Due consideration shall be given to past and prospective loss experience within and outside the District, to physical hazards, to safety and loss prevention factors, to underwriting practice and judgment, to catastrophe hazards, if any, to a reasonable margin for underwriting profit and contingencies; to dividends, savings, or unabsorbed premium deposits allowed or returned by companies to their policyholders, members, or subscribers; to past and prospective expenses both country-wide and those specially applicable to the District; to whether classification rates exist generally for the risks under consideration; to the rarity or peculiar characteristics of the risks; and to all other relevant factors within and outside the District. Due consideration shall be given to the net investment income (including the realized capital gains) on all cash and invested assets held against all unearned premium reserves and loss reserves of any nature. Unrealized capital gains or losses shall not be considered in the rate-making process.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be taken to prohibit as unfairly discriminatory the establishment of classifications or modifications of classifications of risks based upon the size, expense, management, individual experience, location or dispersion of hazard, or any other reasonable considerations attributable to such risks provided such classifications and modifications apply to all risks under the same or substantially similar circumstances or conditions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require uniformity in insurance rates, classifications, rating plans, or practices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall abridge or restrict the freedom of contract of companies, agents, brokers, or employees with reference to the commissions or salaries to be paid to such agents, brokers, or employees by companies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No company, agent, or broker shall make, issue, or deliver, or knowingly permit the making, issuance, or delivery of any policy of insurance within the scope of this chapter contrary to pertinent filings which are in effect for the company as provided in this chapter, except that upon the written application of the insured stating his reasons therefor, filed with and approved by the Commissioner, a rate in excess of that provided by a filing otherwise applicable may be used on any specific risk.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every insurer writing motor vehicle insurance in the District shall file with the Commissioner, in such form as he shall order, complete financial records showing the amount of profit on every line of motor vehicle insurance during the previous year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2703_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office of the People’s Counsel shall serve as advocate for consumers in rate hearings before the Commissioner and the costs associated with such advocacy shall be borne by the insurer or insurers requesting the rate hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
