<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2502.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-2502.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_2502_02">
        <akn:num>31-2502.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certificate of authority to do business — Issuance or renewal.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2502_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall issue a certificate of authority to a company when it shall have complied with the requirements of the laws of the District so as to be entitled to do business therein. The Commissioner may, however, satisfy himself by such investigation as he may consider proper or necessary that the company is duly qualified under the laws of the District to transact business therein, and may refuse to issue or renew the certificate to a company if the issuance or renewal of the certificate would adversely affect the public interest. In each case, the certificate shall be issued under the seal of the Commissioner authorizing and empowering the company to transact the kind of business specified in the certificate, and the certificate shall expire on the 30th day of April next succeeding the date of its issuance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2502_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-2502_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No company shall transact any business in or from the District until it shall have received a certificate of authority as authorized by this section, and no company shall transact any business not specified in the certificate of authority. No domestic mutual company shall transact any business in the District until it has bona fide applications for insurance covering not less than 200 separate risks in not less than 20 policies to be issued to not less than 20 members, and has received the cash premium therefor, and has a surplus of not less than the amount provided under §§ 31-2502.12 and 31-2502.13.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
