<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3932.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3932.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3932_08">
        <akn:num>31-3932.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Trust arrangements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Assets of the SPFC that are pledged to secure obligations of the SPFC to a counterparty under an SPFC contract shall be held in trust that is administered by a qualified United States financial institution. The qualified United States financial institution shall not control, be controlled by, or be under common control with, the SPFC or the counterparty.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Assets of the SPFC held in trust to secure obligations under the SPFC contract shall at all times be held in:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Assets of an SPFC held in trust to secure obligations under an SPFC contract shall be held by the trustee at one of the trustee’s offices or branch offices in the United States and may be held in certificated or electronic form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions for withdrawal by the counterparty of assets from the trust shall be clean and unconditional, subject only to the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The trust agreement shall be established for the sole use and benefit of the counterparty at least to the full extent of the obligations of the SPFC to the counterparty under the SPFC contract. If there is more than one counterparty, a separate trust agreement shall be entered into with each counterparty and, if there more than one SPFC contract with the same counterparty, a separate trust account shall be maintained for each SPFC contract with the counterparty, in each case unless otherwise approved by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The trust agreement shall provide for the trustee to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The trust agreement:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
