<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-311.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-311.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_311_03">
        <akn:num>31-311.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Management’s report of internal control over financial reporting.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An insurer required to file an audited financial report pursuant to this chapter that has annual direct written and assumed premiums of at least $500 million, excluding premiums reinsured with the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and Federal Flood Program, shall prepare a management’s report of the insurer’s or group of insurers’ internal control over financial reporting. The report shall be filed with the Mayor along with the communication of internal control related matters noted in an audit described in § 31-309. A management’s report of internal control over financial reporting shall be made as of December 31 immediately preceding the date of the report.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor may require an insurer to file a management’s report of internal control over financial reporting if the insurer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A management’s report of internal control over financial reporting shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Management shall document and make available during the course of any financial condition examination the basis upon which its assertions offered pursuant to this section are made. Management may base its assertions, in part, on its review, monitoring, and testing of internal controls undertaken in the normal course of its activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Management shall have discretion as to the nature of the internal control framework used, and the nature and extent of documentation, to make its assertions in a cost effective manner and, as such, may include assembly of or reference to existing documentation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-311_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A management’s report on internal control over financial reporting filed with the Mayor pursuant to this section, including any supporting documentation submitted in support thereof, shall be kept confidential.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
