<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3427"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3427/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3427">
        <akn:num>31-3427</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Acquisition of control of or merger of a health maintenance organization.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3427_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may make a tender for or a request or invitation for tenders of, or enter into an agreement to exchange securities for or acquire in the open market or otherwise, any voting security of a health maintenance organization, or enter into any other agreement if, after the consummation thereof, that person would, directly or indirectly (or by conversion or by exercise of any right to acquire), be in control of the health maintenance organization, and no person may enter into an agreement to merge or consolidate with or otherwise to acquire control of a health maintenance organization, unless, at the time any offer, request, or invitation is made or any agreement is entered into, or prior to the acquisition, unless, at the time any offer, request, or invitation is made or any agreement is entered into, or prior to the acquisition of the securities if no offer or agreement is involved, the person has filed with the Commissioner and has sent to the health maintenance organization the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3427_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the person required to file the statement referred to in this section is a partnership, limited partnership, syndicate, or other group, the Commissioner may require that the information called for by subsection (a)(1) through (8) of this section shall be given with respect to each partner of such partnership or limited partnership, each member of such syndicate or group, and each person who controls such partner or member. If any such partner, member, or person is a corporation or the person required to file the statement referred to herein is a corporation, the Commissioner may require that the information called for by subsection (a)(1) through (8) of this section shall be given with respect to such corporation, each officer and director of such corporation, and each person who is directly or indirectly the beneficial owner of more than 10% of the outstanding voting securities of such corporation. If any material change occurs in the facts set forth in the statement filed with the Commissioner and sent to such health maintenance organization pursuant to this section, an amendment setting forth such change, together with copies of all documents and other material relevant to such change, shall be filed with the Commissioner and sent to such insurer within 2 business days after the person learns of such change. Such insurer shall send such amendment to its shareholders.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
