<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3606"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3606/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3606">
        <akn:num>31-3606</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Disclosure.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3606_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3606_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The outline of coverage shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3606_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of a policy issued to a group described in § 31-3601(4)(D), an outline of coverage shall not be required to be delivered; provided that, the information described in subsection (e) of this section is contained in other material relating to enrollment. Upon request, these other materials shall be made available to the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3606_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certificate issued pursuant to a group long-term care insurance policy which is delivered or issued for delivery in the District of Columbia shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3606_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At the time of policy, deliver, a policy summary shall be delivered for an individual life insurance policy which provides long-term care benefits within the policy or by rider. In the case of direct response solicitations, the insurer shall deliver the policy summary either upon the applicant’s request, or the time of policy delivery, whichever occurs later. In addition to complying with all other applicable requirements, the summary shall also include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3606_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an application for a long-term care insurance contract or certificate is approved, the issuer shall deliver the contract or certificate of insurance to the applicant no later than 30 days after the date of approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
