<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3931.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3931.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3931_09">
        <akn:num>31-3931.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Application requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A captive insurer shall apply to the Commissioner for a certificate of authority. If one or more protected cells are established as separate legal entities, each protected cell shall apply for a certificate of authority. The application shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A captive insurer shall include in its application for a certificate of authority evidence of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An application by a captive insurer or protected cell for a certificate of authority shall include a nonrefundable application fee to be determined by the Commissioner. The Commissioner may require the applicant to retain independent legal, financial, and examination services from outside the Department to review and make recommendations regarding the applicant’s qualifications, and to submit those reports and recommendations to the Commissioner for his or her review. The cost of those services shall be paid by the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Commissioner determines that the documents and statements filed by the captive insurer or protected cell of a captive insurer are complete and satisfy the requirements for a certificate of authority, the Commissioner shall issue a certificate of authority to the captive insurer or protected cell within 30 days. Each certificate shall be renewed each year not later than the 30th day of April succeeding the date of its issuance. The Commissioner may impose an administrative fine or penalty on a captive insurer or protected cell that fails to renew its certificate of authority before August 1. The Commissioner may suspend or revoke the certificate of authority of a captive insurer or protected cell that fails to renew its certificate of authority on or after August 1.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A captive insurer shall pay a fee to be established by the Commissioner for the issuance of a certificate of authority and an annual fee to be established by the Commissioner for the renewal of its certificate of authority. A captive insurer may be required to pay a fee for one or more protected cells.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A captive insurer shall include its strategic business plan with its application for the issuance of its certificate of authority. If the captive insurer intends to make any material or substantive changes to its strategic business plan, the captive insurer shall file a copy of the amended strategic business plan with the Commissioner for prior written approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_09_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
