<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3303.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3303.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3303_06">
        <akn:num>31-3303.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Availability.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If coverage is offered to small employers under this subchapter, such coverage shall be offered and made available to every small employer that applies for such coverage. Participation in such plan shall be made available to all the eligible employees of a covered small employer and their dependents. No coverage may be offered to only certain eligible employees or their dependents and no employees or their dependents may be excluded or charged additional premiums because of health status.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No coverage offered under this subchapter shall exclude an employer based solely on the nature of the employer’s business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to health insurance coverage offered by a health insurer if such coverage is made available in the small group market only through one or more bona fide associations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A health insurer that offers health insurance coverage in a small group market through a network plan may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A health insurer, upon denying health insurance coverage in the District of Columbia in accordance with subsection (d)(2) of this section, may not offer coverage in the small group market within such service area for a period of 180 days after the date such coverage is denied.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A health insurer may deny health insurance coverage in the small group market if the health insurer has demonstrated, if required, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A health insurer upon denying health insurance coverage in connection with group health plans in accordance with subsection (d) of this section in the District of Columbia may not offer coverage in connection with group health plans in the small group market for a period of 180 days after the date such coverage is denied or until the health insurer has demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Commissioner that the health insurer has sufficient financial reserves to underwrite additional coverage, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3303_06_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
