<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3932.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3932.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3932_05">
        <akn:num>31-3932.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Capital and surplus.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other capital required to be maintained pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, an SPFC authorized to do business in the District shall at all times maintain a minimum unimpaired capital of $100,000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided by the Commissioner pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the capital required to be maintained pursuant to this section shall be in the form of cash or an irrevocable letter of credit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may require an SPFC, including each protected cell, to maintain additional unimpaired capital based on the type, volume, and nature of the insurance business that is transacted by the SPFC and may determine the amount of capital, if any, that may be in the form of an irrevocable letter of credit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A letter of credit used by an SPFC or segregated account as evidence of capital required pursuant to this section shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An SPFC shall not be issued a certificate of authority, and shall not hold a certificate of authority, unless the SPFC has and maintains, in addition to any other surplus required to be maintained pursuant to subsection (g) of this section, an unencumbered surplus of not less than $150,000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided by the Commissioner pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, the surplus required to be maintained pursuant to this section shall be in the form of cash or an irrevocable letter of credit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may prescribe additional requirements relating to surplus based on the type, volume, and nature of the insurance business that is transacted by an SPFC or protected cell and requirements regarding which surplus, if any, may be in the form of an irrevocable letter of credit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A letter of credit used by an SPFC or segregated account as evidence of surplus required pursuant to this section shall meet the same requirements as a letter of credit issued for paid in capital found subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
