<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3508"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3508/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3508">
        <akn:num>31-3508</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Filing of subscriber contract forms and rates.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Contract form filings. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rate filings for individual subscriber contracts. — All rates for individual subscriber contracts issued in the District of Columbia shall be subject to the prior approval of the Mayor. Each proposed rate filing shall be on file for a waiting period of 60 days before it becomes effective. When, in the Mayor’s opinion, a rate filing is not accompanied by the information needed to support it and the Mayor does not have sufficient information to determine whether the rate filing meets the requirements of this section, a corporation shall be required to furnish the needed information. In such event, the waiting period shall be suspended and shall recommence as of the date the information is furnished. Upon written application by the corporation, the Mayor may authorize a rate filing which the Mayor has reviewed to become effective before the expiration of the waiting period or any extension thereof. A filing shall be deemed approved unless disapproved by the Mayor within the waiting period or any extension thereof requested by the corporation. All approved rate filings for individual subscriber contracts submitted in other jurisdictions shall be filed with the Mayor for information purposes only.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rate filings for group subscriber contracts. — All rates for group subscriber contracts, other than experience rated groups, issued in the District of Columbia shall be filed with the Mayor no later than the date on which a corporation proposes to make such rates effective. The rate filing shall be subject to review and disapproval by the Mayor for a period of 60 days after the filing date. If not disapproved before the expiration of the review period or any extension thereof requested by the corporation, the filing shall be deemed approved. Any disapproval under this subsection shall be applied retrospectively to the date the corporation made such rates effective. Upon application by the corporation, the Mayor may affirmatively approve a filing prior to the end of the review period. All approved rate filings for group subscriber contracts, other than experience rated groups, submitted in other jurisdictions shall be filed with the Mayor for information purposes only.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Contract form and rate filings generally. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Rate filings generally. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Transition provision for contract forms and rates. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3508_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A corporation whose proposed form of subscriber contract or proposed contract rate has been disapproved by the Mayor may contest the Mayor’s action in accordance with the procedures of § 31-3522.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
