<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3403.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3403.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3403_01">
        <akn:num>31-3403.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Premium tax.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective January 1, 2009, all health maintenance organizations shall pay to the District of Columbia, for each calendar year, a sum of money as taxes equal to 2% of their policy and membership fees and net premium receipts or consideration received in such calendar year, excluding those fees, receipts, or consideration received pursuant to any federal employee health-benefit program or Medicare, on all policies or contracts in the District of Columbia. The premium tax shall be in lieu of all other taxes except:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The certificate of authority of any health maintenance organization may be revoked for failure to pay the required premium tax.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All revenues generated pursuant to this section shall be collected in a manner prescribed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any revenues generated from this section arising from contracts for services under the District’s Medicaid program, DC HealthCare Alliance program, or Healthy DC program shall be deposited in the Healthy DC and Health Care Expansion Fund, established by § 31-3514.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Of all other revenues generated pursuant to this section, 75% shall be deposited in the Healthy DC and Health Care Expansion Fund and 25% shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term, “health maintenance organization” shall include prepaid health plans.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
