<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3931.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3931.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3931_12">
        <akn:num>31-3931.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tax on premiums collected.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a captive insurer shall pay to the District, not later than March 2 of each year, a tax at the rate of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A captive insurer organized as a risk retention group, as defined in ยง 31-4101(12), shall pay to the District, not later than March 2 of each year, a tax at the rate of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the sum of the taxes to be paid by a captive insurer, other than a risk retention group licensed as an association captive insurer, calculated pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section is less than $7,500 in any given year, the captive insurer shall pay a minimum tax of $7,500 for the year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the sum of the taxes to be paid by a risk retention group, licensed as an association captive insurer, calculated pursuant to subsections (a-1) and (b) of this section is less than $15,000 in any given year, the captive insurer shall pay a minimum tax of $15,000 for the year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The total tax paid by a captive insurer shall not exceed $100,000 in any year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of a branch captive insurer, the tax provided for in this section shall apply only to the branch business of the branch captive insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of annuity business, the tax provided for in this section shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any specific statute to the contrary and except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the tax provided for by this section shall constitute all the taxes collectible pursuant to the laws of the District from a captive insurer, and no occupation tax or other taxes shall be levied or collected from a captive insurer by the District, except for real property taxes pursuant to Chapter 8 of Title 47 or personal property taxes pursuant to subchapter II of Chapter 15 of Title 47.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A captive insurer that is issued a certificate of authority during the last quarter of the calendar year may file a written request with the Commissioner for a reduction in the minimum premium tax obligation calculated pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of this section. The Commissioner may grant the a [sic] request pursuant to an appropriate methodology adopted by rule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The tax provided for in this section shall be calculated on an annual basis, notwithstanding policies, contracts, insurance, or contracts of reinsurance issued on a multiyear basis. In the case of multiyear policies or contracts, the premium shall be prorated for purposes of determining the tax obligation under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>One hundred percent of the revenues collected from the tax imposed pursuant to this section shall be credited to the account for the regulation and supervision of captive insurers created by ยง 31-1202(BB).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3931_12_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
