<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3517"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3517/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3517">
        <akn:num>31-3517</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Management contracts and service agreements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3517_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any management contract or service agreement which delegates to any person or organization all or part of a substantial management duty, function, or other form of control of a corporation, such as adjustment of claims, production of business, investment of assets, or general servicing of the corporation’s business, must be filed with the Mayor at least 30 days before the effective date of the contract or agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3517_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This requirement in subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to personal services contracts of executives of a corporation. Nor shall that requirement apply to contracts by groups of affiliated companies for shared services, such as maintenance, security, purchasing, and the like, where costs to the individual member companies are charged on an actually incurred or pro rata basis, except that these contracts shall be in writing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3517_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall disapprove any management contract or service agreement filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section if, at any time, the Mayor finds one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3517_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor disapproves any management contract or service agreement filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, written notice of the reason for such action shall be given to the corporation, which may contest the Mayor’s action in accordance with the procedures in § 31-3522.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3517_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any amendments to a management contract or service agreement shall be filed with the Mayor at least 30 days before they become effective. Any change in the officers, directors, or trustees of the contractor under a management contract or service agreement shall be reported to the Mayor within 10 days after such change occurs. Upon review of such amendments and changes, the Mayor may disapprove the management contract or service agreement in accordance with the provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3517_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any management contract or service agreement filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, and any amendment thereto, shall be deemed approved unless disapproved by the Mayor within 30 days after it is filed with the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
