<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3151"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3151/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3151">
        <akn:num>31-3151</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Application” means a carrier’s application pursuant to this chapter for approval to voluntarily withdraw from the District of Columbia health insurance market.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Carrier” means any person or organization subject to the authority of the Commissioner that provides one or more health benefit plans in the District of Columbia, and includes an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, or multiple employer welfare arrangement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health benefit plan” means any accident and health insurance policy or certificate, hospital and medical services corporation contract, health maintenance organization subscriber contract, a plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or a plan provided by another benefit arrangement. The term “health benefit plan” does not mean accident only, credit, or disability insurance; coverage of Medicare services or federal employee health plans, pursuant to contracts with the United States government; Medicare supplement or long-term care insurance; dental only or vision only insurance; specified disease insurance; hospital confinement indemnity coverage; limited benefit health coverage; coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance; insurance arising out of a workers’ compensation or similar law; automobile medical payment insurance; medical expense and loss of income benefits; or insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“HIPAA” means the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, approved August 21, 1996 (110 Stat. 1936; scattered sections of the United States Code).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medicare” means the health insurance program established pursuant to the Health Insurance for the Aged Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 290; 42 U.S.C. § 401 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3151_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Withdraw” means the full cessation of underwriting insurance policies, including the nonrenewal of existing insurance policies, relative to any line of business or any subgroup thereof, including individual accounts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
