<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3521"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3521/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3521">
        <akn:num>31-3521</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sanctions for violations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3521_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the directors or trustees of a corporation issued a certificate of authority under this chapter knowingly violate, or knowingly permit any of the officers, employees, or agents of the corporation to violate, any provision of this chapter, any other provision of law made applicable to the corporation by this chapter, or any regulation promulgated under this chapter or such other provisions of law, the certificate of authority granted to the corporation may be suspended or revoked upon a determination of such violation by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3521_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Forfeiture of monetary gain; civil money penalties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3521_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever the Mayor determines that a corporation issued a certificate of authority under this chapter, or that a director, trustee, officer, employee, or agent of such a corporation has committed or is about to commit a violation of this chapter or of any rule, regulation, or order issued hereunder, the Mayor may issue an order directing such corporation or individual to cease and desist from violating or continuing to violate this chapter or any such rule, regulation, or order, subject to the notice, hearing, and other procedural requirements in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3521_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The foregoing penalties and remedies shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other penalty which may be imposed pursuant to any other provision of law which this chapter makes applicable to a corporation and its officers, directors, employees, and agents. This section shall not be construed to prevent any person financially damaged by a director, trustee, officer, employee, or agent of a corporation from bringing a separate cause of action in a court of competent jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3521_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever the Mayor determines that a corporation issued a certificate of authority under this chapter, or that a director, trustee, officer, employee, or agent of such a corporation, has willfully violated this chapter, the Mayor shall report such violation to the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia. Willful violations of this chapter shall be deemed misdemeanors, except where other provisions of this chapter or other provisions of law made applicable by this chapter provide for greater criminal liability. Prosecutions authorized by this section shall be upon information filed in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel or any of his or her assistants. Any corporation convicted of a willful violation of this chapter shall be fined in an amount not to exceed $50,000 for each violation. In addition to any fines or punishments imposed for violations of any other laws, any individual convicted of a willful violation of this chapter shall be fined in an amount not to exceed $5,000 for each violation; or, if such violation involves the deliberate perpetration of a fraud upon the corporation, its subscribers, or the Mayor, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
