<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3102"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3102/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3102">
        <akn:num>31-3102</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Coverage.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as described in subsection (b) of this section, each health insurer that offers individual or group health plans or certificates issued or delivered in the District to an employer or individual shall provide coverage for the medical and psychological treatment of drug abuse, alcohol abuse, and mental illness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The requirements of this chapter shall not apply to dread disease policies, student policies, nursing home policies, and home health care policies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Covered benefits for drug abuse, alcohol abuse, and mental illness in insurance policies and contracts subject to this chapter shall be limited to inpatient, residential, and outpatient services certified as necessary by a physician, psychologist, advanced practice registered nurse, or social worker.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before an insured party may qualify to receive benefits under this chapter, a physician, psychologist, advanced practice registered nurse, or social worker shall certify that the individual has a drug addiction or an alcohol addiction or a mental illness and prescribe appropriate treatment, which may include referral to other treatment providers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All drug abuse, alcohol abuse, and mental illness treatment or services eligible for health insurance coverage shall be subject to peer review procedures. These procedures may be initiated by a health insurer in the course of reviewing claims for payment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All individual health benefit plans or certificates shall offer coverage for the medical and psychological treatment of drug abuse, alcohol abuse, and mental illness. Coverage shall be offered for at least the minimum levels set forth in §§ 31-3103 and 31-3104.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Group health benefit plans or certificates that are the result of collective bargaining between a legally-certified union and the employer shall be required to include coverage for inpatient and outpatient treatment of drug abuse, alcohol abuse, and mental illness. The minimum levels of coverage set forth in §§ 31-3103 and 31-3104 shall not apply to those group health benefit plans or certificates until 5 years from February 28, 1987, unless the Mayor requests the Council to extend the exemption to a time certain and the Council, by resolution, approves the extension.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a large group health benefit plan offers a participant or beneficiary 2 or more benefit package options under the plan, the requirements of this chapter shall be applied separately to each option.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3102_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A health insurer may require that substance abuse and mental illness insurance coverage shall be provided through a managed care system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
