<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3311.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3311.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3311_02">
        <akn:num>31-3311.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Aggregate medical loss ratios; dividend; and rating bands.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3311_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For each calendar year, an insurer shall maintain an aggregate minimum medical loss ratio, as defined by rule, of 80% for individual policies, as defined by rule, 80% for small group policies, as defined by rule, and 85% for large group policies, as defined by rule. The medical loss ratio shall be defined by the Commissioner and shall be determined by rule in a manner and  generally consistent with the same standards as the medical loss ratio defined in section 2718(b) of the Public Health Service Act, approved March 23, 2010 (124 Stat. 136; 42 U.S.C. § 300gg-18(b)). No later than May 31st of each year, insurers shall file an annual report with the Commissioner, in a manner and on a form prescribed by Commissioner, indicating the medical loss ratio calculated for all policies and contracts written for the previous calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3311_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All filings of rates and rating schedules shall demonstrate that actual expected claims in relation to premiums comply with the requirements of this chapter when combined with actual experience to date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3311_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In each case where the insurer fails to substantially comply with the medical loss ratio requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section, the insurer shall issue a rebate for all policyholders in an amount determined in accordance with section 2718(b)(1)(B) of the Public Health Service Act, approved March 23, 2010 (124 Stat. 136; 42 U.S.C. § 300gg-18(b)(1)(B). The annual  report required by this section shall include the insurer’s calculation of the rebates and an explanation of the insurer’s plan to issue rebates. The instructions and format for calculating and reporting medical loss ratios and issuing rebates shall be  prescribed by the Commissioner by rule. The Commissioner shall establish, by rule, procedures for the distribution of a rebate in  the event of cancellation or termination by a policyholder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3311_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A plan of individual or small group health insurance rates shall not include a standard rate for any age that is more than 300% of the standard rate for the age with the lowest rate in the same plan and the standard rate for any age shall not be more than 104% of the standard rate for the previous age.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3311_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An insurer’s failure to comply with the rebate requirements in subsection (c) of this section or rating band requirements set forth in subsection (d) of this section shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act or practice and shall be subject to the penalties in Chapter 22A of this title [§ 31-2231.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3311_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may audit any insurer to assure compliance with this section. Insurers shall retain at their principal place of business information necessary for the Commissioner to perform compliance audits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
