<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3301.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3301.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3301_01">
        <akn:num>31-3301.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliation period” means a period which, under the terms of the health insurance coverage offered by a health maintenance organization, must expire before the health insurance coverage becomes effective. The health maintenance organization is not required to provide health care services or benefits during such period and no premium shall be charged to the participant or beneficiary for any coverage during the period. Such period shall begin on the enrollment date. An affiliation period under a plan shall run concurrently with any waiting period under the plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Beneficiary” has the meaning given such term under section 3(8) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 834; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(8)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bona fide association” means, with respect to health insurance coverage offered in the District of Columbia, an association which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Certification” means a written certification of the period of creditable coverage applicable to an individual.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Church plan” has the meaning given such term under section 3(33) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 838; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(33)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“COBRA continuation provision” means any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Dependent” means the spouse or child of an eligible employee, subject to the applicable terms of the policy, contract, or plan covering the eligible employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_9A">
      <akn:num>(9A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic partnership” shall have the same meaning as provided in § 32-701(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible employee” means an employee who works for a small group employer on a full-time basis, has a normal work week of 30 or more hours, has satisfied applicable waiting period requirements, and is not a part-time, temporary, or substitute employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible individual” means an individual:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employer” has the meaning given such term under section 3(5) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 12, 1974 (88 Stat. 834; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(5)), except that such term shall include only employers of 2 or more employees.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Enrollment date” means, with respect to an eligible individual covered under a group health plan or health insurance coverage, the date of enrollment of the eligible individual in the plan or coverage or, if earlier, the first day of the waiting period for such enrollment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Established geographic service area” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Excepted benefits” means benefits under one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal governmental plan” means a governmental plan established or maintained for its employees by the government of the United States or by an agency or instrumentality of such government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Governmental plan” has the meaning given such term under section 3(32) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 837; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(32)) and any federal governmental plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Group health insurance coverage” means health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Group health plan” means an employee welfare benefit plan (as defined in section 3(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. § 1002(1)), to the extent that the plan provides medical care and includes items and services paid for as medical care to employees or their dependents (as defined under the terms of the plan) directly or through insurance, reimbursement, or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_19A">
      <akn:num>(19A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health Benefit Exchange Authority Establishment Act” means Chapter 31D of this title [§ 31-3171.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health benefit plan” means any accident and health insurance policy or certificate, hospital and medical services corporation contract, health maintenance organization subscriber contract, plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or plan provided by another benefit arrangement. The term “health benefit plan” does not mean accident only, credit, or disability insurance; coverage of Medicare services or federal employee health plans, pursuant to contracts with the United States government; Medicare supplement or long-term care insurance; dental only or vision only insurance; specified disease insurance; hospital confinement indemnity coverage; limited benefit health coverage; coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance; insurance arising out of a workers’ compensation or similar law; automobile medical payment insurance; medical expense and loss of income benefits; or insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health insurance coverage” means benefits consisting of medical care (provided directly, through insurance or reimbursement, or otherwise and includes items and services paid for as medical care) under any hospital or medical service policy or certificate, hospital, or medical service plan contract, or health maintenance organization contract offered by a health insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health insurer” means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District of Columbia, including an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health maintenance organization” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Health status-related factor” means the following in relation to the individual or a dependent eligible for coverage under a group health plan or health insurance coverage offered by a health insurer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“High level policy form” means a policy or plan under which the actuarial value of the benefit under the coverage is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Individual health insurance coverage” means health insurance coverage offered to individuals in the individual market, which includes a health benefit plan provided to individuals through a trust arrangement, association, or other discretionary group that is not an employer plan, but does not include coverage defined as excepted benefits. The term “individual health insurance coverage” does not include short-term limited duration coverage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Individual market” means the market for health insurance coverage offered to individuals other than in connection with a group health plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Initial enrollment period” means a period of at least 30 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Large group market” means the health insurance market under which individuals obtain health insurance coverage (directly or through any arrangement) on behalf of themselves (and their dependents) through a group health plan maintained by a large employer or through a health insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Late enrollee” means an eligible employee or dependent who requests enrollment in a group health benefit plan after the initial enrollment period provided under the terms of the group health benefit plan, or a participant or beneficiary who enrolls under the plan other than during (i) the first period in which the individual is eligible to enroll under the plan, or (ii) a special enrollment period as required pursuant to this statute. An eligible employee or dependent shall not be considered a late enrollee if all of the conditions set forth below in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of this paragraph are met, or one of the conditions set forth below in subparagraphs (E) or (F) of this paragraph is met:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Low level policy form” means a policy or plan under which the actuarial value of the benefit under the coverage is at least 85%, but not greater than 100%, of the weighted average.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medical care” means amounts paid for the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease, or amounts paid for the purpose of affecting any structure or function of the body.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Network plan” means health insurance coverage of a health insurer under which the financing and delivery of medical care (including items and services paid for as medical care) are provided, in whole or in part, through a defined set of providers under contract with the health insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_35">
      <akn:num>(35)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nonfederal governmental plan” means a governmental plan that is not a federal governmental plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_36">
      <akn:num>(36)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Participant” has the meaning given such term under section 3(7) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 834; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(7)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_37">
      <akn:num>(37)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Placed for adoption”, “placement”, or “being placed for adoption”, in connection with any placement for adoption of a child with any person, means the assumption and retention by such person of a legal obligation for total or partial support of such child in anticipation of adoption of such child. The child’s placement with such person terminates upon the termination of such legal obligation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_38">
      <akn:num>(38)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Plan sponsor” has the meaning given such term under section 3(16)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 835; 29 U.S.C. § 1002(16)(B)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_39">
      <akn:num>(39)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Preexisting condition exclusion” means, with respect to coverage, a limitation or exclusion of benefits relating to a condition based on the fact that the condition was present before the first day of coverage, whether or not any medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment was recommended or received before that day. Genetic information shall not be treated as a preexisting condition in the absence of a diagnosis of the condition related to such information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_40">
      <akn:num>(40)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Preexisting conditions provision” means a provision in a health benefit plan that limits, denies, or excludes benefits for an enrollee for expenses or services related to a preexisting condition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_41">
      <akn:num>(41)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Premium” means all moneys paid by a small employer and eligible employees as a condition of coverage from a health insurer, including fees and other contributions associated with the health benefit plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_42">
      <akn:num>(42)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_43">
      <akn:num>(43)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means each of the several states, and the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_44">
      <akn:num>(44)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Waiting period” means, with respect to a group health plan or health insurance coverage provided by a health insurer and an individual who is a potential participant or beneficiary in the plan, the period that must pass with respect to the individual before the individual is eligible to be covered for benefits under the terms of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3301_01_45">
      <akn:num>(45)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
