<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3171.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3171.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3171_09">
        <akn:num>31-3171.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Health benefit plan certification.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be certified as a qualified health plan, a health benefit plan shall, at a minimum:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall not withhold certification from a health benefit plan:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall require each health carrier seeking certification of a plan as a qualified health plan to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall not exempt any health carrier seeking certification as a qualified health plan, regardless of the type or size of the health carrier, from District licensure or solvency requirements, and shall apply the criteria of this section in a manner that assures a level playing field between or among health carriers participating in the exchanges.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Authority shall take the information required by subsection (c)(1) of this section, along with the information and the recommendations provided to the Authority by the Commissioner under section 2794(b) of the PHSA, into consideration when determining whether to allow the health carrier to make plans available through the exchanges.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A qualified health plan may provide additional services that are not in the essential health benefits package required in subsection (a)(1) of this section, if the services are eligible for claims submission and reimbursement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_09_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of the essential health benefits benchmark plan, as defined in federal regulations promulgated pursuant to section 1302(a) of the Federal Act, the term “habilitative services” includes health care services that help a person keep, learn, or improve skills and functioning for daily living, including applied behavioral analysis for the treatment of autism spectrum disorder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
