<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3510"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3510/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3510">
        <akn:num>31-3510</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Investments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3510_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Without the Mayor’s prior written consent, a corporation’s aggregate investments in real estate pursuant to § 31-4435(d)(1)(A) through (F) [repealed], shall not at any time exceed 20% of the amount of the corporation’s admitted assets as reported on the corporation’s annual financial statement most recently filed with the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3510_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A corporation’s investments in real estate pursuant to § 31-4435(d)(1)(A) through (F) [repealed], shall in no event exceed the actual cost plus the capitalized value (less normal depreciation) of the permanent improvements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3510_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For real estate owned by a corporation pursuant to § 31-4435(d)(1)(A) [repealed] on April 9, 1997, the corporation may, as its option, determine admitted asset value in accordance with an appraisal most recently conducted prior to April 9, 1997; provided, that the appraisal is acceptable to the Mayor. The difference between the admitted asset value as so identified and the book value (equal to the historical cost, less the value of encumbrances and accumulated depreciation) shall be accounted for as an unrealized gain and credited to reserves and unassigned funds and shall be amortized and charged to reserves and unassigned funds. Thereafter, such real estate shall be valued, for purposes of the financial statements required by § 31-1901, at such appraised value, less accumulated amortization, plus the capitalized value of permanent improvements, less normal depreciation. Normal depreciation on the capitalized value of permanent improvements shall be charged as an expense in the underwriting and investment exhibit to the corporation’s annual financial statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3510_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A corporation shall not invest in or otherwise acquire any affiliate or subsidiary, as those terms are defined in § 31-701, except in accordance with the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
