<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3171.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3171.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3171_06">
        <akn:num>31-3171.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers and duties of executive board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to any limitations under this chapter, or other applicable law, the executive board shall have all the powers necessary to carry out the functions authorized by the Federal Act and consistent with the purposes of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The enumeration of specific powers in this chapter is not intended to restrict the executive board’s power to take any lawful action that it determines is necessary to carry out the functions authorized by the Federal Act and is consistent with the purposes of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this chapter, the executive board may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The executive board shall adopt written policies and procedures, which shall be made publicly accessible on the Authority’s website and published in the District of Columbia Register, governing all procurements of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The executive board may limit the number of plans offered in the exchanges using selective criteria or contracting; provided, that individuals and employers have an adequate number and selection of choices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3171_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The executive board may merge the exchanges for individual coverage within the American Health Benefits Exchange and the SHOP Exchange if a merger is considered by the Authority to be in the best interest of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
