<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3501"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3501/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3501">
        <akn:num>31-3501</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Community health reinvestment” means expenditures that promote and safeguard the public health or that benefit current or future subscribers, including premium rate reductions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_1B">
      <akn:num>(1B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Contractholder” means a person entering into a subscriber contract with a corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Corporation” means a nonstock, nonprofit corporation which is subject to regulation and licensing under this chapter and which offers subscriber contracts as part of a hospital service plan, a medical service plan, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domestic corporation” means a corporation organized under the laws of the District, or formed or organized under an act of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Healthy DC and Health Care Expansion Fund” means the Healthy DC and Health Care Expansion Fund established by § 31-3514.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hospital service plan” means a plan for providing hospital and related services by hospitals and others which entitles a subscriber to certain hospital and related services, or to benefits and indemnification for such services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the Mayor’s designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medical service plan” means a plan for providing medical services and related services by physicians and others which entitles a subscriber to certain medical and related services, or to benefits and indemnification for such services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Plan” means a hospital service plan, a medical service plan, or a combination of the two.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_7A">
      <akn:num>(7A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public-private partnership” means a mutually acceptable written agreement between the Mayor and a hospital and medical services corporation that is certified by the Commissioner upon the execution and delivery of the agreement by the parties and which agreement:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_7B">
      <akn:num>(7B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“RS Fund” means the rate stabilization fund established by § 31-3514(j).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_7C">
      <akn:num>(7C)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subscriber” means any person entitled to benefits under the terms and conditions of a subscriber contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subscriber contract” means a written group or individual contract which is issued to a contractholder by a corporation which provides for subscriber participation in a hospital service plan, a medical service plan, or a combination of the two.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subsidiary” means an affiliate controlled by a corporation directly or indirectly through 1 or more intermediaries.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Surplus” means the amount by which all admitted assets of the corporation exceed its liabilities, inclusive of the reserves required pursuant to § 31-3509.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3501_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
