<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3407"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3407/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3407">
        <akn:num>31-3407</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Requirements for group contract, individual contract, and evidence of coverage.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every group and individual contract holder is entitled to a group or individual contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the requirements of subsection (a)(2)(A) through (Y) of this section, an individual contract shall provide for a 10-day period to examine and return the contract and have the dues refunded. If services were received during the 10-day period and the person returns the contract to receive a refund of the dues paid, the person must pay for such services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every enrollee shall receive an evidence of coverage from the group contract holder or the health maintenance organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may adopt regulations establishing readability standards for individual contract, group contract, and evidence of coverage forms.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No group or individual contract, evidence of coverage, or amendment thereto shall be delivered or issued for delivery in the District unless its form has been filed with and approved by the Commissioner pursuant to subsections (f) and (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an evidence of coverage issued pursuant to a contract issued in the District is intended for delivery in the District, the evidence of coverage must be submitted to and approved by the Commissioner in accordance with subsection (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every form required by this section shall be filed with the Commissioner not less than 30 days prior to delivery or issue for delivery in the District. At any time during the initial 30-day period, the Commissioner may extend the period for review for an additional 30 days. Notice of an extension shall be in writing. At the end of the review period, the form is deemed approved if the Commissioner has taken no action. The filer shall notify the Commissioner in writing prior to using a form that is deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3407_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may require the submission of any relevant information the Commissioner deems necessary in determining whether to approve or disapprove a filing made pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
