<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3932.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3932.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3932_02">
        <akn:num>31-3932.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Counterparty” means the insurer that cedes risk to an SPFC and which, unless otherwise approved by the Commissioner, is the parent or an affiliated company of the SPFC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fair value” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insolvency” or “insolvent” means an inability to pay obligations when they are due, unless those obligations are the subject of a bona fide dispute.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurance securitization” means a package of related risk-transfer instruments, capital market offerings, and facilitating administrative agreements by which proceeds are obtained by an SPFC directly or indirectly through the issuance of securities, and which proceeds are held in trust pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter to secure the obligations of the SPFC under one or more SPFC contracts with a counterparty, where investment risk to the holders of these securities is contingent upon the obligations of the SPFC to the counterparty under the SPFC contract in accordance with the terms of the transaction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Management” means the board of directors, managing board, or other individuals vested with overall responsibility for the management of the affairs of an SPFC, including the election and appointment of officers or other of those agents to act on behalf of the SPFC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Organizational document” means the articles of incorporation, articles of organization, bylaws, operating agreement, or other foundational documents that establish an SPFC as a legal entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Permitted investments” means those investments that meet the qualifications set forth in § 31-3932.07.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified United States financial institution” means a financial institution that is eligible to act as a fiduciary of a trust and is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Securities” has the same meaning as the term “security” in § 31-5601.01(31).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“SPFC” or “Special Purpose Financial Captive” means a captive insurer that is formed for the purpose of an insurance securitization and that only insures or reinsures the risks of its counterparty.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“SPFC contract” means a contract between an SPFC and the counterparty pursuant to which the SPFC agrees to provide insurance or reinsurance protection to the counterparty for risks associated with the counterparty’s insurance or reinsurance business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“SPFC securities” means securities issued by an SPFC.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3932_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Surplus note” means an unsecured subordinated debt obligation possessing characteristics consistent with paragraph 3 of the Statement of Statutory Accounting Principles No. 41, as amended, National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
