<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3402"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3402/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3402">
        <akn:num>31-3402</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of health maintenance organizations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3402_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person may apply to the Commissioner for a certificate of authority to establish and operate a health maintenance organization in compliance with this chapter. No person shall establish or operate a health maintenance organization in the District without obtaining a certificate of authority under this chapter, except as provided for herein. Any person who shall establish and operate a health maintenance organization without obtaining a certificate of authority shall be prohibited from receiving a certificate of authority to do business as a health maintenance organization for a period not to exceed 5 years as determined by the Commissioner. All health maintenance organizations shall, as a condition of certification, agree to accept the risk for the provision of services rendered to enrollees on a prepaid basis except for enrollee responsibility for copayments or deductibles, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3402_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A foreign corporation may qualify under this chapter subject to its registration to do business pursuant to this section and compliance with all provisions of this chapter and other applicable District laws.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3402_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All health maintenance organizations operating as health maintenance organizations in the District shall submit an application for a certificate of authority under subsection (d) of this section within 120 days after April 9, 1997. Each applicant may continue to operate until the Commissioner acts upon the application. In the event that an application is denied pursuant to ยง 31-3403, the applicant shall thereafter be treated as a health maintenance organization whose certificate of authority has been revoked. Notwithstanding a revocation under this chapter, any contracts issued to groups or individuals residing in the District shall remain in effect with respect to a health maintenance organization which has a valid certificate of authority issued by the Maryland Insurance Division or Virginia Bureau of Insurance until the next renewal date or anniversary date of coverage of such contracts, or 120 days from the date the application is denied, whichever date shall occur later.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3402_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each application for a certificate of authority shall be accompanied by a filing fee of $500, which shall be deposited in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund established by ยง 31-1202, and shall be verified by an officer or authorized representative of the applicant, shall be in a form prescribed by the Commissioner, and shall set forth or be accompanied by the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3402_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
