<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3403"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-3403/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_3403">
        <akn:num>31-3403</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Issuance of certificate of authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of an application for issuance of a certificate of authority, the Commissioner, in consultation with the Director of the Department of Health, shall determine whether the applicant, with respect to the health care services to be provided, has complied with ยง 31-3406.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 45 days of receipt of the application for issuance of a certificate of authority, the Commissioner, in consultation with the Director of the Department of Health, shall certify that the proposed health maintenance organization meets the requirements of ยง 31-3406 or notify the applicant that it does not meet such requirements and specify in what respects it is deficient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall issue a certificate of authority to any person filing a completed application upon receiving the prescribed fees and upon the Commissioner being satisfied that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certificate of authority may be denied only after the Commissioner complies with the requirements of ยง 31-3419.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner, in carrying out his obligations under this chapter, may contract with qualified persons to make recommendations concerning the determinations required to be made by him. Recommendations may be accepted in full or in part by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each certificate of authority to do business in the District of Columbia shall renew on May 1 of each year following the date of its issuance unless it has been revoked or the renewal fee under subsection (h) of this section has not been paid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may charge a renewal license fee to health maintenance organizations licensed to do business in the District of Columbia. The renewal fee shall be paid before April 2 of each renewal year. The fee shall be remitted in a manner prescribed by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-3403_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After receiving its certificate of authority, a health maintenance organization shall submit to the Commissioner information concerning any modification or amendment to its application for a certificate of authority or supporting documentation prior to the effectuation of the modification or amendment or provide this information or documentation to the Commissioner when the health maintenance organization files its annual report.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
