<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4712"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4712/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_4712">
        <akn:num>31-4712</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Accident and sickness policies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Filing requirements. — No policy of insurance against loss resulting from sickness or from bodily injury or death by accident, or both, shall be issued or delivered to any person in the District by any company organized under this or any other law of the District, or, if a foreign or alien company, authorized to do business in the District, including, but not limited to, all Health Maintenance Organizations, Group Hospitalization and Medical Services, Inc., all life insurance companies licensed to do business in the District, and all for-profit as well as nonprofit health insurers issuing or delivering expense incurred accident and sickness health insurance policies and certificates, until a copy of the form thereof, and of the classification of risks and the premium rates appertaining thereto, have been filed with the Commissioner; nor shall it be so issued or delivered until the expiration of 30 days after it has been so filed, unless the Commissioner shall sooner give his written approval thereto. If the Commissioner shall give written notice to the company which has filed such form that it does not comply with the requirements of law, specifying the reasons for his opinion, it shall be unlawful thereafter for any such insurer to issue any policy in such form. Rates filed with respect to a policy or certificate subject to the Reasonable Health Insurance Ratemaking Reform Act of 2010 [Chapters 30A, 31C, and 33A of this title] shall also comply with the provisions of such act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Form. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Provisions. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Conforming to statutory requirements. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Applications. —</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Waiver of insurer’s rights. — The acknowledgment by any insurer of the receipt of notice given under any policy covered by this section, or the furnishing of forms for filing proofs of loss, or the acceptance of such proofs, or the investigation of any claim thereunder shall not operate as a waiver of any of the rights of the insurer in defense of any claim arising under such policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Limitations on coverage. — If any such policy contains a provision establishing, as an age limit or otherwise, a date after which the coverage provided by the policy will not be effective, and if such date falls within a period for which premium is accepted by the insurer or if the insurer accepts a premium after such date, the coverage provided by the policy will continue in force subject to any right of cancellation until the end of the period for which premium has been accepted. In the event the age of the insured has been misstated and if, according to the correct age of the insured, the coverage provided by the policy would not have become effective, or would have ceased prior to the acceptance of such premium or premiums, then the liability of the insurer shall be limited to the refund, upon request, of all premiums paid for the period not covered by the policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4712_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Exceptions. — Except as provided in § 31-4724, nothing in this section shall apply to or affect:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
