<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4705.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4705.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_4705_03">
        <akn:num>31-4705.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Standard nonforfeiture law — Individual deferred annuities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to any reinsurance, group annuity purchased under a retirement plan or plan of deferred compensation established or maintained by an employer (including a partnership or sole proprietorship) or by an employee organization, or by both, other than a plan providing individual retirement accounts of individual retirement annuities under § 408 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (88 Stat. 959; § 408 of Title 26, United States Code), as now or hereafter amended, premium deposit fund, variable contract, immediate annuity, any deferred annuity contract after annuity payments have commenced, or reversionary annuity, nor to any contract which shall be delivered outside the District of Columbia through an agent or other representative of the company issuing the contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The minimum values as specified in subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), and (i) of this section of any paid-up annuity, cash surrender or death benefits available under an annuity contract shall be based upon minimum nonforfeiture amounts as defined in this subsection:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any paid-up annuity benefit available under a contract shall be such that its present value on the date annuity payments are to commence is at least equal to the minimum nonforfeiture amount on that date. Such present value shall be computed using the mortality table, if any, and the interest rate specified in the contract for determining the minimum paid-up annuity benefits guaranteed in the contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For contracts which provide cash surrender benefits, such cash surrender benefits available prior to maturity shall not be less than the present value as of the date of surrender of that portion of the maturity value of the paid-up annuity benefit which would be provided under the contract at maturity arising from considerations paid prior to the time of cash surrender reduced by the amount appropriate to reflect any prior withdrawals from or partial surrenders of the contract, such present value being calculated on the basis of an interest rate not more than 1 percent higher than the interest rate specified in the contract for accumulating the net considerations to determine such maturity value, decreased by the amount of any indebtedness to the company on the contract, including interest due and accrued, and increased by any existing additional amounts credited by the company to the contract. In no event shall any cash surrender benefit be less than the minimum nonforfeiture amount at that time. The death benefit under such contracts shall be at least equal to the cash surrender benefit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For contracts which do not provide cash surrender benefits, the present value of any paid-up annuity benefit available as a nonforfeiture option at any time prior to maturity shall not be less than the present value of that portion of the maturity value of the paid-up annuity benefit provided under the contract arising from considerations paid prior to the time the contract is surrendered in exchange for, or changed to, a deferred paid-up annuity, such present value being calculated for the period prior to the maturity date on the basis of the interest rate specified in the contract for accumulating the net considerations to determine such maturity value, and increased by any existing additional amounts credited by the company to the contract. For contracts which do not provide any death benefits prior to the commencement of any annuity payments, such present values shall be calculated on the basis of such interest rate and the mortality table specified in the contract for determining the maturity value of the paid-up annuity benefit. However, in no event shall the present value of the paid-up annuity benefit be less than the minimum nonforfeiture amount at the time.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of determining the benefits calculated under subsections (e) and (f) of this section, in the case of annuity contracts under which an election may be made to have annuity payments commence at optional maturity dates, the maturity date shall be deemed to be the latest date for which election shall be permitted by the contract, but shall not be deemed to be later than the anniversary of the contract next following the annuitant’s 70th birthday or the 10th anniversary of the contract, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any contract which does not provide cash surrender benefits or does not provide death benefits at least equal to the minimum nonforfeiture amount prior to the commencement of any annuity payments shall include a statement in a prominent place in the contract that such benefits are not provided.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any paid-up annuity, cash surrender or death benefits available at any time, other than on the contract anniversary under any contract with fixed scheduled considerations, shall be calculated with allowance for the lapse of time and the payment of any scheduled considerations beyond the beginning of the contract year in which cessation of payment of considerations under the contract occurs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For any contract which provides, within the same contract by rider or supplemental contract provision, both annuity benefits and life insurance benefits that are in excess of the greater of cash surrender benefits or a return of the gross considerations with interest, the minimum nonforfeiture benefits shall be equal to the sum of the minimum nonforfeiture benefits for the annuity portion and the minimum nonforfeiture benefits, if any, for the life insurance portion computed as if each portion were a separate contract. Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), and (i) of this section, additional benefits payable: (1) in the event of total and permanent disability; (2) as reversionary annuity or deferred reversionary annuity benefits; or (3) as other policy benefits additional to life insurance, endowment and annuity benefits; and considerations for all such additional benefits, shall be disregarded in ascertaining the minimum nonforfeiture amounts, paid-up annuity, cash surrender and death benefits that may be required by this section. The inclusion of such additional benefits shall not be required in any paid-up benefits, unless such additional benefits separately would require minimum nonforfeiture amounts, paid-up annuity, cash surrender and death benefits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_03_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After October 13, 1978, any company may file with the Commissioner a written notice of its election to comply with the provisions of this section after a specified date which is no more than 2 years after such effective date. After the filing of such notice, then upon such specified date, which shall be the operative date of this section for such company, this section shall become operative with respect to annuity contracts thereafter issued by such company. If a company makes no such election, the operative date of this section for such company shall be 2 years after October 13, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
