<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4705"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4705/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_4705">
        <akn:num>31-4705</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Annuity and pure endowment contracts; forms to be filed and approved; required provisions; applications, riders and endorsements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On and after January 1, 1935, no annuity or pure endowment contract shall be issued or delivered in the District unless and until a copy of the form thereof has been filed with the Commissioner and formally approved by him.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except in the case of a reversionary annuity, otherwise called a “survivorship annuity,” or an annuity contracted by an employer in behalf of his employees, no annuity or pure endowment contract shall be so issued or delivered in this District unless it contains, in substance, the following provisions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No contract for a reversionary annuity shall be so issued or delivered unless it contains in substance the following provisions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any of the foregoing provisions or portions thereof not applicable to nonparticipating contracts nor to contracts for which a single stipulated payment to the company is made shall, to that extent, not be incorporated therein; and any such contract may be issued or delivered in this District, which, in the opinion of the Commissioner, contains provisions on any 1 or more of the several foregoing requirements, more favorable to the holder of the contract than hereinbefore required.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing herein contained shall be construed to prevent a life company, which issues life insurance on a participating basis, from issuing annuities, reversionary annuities, or pure endowments on a nonparticipating basis.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any such contract or any application, endorsement, or rider form used in connection therewith, issued in violation of this section, shall, nevertheless, be held valid, but shall be construed as provided in this section and when any provision in such contract, application, endorsement, or rider is in conflict with any provision of this section or with any other statutory provision, the rights, duties, and obligations of the company, of the holder of the contract and of the beneficiary or annuitant thereunder shall be governed by the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to contracts of reinsurance nor to contracts for deferred annuities or reversionary annuities included in life insurance policies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4705_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, application forms, rider forms, and endorsement forms for use in connection with any such contract, excepting riders or endorsements relating to the manner of distribution of benefits or to the reservation of rights and benefits under any such contract, and used at the request of the individual holders of such contracts, shall be deemed to be parts of such contract and shall require the approval of the Commissioner. No rider and no endorsement, except as stated above, shall be attached to or printed or stamped upon any such contract issued or delivered in the District until the form of such rider or endorsement has been filed with the Commissioner and formally approved by him.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
