<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4103"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4103/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_4103">
        <akn:num>31-4103</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Risk retention groups not chartered in the District.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any risk retention group doing business in the District shall submit to the Mayor:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any risk retention group, its agents, and representatives shall comply with District law governing fraud or deceptive practices. If the Mayor seeks an injunction regarding this conduct, the injunction shall be obtained from a court of competent jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any risk retention group shall comply with the laws governing the proper transaction of insurance business as provided by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any risk retention group must submit to an examination by the Commissioner to determine its financial condition if the superintendent or Commissioner of the jurisdiction in which the group is chartered and licensed has not initiated an examination within 60 days after a request by the Commissioner of the District. Any examination shall be coordinated to avoid unjustified repetition and conducted in an expeditious manner and in accordance with the NAIC’s Examiner Handbook. Cost of the examination shall be borne by the risk retention group.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every application form for insurance from a risk retention group, and every policy, on its front and declaration page issued by a risk retention group, shall contain in 10-point type the following notice:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following acts by a risk retention group are prohibited:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After April 26, 1994, risk retention groups shall not be allowed to do business in the District if an insurance company is directly or indirectly a member or owner of the risk retention group, other than in the case of a risk retention group all of whose members are insurance companies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The terms of any insurance policy issued by risk retention groups shall not provide, or be construed to provide, coverage prohibited generally by a statute of the District or declared unlawful by the highest court of the District whose law applies to such a policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A risk retention group not chartered in the District and doing business in the District shall comply with a lawful order issued in a voluntary dissolution proceeding or in a delinquency proceeding commenced by a state insurance commissioner if there has been a finding of financial impairment after an examination under paragraph (6) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A risk retention group that violates any provision of this chapter will be subject to fines and penalties, including revocation of its right to do business in the District, applicable to licensed insurers generally.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4103_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to complying with the requirements of this section, any risk retention group operating in the District prior to enactment of this chapter shall, within 30 days after October 21, 1993, comply with paragraph (1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
