<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4107"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4107/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_4107">
        <akn:num>31-4107</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice and registration requirements of purchasing groups.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4107_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A purchasing group which intends to do business in the District shall, prior to doing business, furnish notice to the Commissioner which shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4107_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A purchasing group shall, within 10 days, notify the Commissioner of any changes in any of the items set forth in subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4107_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The purchasing group shall register with the District and provide proof of compliance with the service of process provisions of § 31-202, for which a filing fee shall be determined by the Commissioner, except that these requirements shall not apply in the case of a purchasing group which only purchases insurance that was authorized under the federal Product Liability Risk Retention Act of 1981 (15 U.S.C. § 3901 et seq.), and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4107_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each purchasing group that is required to give notice pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall also furnish information required by the Commissioner to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4107_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any purchasing group which was doing business in the District prior to the enactment of this chapter shall, within 30 days after October 21, 1993, furnish notice to the Mayor pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section and furnish the information required pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
