<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4101"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-4101/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_4101">
        <akn:num>31-4101</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking, or the commissioner, director, or superintendent of insurance in any other state.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Completed operations liability” means liability arising out of installation, maintenance, or repair of any product at a site which is not owned or controlled by:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Domicile”, for purposes of determining the state in which a purchasing group is domiciled, means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hazardous financial condition” means that, based on its present reasonably anticipated financial condition, a risk retention group, although not yet financially impaired or insolvent, is unlikely to be able to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insurance” means primary insurance, excess insurance, reinsurance, surplus lines insurance, and any other arrangement for shifting and distributing risk which is determined to be insurance under the laws of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Liability” means legal liability for damages, including costs of defense, legal costs, and fees, and other claims expenses, because of injuries to other persons, damage to their property, or other damage or loss to other persons resulting from or arising out of any business (whether profit or nonprofit), trade, product, services (including professional services), premises, or operations, or any activity of any state or local government, or any agency or political subdivision thereof. The term “liability” does not include personal risk liability and an employer’s liability with respect to its employees other than legal liability under the Federal Employers’ Liability Act (45 U.S.C. § 51 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“NAIC” means National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personal risk liability” means liability for damages because of injury to any person, damage to property, or other loss or damage resulting from any personal, familial, or household responsibilities or activities, rather than from responsibilities or activities referred to in paragraph (10) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Plan of operation or a feasibility study” means an analysis which presents the expected activities and results of a risk retention group including, at a minimum:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Product liability” means liability for damages because of any personal injury, death, emotional harm, consequential economic damage, or property damage (including damages resulting from the loss of use of property) arising out of the manufacture, design, importation, distribution, packaging, labeling, lease, or sale of a product, but does not include the liability of any person for those damages if the product involved was in the possession of the person when the incident giving rise to the claim occurred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Purchasing group” means any group which:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Risk retention group” means any corporation or other limited liability association:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means any state of the United States or the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-4101_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
