<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5041.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5041.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5041_06">
        <akn:num>31-5041.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Conditions for providing escrow, settlement, closing, and indemnity deposit services.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds deposited with the title insurance producer or insurer in connection with an escrow, settlement, closing, or indemnity deposit shall be submitted for collection to or deposited in a fiduciary trust account in accordance with Chapter 24 of Title 42 [§ 42-2401 et seq.], unless otherwise agreed upon in writing, and in accordance with the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Funds held in an indemnity deposit account shall be disbursed only pursuant to a written agreement specifying:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any interest received on funds deposited in connection with any escrow, settlement, indemnity deposit, or closing shall be paid, net of administrative costs, to the depositing party, unless the depositor’s written instructions for the funds, a court order, or a governing law provides otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Disbursements may be made out of an escrow, settlement, or closing account only if deposits in amounts at least equal to the disbursement have first been made directly relating to the transaction disbursed against and if the deposits are in one of the following forms:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall not prohibit the recording of documents prior to the time funds are available for disbursement with respect to a transaction that does not relate to real or personal property; provided, that all parties consent to the transaction in writing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A title insurance producer who maintains or operates fiduciary trust accounts in connection with providing escrow, closing settlement services shall have an annual audit made of its escrow, settlement, closing, and indemnity deposit accounts, conducted by an accountant at its expense. Alternatively, any title insurer, at its expense, may conduct, or cause to be conducted, an annual audit of the escrow, settlement, closing, and security deposit accounts of the title insurance producer, subject to the rules by the Commissioner as hereinafter set forth. The Commissioner may promulgate rules setting forth the minimum threshold level at which an audit would be required, the standards of audit, and the forms of audit report required. Title insurance producers who are attorneys licensed in any state or the District of Columbia, who are not exclusively in the business of title insurance, and who issue title insurance policies as part of their legal representation of clients shall be exempt from the requirements of this subsection; provided, that the title insurer may, at its expense, conduct, or cause to be conducted, an annual review or audit of the escrow, settlement, closing, and indemnity deposit accounts of the attorney. The Commissioner may also require the title insurance producer or escrow agent to provide a copy of its audit report to the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the title insurance producer is appointed by 2 or more title insurers and maintains fiduciary trust accounts in connection with providing escrow, closing settlement services, the title insurance producer shall allow each title insurer reasonable access to the accounts and any or all of the supporting account information to ascertain the safety and security of the funds held by the title insurance producer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may prescribe standard disclosures that must be included in all agreements for escrow, settlement, closing, or indemnity deposits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
