<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5604.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5604.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5604_02">
        <akn:num>31-5604.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Exempt transactions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An isolated nonissuer transaction, whether or not effected through a broker-dealer;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nonissuer transaction by a licensed agent of a licensed broker-dealer, and a resale transaction by a sponsor of a unit investment trust registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, in a security of a class that has been outstanding and publicly held for at least 90 days; provided, that at the time of the transaction:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nonissuer transaction in a security by a licensed agent of a licensed broker-dealer if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nonissuer transaction in an outstanding security if the issuer of the security has a class of securities subject to registration under section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78l] and has been subject to the reporting requirements of sections 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78m or 15 U.S.C. § 78o(d)] for not less than 90 days next preceding the transaction, or has filed and maintained with the Commissioner for not less than 90 days preceding the transaction information, in the form that the Commissioner, by rule, specifies, substantially comparable to the information that the issuer would be required to file under section 12(b) or (g) [15 U.S.C. § 78l] of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 if the issuer had a class of its securities registered under section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78l];</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nonissuer transaction in a security that has a fixed maturity or a fixed interest or dividend provision and for which there has been no default in the payment of principal, interest, or dividends on the security during the current fiscal year or within the 3 past years, or, if less than 3 years, during the existence of the issuer and any predecessors;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A nonissuer transaction effected by or through a licensed broker-dealer under an unsolicited order or offer to purchase, if either the confirmation of the transaction delivered to the customer clearly states that the transaction was unsolicited, or the broker-dealer obtains a written acknowledgment signed by the customer that the transaction was unsolicited, and a copy of the confirmation or the acknowledgment is preserved by the broker-dealer for such period as the Commissioner may, by rule, require;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction between the issuer or other person on whose behalf the offering of a security is made and an underwriter, or a transaction among underwriters;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction in a bond or other evidence of indebtedness secured by a real estate mortgage, deed of trust, personal property security agreement, or by an agreement for the sale of real estate or personal property, if the entire mortgage, deed of trust, or agreement, together with all the bonds or other evidences of indebtedness secured thereby, is offered and sold as a unit;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction by an executor, administrator, sheriff, marshal, receiver, trustee in bankruptcy, guardian, or conservator;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction executed by a bona fide secured party without any purpose of evading this chapter;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An offer to sell, or the sale of a, security to a financial institution or institutional investor or to a broker-dealer, whether the purchaser is acting for itself or in some fiduciary capacity;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_11A">
      <akn:num>(11A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An offer to sell, or the sale of a security, by an issuer to an accredited investor;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To the extent permitted by rule or order of the Commissioner, an offer or sale within the District by an issuer now or hereafter exempt from section 5 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. § 77e] by a rule or regulation adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission under section 3(b) or section 4(2) of that Act [15 U.S.C. § 77c or 15 U.S.C. § 77d] if the issuer files with the Commissioner a notice of intent to claim exemption under this paragraph, at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Commissioner determines;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An offer or sale of a preorganization certificate or subscription if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction pursuant to an offer to existing security holders of the issuer, including persons who at the time of the transaction are holders of convertible securities, nontransferable warrants, or transferable warrants exercisable within not more than 90 days of their issuance, if no commission or other remuneration, other than a standby commission, is paid or given directly or indirectly for soliciting a security holder in the District except to a licensed or exempt broker-dealer;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction involving an offer to sell, but not a sale, of a security if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The issuance of a security dividend, whether the corporation distributing the dividend is the issuer of the security or not, if nothing of value is given by security holders for the distribution other than the surrender of a right to a cash dividend where the security holder can elect to take a dividend in cash or in a security;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction involving an offer to sell, but not a sale, of a security if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A transaction incident to a right of conversion or a statutory or judicially approved reclassification, recapitalization, reorganization, quasi-reorganization, stock split, reverse stock split, merger, triangular merger, consolidation, sale of assets, or exchange of securities; and</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5604_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An offer or sale of units of fractional undivided interests in a unit investment trust registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940 if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
