<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5607.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5607.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5607_05">
        <akn:num>31-5607.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rules, forms, and orders.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5607_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to specific authority otherwise granted by this chapter, the Commissioner:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5607_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To keep rules adopted by the Commissioner in harmony with the regulations adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission under the federal securities laws and to encourage uniformity with the rules of securities agencies and administrators in other states, the Commissioner, so far as is consistent with this chapter, shall take into consideration the regulations adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission and the rules of securities agencies and administrators in other states which have enacted a law comparable to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5607_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless specifically provided in this chapter to the contrary, a rule or order may not be adopted, amended, or repealed unless the Commissioner determines that the action is in the public interest and appropriate for the protection of investors and is consistent with the purposes fairly intended by the policy and provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5607_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may, by rule or order, prescribe the form and content of financial statements required under this chapter, the circumstances under which consolidated financial statements must be filed, and whether a required financial statement must be certified and by whom. Unless the Commissioner provides, by rule or order, otherwise, and subject to the limitations of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78o] and section 222 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 [15 U.S.C. § 80b-18a], a financial statement required under this chapter must be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles or other accounting principles as are prescribed for the issuer of the financial statement by the Securities and Exchange Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
