<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5602.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5602.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5602_10">
        <akn:num>31-5602.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Limited registration of Canadian broker-dealers and agents.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Canadian broker-dealer may be licensed under this section if the broker-dealer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An agent may be licensed under this section if the agent represents a Canadian broker-dealer that is licensed under this section, and the agent:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If no denial order is in effect and no proceeding is pending under ยง 31-5602.07, the license shall become effective no later than noon on the 30th day after an application is filed. If the application is incomplete, the Commissioner may request additional information from the applicant and delay the effective date for 30 days from the date of receipt of the request for information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An agent licensed under this section may effect transactions in securities in the District of Columbia as permitted for the Canadian broker-dealer licensed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Canadian broker-dealer licensed under this section shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An agent of a Canadian broker-dealer licensed under this section shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Renewal applications for Canadian broker-dealers and agents under this section shall be filed annually before December 1 and may be made by filing the most recent renewal application, if any, filed in the jurisdiction in which the broker-dealer has its principal office or, if a renewal application is not required, the most recent application filed under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for an initial license or renewal under this section shall pay the fee for broker-dealers and agents required by rules issued by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_10_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Canadian broker-dealer or agent licensed under this section and acting in accordance with the limitations in subsection (d) or (e) of this section shall be exempt from all of the requirements of this chapter, except the provisions of subchapters V and VI.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
