<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5601.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5601.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5601_01">
        <akn:num>31-5601.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Accredited investor” shall have the same meaning as in section 2(a)(15) of the Securities Act of 1933, approved May 27, 1933 (48 Stat. 74; 15 U.S.C. § 77b(a)(15)), or any other person that the Securities and Exchange Commission may so designate by rule, regulation, or order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Advertisement” means a publicly disseminated, written, or printed communication, including by radio, television, Internet, or other public media, used in connection with a sale or purchase, or an offer to sell or purchase, a security.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” of, or a person “affiliated” with, a specified person, means a person that directly, or indirectly through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, the person specified.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Broker-dealer” means a person engaged in the business of effecting offers, purchases, or sales in securities for the account of others or for his or her own account. The term “broker-dealer” shall not include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Canadian broker-dealer” means a broker-dealer that has its principal office in a province or territory of Canada.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commodity Exchange Act” means the Commodity Exchange Act, approved September 21, 1922 (42 Stat. 998; 7 U.S.C. § 1 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Control”, including the terms “controlling”, “controlled by”, and “under common control with”, means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management or policies of a person, whether through the ownership of voting securities, by contract, or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal covered adviser” means a person who is registered, or required to be registered, under section 203 [§ 31-5602.03] of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940. The term “federal covered adviser” shall not include a person who is not an investment adviser as defined under paragraph 17(B)(ii) through (xiii) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal covered security” means a security which is a covered security under section 18(b) of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. § 77r] or the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Filed” means the actual delivery of a document or application to the Commissioner or designee of the Commissioner or to the principal office of the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financial or institutional investor” means any of the following, whether acting for itself or others in a fiduciary capacity:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fraud”, “deceit”, and “defraud” are not limited to common law fraud or deceit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Guaranteed” means guaranteed as to payment of all, or substantially all, of principal and interest or dividends.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Insured” means insured as to payment of all, or substantially all, of principal and interest or dividends.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment adviser representative” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment Advisers Act of 1940” means the Investment Advisers Act of 1940, approved August 22, 1940 (54 Stat. 847; 15 U.S.C. § 80b-1 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Investment Company Act of 1940” means the Investment Company Act of 1940, approved August 22, 1946 (54 Stat. 789; 15 U.S.C. § 80a-1 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuer” means a person who issues, or proposes to issue, a security; provided, that with respect to certificates of deposit, voting-trust certificates, collateral-trust certificates, or certificates of interest or shares in an unincorporated investment trust not having a board of directors or persons performing similar functions or of the fixed, restricted management, or unit type, the term “issuer” means the person performing the acts and assuming the duties of depositor or manager under the provisions of the trust or other agreement or instrument under which the security is issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Non-issuer transaction” means a transaction not directly or indirectly for the benefit of the issuer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, a corporation, a partnership, an association, a joint-stock company, a limited liability company, a trust where the interests of the beneficiaries are evidenced by a security, an unincorporated organization, a government, or a political subdivision of a government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Price amendment” means the final federal amendment which includes a statement of: the offering price; underwriting and selling discounts or commissions; amount of proceeds; conversion rates; call prices; and other matters dependent upon the offering price.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Promoter” includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935” means the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, approved August 26, 1935 (49 Stat. 838; 15 U.S.C. § 79a et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_27">
      <akn:num>(27)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sale” or “sell” includes every contract to sell, exchange, or dispose of a security or interest in a security for value. In this context:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_28">
      <akn:num>(28)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Securities Act of 1933” means the Securities Act of 1933, approved May 27, 1933 (48 Stat. 74; 15 U.S.C. § 77a et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_29">
      <akn:num>(29)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Securities Exchange Act of 1934” means the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, approved June 6, 1934 (48 Stat. 881; 15 U.S.C. § 78a et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_30">
      <akn:num>(30)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Securities and Exchange Commission” means the United States Securities and Exchange Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_31">
      <akn:num>(31)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Security” means any note; stock; treasury stock; bond; debenture; evidence of indebtedness; certificate of interest or participation in a profit-sharing agreement; a limited partnership interest; collateral-trust certificate; preorganization certificate or subscription; transferable share; investment contract; voting-trust certificate; certificate of deposit for a security; fractional undivided interest in an oil, gas, or other mineral lease or in payments out of production under a lease, right, or royalty; a put, call, straddle, or option entered into a national securities exchange relating to foreign currency; a put, call, straddle, or option on a security, certificate of deposit, or group or index of securities, including an interest in or based on the value of any of the foregoing; or an interest or instrument commonly known as a security; or certificate of interest or participation in, temporary or interim certificate for, receipt for, whole or partial guarantee of, or warrant or right to subscribe to or purchase, any of the foregoing. The term “security” shall not include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_32">
      <akn:num>(32)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Self-regulatory organization” means a national securities exchange registered under section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78f]; a national securities association of brokers and dealers registered under section 15A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78o-3]; the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board established under section 15B(b)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78o-4]; a clearing agency registered under section 17A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. § 78q-1]; or a futures association under section 21 of the Commodity Exchange Act [7 U.S.C. § 21].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_33">
      <akn:num>(33)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state, territory, or possession of the United States, and Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5601_01_34">
      <akn:num>(34)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Underwriter” means a person who has purchased from an issuer with a view to, or sells for an issuer in connection with, the distribution of a security; participates, or has a direct or indirect participation in, such undertaking; or participates, or has a participation in, the direct or indirect underwriting of such undertaking. The term “underwriter” shall not include a person whose interest is limited to a commission from an underwriter or dealer not in excess of the usual and customary distributor’s or seller’s commission. As used in this paragraph, the term “issuer” shall include a person directly or indirectly controlling, or controlled by, the issuer or a person under direct or indirect common control with the issuer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
