<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5031.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5031.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5031_13">
        <akn:num>31-5031.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties of title insurers utilizing the services of title insurance producers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The title insurer shall not accept business from a title insurance producer unless there is in force a written contract between the parties which sets forth the responsibilities of each party and, if both parties share responsibility for a particular function, specifies the division of responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The title insurer shall, at least annually, conduct an on-site review, or a review conducted electronically that would accomplish the functional equivalent of the same, of the underwriting, claims, and escrow practices of the title insurance producer which shall include a review of the producer’s policy blank inventory and processing operations. If the title insurance producer does not maintain separate bank or trust accounts for each title insurer it represents, the title insurer shall verify that the funds held on its behalf are reasonably ascertainable from the books of account and records of the title insurance producer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 30 days after executing or terminating a contract with a title insurance producer, the title insurer shall provide written notification of the appointment or termination and the reason for termination to the Commissioner. Notices of appointment of a title insurance producer shall be made on a form promulgated by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A domestic title insurer shall not appoint to its board of directors an officer, director, employee, controlling shareholder, or any title insurance producer who wrote 1% or more of the title insurer’s direct premiums written during the previous calendar year as shown on the title insurer’s most recent annual statement on file with the Commissioner. This subsection shall not apply to relationships governed by Chapter 7 of this title [§ 31-701 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The title insurer shall maintain an inventory of all policy forms or policy numbers allocated to each title insurance producer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The title insurer shall have on file proof that the title insurance producer is licensed in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5031_13_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The title insurer shall establish the underwriting guidelines and, if applicable, limitations on title claims settlement authority to be incorporated into contracts with its title insurance producers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
