<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5231"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5231/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5231">
        <akn:num>31-5231</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Allocation Date” means the date on which the Certified Investors of a Certified Capital Company are allocated Premium Tax Credits by the Commissioner under § 31-5234.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Certified Capital” means an investment of cash by a Certified Investor in a Certified Capital Company that fully funds the purchase price of an equity interest in the Certified Capital Company, a Qualified Debt Instrument, or a combination of the two.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Certified Capital Company” means a partnership, corporation, trust, or limited liability company, whether organized on a profit or not for profit basis, that has as its primary business activity the investment of cash in Qualified Businesses and that is certified by the Commissioner as meeting the criteria of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Certified Investor” means any insurance company, approved by the Commissioner, that invests Certified Capital pursuant to an allocation of Premium Tax Credits under § 31-5234.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities Regulation [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District Premium Tax Liability” means any liability incurred by an insurance company under § 31-205 or, in the case of a repeal or reduction by the District of the tax imposed by § 31-205, any other tax liability incurred by an insurance company under District law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Economic Impact Study” means an assessment of the performance of the Certified Capital Company program that includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_8B">
      <akn:num>(8B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Follow-on Investment” means any Qualified Investment that a Certified Capital Company makes in a Qualified Business that is subsequent to its Initial Investment in that Qualified Business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_8C">
      <akn:num>(8C)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Initial Investment” means the 1st Qualified Investment that a Certified Capital Company makes in a Qualified Business after May 27, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any natural person or entity, including a corporation, general or limited partnership, trust, or limited liability company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Premium Tax Credit” means a tax credit which may be applied against a Certified Investor’s District Premium Tax Liability under § 31-5233.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Premium Tax Credit Allocation Request” means an application for allocation of Premium Tax Credits prepared and executed by a Certified Investor on a form provided by the Commissioner and filed by a Certified Capital Company with the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_11A">
      <akn:num>(11A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Principal Business Operations” means the location where a business conducts its primary business activities, its managers and the majority of its employees work, and its material books and records are maintained.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Debt Instrument” means a debt instrument issued to a Certified Investor by a Certified Capital Company, at par value or a premium, with an original maturity date of at least 5 years from date of issuance and a repayment schedule which is no faster than a level principal amortization over 5 years, which does not permit the Certified Investor to receive prepayment of interest, and which contains no interest, distribution, or payment features which are related to the profitability of the issuing Certified Capital Company or the performance of its investment portfolio.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Distribution” means any distribution or payment of a Certified Capital Company in connection with the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Investment” means the investment of cash by a Certified Capital Company in a Qualified Business for the purchase of any debt, debt participation, equity, or hybrid security, of any nature and description, including a debt instrument or security which has the characteristics of debt but which provides for conversion into equity or equity participation instruments, such as options or warrants; provided, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tier One Qualified Business” means any Qualified Business:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tier Two Qualified Business” means any Qualified Business that did not receive a Qualified Investment prior to May 27, 2010, that is not a Tier One Qualified Business, and that is engaged in one of the lines of business set forth in paragraph (16)(B)(i) through (x) of this section as its primary line of business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5231_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tier Three Qualified Business” means any Qualified Business that did not receive a Qualified Investment prior to May 27, 2010, and that is not a Tier One Qualified Business or a Tier Two Qualified Business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
