<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5004"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5004/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5004">
        <akn:num>31-5004</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Rules and regulations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5004_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Industry Placement Facility shall on its own motion, or within 30 days after a request by the Mayor, submit to the Mayor such proposed rules and regulations applicable to insurers, agents, and brokers deemed necessary to assure all property owners fair access to basic property insurance through the normal insurance markets, including rules and regulations concerning:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5004_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may adopt such of the rules and regulations submitted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section as he approves. If the Mayor disapproves any proposed rule or regulation submitted, he shall state the reasons for so doing, and he shall require the Facility to submit a revision thereof within such time as he may designate, but not less than 10 days. During such designated time, the Mayor and the Facility shall consult regarding any such disapproved rule or regulation. If the Facility fails to submit a proposed rule or regulation, or revision thereof, within the designated time, or if a revised rule or regulation is unacceptable to the Mayor, the Mayor may make such rules and regulations covering the proposed general subject matter as he shall deem necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Any rule or regulation adopted or made under this section shall be consistent with the requirements of part A of title XII of the National Housing Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
