<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5405"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5405/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5405">
        <akn:num>31-5405</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers and duties of the Association.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a member insurer is an impaired domestic insurer, the Association may, in its discretion and subject to any conditions imposed by the Association that do not impair the contractual obligations of the impaired insurer that are approved by the Mayor, and that are, except in cases of court-ordered conservation or rehabilitation, also approved by the impaired insurer:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a member insurer is an insolvent insurer, the Association shall, in its discretion:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When proceeding under subsection (b)(1)(B) or (c)(2) of this section, the Association shall, with respect only to life and health insurance policies and certificates:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Association elects to reissue terminated coverage at a premium rate different from that charged under the terminated policy, the premium shall be set by the Association in accordance with the amount of insurance provided and the age and class of risk, subject to prior approval of the Mayor or by a court of competent jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association’s obligations with respect to coverage under policies of the impaired or insolvent insurer or under any reissued or alternative policies shall cease on the date the policies are replaced by other similar policies by either the policyholder, the insured, or the Association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When proceeding under subsection (b)(1)(B) or (c) of this section with respect to any policy or contract carrying guaranteed minimum interest rates, the Association shall assure the payment or crediting of a rate of interest consistent with § 31-5402(b)(2)(C).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nonpayment of premiums within 31 days after the date required under the terms of any guaranteed, assumed, alternative, or reissued policy or contract or substitute coverage shall terminate the Association’s obligations under the policy or coverage, except with respect to any claims incurred or any net cash surrender value which may be due in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Premiums due for coverage after entry of an order of liquidation of an insolvent insurer shall belong to and be payable at the direction of the Association, and the Association shall be liable for unearned premiums due to policy or contract owners arising after the entry of the order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The protection provided by this chapter shall not apply where any guaranty protection is provided to residents of the District of Columbia by the laws of the domiciliary state or jurisdiction of the impaired or insolvent insurer, other than the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In carrying out its duties under subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Association may, subject to approval by the court:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_m_1">
      <akn:num>(m-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A deposit in the District held pursuant to law or required by the Commissioner for the benefit of creditors, including policy owners, not turned over to the domiciliary liquidator upon the entry of a final order of liquidation or order approving a rehabilitation plan of an insurer domiciled in the District or in a reciprocal state, pursuant to Chapter 13 of this title [§  31-1301 et seq.], shall be promptly paid to the Association. The Association shall be entitled to retain a portion of any amount so paid to it equal to the percentage determined by dividing the aggregate amount of policy owners claims related to that insolvency for which the Association has provided statutory benefits by the aggregate amount of all policy owners’ claims in this state related to that insolvency and shall remit to the domiciliary receiver the amount so paid to the Association less the amount retained pursuant to this subsection. Any amount so paid to the Association and retained by it shall be treated as a distribution of the liquidator’s assets pursuant to Chapter 13 of this title [§  31-1301 et seq.], dealing with early access disbursements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Association fails to act within a reasonable period of time under subsections (b)(1)(B), (c), and (d) of this section, the Mayor shall assume the powers and duties of the Association under this chapter with respect to impaired or insolvent insurers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association may render assistance and advice to the Mayor, upon request, concerning rehabilitation, payment of claims, continuance of coverage, or the performance of other contractual obligations of any impaired or insolvent insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association shall have standing to appear or intervene before any court in the District of Columbia with jurisdiction over an impaired or insolvent insurer for which the Association is or may become obligated under this chapter or with jurisdiction over any person or property against which the Association may have rights through subrogation or otherwise. Standing shall extend to all matters germane to the powers and duties of the Association, including, but not limited to, proposals for reinsuring, modifying, or guaranteeing the policies or contracts of the impaired or insolvent insurer and the determination of the policies or contracts and contractual obligations. The Association shall also have the right to appear or intervene before a court in another state with jurisdiction over an impaired or insolvent insurer for which the Association is or may become obligated or a court with jurisdiction over any person or property against whom the Association may have rights through subrogation or otherwise of the insurer’s policyholders.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association may join an organization of 1 or more other state associations of similar purposes to further the purposes and administration of the powers and duties of the Association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_t">
      <akn:num>(t)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_u">
      <akn:num>(u)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors of the Association shall have discretion and may exercise reasonable business judgment to determine the means by which the Association is to provide the benefits of this chapter in an economical and efficient manner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_v">
      <akn:num>(v)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Where the Association has arranged or offered to provide the benefits of this chapter to a covered person under a plan or arrangement that fulfills the Association’s obligations under this chapter, the person shall not be entitled to benefits from the Association in addition to or other than those provided under the plan or arrangement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5405_w">
      <akn:num>(w)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Venue in a suit against the Association arising under the chapter shall be in the District. The Association shall not be required to give an appeal bond in an appeal that relates to a cause of action arising under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
