<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5406"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5406/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5406">
        <akn:num>31-5406</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Assessments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors shall assess the member insurers for the amounts necessary to carry out the powers and duties of the Association. Assessments shall be made separately for the life insurance and annuity account and for the health insurance account and shall be maintained in a District of Columbia bank, which is subject to the District of Columbia Community Development Program under the supervision of the District of Columbia Office of Banking and Financial Institutions. Assessments shall be due not less than 30 days after prior written notice to the member insurers and shall accrue interest monthly until paid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There shall be 2 assessments, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be proper for any member insurer, in determining its premium rates and policyholder dividends for any kind of insurance within the scope of this chapter, to consider the amount reasonably necessary to meet its assessment obligations under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association shall issue to each insurer paying an assessment under this chapter, other than a Class A assessment, a certificate of contribution, in a form prescribed by the Mayor, for the amount of the assessment so paid. All outstanding certificates shall be of equal value, dignity, and priority without references to amounts or dates of issue. A certificate of contribution may be shown by the insurer in its financial statement as an asset in the form and for the amount, if any, and period of time as the Mayor may approve.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5406_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
