<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5005"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5005/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5005">
        <akn:num>31-5005</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Joint Underwriting Association; establishment; composition; plan of operation; participation by members; board of directors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5005_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to establish by order a Joint Underwriting Association if he finds, after notice and hearing, that such Association is necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Such Joint Underwriting Association shall consist of all insurers licensed to write and engaged in writing in the District of Columbia, on a direct basis, such basic property insurance as may be designated by the Mayor or any component thereof in multiperil policies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5005_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every such insurer shall be and remain a member of the Association and shall comply with all requirements of membership as a condition of its authority to transact such kinds of insurance in the District of Columbia, except that in lieu of revoking or suspending the certificate of authority of any company for any failure to comply with any of the requirements of membership, the Mayor may subject such company to a penalty of not more than $200 for each such failure to so comply when in his judgment he finds that the public interest would be best served by the continued operation of the company in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5005_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5005_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All members of the Association shall participate in its writings, expenses, profits, and losses, or in such categories thereof as may be separately established by the Association, subject to approval by the Mayor, in the proportion that the premiums written by each such member during the preceding calendar year bear to the aggregate premiums written in the District of Columbia by all members of the Association, or in accordance with such other formula as the Association may devise with the approval of the Mayor. Such participation by each insurer in the Association shall be determined annually on the basis of such premiums written during the preceding calendar year as disclosed in the annual statements and other reports filed by the insurer with the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5005_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Association shall be governed by a board of 11 directors, elected annually by cumulative voting by the members of the Association, whose votes in such election shall be weighted in accordance with the proportionate amount of each member’s net direct premiums written in the District of Columbia during the preceding calendar year. The 1st board shall be elected at a meeting of the members or their authorized representatives, which shall be held within 30 days after the effective date of the order under this section establishing the Association, at a time and place designated by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
