<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5603.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5603.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5603_03">
        <akn:num>31-5603.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Registration by coordination.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A security for which a registration statement has been filed under the Securities Act of 1933 in connection with the offering of the security may be registered by coordination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the information specified in § 31-5603.06(c) and the consent to service of process required under § 31-5607.06, a registration statement under this section shall contain the following information and be accompanied by the following documents:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A registration statement under this section shall become effective at the time that the federal registration statement becomes effective if all of the following conditions are satisfied:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The registrant shall promptly notify the Commissioner, in writing, facsimile transmission, or other means considered acceptable by the Commissioner, of the date and time when the federal registration statement became effective and the content of the price amendment, if any, and shall promptly file a post-effective amendment containing the information and documents in the price amendment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon failure to receive the required notification and post-effective amendment with respect to the price amendment, the Commissioner may enter a stop order, without notice or hearing, retroactively the denying the effectiveness of the registration statement or suspending its effectiveness until there is compliance with subsection (d) of this section if the Commissioner promptly notifies the registrant by telephone or otherwise, and promptly confirms by letter, facsimile transmission, or otherwise if the Commissioner notifies by telephone, of the issuance of the order. If the registrant proves compliance with the requirements of subsection (d) of this section as to notice and post-effective amendment, the stop order shall be void as of the time of its entry.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may, by rule or otherwise, waive either or both of the conditions specified in subsection (c)(2) or (3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the federal registration statement becomes effective before all of the conditions in subsection (c) of this section are satisfied and they are not waived, the registration statement shall become effective when all the conditions are satisfied. If the registrant advises the Commissioner of the date when the federal registration statement is expected to become effective, the Commissioner shall promptly advise the registrant by telephone, facsimile, or otherwise, at the registrant’s expense, whether all of the conditions are satisfied and whether the Commissioner then contemplates the institution of a proceeding under § 31-5603.06. This advice by the Commissioner shall not preclude the institution of a proceeding for a stop order suspending the effectiveness of the registration statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5603_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may, by rule or order, waive or modify the application of a requirement of this section if a provision, or an amendment, repeal, or other alteration of the securities registration provisions, of the Securities Act of 1933, or the regulations adopted thereunder, render the waiver or modification appropriate for further coordination of District and federal law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
