<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5602.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5602.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5602_02">
        <akn:num>31-5602.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Licensing of investment adviser and investment adviser representative.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall transact business in the District as an investment adviser or as an investment adviser representative unless the person is licensed, or exempt from licensure, under this chapter, or the person has no place of business in the District, and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When an investment adviser representative begins or terminates employment with a licensed investment adviser or federal covered adviser, the investment adviser or the investment adviser representative shall promptly notify the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except for advisers whose only clients are those described in subsection (a) of this section, a federal covered adviser shall not conduct advisory business in the District unless the federal covered adviser complies with ยง 31-5602.03(e).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless sooner terminated under this chapter or renewed, the license of an investment adviser and investment adviser representative, and the notice filing of each federal covered adviser, shall expire on December 31.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5602_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No investment adviser representative may be registered with more than one investment adviser unless the investment advisers which employ or associate with the investment adviser representative are under common ownership or control.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
