<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5409"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5409/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5409">
        <akn:num>31-5409</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Prevention of insolvencies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To aid in the detection and prevention of insurer impairments or insolvencies, the Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may seek the advice and recommendations of the Board of Directors concerning any matter affecting the Mayor’s duties and responsibilities regarding the financial condition of member insurers and companies seeking admission to transact insurance business in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors may, upon majority vote, make reports and recommendations to the Mayor upon any matter germane to the solvency, liquidation, rehabilitation, or conservation of any member insurer, or germane to the solvency of any company seeking to transact insurance business in the District of Columbia. These reports and recommendations shall be internal working documents, and, consequently, shall not be considered public documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be the duty of the Board of Directors, upon majority vote, to notify the Mayor of any information indicating whether any member insurer may be an impaired or insolvent insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors may, upon majority vote, make recommendations to the Mayor for the detection and prevention of insurer insolvencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5409_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board of Directors, at the conclusion of any insurer insolvency in which the Association was obligated to pay covered claims, shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
