<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5041.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5041.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5041_01">
        <akn:num>31-5041.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Abstract of title” means a written history, synopsis, or summary of the recorded instruments affecting a title to real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means, with respect to a person, another person that directly, or indirectly through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with the person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Aggrieved party” means a lender, title insurer, consumer, or the District of Columbia, who shall have suffered economic harm as a result of matters insured under any fidelity coverage required under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Attorney” means a person who is admitted to practice law in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business entity” means a corporation, association, partnership, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or other legal entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Escrow” means written instruments, money, or other items deposited by a party with a depository, escrow producer, or escrowee for delivery to another party upon the performance of a specified condition or the happening of a certain event.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Escrow Officer” means a person who maintains an escrow or indemnified deposit account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Indemnity” or “indemnity deposit” means funds or other property received by the title insurer as collateral to secure an indemnitor’s obligation under an indemnity agreement pursuant to which the insurer is granted a perfected security interest in the collateral in exchange for agreeing to provide coverage in a title insurance policy for a specific title exception to coverage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Individual means a natural person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual or business entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personal property” means stock ownership in a cooperative housing association.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Producer Licensing Act” means Chapter 11A of this title [§ 31-1131.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified financial institution” means an institution that is:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“RESPA” means the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974, approved December 22, 1974 (88 Stat. 1724; 12 U.S.C. § 2601 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Subsidiary” means an affiliate controlled by a person, directly or indirectly, through one or more intermediaries.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Title insurance business” or “business of title insurance” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Title insurance commitment” means a preliminary report or binder issued prior to the issuance of a title insurance policy containing the terms, conditions, exceptions, and any other matters under which the title insurer is willing to issue its title insurance policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Title insurance policy” means a contract insuring or indemnifying owners of, or other persons lawfully interested in, real or personal property or an interest in real or personal property against loss or damage arising from any of the following conditions existing on or before the policy date and not expressly excepted or excluded from coverage:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Title insurer” or “insurer” means a company organized under laws of this state for the purpose of transacting the business of title insurance and any foreign or non-U.S. title insurer licensed in the District to transact the business of title insurance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5041_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Underwrite” means to accept or reject, or have the authority to accept or reject, risk on behalf of a title insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
