<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5327"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5327/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5327">
        <akn:num>31-5327</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Injunction; liquidation; receivership of domestic society.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5327_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the Commissioner, upon investigation, finds that a domestic society has exceeded its powers; has failed to comply with any provision of this chapter; is not fulfilling its contracts in good faith; has a membership of less than 90 after an existence of one year or more; or is conducting business fraudulently or in a manner hazardous to its members, creditors, the public, or the business, the Commissioner shall notify the society of such deficiency and state in writing the reasons for his or her dissatisfaction. The Commissioner shall immediately issue a written notice to the society requiring that the deficiency be corrected.  After such notice the society shall have a 30-day period in which to comply with the Commissioner’s request for correction.  If the society fails to comply, the Commissioner shall notify the society of such findings of noncompliance and require the society to show cause on a date named why it should not be enjoined from carrying on any business until the violation complained of shall have been corrected, or why an action in quo warranto should not be commenced against the society.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5327_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If on such date the society does not present good and sufficient reasons why it should not be so enjoined or why such action should not be commenced, the Commissioner may present the facts relating thereto to the Corporation Counsel of the District who shall, if he or she deems the circumstances warrant, commence an action to enjoin the society from transacting business or in quo warranto.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5327_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court shall thereupon notify the officers of the society of a hearing. If after a full hearing it appears that the society should be so enjoined or liquidated or a receiver appointed, the court shall enter the necessary order. No society so enjoined shall have the authority to do business until the:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5327_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the court orders the society liquidated, it shall be enjoined from carrying on any further business, whereupon the receiver of the society shall proceed immediately to take possession of the books, papers, money, and other assets of the society and, under the direction of the court, proceed forthwith to close the affairs of the society and to distribute its funds to those entitled thereto.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5327_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No action under this section shall be recognized in any court of the District unless brought by the Corporation Counsel upon request of the Commissioner. Whenever a receiver is to be appointed for a domestic society, the court shall appoint the Commissioner as such receiver.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5327_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section relating to hearing by the Commissioner, action by the Corporation Counsel at the request of the Commissioner, hearing by the court, injunction and receivership shall be applicable to a society which voluntarily determines to discontinue business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
