<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5605.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5605.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5605_02">
        <akn:num>31-5605.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Fraudulent transactions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person shall not:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The prohibition of subsection (a)(2) of this section shall not apply to any information published or circulated relating to a federal covered security. The prohibition of subsection (a)(4) of this section shall not apply to a transaction with a federal covered adviser or to a transaction with a customer of a broker-dealer if the broker-dealer is not acting as an investment adviser in relation to the transaction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term “investment” means a commitment of money or property principally induced by a representation that an economic benefit may be derived from the commitment; provided, that the term “investment” shall not include a commitment of money or property for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the solicitation of, or dealings with, advisory clients, a person shall not knowingly make an untrue statement of a material fact, or omit to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statements made, in light of the circumstances under which they are made, not misleading.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as may be permitted by rule or order of the Commissioner, an investment adviser shall not enter into, extend, or renew an investment advisory contract unless it provides in writing that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An investment adviser shall not take or have custody of any securities or funds of a client if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5605_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may, by rule or order, adopt exemptions from subsections (a)(4), (e)(1), (e)(2), and (e)(3) of this section if the exemptions are consistent with the public interest and within the purposes fairly intended by the policy and provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
