<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5237"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-5237/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_5237">
        <akn:num>31-5237</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Decertification.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall conduct an annual review of each Certified Capital Company to determine if the Certified Capital Company is complying with the requirements of certification, to advise the Certified Capital Company as to the eligibility status of its Qualified Investments, and to ensure that no investment has been made in violation of this chapter. The cost of the annual review shall be paid by each Certified Capital Company under a fee schedule adopted by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any material violation of this chapter shall be grounds for decertification of the Certified Capital Company. If the Commissioner determines that a Certified Capital Company is not in compliance with the requirements of this chapter, the Commissioner shall, by written notice, inform the officers of the Certified Capital Company that the Certified Capital Company is subject to decertification in 120 days from the date of mailing of the notice unless the deficiencies are corrected.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Certified Capital Company is not in compliance with this chapter at the end of the 120-day notice period, the Commissioner may send a notice of decertification to the Certified Capital Company and to all other appropriate District agencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Decertification of a Certified Capital Company may cause the recapture of Premium Tax Credits previously claimed and the forfeiture of future Premium Tax Credits to be claimed by Certified Investors with respect to the Certified Capital Company, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a Certified Capital Company has invested an amount cumulatively equal to 100% of its Certified Capital in Qualified Investments, notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Certified Capital Company shall not be subject to regulation by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall send written notice to each Certified Investor whose Premium Tax Credits have been subject to recapture or forfeiture at the address last shown on the last premium tax filing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-5237_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
