<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-705"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-705/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_705">
        <akn:num>31-705</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Registration of insurers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every insurer subject to registration shall file the registration statement on a form prescribed by the NAIC, which shall contain the following current information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All registration statements shall contain a summary outlining all items in the current registration statement which are different from the prior registration statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No information need be disclosed on the registration statement filed pursuant to subsection (b) of this section if the information is not material for the purposes of this section. Unless the Mayor by rule, regulation, or order provides otherwise, sales, purchases, exchanges, loans or extensions of credit, investments, or guarantees involving one-half of 1% or less of an insurer’s admitted assets as of the 31st day of December next preceding shall not be deemed material for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to § 31-706(b), each registered insurer shall report to the Mayor all dividends and other distributions to shareholders within 15 business days following their declaration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person within an insurance holding company system subject to registration shall be required to provide complete and accurate information to an insurer, where the information is reasonably necessary to enable the insurer to comply with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall terminate the registration of any insurer which demonstrates that it no longer is a member of an insurance holding company system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may require or allow 2 or more affiliated insurers subject to registration to file a consolidated registration statement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may allow an insurer which is authorized to do business in the District and which is part of an insurance holding company system to register on behalf of any affiliated insurer which is required to register under subsection (a) of this section and to file all information and material required to be filed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to any insurer, information, or transaction if and to the extent that the Mayor by rule, regulation, or order shall exempt the same from the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person may file with the Mayor a disclaimer of affiliation with any authorized insurer or the disclaimer may be filed by the insurer or any member of an insurance holding company system. The disclaimer shall fully disclose all material relationships and bases for affiliation between the person and the insurer as well as the basis for disclaiming the affiliation. A disclaimer of affiliation shall be deemed to have been granted, unless the Mayor, within 30 days following receipt of a complete disclaimer, notifies the filing party that the disclaimer is disallowed. In the event of disallowance, the disclaiming party may request an administrative hearing, which shall be granted. The disclaiming party shall be relieved of its duty to register under this section if approval of the disclaimer has been granted by the Mayor or has been deemed approved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_k_1">
      <akn:num>(k-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The ultimate controlling person of every insurer subject to registration shall also file an annual enterprise risk report. The report shall, to the best of the ultimate controlling person’s knowledge and belief, identify the material risks within the insurance holding company system that could pose enterprise risk to the insurer. The report shall be filed with the lead state commissioner of the insurance holding company system as determined by the procedures within the Financial Analysis Handbook adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-705_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The failure to file a registration statement or any summary of the registration statement or enterprise risk filing required by this section within the time specified for such a filing shall be a violation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
