<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-710"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-710/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_710">
        <akn:num>31-710</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sanctions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any officer, director, or employee of an insurance holding company system who willfully and knowingly subscribes to, or makes or causes to be made, any false statements, false reports, or false filings with the intent to deceive the Mayor in the performance of his or her duties under this subchapter, upon conviction, shall be imprisoned for not more than 3 to 5 years or fined $100,000, or both. Any fines imposed shall be paid by the officer, director, or employee in his or her individual capacity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever it appears to the Mayor that a person has committed a violation of ยง 31-703, which prevents the full understanding of the enterprise risk to the insurer by affiliates or by the insurance holding company system, the violation may serve as an independent basis for disapproving dividends or distributions and for placing the insurer under an order of supervision in accordance with the insurance laws of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-710_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this subchapter, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this subchapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction of this subchapter shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
