<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-906"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/31-906/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_31_906">
        <akn:num>31-906</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Required provisions in a plan of conversion.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall set forth the reasons for the proposed conversion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall provide that all policies in force on the effective date of conversion shall continue to remain in force under the terms of those policies, except that any voting rights of the policyholders provided for under the policies or under District law and any contingent liability policy provisions of the type described in District law shall be extinguished on the effective date of the conversion.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall further provide that the holders of participating policies in effect on the date of conversion shall continue to have the right to receive dividends as provided in the participating policies, if any.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except mutual company’s life policies, guaranteed reviewable accident and health policies, and noncancelable accident and health policies, the converted stock company may issue the insured a nonparticipating policy as a substitute for the participating policy upon the renewal date of a participating policy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The subscription rights shall be allocated in whole shares among the eligible members using a fair and equitable formula. This formula may, but need not, take into account how the different classes of policies of the eligible members contributed to the surplus of the mutual company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall provide a fair and equitable means for the allocation of shares of capital stock in the event of an oversubscription to shares by eligible members exercising subscription rights received pursuant to subsection (e) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall provide that any shares of capital stock not subscribed to by eligible members exercising subscription rights received under subsections (e) and (f) of this section shall be sold in a public offering through an underwriter. If the shares of capital stock not subscribed to by eligible members is so small in number as to not warrant the expense of a public offering, the plan of conversion may provide for the purchase of the unsubscribed shares by a private placement or other alternative method approved by the Commissioner that is fair and equitable to the eligible members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall set the total price of the capital stock equal to the estimated pro forma market value of the converted stock company based upon an independent evaluation by a qualified person. The pro forma market value may be the value or range of values that is estimated to be necessary to attract full subscription for shares as indicated by the independent evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall set the purchase price of each share of capital stock equal to any reasonable amount that will not inhibit the purchase of shares by members. The purchase price of each share shall be uniform for all purchasers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall provide for a closed block of business for participating life policies of a Class 1 mutual company.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31-906_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The plan shall provide that any one person or group of persons acting in concert may not acquire, through public offering or subscription rights, more than 5% of the capital stock of the converted stock company for a period of 5 years from the effective date of the plan except with the approval of the Commissioner. This limitation does not apply to any entity that is to purchase 100% of the capital stock of the converted company as part of the plan of conversion approved by the Commissioner or to a purchase of stock by a tax-qualified employee benefit plan pursuant to subscription rights granted to that plan as authorized under § 31-907(b) and to a purchase of unsubscribed stock pursuant to subsection (h) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
