<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/45-301"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/45-301/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_45_301">
        <akn:num>45-301</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Established; composition; term of office; residency requirement; vacancies; compensation; requests for information; power to enter into contracts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as an advisory body to the Council of the District of Columbia the District of Columbia Law Revision Commission (“Commission”), which shall be composed of 9 members, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may be appointed as a member of the Commission after the effective date of this chapter unless he or she is a bona fide resident of the District of Columbia who has maintained an actual place of abode in the District of Columbia for at least 90 days immediately prior to his or her appointment to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Commission shall serve for 4-year terms and may be reappointed for no more than 2 consecutive terms.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chairman of the Commission shall be selected by the members of the Commission from among their number.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appointments to fill vacancies on the Commission shall be made in the same manner, and on the same basis, as original appointments to the Commission. A member appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve until the expiration of the term of the member whose vacancy he or she was appointed to fill.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation; provided, that each member may be reimbursed for actual expenses pursuant to § 1-611.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission may request from any department, agency, or instrumentality of the executive branch of the District of Columbia or federal government, including independent agencies, any information necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. Each department, agency, instrumentality, or independent agency of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed, to the extent permitted by law, to furnish the Commission the requested information.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45-301_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission may establish such advisory groups, committees, or subcommittees, consisting of members or nonmembers, as it deems necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
