<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-103.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-103.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_103_06">
        <akn:num>44-103.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Inspections.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the inspections required by § 44-103.02(e), the Mayor may inspect an ALR at the Mayor’s discretion to ensure compliance with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall at all times ensure that any ALR licensed pursuant to this chapter is able to continually provide appropriate care to its residents. The Mayor shall notify an ALR if, at any time, the Mayor determines that the ALR is unable to provide appropriate care to any of its residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Inspection of an ALR, or prospective ALR, for purposes of initial licensure or compliance after license renewal shall be conducted by the Mayor following the procedures set forth in § 44-505 and the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, upon inspection, the Mayor determines that an ALR, or prospective ALR, is in violation of one or more of the requirements of this chapter, the Mayor shall give written notice of such violation to the ALR, or prospective ALR, within 15 working days of the inspection and may suggest a remedy for each violation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The violating ALR, or prospective ALR, shall submit a written response to the Mayor within 15 working days of receipt of the Mayor’s notice. The violating ALR, or prospective ALR, may deny the alleged violation, accept the Mayor’s suggested remedy, or propose its own remedy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor accepts the ALR’s, or prospective ALR’s, written response, the Mayor may either issue a license to the ALR, or prospective ALR, if appropriate, or conduct a follow-up inspection to confirm compliance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor and the ALR, or prospective ALR, cannot agree on an acceptable corrective action, or if the ALR, or prospective ALR, fails to respond in writing within 15 working days of receipt of the Mayor’s notice, the Mayor shall determine what action to take, including a penalty in accordance with this chapter and give the ALR, or prospective ALR, notice of his or her determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may inspect an ALR for the purpose of investigating a complaint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
