<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-107.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-107.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_107_01">
        <akn:num>44-107.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Staffing standards.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An ALR shall be supervised by an ALA who shall be responsible for all personnel and services within the ALR.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The ALA shall ensure that each resident has access to appropriate medical, rehabilitation, and psychosocial services as established in the ISP and that there is appropriate oversight, monitoring, and coordination of all components of the ISP, including necessary transportation and the delivery of needed supplies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An ALA shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Newly hired staff shall have 30 days to document their communicable disease status. For the purposes of this subsection, “newly hired staff” means any individual who is hired by an ALR regardless of the individual’s previous work experience. An employee who is transferring from one ALR to another ALR that is under the same management or ownership, without break in service, shall not be considered newly hired staff.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Employees shall be required on an annual basis to document freedom from tuberculosis in a communicable form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Staff who have not completed the training required by § 44-107.02 must work at all times under the supervision of a staff member who has satisfactorily completed this training.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-107_01_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of subsection (g)(5) of this section “ongoing training” means a regularly scheduled program of staff training designed by the ALR to assure that all staff who have direct resident contact possess the skills necessary to provide high quality services in a manner appropriate to the philosophy of assisted living and includes staff training in how to monitor changes in a resident’s condition, including physical and cognitive assessments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
