<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-151.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-151.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_151_01">
        <akn:num>44-151.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Assisted living” means an assisted living residence as defined in § 44-102.01(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Continuing care facility” means a building, or complex of buildings under one management at one or more sites, if continuing care services are provided.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Continuing care services” means the continuum of care, ranging from independent living to assisted living to nursing home care, provided pursuant to a contract for the life of the individual purchasing the services or for a period of not less than one year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Entrance fee” means a payment that assures a resident a place in a facility for a term of at least a year or for life.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hazardous financial condition” means a provider is insolvent or in imminent danger of becoming insolvent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Independent living” means an individual residing in a continuing care facility’s living unit with no need for specialized health care services beyond general preventative health care.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Living unit” means a room, apartment, cottage, or other area within a continuing care facility set aside for the exclusive use or control of one or more identified residents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Nursing home” means a nursing home as defined in § 44-501(3).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Provider” means the promoter, developer, or owner, whether a natural person, partnership, or other unincorporated association, however organized, trust, or corporation, whether operated for profit or not, or any other person, that solicits or undertakes to provide continuing care services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-151_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Resident” means a purchaser of, a nominee of, or a subscriber to, a continuing care contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
