<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-1003.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-1003.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_1003_06">
        <akn:num>44-1003.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice to facility owner or administrator; informal conference.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-1003_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before a resident is transferred or discharged under § 44-1003.05(a)(1) through (3), the Mayor shall provide the licensee or administrator of the facility with a written notice stating the reasons for the intended action and informing the licensee or administrator of his or her right to an informal conference and a subsequent hearing. The licensee or administrator may contest a nonemergency transfer or discharge by submitting to the Mayor a written request for an informal conference within 4 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after he or she receives notice of the proposed transfer or discharge. A timely request for an informal conference shall stay the nonemergency transfer or discharge pending the Mayor’s decision after the conference.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-1003_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall hold an informal conference within 4 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after a timely request for the conference is received. Following the conference, the Mayor shall affirm, modify, or reverse his or her previous decision to transfer or discharge the resident.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
