<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-103.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-103.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_103_04">
        <akn:num>44-103.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Renewal of ALR license.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An ALR license shall be renewed every 12 months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Applications for renewal of a license shall be made in writing on a form or forms prescribed by the Mayor at least 60 days prior to the expiration of the license. The Mayor shall renew a license after receiving an application containing the information required by ยง 44-103.02(d) and completion of an inspection of the premises, if the Mayor finds that the application meets the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue the renewal license prior to the expiration date of the existing license if the applicant submits an application for renewal within 90 to 60 days prior to the expiration of the license and the Mayor finds that the application meets the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An applicant for renewal shall pay a renewal fee as determined by the Mayor. The fee shall cover the costs involved in processing the renewal applications and conducting inspections of the premises.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-103_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Based on information provided to the Mayor and by the on-site inspection, the Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
