<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-233"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-233/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_233">
        <akn:num>44-233</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>AED use and tort immunity.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person or entity who, in good faith and without compensation, uses an AED to provide emergency care or treatment shall be immune from civil liability for any personal injury resulting from the care or treatment, or resulting from any act or failure to act in providing or arranging further medical treatment, if the person acts as an ordinary, reasonably prudent person would have acted under the same or similar circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The immunity from civil liability provided under subsection (a) of this section shall extend to the licensed physician or medical authority involved in automated external defibrillator site placement, the person who provides training in CPR and the use of the automated external defibrillator, and the person or entity responsible for the site where the automated external defibrillator is located.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The immunity from civil liability provided under this chapter shall not apply if the personal injury results from the gross negligence or the willful or wanton misconduct of the person providing the emergency care.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section expressly excludes from the provision of immunity designers, manufacturers, or sellers of automated external defibrillators who have claims brought against them based upon current District of Columbia law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who, in good faith and without compensation, uses a defibrillator at the scene of an emergency, and all other persons and entities providing services without compensation under this section, shall be immune from civil liability for any personal injury that results from any act or omission in the use of the defibrillator in an emergency situation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The immunity from civil liability under this section shall not apply to a licensed or certified health professional who used the automated external defibrillator device while acting within the scope of the license or certification of the professional or within the scope of the employment or agency of the professional.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-233_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other immunities available under statutory or common law, the District is not civilly liable for any act or omission in the provision of automated external defibrillation if, at the time of the act or omission, the recreation facility possessed a valid recreation facility certificate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
