<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-301.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-301.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_301_07">
        <akn:num>44-301.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>External appeals process for matters other than rescissions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall establish and maintain an external appeals process whereby a member or member representative who is dissatisfied with a decision rendered in an internal appeals process shall have the opportunity to pursue an external appeal before an independent review organization. The member or member’s representative has a right to pursue an external appeal if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To initiate an external appeal, a member or member representative shall, within 4 months from receipt of the written decision of the formal internal appeal panel, file a written request with the Director.  The member or member representative shall submit a signed form allowing the insurer to release medical records of the member that are pertinent to the appeal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of the request for an external appeal, together with the executed release form, the Director shall determine whether:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon completion of the preliminary review, the Director shall notify the member or member representative and insurer in writing as to whether the appeal has been accepted for processing.  If the appeal is accepted by the Director, the Director shall assign the appeal to an independent review organization for full review. If the appeal is not accepted by the Director, the Director shall provide a statement of the reasons for the nonacceptance to the member or member representative and the insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The staff of the independent review organization that is assigned to the appeal pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, shall have meaningful prior experience in performing utilization review, peer review, quality of care assessment or assurance, or the hearing of appeals. Any independent review organization,  its staff,  and its professional and medical reviewers, shall not have any material, professional, familial, or financial affiliation with the insurer that is a party to the appeal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The member or member’s representative may initiate an external appeal without exhaustion of the internal appeals process described in § 44-301.06 in a case of an emergency or urgent medical condition, when the insurer has failed to comply with the procedures set forth in § 44-301.06, or when further participation in the internal process would require the provision of mental health information that the patient or treating mental health professional considers confidential.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The insurer shall provide timely access to all its records relating to the matter under review and to all provisions of the health benefits plan or health insurance coverage, including any evidence of coverage, “member handbook”, certificate of insurance or contract and health benefits plan relating to the matter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The full review of an appeal of a health benefits decision shall be initially conducted by 2 physicians licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia, Maryland, or Virginia, or in the case of mental health services, 2 health professional peers with an equal or greater degree of training and experience in the particular kind of mental health treatment under review licensed to practice medicine in the District of Columbia, Maryland, or Virginia. On an exceptions basis, when necessary based on the medical, surgical, or mental condition under review, the independent review organization may select medical reviewers licensed anywhere in the United States who have no history of disciplinary action taken or sanctions pending against them by any governmental or professional regulatory body.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_j_1">
      <akn:num>(j-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before issuing a decision in accordance with the time frames provided in subsection (m) of this section, the independent review organization shall provide free of charge to the member, or member’s representative, any new or additional evidence and any new or additional rationale, relied upon or generated by the independent review organization, or at the direction of the health insurer, in connection with the grievance or appeal decision sufficiently in advance of the date the decision is required to be provided to permit the member, or the member’s representative, a reasonable opportunity to respond before that date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The member or member representative and one insurer representative may request to appear in person before the independent review organization.  The independent review organization shall conduct the hearing in the District of Columbia.  The independent review organization’s procedures for conducting a review, when the member or member representative or the insurer has requested to appear in person, shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The independent review organization shall complete its review and issue its recommended decision as soon as possible in accordance with the medical exigencies of the case. Except as provided for in this subsection, the independent review organization shall complete its review within 45 calendar days, or 72 hours in the case of an expedited appeal, from the time the Director assigns the appeal to the independent review organization. An insurer shall provide all documentation to the independent review organization within 5 days of receipt of the notice of approval of the appeal by the Director, or within 24 hours of receipt of the notice of approval of the grievance, for an expedited review. If an insurer does not provide the independent review organization all documentation required by this subsection within the time frames, or obtain the necessary extensions, the independent review organization may decide the appeal without receiving the information. The independent review organization shall extend its review for a reasonable period of time as may be necessary due to circumstances beyond its or the insurer’s  control, but only when the delay will not result in increased medical risk, including increased mental health risk, to the member. In such an event, the independent review organization shall, prior to the conclusion of the initial review period, provide written notice to the member or member representative and to the insurer setting forth the status of its review and the specific reasons for the delay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_m_1">
      <akn:num>(m-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Expedited appeals shall be furnished:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the independent review organization determines that the member was deprived of medically necessary covered services or benefits, the independent review organization shall recommend to the Director the appropriate covered health services or benefits the member should receive. The Director shall forward copies of the recommendation to the member or member representative and the insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The independent review organization shall refer a case for review to a consultant physician or other health care provider in the same specialty or area of practice who would generally manage the type of treatment that is the subject of the appeal. All final recommendations of the independent review organization shall be approved by the medical director of the independent review organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The decision of the independent review organization shall be binding on the plan or issuer and the member, except to the extent that there are other remedies under District or federal law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_07_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
