<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-301.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-301.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_301_08">
        <akn:num>44-301.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certification and general requirements for independent review organizations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each independent review organization selected by the Director to review external appeals must be certified every 2 years by the Director.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall be responsible for developing, applying, and enforcing certification standards for independent review organizations. These standards shall ensure that an independent review organization:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An independent review organization may not be a subsidiary of, or in any way owned or controlled by a health benefits plan, insurer, or trade association of health care providers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall develop an application form for certifying an independent review organization that contains a description of the organization, including names, biographical sketches of all directors, officers, and executives of the organization.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The independent review organization shall submit to the Director the following information, for purposes of creating a file of public records, upon initial application for certification, and thereafter upon any change to any of this information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The independent review organization shall have a quality assurance mechanism in place that ensures the timeliness and quality of the reviews, the qualifications and independence of the experts, and the confidentiality of medical records and review materials.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Neither an independent review organization nor an individual working for an external review panel pursuant to this chapter shall be held liable for any recommendation presented by the independent review organization, except in cases of gross negligence, recklessness, or intentional misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An insurer, bound by the decision of the independent review entity, shall not be liable for following such decision.  A determination by the independent review entity in favor of the insurer shall create a rebuttal presumption in any subsequent action at law that the insurer’s coverage determination was appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall, from time to time, enter into contracts with as many independent review organizations as the Director deems necessary to conduct the external appeals. The contracts shall set forth all terms which the Director deems necessary to ensure a member’s right of appeal, including an assessment of separate costs to the insurer for the independent review organization review.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As part of the contract process set forth in subsection (j) of this section, all independent review organizations shall submit to the Director and shall maintain a current list identifying all insurers, health care facilities, and other health care providers with whom the independent review organization maintains any health related business arrangements. The list shall include a brief description of the nature of any such arrangement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon  receipt of any request for an external appeal, the Director shall assign that appeal to one of the approved independent review organizations on a random basis.  The Director may reserve the right to deny any assignment to any independent review organization if the Director determines that making an assignment would result in a conflict of interest or would otherwise create an appearance of impropriety.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The terms and conditions of a contract entered into pursuant to subsection (j) of this section shall provide that the reasonable direct costs of the external review process, not including costs of representation of a member, shall be paid by the insurer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-301_08_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
