<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-407"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-407/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_407">
        <akn:num>44-407</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Activities exempt from certificate of need review.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>HCFs and persons proposing projects exempted from certificate of need review must file with the SHPDA a letter of notice in accordance with rules promulgated pursuant to § 44-421.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following projects are exempt from certificate of need review:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of a project exempt under subsection (b)(13) of this section, the facility shall provide the Department of Mental Health with a copy of the letter of notice required by SHPDA for projects exempt from the certificate of need review.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Changes in ownership, whether voluntary or involuntary, of the short-term, acute-care hospital known as the United Medical Center and a long-term acute-care hospital and a skilled-nursing facility at the same location, known as the Southern Avenue Facilities, shall be exempt from the certificate-of-need requirements for the purpose of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An HMO, or combination of HMOs, shall be exempt from certificate of need requirements if it meets the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District government is exempt from certificate of need requirements until January 1, 1998.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any proposal to offer or develop a new institutional health service, obligate a new capital expenditure, or reduce or terminate a health service that would otherwise be subject to certificate of need requirements, by a health care entity that has contracted with the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility Management Assistance Authority, or with the Mayor pursuant to § 7-1405, to provide new health care services shall be exempt from certificate of need requirements only for the purpose of maintaining the same level of care and services provided by the District of Columbia Health and Hospitals Public Benefit Corporation (“Public Benefit Corporation”). The exemptions granted by this subsection shall be for a period of 225 days from July 12, 2001, except that proposals to develop trauma I capability to match the levels existing at D.C. General Hospital as of January 1, 2001, shall be exempt from certificate of need requirements for a period of 1 year from July 12, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Administrator of the Health Care Safety Net Administration (“Administrator”), established pursuant to § 7-1401, shall determine which new institutional health services, capital expenditures, and reductions or terminations of health services qualify as health care services being taken over from the Public Benefit Corporation. The Administrator’s authority to make determinations and the exemptions from certificate of need review pursuant to subsection (e) shall expire 1 year after the date the first contract for health care services entered into pursuant to § 7-1405 is signed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-407_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District government and the Public Benefit Corporation are exempt from certificate of need requirements for any changes in health care service that may result from the abolishment of the Public Benefit Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
