<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-409"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-409/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_409">
        <akn:num>44-409</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Adoption of procedures and criteria for review by the SHPDA governing application and review.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All applications for a certificate of need shall be reviewed by the SHPDA.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Existing procedures and criteria in effect on April 9, 1997, are valid insofar as they are not inconsistent with this chapter, until new rules of procedures and criteria are adopted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In accordance with § 44-421 the SHPDA shall establish, adopt, and publish procedures and criteria for the review of certificate of need applications, for new or renewal applications, for expedited administrative review, or for exemptions from review.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The SHPDA shall provide the applicant, the SHCC, and all previously appearing parties with a detailed explanation of any decision.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The general public shall have access to all applications reviewed by the SHPDA and all other written materials essential to SHPDA’s review contained in the SHPDA’s files, except that the SHPDA shall establish a procedure to restrict access of the general public from portions of applications or supporting documents which contain detailed descriptions of security systems, medical record systems, controlled storage systems or proprietary financial information. The SHPDA is authorized to charge reasonable fees for the costs of providing to the public documents covered under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In issuing a certificate of need, the SHPDA shall specify in the certificate the maximum amount of capital expenditures which may be obligated under the certificate. The SHPDA shall prescribe the extent to which a project authorized by a certificate of need shall be subject to further review if the amount of capital expenditures obligated or expected to be obligated for the project exceeds the maximum specified in the certificate of need.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The SHPDA may impose a condition upon the grant of a certificate of need if it is necessary to meet a criterion or standard previously adopted and published by the SHPDA. The SHPDA shall modify or remove a condition upon application at any time by the holder of the certificate of need or other person if the circumstances upon which the condition is premised change and no longer justify the condition, or if the condition, for any other reason, is no longer appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No certificate of need holder shall begin operation of the bed, facility, or health service approved in the certificate of need until the SHPDA has conducted a review to determine compliance with the certificate of need requirements. If the SHPDA does not make a finding of noncompliance within 30 days of receiving notification from the certificate of need holder of its intent to begin operation, the SHPDA shall be deemed to have determined compliance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-409_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>SHPDA shall require that all prospective certificate of need applicants certify, in writing, that for the five-year period following the award of the certificate of need the percentage of uncompensated care (charity and bad-debt) provided each year to the population served by the HCF will be equal to or exceed the average of the percentage of uncompensated care provided by the HCF for the 2 fiscal years immediately preceding the review of an application for a certificate of need pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
