<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-502"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-502/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_502">
        <akn:num>44-502</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>License requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, it shall be unlawful to operate a facility or agency in the District of Columbia, whether public or private, for profit or not for profit, without being licensed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This subchapter shall not apply to a facility or agency operated by the federal government or, except in the case of community residence facilities, by and for the adherents of a church or religious denomination that, in accordance with established tenets, recognizes spiritual healing as the sole means of treating illness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Facilities and agencies that, prior to February 24, 1984, were not or would not have been subject to licensure in the District of Columbia may operate without a license until 6 months after the adoption of applicable rules under § 44-504.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The continued operation of a facility or agency pending action by the Mayor on an application for licensure renewal or initial licensure under subsection (c) of this section shall not be deemed unlawful if a completed application was timely filed but, through no fault of the facility or agency or its governing body, staff, or employees, the Mayor has failed to act on the application before the expiration of the facility’s or agency’s current license or, under subsection (c) of this section, its authorized period of operation. A facility or agency operating under this subsection shall comply with all other provisions of this subchapter and rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Application forms shall list all certificates of approval, authority, occupancy, or need that are required as a precondition to lawful operation in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A license shall be valid only for the premises stated on the license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any change in the ownership of a facility or agency owned by an individual, partnership, or association, or in the legal or beneficial ownership of 10% or more of the stock of a corporation that owns or operates a facility or agency, shall be subject to written notice of the change being given to the governmental licensing authority at least 30 days prior to the change in ownership. Upon notification, the governmental licensing authority may, at its discretion, require reinspection and relicensure to ensure that the facility or agency will remain in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter, rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter, and all other applicable provisions of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless sooner terminated or renewed, a license required by this subchapter shall expire one year from the date of issue or the last renewal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each facility licensed under this subchapter shall post its license in a conspicuous place on the premises, and each agency licensed under this subchapter shall have its license readily available for inspection by the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-502_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement or a Public Health: Human Services Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
