<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-505"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/44-505/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_44_505">
        <akn:num>44-505</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Inspections.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-505_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To ensure that each new facility and agency will be in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter, rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter, and all other applicable laws and rules, the Mayor shall conduct an on-site inspection prior to a facility’s or agency’s initial licensure. Instead of issuing a full-year license to a new facility or agency, the Mayor may issue a provisional license under § 44-506 pending satisfactory completion of additional, follow-up inspections.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-505_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After initial licensure the Mayor shall conduct an on-site inspection as a precondition to licensure renewal, except that the Mayor may accept accreditation by a private accrediting body, federal certification for participation in a health-insurance or medical assistance program, or federal qualification of a health maintenance organization as evidence of, and in lieu of inspecting for, compliance with any or all of the provisions of this subchapter and rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter that incorporate or are substantially similar to applicable standards or conditions of participation established by that body or the federal government. Acceptance of private accreditation by the Mayor shall be contingent on the facility’s or agency’s:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-505_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An authorized government official may enter the premises of a facility or agency during operating hours for the purpose of conducting an announced or unannounced inspection to check for compliance with any provision of this subchapter, rule adopted pursuant to this subchapter, or other provision of District of Columbia law. In conducting an inspection, the official shall make every effort not to disrupt the normal operations of the facility or agency and its staff.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-505_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44-505_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall have the authority, upon a showing of undue hardship and if not inconsistent with other provisions of this chapter or deleterious to the public health and safety, to grant variances with respect to the standards to be established under § 44-504(a)(3) and (h-1). The Mayor shall maintain a public record listing all variances granted under this subsection and containing a complete written explanation of the basis for each variance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
