<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/15-106"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/15-106/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_15_106">
        <akn:num>15-106</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Judgment and damages assessed in actions on bonds or penal sums.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_15-106_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In a civil action on a bond or on a penal sum for the nonperformance of covenants or agreements contained in an indenture, deed, or writing, the plaintiff may assign as many breaches as he chooses. Damages shall be assessed for such breaches as he proves and judgment rendered for the whole penalty, but execution shall issue for as much only as is found in damages, with costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15-106_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In an action brought under subsection (a) of this section, upon judgment for the plaintiff on motion, default, or confession, the plaintiff may assign as many breaches as he chooses, the truth of which shall be determined. The damages shall be assessed and execution shall issue for such damages only, with costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15-106_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payment into court, after entry of judgment and prior to the issuance of execution, of the amount of the damages and costs assessed, for the use of the plaintiff or his representatives, stays execution, and the stay shall be entered on the record. Payment to the plaintiff or his representatives, after execution, of the amount of the damages and costs assessed, together with all fees and other reasonable costs of execution, forthwith discharges the defendant’s real and personal property from execution, and the discharge shall be entered on the record. However, the judgment shall remain as a security to the plaintiff or his representatives for any other breaches which he or they afterwards prove. From time to time, the plaintiff may, by motion and hearing, with reasonable notice to the defendant, assign other breaches, and damages shall be assessed for such breaches as he proves, with costs. Payment into court, before execution, or to the plaintiff or his representative, after execution, as herein described, has the same effect as hereinbefore directed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15-106_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In proceedings under this section, the right of trial by jury, as to issues of fact and the amount of damages to be assessed, is preserved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15-106_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section is subject to section 28-2502 of this Code and to section 1874 of Title 28, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
