<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/48-903.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/48-903.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_48_903_02">
        <akn:num>48-903.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Registration — Required; renewal; exceptions; waiver; inspection.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_48-903_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every person who manufactures, distributes, or dispenses any controlled substance within the District of Columbia, or who proposes to engage in the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of any controlled substance within the District of Columbia, must obtain annually a registration issued by the Mayor in accordance with the rules. Applications to renew a registration must be filed in a timely manner, not less than 60 days prior to the expiration of the registration, or the registration shall abate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48-903_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Persons registered with the Mayor under this chapter to manufacture, distribute, dispense, or conduct research with controlled substances may possess, manufacture, distribute, dispense, or conduct research with those substances to the extent authorized by their registration and in conformity with the other provisions of this subchapter. Any person registered under this subchapter whose authority to possess, distribute, dispense, or conduct research with controlled substances is limited or otherwise restricted by any federal, state, or District of Columbia law, shall use such registration only to the extent authorized by said federal, state, or District of Columbia law unless otherwise specified.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48-903_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following persons need not register and may lawfully possess controlled substances under this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48-903_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may waive by rule the requirement for registration of certain manufacturers, distributors, or dispensers if the Mayor finds it consistent with the public health and safety.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48-903_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A separate registration is required for each principal place of business or professional practice where the applicant manufactures, distributes, or dispenses controlled substances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48-903_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may inspect the establishment of a registrant or applicant for registration in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
