<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-107.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-107.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_107_02">
        <akn:num>8-107.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sale and use of phosphate cleaners prohibited; exceptions; manufacturer’s package statement; testing of products for compliance; exemptions for use of noncomplying cleaners; rules and regulations; annual report by Mayor.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, after 180 days after March 25, 1986, no cleaning agent may be used, sold, or furnished in the District of Columbia if it contains a phosphorous compound in a concentration exceeding a trace quantity of phosphorus, except that a cleaning agent with more than a trace quantity of phosphorus may be used for cleaning health care equipment, for use by any commercial or institutional laundry in providing laundry services for a hospital or health care facility; for cleaning food processing equipment, beverage and dairy products handling and processing equipment, and other institutional and industrial applications meeting the requirements of subsection (e) of this section, and designed specifically for cleaning dishes washed in dishwashers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, after 180 days after March 25, 1986, no cleaning agent for use in dishwashers may be used, sold, or furnished in the District of Columbia if it contains elemental phosphorus exceeding 0.5% by weight.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A manufacturer may state on packages containing the cleaning agent which the manufacturer has produced either of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After the Mayor issues rules for applying for and receiving an exemption from the obligations in subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the Mayor may permit the use of cleaning agents that do not comply with subsection (a) or (b) under the following circumstances:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-107_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall report annually, in writing, to the Council on March 1 the reasons for and the number of exemptions granted pursuant to this section and shall identify each person or organization granted an exemption by name and address.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
