<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1061"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1061/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1061">
        <akn:num>8-1061</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Solid Waste Transfer Facility Site Selection Advisory Panel established.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established the Solid Waste Transfer Facility Site Selection Advisory Panel (“Panel”) with the purpose of preparing comprehensive recommendations to the Council that identify tracts of land suitable for solid waste transfer operations within appropriately zoned sections of the District that safeguard the health, safety and welfare of residents and businesses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall submit its recommendations in a report, which shall include a map that identifies potential sites for the location of solid waste facilities, within 6 months of the Panel’s first meeting.  The Panel shall rate each site according to its suitability for the purpose of solid waste transfer and shall consider the proximity of other potential sites in rating each site.  The potential sites the Panel identifies shall comply with all siting requirements of this chapter, shall not be inconsistent with the Comprehensive Plan and shall not increase or compound existing detrimental environmental impacts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to identifying potential sites and rating these sites, the Panel shall study and report on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel is authorized to seek the advice of experts with knowledge of the following areas of concern:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall consult with District agencies with solid waste management expertise, including, but not limited to, the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, the Department of Public Works and the Department of Health.  The Panel shall also consult with the Washington Area Council of Governments and its staff to inform the Panel of regional considerations in solid waste management.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall consult with the National Environmental Justice Advisory Council, which is a federal advisory committee established to provide independent judgment to the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency on environmental issues and which is studying or will study the health and environmental impacts of municipal waste transfer operations on minority and disadvantaged communities, including the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1061_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 45 days of its first meeting, the Panel shall provide notice of and hold a public meeting to receive testimony from citizens in respect to the operation of solid waste facilities in the District of Columbia, and shall hold an additional public meeting to present the Panel’s findings and a draft report to the community for comment 20 days prior to submitting to the Council the report required by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
