<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-103.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-103.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_103_06">
        <akn:num>8-103.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certain discharges permitted; terms of permit; additional enforcement procedures; effect of federal permit; public hearing on permit; special requirements for treatment facilities; permits for industrial discharges; certain discharges from watercraft prohibited.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except that no one may discharge into a sewer corrosive, flammable, or explosive material, or material that may adversely affect the structure of a sewer line, the Mayor may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor permits any discharge under subsection (a)(1) of this section, then the Mayor shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before any permit is issued under subsection (a)(1), (3), or (4) of this section, or any federal permit is certified under subsection (j) of this section, the Mayor may require the person seeking the permit or certification to perform studies to ensure conformance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the enforcement procedures otherwise provided for in this subchapter, if any person violates a permit condition, discharges without a permit, or submits a fraudulent report to the Mayor, the Mayor may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Those persons having a permit which has been issued by the United States Environmental Protection Agency prior to March 16, 1985, shall be exempted from the requirement for obtaining a permit under the provisions of this subchapter until the expiration date of the United States Environmental Protection Agency permit, at which time a permit from the District will be required. However, the conditions of the permit issued by the United States shall continue in force until the effective date of a permit issued by the Mayor if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before issuing any permit, the Mayor shall provide notice of the intent to issue the permit and the opportunity for a public hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before a federal permit is issued, the Mayor shall certify whether the permit conforms with this subchapter, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and the related regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may issue permits for industrial discharges to sanitary sewers flowing to municipal treatment facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-103_06_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The discharge of sanitary sewage, wash or process water, oil laden bilge water, refuse, or litter from watercraft is prohibited.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
