<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-102.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-102.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_102_07">
        <akn:num>8-102.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Issuance of Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-102_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue reflectorized motor vehicle identification tags of a design to enhance public awareness of the District of Columbia’s efforts to restore and protect the Anacostia River and these identification tags may be called Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates. These identification tags shall retain and display the “TAXATION WITHOUT REPRESENTATION” slogan of the current District of Columbia motor vehicle identification tags.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-102_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the annual registration fee required by § 50-1501.03(a), a one-time fee of $25 shall be charged each time new Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates are issued. There shall also be a $20 renewal fee for Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates, which fee shall be charged biennially.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-102_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall recover the cost of producing and issuing the Anacostia River Commemorative License Plates from the proceeds collected from the one-time $25 fee and the biennial $20 renewal fee established under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-102_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The balance shall be paid into the Anacostia River Clean Up and Protection Fund established by § 8-102.05(a) and used for the purposes described therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-102_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall implement this section within 180 days after September 23, 2009. If an extension is necessary, the Mayor shall notify the Council prior to the implementation date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
