<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1051"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1051/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1051">
        <akn:num>8-1051</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Composting facility” means any location or structure which uses a microbial process to convert organic material, including wood, paper, mulch, or yard or food waste into a soil amendment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Construction and demolition wastes” means the waste building materials and rubble resulting from construction, remodeling, repair, and demolition operation on houses, commercial buildings, pavements, and other structures.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Existing solid waste facility” means a solid waste facility in construction, including site preparation, or operating on March 23, 1995.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Final disposal” means depositing or placing solid waste for its final location.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intermediate materials recycling facility” means a fully enclosed structure used for the receipt, separation, storage, conversion, baling, briquetting, crushing, compacting, grinding, shredding, or processing of paper, metal, glass, plastics, tires, bulk waste, or other nonbiodegradable recyclable materials for the purpose of reutilization of such materials. The term “intermediate materials recycling facility” shall not include a facility used for the storage or processing of biodegradable materials, construction and demolition wastes, white goods, and hazardous substances, as defined in § 8-109.02(4), and the rules and regulations pursuant thereto.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Open solid waste facility” means any privately owned or operated solid waste disposal or solid waste handling facility where solid waste is stored or processed outside of a fully enclosed building or structure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, trust, association, firm, joint stock company, organization, commission, or any other private entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Recyclable material” means material which would otherwise become solid waste, and that may be collected, separated, or processed and returned to the economic mainstream as a raw material or product.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residue” means the solid waste, as measured by weight, requiring disposal after recyclable material is removed during or after processing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Solid waste” means garbage, refuse, construction and demolition waste or any other waste product, including solid, liquid, semisolid, or contained gaseous material, resulting from commercial, industrial, or government operation, or residential or community activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Solid waste disposal facility” means any facility where solid waste is discharged, deposited, tipped, dumped, or placed for final disposal, including an incinerator, waste-to-energy facility, rubble fill, or landfill.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Solid waste facility” means any privately owned or operated solid waste disposal facility or solid waste handling facility, which accepts solid waste that is not the incidental by-product of the facility’s manufacturing or operational processes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Solid waste handling facility” means any facility where solid waste temporarily is deposited, or placed for processing, at any time prior to its final disposal at a solid waste disposal facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Source separated” means the end result when recyclable material is separated from solid waste at its point of origin for separate collection and processing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Substantially alter” means to make any physical modification to a solid waste facility which increases or decreases the solid waste facility’s maximum annual capacity, by more than 10% per year, as indicated in the solid waste facility’s solid waste facility permit, or in any way alters or modifies the method by which the waste is processed or disposed, or which increases the amount of any air pollutant not previously emitted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Abate” means to control disease vectors including rats and other vermin.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Arterial road” means a traffic route of 4 or more lanes with traffic controlled by traffic signal lights.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Best Available Control Technology” or “BACT” means measures, processes, methods, systems, or techniques to contain the emission of odors and air and liquid pollutants through procedures including enclosing processes or systems to eliminate emissions, and by collecting, capturing or treating pollutants before release from a process, stack, storage or fugitive emissions point.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Facility” means any building, structure, or portion of a site where solid waste is handled or stored.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hazardous waste” means any waste defined as hazardous in § 8-1302(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Infectious waste” shall include, but is not limited to, the following types of solid waste:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Operations area” means any area where solid waste handling or related activities including storage, heavy equipment operations, truck idling, covering, uncovering, cleaning, queuing or parking occurs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Radioactive hazardous waste” means any waste which contains or is contaminated with low level radioactive waste material emitting primarily gamma or beta radiation registering above normal background levels.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential street” means any street on which 50% or more of the street frontage is used for residential purposes, for residential and non-business property, or is zoned as residential property. The designation of a street as a residential street shall be determined block-by-block.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_25">
      <akn:num>(25)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Site” means the total area of any lot or lots that are partially or completely occupied by a solid waste handling facility or its operations area or any lot or lots owned or leased by the owner or operator of a solid waste handling facility that are adjacent to a lot or lots that are partially or completely devoted to solid waste handling operations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1051_26">
      <akn:num>(26)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tracking” means the deposit of a trail of liquid, liquid waste, muck, dust or of any garbage on public space by vehicles entering and exiting solid waste facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
