<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1302"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1302/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1302">
        <akn:num>8-1302</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “disposal” means the discharge, deposit, injection, dumping, spilling, leaking, or placing of any hazardous waste into or on any land or water so that such hazardous waste or any constituent thereof may enter the environment, be emitted into the air, or discharged into any waters, including ground waters.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “guarantor” means any person, other than the owner or operator, who provides evidence of financial responsibility for an owner or operator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “hazardous waste” means any waste or combination of wastes of a solid, liquid, contained gaseous, or semisolid form which, because of its quantity, concentration, or physical, chemical, or infectious characteristics, as established by the Mayor, may: (1) cause, or significantly contribute to an increase in mortality or an increase in serious irreversible, or incapacitating reversible, illness; or (2) pose a substantial present or potential hazard to human health or the environment when improperly treated, stored, transported, or disposed of, or otherwise managed. Such wastes include, but are not limited to, those which are toxic, carcinogenic, flammable, irritants, strong sensitizers, or which generate pressure through decomposition, heat or other means, as well as containers and receptacles previously used in the transportation, storage, use or application of the substances described as a hazardous waste.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “generation” means the act or process of producing hazardous waste.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_3A">
      <akn:num>(3A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “generator” means any person by site whose act or process produces hazardous waste or whose act first causes a hazardous waste to be subject to regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_3B">
      <akn:num>(3B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “manifest” means the form used for identifying the quantity, composition, and the origin, routing and destination of hazardous waste during its transportation from the point of generation to the point of disposal, treatment, or storage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his or her designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation (including a government corporation), trust, association, firm, joint-stock company, organization, commission, the District or federal government, or other entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_5A">
      <akn:num>(5A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “person responsible” means a person who is or has been the generator of hazardous waste, the owner or operator of a site that contains or a vehicle that transports hazardous waste, or a person who by contract, agreement, or otherwise arranges or has arranged for disposal or treatment of hazardous waste.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_5B">
      <akn:num>(5B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “storage” means containment in such a manner as not to constitute disposal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “toxic chemical” means a chemical or chemical category listed in 40 C.F.R. 372.65.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “transport” means the movement from the point of generation to any intermediate site, and finally to the point of ultimate storage or disposal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “treatment” means any method, technique, or process, including neutralization, designed to change the physical, chemical, or biological character or composition of a hazardous waste so as to neutralize or as to render it nonhazardous, safer for transport, amenable for recovery or storage, or reduced in volume.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1302_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “treatment facility” means a location for treatment, including an incinerator or a facility where generation has occurred.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
