<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-152.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-152.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_152_05">
        <akn:num>8-152.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Stormwater Advisory Panel.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established within the District Department of the Environment a Stormwater Advisory Panel (“Panel”), pursuant to § 8-151.03(b)(2). The Panel shall coordinate the responsibilities of the agencies and DC WASA, and shall prepare comprehensive recommendations to the Council that identify the best means by which the District can meet or exceed all present and future federal regulatory and permit requirements, pertaining to the discharge of stormwater into receiving waters.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall be comprised of the executive officers with responsibilities pursuant to the MS4 Permit, with oversight responsibility for the administrative and financial aspects of stormwater management, or that engage in activities that impact the District’s stormwater discharge:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall hold its first meeting within 90 days of March 25, 2009. The Panel shall hold at least one public hearing to receive testimony from citizens with respect to the issues stated in subsection (e)(1) and (2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall meet at least 2 times each year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Panel shall provide its recommendations in the annual report required to be submitted to EPA Region III under the MS4 Permit. The report shall make specific findings on:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within one year of March 25, 2009, the Panel shall provide to the Council and the Mayor a study of the needs for achieving water quality compliance from the District’s stormwater runoff.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Panel members shall ensure that their agencies participate in the Environmental Management System to track compliance with the District’s MS4 Permit obligations and other stormwater management responsibilities required to reduce pollution to the District’s waters.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-152_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days after March 25, 2009, the Panel shall establish a Technical Working Group (“TWG”) of agency technical staff.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
