<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1773.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1773.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1773_01">
        <akn:num>8-1773.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commission” means the Public Service Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District Department of the Environment,” “DDOE,” or “Energy Office” means the District Department of the Environment Energy Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Electric company” shall have the same meaning as in § 34-207.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Energy Assistance Trust Fund” or “EATF” means the Energy Assistance Trust Fund established under § 8-1774.11.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_4A">
      <akn:num>(4A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“ENERGY STAR Portfolio Manager” means the ENERGY STAR Portfolio Manager tool developed by the Environmental Protection Agency, or any alternative approved by the Mayor that rates the performance of a qualifying building, relative to similar buildings nationwide, accounting for the impacts of year-to-year weather variations, building size, location, and several operating characteristics, using the Environmental Protection Agency’s national energy performance rating system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Existing electricity programs” means those programs operated by the District Department of the Environment under the names “Weatherization Plus,” “Low Income Appliance Replacement Program,” and “Weatherization and Rehabilitation.”</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Existing low-income program” means the program operated under the name “LIHEAP Expansion and Energy Education”.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Existing natural gas programs” means those programs proposed or operated by the District Department of the Environment under the names “Heating System Repair, Replacement, and Tune-Up Program,” “Residential Weatherization and Efficiency Program,” “Energy Awareness Program”. and “Saving Energy in D.C. Schools.”</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fiscal Agent” means the Office of the Chief Financial Officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Gas company” shall have the same meaning as in § 34-209.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Green-collar jobs” means jobs in the environmental sector of the economy which jobs may involve the implementation of environmentally-conscious design, policy, or technology.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“OIML” means the International Association of Legal Metrology.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Request for Proposals” or “RFP” means the request for proposals prepared by the District Department of the Environment for the SEU.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential Aid Discount” means the utility discount program offered by the electric company to low-income electricity customers in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential Essential Service” means the utility discount program offered by the gas company to low-income natural gas customers in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Solar thermal systems” means systems which utilize the sun’s radiation to efficiently heat fluids or air.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“SRCC” means the Solar Rating and Certification Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Substantial improvement” has the same meaning as in section 202 of Title 12J of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (12J DCMR § 202).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sustainable Energy Trust Fund” or “SETF” means the Sustainable Energy Trust Fund established under § 8-1774.10.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sustainable Energy Utility” or “SEU” means the private contractor selected to develop, coordinate, and provide programs for the purpose of promoting the sustainable use of energy in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Sustainable Energy Utility Advisory Board”, “Advisory Board”, or “Board” means the board established under § 8-1774.03 that advises the DDOE on the procurement of the contract with the SEU and monitors the progress of the SEU under its contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Temporary electricity programs” means those programs operated by the District Department of the Environment under the names “Affordable Housing Energy Efficient Rebate Program”, “Weatherization Rehabilitation Asset Partnership”, and “Home Energy Rating System”.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1773_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Utility or energy company” means a company distributing, supplying, or transmitting electricity or natural gas in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
