<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1778_02">
        <akn:num>8-1778.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Declaration of public purpose.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Energy conservation efforts, including the promotion of Energy Efficiency Improvements to residential, commercial, and other real property, are necessary to address the issue of global climate change and to reduce the consumers’ energy costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The upfront cost of making residential, commercial, or other real property more energy efficient prevents many property owners from making Energy Efficient Improvements. To make Energy Efficient Improvements more accessible and to promote the installation of those improvements, it is necessary to authorize a procedure to provide funds for the initial cost of installing Energy Efficiency Improvements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council declares that a public purpose will be served by a voluntary assessment program that provides the authority and the means to provide funds for the initial installation of Energy Efficiency Improvements that are permanently attached to residential, commercial, industrial, or other real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Section 1-204.90 provides that the Council may, by act, authorize the issuance of District bonds to borrow money to finance, refinance, or reimburse, and to assist in the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of, the cost of capital projects or undertakings that will contribute to the health, welfare, or safety of residents of the District as determined by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council finds that authorization, issuance, sale, and delivery of bonds for the payment of costs of a program to provide funds for the initial installation of Energy Efficiency Improvements that are permanently attached to residential, commercial, or other real property will contribute to the health, welfare, and safety of residents of the District, are in the public interest, and will accomplish the purposes and intent of § 1-204.90.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
