<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1772.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1772.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1772_03">
        <akn:num>8-1772.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1772_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor determines that a violation of this chapter has occurred, the person in violation shall be subject to the penalties set forth in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1772_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall impose a penalty on retail establishments in violation of this chapter, which shall be a class 4 infraction under the schedule of fines in Chapter 32 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (16 DCMR § 3200 et seq.)</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1772_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Retail establishments shall not be fined more than once in a 24-hour period for a violation of § 8-1772.02.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1772_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If payment of any amounts due under this section is not received by or before the due date, a penalty shall be added as provided by the Mayor through rulemaking.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1772_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A violation of this chapter shall be a civil infraction for purposes of Chapter 18 of Title 2 [§ 2-1801.01 et seq.] (“Civil Infractions Act”). Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as sanctions for an infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or the rules issued under authority of this chapter, pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act. Adjudication of infractions shall be pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1772_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The enforcement of this chapter shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of the Environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
