<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1778_01">
        <akn:num>8-1778.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Administrator” means the person retained pursuant to the authority granted in § 8-1778.45 to administer the Energy Efficiency Loan program authorized by subchapter III of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Authorized Delegate” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bond Counsel” means a firm or firms of attorneys designated as bond counsel from time to time by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bonds” means the District of Columbia revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, and other obligations), in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Certification Standard” means a certification or accreditation standard for building energy retrofit installation, such as those provided by the Building Performance Institute, the Residential Energy Services Network, or a nationally recognized program approved by the United States Department of Energy or the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chief Financial Officer” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Closing Documents” means all documents and agreements, other than Financing Documents, that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Debt Service” means payment of principal, premium, if any, and interest on the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Energy Efficiency Audit” means a formal evaluation by a certified contractor of the energy consumption of a residential, commercial, or other building for the purpose of identifying methods of improving energy efficiency and reducing energy waste.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Energy Efficiency Improvement” means an installation or modification that is designed to reduce energy or water utility costs of residential, commercial, or other building types. The term “Energy Efficiency Improvement” includes:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Energy Efficiency Loan” means a loan to a property owner for the purpose of installing one of more Energy Efficiency Improvements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_11A">
      <akn:num>(11A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Energy Efficiency Loan Agreement” means a loan or other agreement to make, document, or implement an Energy Efficiency Loan entered into pursuant to § 8-1778.41(c).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financing Documents” means the documents, other than Closing Documents, that relate to the financing or refinancing of transactions to be effected through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the bonds, including any required collection agreement, offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home Rule Act” means Chapter 2 of Title 1 [§ 1-201.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Indenture” means the trust indentures, including a master trust indenture and any supplemental trust indenture, pursuant to which one or more series of the bonds are issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_14A">
      <akn:num>(14A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuance Costs” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_14B">
      <akn:num>(14B)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Private Lending Institution” means a non-government business organization that makes an Energy Efficiency Loan and is approved by the Mayor to participate in the Energy Efficiency Loan program pursuant to §§ 8-1778.31 and 8-1778.48.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Property owner” means an owner of real property in the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualified Apprenticeship Program” means an apprenticeship program registered with the District of Columbia Apprenticeship Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Quality Assurance Program” means a program that establishes energy benchmarks, monitors and verifies the quality of Energy Efficiency Improvements, and measures actual energy savings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Special Assessment” means the special assessment authorized by subchapter IX of Chapter 8 of Title 47 [§ 47-895.31 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Trustee” means the trustee under the indenture.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
