<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.21"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.21/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1778_21">
        <akn:num>8-1778.21</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Special Energy Assessment Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_21_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_21_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Receipt of the principal and interest portion of the Special Assessment and all amounts deposited in each Special Energy Assessment Bond Debt Service Account, plus all investments or earnings on those amounts, shall be irrevocably dedicated and pledged to the payment of the principal of, and interest on, the applicable bonds as provided in this chapter. Any escrow or other agreement entered into by the District providing for holding funds for the benefit of the holders of the bonds shall be maintained as long as any of the bonds are outstanding under the applicable Financing Documents. The administrative costs portion of the Special Assessment deposited in the Special Energy Assessment Program Administrative Account, plus all investments or earnings on those amounts, shall be used only for the payment of the costs of administering the Energy Efficiency Loan program authorized by subchapter III of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_21_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, at the end of any fiscal year of the District following the issuance of bonds authorized by this chapter, the value of cash and investments in a Special Energy Assessment Bond Debt Service Account exceeds the amount of all payments authorized by this chapter and the Financing Documents applicable to that series of bonds, including required deposits into reserve funds, amounts to be set aside for additional series of bonds issued under this chapter, and any coverage requirements associated with the sale of the bonds, during the upcoming fiscal year, the excess shall be transferred to the General Fund of the District of Columbia, unless the District elects to use the excess to redeem that series of bonds prior to maturity. Amounts deposited in the Special Energy Assessment Program Administrative Account shall remain in, and shall be used for the purposes of, that account.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_21_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
