<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.25"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.25/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1778_25">
        <akn:num>8-1778.25</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sale of the bonds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_25_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds of any series may be sold at negotiated or competitive sale at, above, or below par, to one or more persons or entities, and upon terms that the Mayor considers to be in the best interests of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_25_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or an Authorized Delegate may execute, in connection with each sale of the bonds, offering documents on behalf of the District, may deem final any such offering document on behalf of the District for purposes of compliance with federal laws and regulations governing such matters, and may authorize the distribution of the documents in connection with the sale of the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_25_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to deliver the executed and sealed bonds, on behalf of the District, for authentication, and, after the bonds have been authenticated, to deliver the bonds to the original purchasers of the bonds upon payment of the purchase price.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_25_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall not be issued until the Mayor receives an approving opinion from Bond Counsel as to the validity of the bonds of such series and, if the interest on the bonds is expected to be exempt from federal income taxation, the treatment of the interest on the bonds for the purposes of federal income taxation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_25_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Chapter 3A of Title 2 [ยง 2-351.01 et seq.], and subchapter III-A of Chapter 3 of Title 47 [ยง 47-351.01 et seq.] shall not apply to a contract that the Mayor may from time to time enter into or the Mayor may determine to be necessary or appropriate, for purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
