<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.23"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1778.23/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1778_23">
        <akn:num>8-1778.23</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payment and security.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_23_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as may be otherwise provided in this chapter, Debt Service on each series of bonds shall be payable solely and only from proceeds received from the sale of that series of bonds, income realized from the temporary investment of those proceeds, Special Assessment revenues allocated to the applicable Special Energy Assessment Bond Debt Service Account, amounts received from prepayments of any loans made pursuant to this chapter, income realized from the temporary investment of those Special Assessment revenues prior to payment to the bond holders, and other moneys that, as provided in the Financing Documents, may be made available to the District for payment of the bonds from sources other than the District, all as provided for in the Financing Documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_23_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payment of the bonds shall be secured as provided in the Financing Documents and by an assignment by the District for the benefit of the bondholders of certain of its rights under the Financing Documents and Closing Documents to the trustee for the bonds pursuant to the Financing Documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1778_23_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The trustee is authorized to deposit, invest, and disburse the proceeds received from the sale of the bonds pursuant to the Financing Documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
