<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1808"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-1808/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_1808">
        <akn:num>8-1808</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Prohibited conduct.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No owner of an animal shall allow the animal to go at large.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall knowingly and falsely deny ownership of any animal.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall remove the license of a dog without the permission of its owner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall change the natural color of a baby chicken, duckling, other fowl or rabbit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No dog shall be permitted on any school ground when school is in session or on any public recreation area, other than a dog park, unless the dog is leashed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall sell or offer for sale a baby chicken, duckling, other fowl, or rabbit that has had its natural color changed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall sell or offer for sale a rabbit under the age of 16 weeks or a chick or duck under the age of 8 weeks except for agricultural or scientific purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may sponsor, promote, train an animal to participate in, contribute to the involvement of an animal in, or attend as a spectator any activity or event in which any animal engages in unnatural behavior, is wrestled or fought, mentally or physically harassed, or displayed in such a way that the animal is struck, abused, or mentally or physically stressed or traumatized, or is induced, goaded or encouraged to perform or react through the use of chemical, mechanical, electrical, or manual devices in a manner that will cause, or is likely to cause, physical or other injury or suffering. This prohibition applies to any event or activity at a public or private facility or property and is applicable regardless of the purpose of the event or activity and regardless of whether a fee is charged to spectators.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person who has control or custody of a dog shall, direct, encourage, cause, allow or otherwise aid or assist that dog to threaten, charge, bite, or attack a person or other animal, except that a person may keep a properly trained dog on private property to defend it and its occupants from intruders, and may order a dog to defend a person under attack. This section shall not apply to dogs who work for the Metropolitan Police Department or any other law enforcement agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-1808_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person may display, exhibit, or otherwise move animals in the District of Columbia as part of a circus, carnival, or other special performance or event, without first obtaining a permit, issued by the Mayor, that governs the care and management of the animals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
