<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-2001"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-2001/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_2001">
        <akn:num>8-2001</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Animal control officer” means any employee or legally authorized agent of the District of Columbia (“District”) Animal Care and Control Agency as provided in § 8-1802.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Carriage” means a device by which a person is transported or in which a person rides, for hire, and that is designed to be pulled or drawn by a horse in the horse-drawn carriage trade. The term “carriage” includes a wagon, cart, vehicle, or similar transportation device.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Custodian” means a person who has the immediate possession, bailment, custody, use, or control of a horse. For the purposes of this chapter, the term “custodian” includes a driver.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drive” means the process of operating, transporting, driving, pulling, or hauling a horse-drawn carriage.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Driver” means a person licensed to drive, steer, transport, or operate a carriage or horse used in the horse-drawn carriage trade.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Driver’s license” means a valid document issued by the Mayor to operate a motor vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Horse” means a large solid-hoofed herbivorous domesticated mammal or similar animal that belongs to the Equus caballus family and weighs at least 1,100 pounds, and that is used for the purpose of driving, pulling, or hauling a carriage, or for the purposes of a performance. For the purposes of this chapter, the term “horse” shall not include any animal owned by the District government or the United States government that is used solely for law enforcement purposes, or any animal in the custody of the National Zoological Park.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Horse-drawn carriage trade” means a person or business that operates an enterprise, for hire, or as a contractual service, for the purpose of conveying persons or goods through the use of a horse to pull or haul a wagon, cart, carriage, vehicle, or similar device along the streets and byways in the District. The term “horse-drawn carriage trade” shall not include the use of a horse in a parade or in a funeral for which a permit is issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Identification card” means a document devised, supplied, and certified by the Mayor of the District, and signed and dated by a licensed veterinarian which shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“License” means a valid permit or other document issued by the Mayor to a person or business for the purpose of operating a horse-drawn carriage trade enterprise.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Licensed veterinarian” means a person who is licensed to practice veterinary medicine.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Operator” means the proprietor or the agent of a proprietor of a horse-drawn carriage trade enterprise or a stable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means a person who is vested with the ownership, control, or title of a horse-drawn carriage trade, horse, or stable.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, firm, partnership, association, or group or combination acting in concert, whether as a principal, employer, employee, agent, servant, trustee, fiduciary, receiver, or any other type of legal or personal representative.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Police officer” means a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2001_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Stable” means a barn, establishment, or similar appropriate facility where a horse is permanently or temporarily boarded, housed, or maintained.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
