<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-2202"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-2202/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_2202">
        <akn:num>8-2202</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Wildlife control service providers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A wildlife control services provider shall recommend and employ nonlethal means in preference to lethal means for the control of problem wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All traps and exclusion devices used by a wildlife control services provider shall be labeled with the name, address, and phone number of the wildlife control service provider.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Traps used by a wildlife control services provider shall be set in a manner designed to catch the target animal and in the manner likely to avoid capture of and harm to non-target animals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wildlife shall be captured, handled, and, when permissible, transported, in a manner to ensure against causing unnecessary discomfort, behavioral stress, or physical harm to the animal, including providing protections against weather extremes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All traps shall be checked by the wildlife control services provider in a timely and reasonable manner, but no more than 24 hours after being set, and at least once every 24 hours thereafter; provided, that traps shall be checked more frequently if environmental conditions require.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Captured non-target wildlife shall be released immediately at the site of capture. Captured non-target wildlife that pose an unreasonable risk to the health and safety to persons or domestic animals or that are injured and need veterinary care and rehabilitation shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Captured target wildlife shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wildlife expressing symptoms of disease shall be taken to a licensed wildlife rehabilitator or surrendered to the Animal Care and Control Agency for evaluation and assessment. Outbreaks or potential widespread occurrence of suspect diseases, such as avian botulism, shall be reported to the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A wildlife control services provider shall make every reasonable effort to preserve family units using humane eviction or displacement and reunion strategies and shall not knowingly abandon dependent young wildlife in a structure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Wildlife shall not be kept in captivity longer than 36 hours unless specifically authorized by the Department or unless reunion attempts are being employed. In the case of attempted reunion, a wildlife control services provider may hold wildlife in captivity for up to 72 hours.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Captured wildlife shall be transported in covered, secure containers in such a way as to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A wildlife control services provider shall not use sticky or glue traps to control any wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A wildlife control services provider shall not use leghold and other body-gripping traps, body-crushing traps, snares, or harpoon-type traps to control any wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A wildlife control services provider shall kill wildlife only by methods that conform to the most recently published Report of the American Veterinary Medical Association Panel on Euthanasia, unless otherwise prohibited by this chapter or rules promulgated by the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-2202_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A wildlife control services provider shall use the available method of euthanasia that is the quickest, least stressful, and least painful to the animal under the circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
