<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-231.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-231.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_231_03">
        <akn:num>8-231.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Risk reduction of lead-based paint hazards.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a child under age 6 with an elevated blood lead level resides in, or regularly visits a dwelling unit or child-occupied facility in the District, or upon reasonable belief that any other property located in the District may have contributed to a child’s lead exposure, the Mayor shall conduct a risk assessment of the appropriate properties, and the owner, occupant or owner’s agent shall cooperate with and shall not impede the Mayor’s conduct of such assessment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon reasonable belief, which may be based upon a request by a tenant or may be based on other information, that there is risk of a lead-based paint hazard in a dwelling unit, accessible common area, or child-occupied facility constructed before 1978, the Mayor shall take action, which may include a risk assessment, clearance examination, or visual examination of the dwelling unit, accessible common area, or child-occupied facility, and provide a report to the owner and the tenant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever action taken by the Mayor pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of this section identifies lead-based paint hazards, the Mayor shall determine the actions necessary to eliminate the lead-based paint hazards at the property, including abatement or interim controls, and may order the property owner to perform any action considered necessary by the Mayor to protect the health and safety of the occupants of the property, including relocation in accordance with subsection (d)(1)(D) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed to interfere with tenants’ rights under other District law. If the owner intends to substantially rehabilitate, demolish, or discontinue any housing accommodation to comply with the requirements of this subchapter, the procedures set forth in §§ 42-3505.01 and 42-3507.01 shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever presumed lead-based paint is identified in an uncontained and non-intact condition, the Mayor shall be authorized to issue a Notice of Violation. A Notice of Violation shall include an order to repair non-intact presumed lead-based paint and its underlying cause using lead-safe work practices, and shall require production of a clearance report. Presumed lead-based paint may be rebutted by production of a lead-based paint inspection report from an inspector or risk assessor, affirming that such paint is not lead-based.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
