<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-231.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-231.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_231_04">
        <akn:num>8-231.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Disclosure and risk reduction requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a dwelling unit constructed before 1978, which unit will be occupied or regularly visited by a person at risk, shall provide to the tenant an accurately and fully completed lead disclosure form and a clearance report issued within the previous 12 months. The disclosures required by this subsection shall be disclosed before the tenant is obligated under any contract to lease the dwelling unit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a tenant of a dwelling unit constructed before 1978, in which unit a person at risk resides or which unit a person at risk regularly visits, notifies the owner of the property in writing that a person at risk resides in or regularly visits the dwelling unit, the owner of the dwelling unit shall provide to the tenant within 30 days a clearance report issued within the previous 12 months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Instead of providing the disclosure form and clearance report required by this section, an owner may provide:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a dwelling unit shall provide notice to its tenants of their rights under this subchapter on a form provided by the Mayor whenever the tenant executes or renews a lease for the unit and whenever the owner provides notice of a rent increase.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the owner of a dwelling unit learns of the presence of lead-based paint in a dwelling unit, the owner shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Twelve months after the effective date of rules implementing this subchapter, the Mayor shall submit a report on the status of the implementation of this section. The report shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
