<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-231.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-231.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_231_10">
        <akn:num>8-231.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certification requirements for individuals and business entities conducting lead-based paint activities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual or business entity shall obtain the appropriate certification from the Mayor by demonstrating compliance with subsections (b) or (c) of this section, as applicable, prior to conducting a lead-based paint activity, clearance examination, or renovation in any structure, built before 1978.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual risk assessor, inspector, dust sampling technician, renovator, and supervisor shall submit proof to the Mayor that the individual has passed an examination required by the Mayor, or EPA-approved state program, for that discipline, and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A business entity shall demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Mayor that all its employees and subcontractors conducting a lead-based paint activity, clearance examination, or renovation are:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may establish additional criteria and procedures for certification by rule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Certifications for lead-based paint activities shall expire 24 months from the date of issuance, or when otherwise determined by the Mayor. To maintain certifications for dust sampling technicians, individuals shall complete a refresher course within 5 years from the date of initial issuance of the certification.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Individuals and business entities seeking certification and certification renewal in the District shall pay a reasonable fee set by the Mayor. The Mayor, by rulemaking, may revise the certification and certification renewal fees as necessary to cover the administrative costs associated with the issuance of certificates and inspection of lead-based paint activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-231_10_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except with regard to persons conducting lead-based paint activities pursuant to ยง 8-231.03, who must always comply with the provisions of this section, exceptions to this section are limited to the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
