<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-411"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-411/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_411">
        <akn:num>8-411</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administration and enforcement; adoption of regulations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized, after a public hearing following due notice, to declare any insect, rodent, nematode, fungus, weed, or any other form of terrestrial or aquatic plant or animal life or virus, bacteria, or other microorganism (except viruses, bacteria, or other microorganism on or in living man or other living animals) which is injurious to the environment or the health of man or other animals to be a pest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to prescribe pesticides and equipment to be used; restrict or prohibit the use of such materials to the extent necessary to protect the public health and safety; and to take such other action as he may deem necessary to prevent any unreasonable risk to man or the environment, taking into account the economic, social, and environmental costs and benefits of the use of any pesticide.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When the Mayor has reasonable cause to believe a pesticide or device is being distributed, stored, transported, offered for sale, or used in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, or any of the regulations prescribed under the authority of this chapter, he may issue a written “stop sale, use, or removal” order to the owner or custodian of any such pesticide or device, and after receipt of such order no person shall sell, use, or remove the pesticide or device described in the order except in accordance with the provisions of the order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any pesticide or device that is being transported, or having been transported is sold or offered for sale in the District, or is imported from a foreign country, in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, may be proceeded against in any court of competent jurisdiction by a process in rem for condemnation if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the pesticide or device is condemned, it shall, after entry of the decree, be disposed of by destruction or sale as the court may direct, and the proceeds, if sold, less the court costs, shall be paid into the District Treasury and credited to the general fund; provided, that the pesticide or device shall not be sold contrary to the provisions of this chapter, the FIFRA, or the laws of the jurisdiction in which it is sold; provided further, that upon payment of the costs of the condemnation proceedings and the execution and delivery of a good and sufficient bond conditioned upon assurances that the pesticide shall not be sold or otherwise disposed of contrary to the provisions of this subchapter, the FIFRA, or the laws of any jurisdiction in which it is sold, the court may direct that such pesticide or device be delivered to the owner thereof. The proceedings of such condemnation cases shall conform, as near as may be to the proceedings used for the condemnation of insanitary buildings under § 6-903.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a decree of condemnation is entered against the pesticide or device, court costs and fees, storage, and other proper expenses shall be awarded against the person, if any, intervening as claimant of the pesticide or device.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as requiring the District to prosecute or institute other proceedings for minor violations of the chapter whenever the Mayor believes that the public interest will be best served by a suitable notice in writing to the alleged violator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may bring an action to enjoin the violation or threatened violation of any provision of this chapter or any regulation made pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-411_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to comply with section 4 of the FIFRA [7 U.S.C. § 136b], the Mayor is authorized to make such reports to the Environmental Protection Agency in the form and containing the information as the Administrator may from time to time require.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
