<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-431"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-431/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_431">
        <akn:num>8-431</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Agriculture” means land whose primary purpose and use is to raise crops.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Child-occupied facility” means a building or portion of a building which, as part of its function, receives children under the age of 6 years on a regular basis and is required to obtain a certificate of occupancy as a precondition to performing that function. The term “child-occupied facility” includes day care centers, nurseries, pre-school centers, kindergarten classrooms, child development centers, child development homes, child development facilities, child-placing agencies, infant care centers, and similar entities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Department” means the District Department of the Environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District property” means buildings or land owned, leased, or otherwise occupied by the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District restricted use” means a pesticide identified by the Department as requiring additional restrictions for use to prevent a hazard to human health, the environment, or property as set forth in § 8-432.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“FIFRA” means the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, approved June 23, 1947 (61 Stat. 163; 7 U.S.C. § 136 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Forestry” means trees on land that is at least one acre in size and at least 10% occupied by forest trees of any size or formerly having had such tree cover and not currently developed for non-forest use.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Integrated pest management” or “IPM” means an effective and environmentally sensitive approach to pest management that relies on a combination of common-sense practices. IPM programs use current, comprehensive information on the life cycles of pests and their interaction with the environment. This information, in combination with available pest control methods, is used to manage pest damage economically, and with a strong preference for examining a range of cultural, mechanical, biological, and chemical practices and selecting a method presenting the least possible hazard to people, property, and the environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Minimum risk” means a pesticide registered with the Department, but exempt from federal registration under section 25(b) of the FIFRA [7 U.S.C. § 136w].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Non-essential” means a pesticide that is non-critical to managing pests that threaten health, property, or the environment in the District as set forth in § 8-432.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pest” has the same meaning as provided in section 2299 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2299).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pest management” means the control of plants, insects, herbs, or rodents with chemical agents deployed as pesticides.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pesticide” has the same meaning as provided in section 2299 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2299); provided, that the definition shall not include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pesticide application” means the spraying, laying, injecting, delivering, or other action whereby plants, insects, herbs, or other pests are controlled by a registered pesticide or a chemical agent that includes a registered pesticide.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pesticide applicator” has the same meaning as provided in section 2299 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2299).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pesticide operator” has the same meaning as provided in section 2299 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2299).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Pesticide registration fee” means the fee set for product registration by section 2506 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2506).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reduced risk” has the same meaning as provided in section 2209 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 2209).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Restricted use” means any pesticide or pesticide use classified as restricted through the process outlined by the Administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency in Subpart I of Part 152 of Subchapter E of Chapter 1 of Title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations (40 C.F.R. § 152.160 et seq.), or a pesticide so designated by the Department by the process described in § 8-432.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“School” means a public or private facility whose primary purpose is to provide K-12 educational services and includes adjacent or contiguous recreation centers or athletic fields owned or maintained by the educational facility.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“University” means the University of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Waterbody” means those waters located within the District that are:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-431_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Waterbody-contingent property” means property within 25 feet of a waterbody.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
