<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-631.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-631.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_631_02">
        <akn:num>8-631.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Applicant” means a person who submits an application to participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program established by § 8-633.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_1A">
      <akn:num>(1A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bona fide prospective purchaser” means a person, or tenant of a person, who acquires ownership of a facility after June 13, 2001 and establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Brownfield” means abandoned, idled property or industrial property where expansion or redevelopment is complicated by actual or perceived environmental contamination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Contamination” means a release, discharge, or threatened release of a hazardous substance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DDOE” means the District Department of the Environment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible property” means a brownfield or any contaminated property that is not listed on the National Priority List pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, approved December 11, 1980 (94 Stat. 2767; 42 U.S.C. § 9601 et seq.), and is not the subject of a current cleanup action by the Environmental Protection Agency or the DDOE.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“EPA” means the United States Environmental Protection Agency or its successor agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Federal Act” means the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, approved December 11, 1980 (94 Stat. 2767; 42 U.S.C. § 9601 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hazardous substance” means any substance designated as a hazardous substance pursuant to section 101(14) of the Federal Act [42 U.S.C. § 9601(14)], or any substance identified as a hazardous substance by the DDOE in regulations adopted pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hazardous Substances Response Plan” means the Mayor’s plan, including policies and procedures, for responding to, and evaluating, hazardous substance releases that may threaten public health, welfare, and the environment, and that is consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Non-responsible person” means a person:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Institutional control” means any legal, institutional, or administrative mechanisms meant to prevent contamination or the potential exposure to hazardous substances, including any measure to ensure that use of the property, after completion of response or cleanup action pursuant to this chapter, remains in conformity with the levels of any residual hazardous substance left on the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Participant” means an applicant accepted into the Voluntary Cleanup Program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, trust, association, firm, joint-stock company, organization, commission, independent authority of the District government, or District, state, or federal government agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Program” means the Voluntary Cleanup Program established pursuant to § 8-633.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Release” means the addition, introduction, leaking, pumping, spilling, emitting, discharging, escaping, dumping, injecting, disposing or leaching of any hazardous substance into the environment, including the abandoning or discarding of barrels, containers, and other closed receptacles containing any hazardous substance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_14A">
      <akn:num>(14A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Response” means an action necessary to cleanup or otherwise prevent, minimize, or mitigate damage to the public health or welfare or to the environment from the release or threatened release of a hazardous substance, including a temporary or permanent measure and related enforcement activity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-631_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Responsible person” means a person who is liable pursuant to § 8-632.01.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
