<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-632.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-632.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_632_01">
        <akn:num>8-632.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Liabilities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-632_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful to release any hazardous substance in the District, unless the release is in quantities permitted by federal or District law or by regulations promulgated by the Mayor to implement this chapter. A lawful release of a hazardous substance shall be reported to the Mayor within 24 hours of the release. The notification to the Mayor shall state the location and condition of the property where the hazardous substance was released and the type of hazardous substance that was released. A violation of this subsection shall be punishable by a fine not to exceed $50,000 or imprisonment not to exceed 5 years, or both. Each violation of this subsection shall constitute a separate offense and the penalties prescribed in this subsection shall apply separately to each offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-632_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A responsible person shall be strictly liable, jointly and severally, for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-632_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this chapter, “a responsible person” is a person who, with regard to a property from which there is a release or threatened release of a hazardous substance that causes or contributes to the incurrence of a response cost:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-632_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To establish that a person did not know or did not have reason to know, as provided in subsections (c)(5) and (6) of this section, the person must have undertaken, at the time of acquisition, all appropriate inquiry into the previous ownership and uses of the property consistent with good commercial or customary practice in an effort to minimize liability. To determine that a person did not know or did not have reason to know, a court shall consider any specialized knowledge or experience on the part of the person, the relationship of the purchase price to the value of the property if uncontaminated, commonly known or reasonably ascertainable information about the property, the obviousness of the presence or the likely presence of contamination at the property, and the ability to detect such contamination by appropriate inspection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
