<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-671.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-671.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_671_01">
        <akn:num>8-671.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Activity and use limitations” means restrictions or obligations created under this chapter with respect to real property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Common-interest community” means a condominium, cooperative, or other real property with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person’s ownership of a parcel of real property, is obligated to pay property taxes or insurance premiums, or for maintenance, or improvement of other real property described in a recorded covenant that creates the common-interest community.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Environmental agency” means the District of Columbia’s Environment Health Administration, or its successor, or a federal agency that determines or approves the environmental response project pursuant to which the environmental covenant is created.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Environmental covenant” means a servitude arising under an environmental response project that imposes activity and use limitations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Environmental response project” means a plan or work performed for environmental remediation of real property and conducted:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Holder” means the grantee of an environmental covenant as specified in § 8-671.02(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government, governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-671_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
