<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-731"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-731/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_731">
        <akn:num>8-731</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Complaints of trash collection noise violations; hearings; notice of infraction.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-731_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person may file a complaint of a trash collection noise violation with the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-731_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A complaint under subsection (a) of this section shall be submitted in written form prescribed by the Mayor and made available on the District of Columbia website. The complaint shall be submitted within one week of the alleged violation and shall be signed by an original complainant who shall attest to its accuracy, under penalty of perjury. The complaint shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-731_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A District inspector need not witness a violation for a complaint to be valid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-731_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A complainant under subsection (a) of this section may appear and give testimony at any administrative hearing or administrative review of the complaint, or any other judicial or quasi-judicial action that may result from the complaint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-731_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor deems that the complaint has merit, the Mayor shall file a Notice of Infraction pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2 and with the Office of Administrative Hearings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-731_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to complaints relating to Department of Public Works trash trucks.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
