<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-807"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/8-807/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_8_807">
        <akn:num>8-807</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Penalties for violations.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may impose any or all sanctions stated in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the civil fine permitted under subsection (b) of this section, the following penalties may be imposed:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may recover up to 3 times the cost and expense incurred by the Mayor for abating the nuisance, preventing the recurrence of the violation, and cleaning and clearing the site where the unlawful disposal occurred and for properly disposing of the solid waste.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or hearing examiner may suspend or refuse to reissue any permit or license which authorizes the respondent to engage in the activity to which the sanction relates, or which otherwise substantially relates to the violation, if the respondent fails to pay any fines, penalties, interest, costs, or expense imposed pursuant to this chapter. Suspension of the permit or license shall continue until payment is made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The hearing examiner may agree with the person subject to penalties under this section to allow an alternative sanction requiring the respondent to perform, on a voluntary basis, a specific number of hours of community service comparable to the severity of the violation. The assignment will be made by the hearing examiner according to rules provided for by ยง 8-810 and in conjunction with a representative of the District of Columbia Department of Public Works.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may require the owner of vacant property in the District to fence or otherwise enclose the property to prevent the recurrence of a violation of any part of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8-807_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may promulgate rules to carry out the intent and purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
