<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1501.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1501.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1501_03">
        <akn:num>50-1501.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Fees classified and use of proceeds designated.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Non-resident taxi and limousine driver vehicle registration. — In addition to any fees that may be due under any other statute or regulation, a driver who was exempted from the residency requirements to register a vehicle within the District of Columbia under § 50-1501.02(c)(5)(B) shall be charged an additional fee of $100.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may prorate the fee for registration by an owner or dealer if the registration is issued by the Mayor for a period not to exceed 23 months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The proceeds from fees payable under this chapter shall be paid into the General Fund of the District of Columbia as established by the Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975, effective January 22, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-42; 22 DCR 6318); provided, that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this subchapter, special equipment mounted on a motor vehicle or trailer and not used primarily for the transportation of persons or property shall be taxed as tangible personal property as provided by law. For the purpose of determining the fees authorized by subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(2) and subsections (b)(3) and (b)(8) of this section, the weight of special equipment taxed in accordance with the provisions of this subsection (e) shall be excluded in computing the weight of the vehicle or trailer on which it is mounted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No annual motor vehicle registration fee shall be required for a noncommercial motor vehicle owned by any veteran who has been classified by the United States Veterans Administration as having a total and permanent disability as a result of a service incurred or aggravated condition; provided, that no more than 1 such vehicle per qualified veteran shall receive this fee exemption.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall direct the Director of the Department of Transportation to design and provide application forms for the exemption provided in subsection (f) of this section. The application shall be accompanied by a statement that the veteran has been classified as having a total and permanent disability by the Veterans Administration so as to meet the requirements of this subsection, and that such disability is the result of a service incurred or aggravated condition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To synchronize inspection and registration due dates, the Mayor may declare that a vehicle’s inspection or registration shall expire prior to the date originally established; provided, that the Mayor shall reduce the fee for the vehicle’s next registration or inspection renewal by a percentage equal to the percentage of the reduction of the original time period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may require a 2 year registration period for any registrant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may refund any portion of the registration fee if the registrant does not maintain the registration for the entire registration period established.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may allow any person to pay registration fees in installments, as determined by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1501_03_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may charge an additional fine of $100 for any motor vehicle whose inspection or registration is not renewed by the expiration date, unless the owner surrenders the tags on or before that date.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
