<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1605"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1605/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1605">
        <akn:num>50-1605</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Helmet use requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1605_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful for any person under 16 years of age to operate or to be a passenger on a bicycle or any attachment to a bicycle on a public roadway, public bicycle path or other right-of-way, unless that person wears a protective helmet of good fit, fastened securely upon the head with the straps of the helmet.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1605_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful for any parent or legal guardian of a child under 16 years of age to knowingly permit the child to operate or to be a passenger on a bicycle on a public roadway, public bicycle path, or other public right-of-way, unless at all times when the child is so engaged, he or she wears a protective bicycle helmet of good fit, fastened securely upon the head with the straps of the helmet.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1605_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The parents or legal guardians of any child under 16 years of age found in violation of this section shall be liable for paying a fine of $25. However, the fine shall be suspended for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1605_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The penalties provided for pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall not be enforced until 90 days after May 23, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1605_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any helmet sold or rented, or offered for sale or rent, for use by operators and passengers of bicycles shall be conspicuously labeled in accordance with the standard described in ยง 50-1609(5).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1605_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
