<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1403.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1403.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1403_02">
        <akn:num>50-1403.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Revocation and disqualification of motor vehicle operator’s permit.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall revoke the motor vehicle operator’s permit of a District resident or the privilege to operate a motor vehicle in the District of a nonresident, convicted as a result of the commission of a drug offense or adjudicated a juvenile delinquent as a result of the commission of a drug offense. Where the person is imprisoned as a result of the drug offense, the revocation shall occur following the person’s release from imprisonment. If a person does not have an operator’s permit, or the permit is or has been revoked or suspended at the time of the conviction of a drug offense, the issuance or reinstatement of an operator’s permit will be delayed for a period of at least 6 months and not more than 2 years. If a person is convicted for the commission of a drug offense or adjudicated a delinquent for the commission of a drug offense before the person is 16 years of age, the period of disqualification shall not begin to run until the person is 16 years of age. Notification of the conviction or adjudication shall be sent electronically by the court to the Mayor within one business day of the conviction or adjudication and shall include the person’s name, address, date of birth, conviction date, driver’s license number, if any, social security number, if any, the offense, and any other information required by the Mayor to take the action required by this section. The revocation shall be for not less than six months and not more than 2 years. For the purposes of this section, notwithstanding any other District law, a violation of § 48-1201 shall not constitute a drug offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_02_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may delay issuance of an operator’s permit by disqualifying anyone not already in possession of a valid operator’s permit when such individual is convicted of or adjudicated delinquent as a result of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_02_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In all cases where a person is convicted or adjudicated delinquent of any of the offenses set forth in subsection (a-1) of this section, the disqualification period shall commence on the later of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_02_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The disqualification period referenced in subsection (a-2) of this section shall, for any offense set forth in subsection (a-1) of this section, be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_02_a_4">
      <akn:num>(a-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A copy of the conviction or adjudication shall be forwarded by the court to the Mayor, along with the offender’s social security number or operator’s permit number, together with a copy of the operator’s permit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
