<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1601"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1601/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1601">
        <akn:num>50-1601</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Findings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Increased use of bicycles for transportation and recreation will result in improved air quality, reduced levels of noise and traffic congestion, greater energy conservation, lower transportation costs, fewer parking problems, and increased physical fitness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Bicycle fatalities and accidents can be reduced through broad-based education and facilities improvements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The promotion of bicycle transportation and safety in the District of Columbia (“District”) requires the implementation of a comprehensive bicycle transportation and safety program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A bicycle office is required to coordinate the comprehensive program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Disability and death from injuries sustained in bicycling accidents are a serious threat to the health, welfare and safety of District children.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each year approximately 290 children are involved in fatal accidents, and nearly 400,000 are injured with varying degrees of severity in bicycle related injuries or crashes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Head injuries account for over 60% of bicycle related fatalities and 1/3 of bicycle related emergency room visits.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Use of a bicycle helmet is the single, most effective preventive measure of reducing head injuries 85%, and brain injuries or serious disabilities by 88% from bicycle accidents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1601_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Only 15% of bicyclists use proper head protective equipment, and some studies show that bicycle helmet usage for children under 16 years of age ranges from 5% to 15%.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
