<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1401.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1401.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1401_02">
        <akn:num>50-1401.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Exemptions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner or operator of any motor vehicle who is not a legal resident of the District of Columbia, and who has complied with the laws of any state, territory, or possession of the United States, or of a foreign country or political subdivision thereof, shall, subject to the provisions of this section, be exempt for a continuous 30 day period immediately following the entrance of such owner or operator into the District of Columbia from compliance with § 50-1401.01 and § 50-1501.02. The 30-day exemption period shall not apply to commercial motor vehicles required to obtain a permit, as provided by § 50-1507.03 or charter busses identified in § 50-1501.02(j).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon expiration of the 30 day exemption period, the owner or operator of any motor vehicle shall be required either:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following persons shall, if they have complied with the motor vehicle registration and licensing laws of the state, territory, or possession of the United States of which they are a legal resident, be exempt during their respective term of office or employment from compliance with §§ 50-1401.01 and 50-1501.02, and all applicable provisions of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations requiring the registration of motor vehicles, the display of identification tags, and the licensing of owners or operators of motor vehicles in the District of Columbia:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Those persons listed under subsection (c) of this section shall be required to obtain and display a valid reciprocity sticker. The Mayor shall issue, upon application and a fee of $50, a reciprocity sticker for those persons listed under subsection (c) of this section, valid for 1 year, and renewable for the respective term of office or employment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Persons enrolled as full-time students engaged in higher education (as defined by the respective institutions of higher education in the District of Columbia) in an institution of higher education licensed to operate in the District of Columbia, and who are not residents of the District of Columbia, shall, if they have complied with the motor vehicle registration and licensing laws of the state, territory, or possession of the United States of which they are a legal resident, be exempt during their respective tenure as full-time students engaged in higher education from compliance with §§ 50-1401.01 and 50-1501.02, and all applicable provisions of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations requiring the registration of motor vehicles, the display of identification tags, and the licensing of owners or operators of motor vehicles in the District of Columbia; provided, that the full-time student shall be required to obtain and display a valid reciprocity sticker.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_e_2">
      <akn:num>(e-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor or his designated agent is authorized to enter into reciprocal agreements or arrangements with the duly authorized representatives of a state, territory, or possession of the United States or a foreign country or political subdivision thereof, to vary the conditions under which the validity of motor vehicle registration and identification tags of any category of vehicles such as dealer tags, tags for persons with disabilities, and rental vehicle tags of such state, territory, or possession of the United States or foreign country or political subdivision thereof, shall be recognized in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary to implement and enforce this section. Such rules and regulations shall include, but not be limited to, a determination of how many times during the 30-day exemption period an agent or employee of the Mayor of the District of Columbia must observe a motor vehicle for purposes of the enforcement of this section and a method of enforcing the provisions of this section applicable to commercial vehicles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any operator of a motor vehicle who is not a legal resident of the District of Columbia and who does not have in his immediate possession an operator’s permit issued by a state, territory, or possession of the United States, or foreign country or political subdivision thereof, having motor vehicle reciprocity relations with the District, shall not operate a motor vehicle in the District unless: (1) the laws of the state, territory, or possession of the United States, or foreign country or political subdivision thereof, under which the motor vehicle is registered do not require the issuance of a motor vehicle operator’s permit; or (2) has submitted to examination within 72 hours after entering the District and obtained an operator’s permit in accordance with the provisions of § 50-1401.01. Any individual who violates any provision of this subsection shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not less than $5 and not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01 or imprisoned not less than 30 days, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
