<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1507.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1507.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1507_01">
        <akn:num>50-1507.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apportioned operator” means registrant of a fleet of apportioned vehicles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apportionment” means registration based on a proportional payment of registration fees, whether determined by a quotient of miles traveled, revenue received, average presence, or any other similar method.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Apportionable vehicle” means any vehicle, except recreational vehicles, vehicles displaying restricted plates, buses used in transportation of chartered parties and government-owned vehicles, used or intended for use in two or more member jurisdictions that allocate or proportionally register vehicles and are used for the transportation of persons for hire or designed, used, or maintained primarily for the transportation of property and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Base jurisdiction” means, for purposes of fleet registration, the jurisdiction where the registrant has an established place of business, where mileage is accrued by the fleet, and where operational records of such fleet are maintained or can be made available in accordance with section 1602 of the International Registration Plan (“IRP”).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Base plate” means the plate issued by the base jurisdiction and shall be the only registration identification plate issued for the vehicle by any member jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Combined Gross Vehicle Weight” (“CGVW”) means the total unladen weight of a combination of vehicles and weight of the load carried on that combination of vehicles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Established place of business” means a physical structure owned, leased, or rented by the fleet registrant and used as his or her main office.  The physical structure shall be designated by a street number or road location, be open during normal business hours, and have located within it:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fleet” means one or more apportionable vehicles.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Interjurisdictional movement” means vehicular movement between or through two or more jurisdictions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intrajurisdictional movement” means vehicular movement from one point within a jurisdiction to another point within the same jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“IRP” means the abbreviation for the reciprocal agreement, the International Registration Plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“IVMR” means Individual Vehicle Mileage Record which serves as the original record generated in the course of actual vehicle operation and is used as a source document to verify the registrant’s application for accuracy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member jurisdiction” means a jurisdiction which has applied for membership and has been accepted by all members of the IRP.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Motor carrier” means an individual, partnership, or corporation engaged in the transportation of goods or persons.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means any person, firm, or corporation other than the lienholder holding legal title to a vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Properly registered vehicle” means a vehicle which has been registered in full compliance with the laws of all jurisdictions in which it is intended to operate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reciprocity” means the reciprocal granting of rights and privileges to vehicles properly registered under the IRP and to vehicles not so registered if these vehicles are subject to separate reciprocity agreements, arrangements, declarations, or understandings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Trip permit” means a temporary permit issued by a jurisdiction in lieu of regular registration reciprocity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1507_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Uniform mileage schedule” means the official IRP form provided to record mileage by jurisdictions and total fleet miles derived from operational records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
