<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1401.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1401.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1401_01">
        <akn:num>50-1401.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Fee; examination; age requirements; lost permits; provisions for armed forces personnel; contents; operation without permit prohibited; restrictions for minors.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual to whom a license or permit to operate a motor vehicle has been issued shall have the license or permit in his or her immediate possession at all times while operating a motor vehicle in the District of Columbia and shall exhibit the license or permit to any police officer upon demand. Any person who fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection shall, upon conviction, be fined not less than $10 nor more than $50.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No individual shall operate a motor vehicle in the District, except as provided in § 50-1401.02, without first having obtained an operator’s permit, learner’s permit, provisional permit, or a motorcycle endorsement if operating a motorcycle, issued under the provisions of this subchapter and Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Except as provided in subsection (d-1) of this section, any individual violating any provision of this subsection shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01 or shall be imprisoned not more than 90 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual who operates a motor vehicle with a District of Columbia permit expired for not more than 90 days shall be subject to a civil fine of not more than $100 pursuant to §§ 50-2301.04(b) and 50-2301.05, and shall not be subject to the criminal penalties contained in subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subchapter shall relieve any individual from compliance with § 47-2829(e).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section and §§ 50-1401.02 and 50-1403.01, the term “motor vehicle” means a vehicle propelled by an internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include a traction engine, road roller, vehicle propelled only upon rails or tracks, personal assistive mobility device, as defined by § 50-2201.02(12), a battery-operated wheelchair when operated by a person with a disability, or a motorized bicycle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1401_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>[Expired].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
