<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1403.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-1403.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_1403_01">
        <akn:num>50-1403.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Revocation or suspension; new permit after revocation; nonresidents; penalty for operation with revoked or suspended license.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except where for any violation of this subchapter revocation of the operator’s permit is mandatory or where suspension or revocation is mandatory for accumulated point totals pursuant to Chapter 3 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, the Mayor or his designated agent may revoke or suspend an operator’s permit for any cause which he or his agent may deem sufficient; provided, that in each case where a permit is revoked or suspended the reasons therefor shall be set out in the order of revocation or suspension; provided further, that such order shall take effect 10 (15, if the person is a nonresident) days after its issuance unless the holder of the permit shall have filed within such period, written application with the Mayor of the District of Columbia for a review of his order or the order of his agent, and, if upon such review, the Mayor shall sustain such order, the same shall become effective immediately; provided further, that application to said Mayor for a review shall not operate as a stay of such order of the Mayor or his agent when the order has been issued revoking or suspending a permit on account of mental or physical incapacity, for driving while the person is intoxicated as defined by § 50-2206.01(9), or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor or any drug or any combination thereof, or while the ability to operate a vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor; for manslaughter when an automobile is involved, or for operating a motor vehicle equipped with a smoke screen.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In case the operator’s permit of any individual is revoked no new permit shall be issued to such individual for at least 6 months after the revocation except in the discretion of the Mayor or his designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia, or his designated agent, may suspend or revoke the right of any nonresident person as defined in § 50-1401.02, to operate a motor vehicle in the District of Columbia, for any cause he or his agent may deem sufficient, and the proper authority at the place of issuance of the permit, or other authority to operate a motor vehicle shall be notified of such suspension and the reason therefor, immediately; provided, that such order of suspension or revocation shall take effect 10 days after its issuance, and the same be subject to review and appeal in the manner and under the same conditions as are provided for such matters in subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the provisions of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (§ 2-501 et seq.) and particularly those of § 2-509, shall apply to each proceeding, decision, or other administrative action specified in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-1403_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual found guilty of operating a motor vehicle in the District during the period for which the individual’s license is revoked or suspended, or for which his right to operate is suspended or revoked, shall, for each such offense, be fined not more than the amount set forth in § 22-3571.01 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
