<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2303.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2303.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_2303_06">
        <akn:num>50-2303.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Hearing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each hearing for the adjudication of a traffic infraction pursuant to this subchapter shall be held before a hearing examiner in accordance with Chapter 10 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations except as provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The burden of proof shall be upon the District, and no infraction may be established except upon proof by a preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After due consideration of the evidence and arguments, the hearing examiner shall determine whether the infraction has been established. Where the infraction is not established, an order dismissing the charges shall be entered. Where a determination is made that an infraction has been established or where an answer admitting the commission of the infraction or admitting the commission of the infraction with explanation has been received, an appropriate order shall be entered in the Department’s records. Where a determination has been made that the infraction has been established, the Department shall provide written notice of the decision to the respondent, including an accompanying explanation of why any evidence provided was insufficient.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_f_1">
      <akn:num>(f-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The hearing examiner may impose a civil fine for violation of infractions to which this subchapter is applicable up to and including an amount prescribed by § 50-2301.05 exclusive of fees and charges imposed for the towing or booting of a vehicle or additional penalties imposed for failure to answer to such infraction in a timely manner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2303_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All civil fines and other monies collected pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter shall be paid into the General Fund of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
