<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2206.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2206.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_2206_01">
        <akn:num>50-2206.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Active metabolite” means an active form of a drug after it has been processed by the body.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Alcohol” means a liquid, gas, or solid, containing ethanol from whatever source or by whatever processes produced, whether or not intended for human consumption.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chemical test” or “chemical testing” means any qualitative or quantitative procedure which is designed to demonstrate the existence or absence of a chemical compound or chemical group. Any handheld and portable breath testing instrument, otherwise known as a roadside breath test, is excluded from this definition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial vehicle” means a vehicle used to transport passengers or property:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, except when used in the definition of “prior offense” when it shall also include courts of other jurisdictions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Drug” means any chemical substance that affects the processes of the mind or body, including but not limited to a controlled substance as defined in § 48-901.02(4), and any prescription or non-prescription medication.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Highway” means any street, road, or public thoroughfare, or the entire width between the boundary lines of every publicly or privately maintained way, when any part thereof is open to the use of the public for purposes of vehicular or pedestrian travel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Impaired” means a person’s ability to operate or be in physical control of a vehicle is affected, due to consumption of alcohol or a drug or a combination thereof, in a way that can be perceived or noticed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Intoxicated” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Law enforcement officer” means a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or a sworn member of any other police force operating in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mandatory-minimum term of incarceration” means a term of incarceration which shall be imposed and cannot be suspended by the court. The person shall not be released or granted probation, or granted suspension of sentence before serving the mandatory-minimum sentence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his or her designee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Measurable amount” means any amount of alcohol capable of being, but not required to be, measured.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Minor” means a person under the age of 18 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by internal-combustion engines, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon rails or tracks, personal mobility devices, as defined by paragraph (16) of this section, or a battery-operated wheelchair when operated by a person with a disability.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Personal mobility device” or “PMD” means a motorized propulsion device designed to transport one person or a self-balancing, 2 non-tandem wheeled device, designed to transport only one person with an electric propulsion system, but does not include a battery-operated wheelchair.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prior offense” means any guilty plea or verdict, including a finding of guilty in the case of a juvenile, for an offense under District law or a disposition in another jurisdiction for a substantially similar offense which occurred before the current offense regardless of when the arrest occurred. The term “prior offense” does not include an offense where the later of any term of incarceration, supervised release, parole, or probation ceased or expired more than 15 years before the arrest on the current offense.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Specimen” means that quantity of a person’s blood, breath, or urine necessary to conduct chemical testing to determine alcohol or drug content. A single specimen may be comprised of multiple breaths into a breath test instrument if necessary to complete a valid breath test, or a single blood draw or single urine sample regardless of how many times the blood or urine sample is tested.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“This subchapter” includes all lawful regulations issued thereunder by the Council of the District of Columbia and all lawful rules issued thereunder by the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Traffic” includes not only motor vehicles but also all vehicles, pedestrians, and animals, of every description.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Vehicle” includes any appliance moved over a highway on wheels or traction tread, including street cars, draft animals, and beasts of burden.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Vehicle for hire” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2206_01_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Watercraft” means a boat, ship, or other craft used for water transportation, as well as water skis, an aquaplane, a sailboard, or a similar vessel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
