<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2504"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2504/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_2504">
        <akn:num>50-2504</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Board of Directors — Establishment; Board member qualifications; term of office; removal; quorum; compensation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A Board of Directors (“Board”) is established to manage the affairs of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall be comprised of 5 members, one of whom shall be the Chief Financial Officer of the District. The Board chairperson and 3 other members shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council by resolution.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each member of the Board shall be a resident of the District and shall serve a 4-year term of office. Of the members first appointed to the Board, 1 member shall be appointed to a 2-year term; 2 members shall be appointed for a 3-year term; and the member appointed chairperson shall be appointed for a 4-year term. Thereafter each member shall be appointed for a 4-year term. The terms of the members first appointed shall begin on the date that a majority of the members is first established (with one of the majority being the member appointed chairperson by the Mayor), which shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>One member of the Board shall be a local business person. The remaining members of the Board shall possess expertise in transportation, parking, banking, law, finance, construction, or real estate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A vacancy on the Board shall be filled in the same manner that the original appointment was made. Any person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the unexpired term of the original appointment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No member of the Board shall be appointed to serve more than 2 consecutive 4-year terms of office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may remove a member of the Board for misconduct or neglect of duty after notice to the member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, 3 members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for all purposes. For matters involving a recommendation for the establishment of a public parking district, 4 members shall constitute a quorum. For purposes of bond issuance, 4 of the 5 members shall vote and approve the resolution for the bond issue, one of whom shall be the Chief Financial Officer of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2504_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the availability of appropriations for compensation purposes, each member of the Board shall be entitled to receive the hourly equivalent of the annual rate of pay for the highest step of a grade DS-15 authorized pursuant to Chapter 6 of Title 1, for each hour that the member is engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Board not to exceed $8000 per year, except that a member of the Board who is a full-time officer or employee of the District of Columbia or the federal government shall not be entitled to receive pay under this subsection for performance of duties vested in the Board during the employee’s regularly scheduled working hours. Members may be reimbursed for actual expenses.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
