<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2302.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2302.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_2302_05">
        <akn:num>50-2302.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Answer.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In answer to a notice of infraction, a person to whom the notice was issued may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person fails to answer a notice of infraction within 30 calendar days of the date the notice was issued, or within a greater period of time as prescribed by the Director by regulation, a penalty equal to the amount of the fine shall be added pursuant to § 50-2301.05(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a person fails to answer the notice within 60 calendar days after the date the notice was issued, or within a greater period of time as prescribed by the Director by regulation, the commission of the infraction shall be deemed admitted and all points, penalties, and fines shall be assessed, and, except where the notice of infraction was issued in reliance upon an automated traffic enforcement device, the person’s District of Columbia operator’s permit, or the person’s privilege to drive within the District in the case of a person holding an out-of-state permit, shall be suspended until payment of the penalties, fines, and a reinstatement fee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not more than 50 days after the notice is issued, the Director shall send by regular mail addressed to the person’s address on the Department of Motor Vehicle’s records notice of the outstanding notice of infraction and the effective date of the deemed admission and suspension of driving privileges. For holders of out-of-state licenses, the address in the Department of Motor Vehicle’s records shall be the address available through the Washington Area Law Enforcement System, or similar interstate database containing license information from state issuing agencies, or the address displayed on the person’s driver’s license as presented at the time notice of infraction was issued.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A suspension resulting from a failure to answer shall remain in effect until the person answers the notice, except that once the offense is deemed admitted the suspension may only be lifted by payment of the fine for the offense and any additional penalties established pursuant to § 50-2301.05, as may be due for failure to answer within the time required by subsection (d)(1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2302_05_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The filing of an application under subsection (i) of this section shall not stay any charges, fines, penalties, points, or suspension of a person&#x27;s license or privilege to drive in the District; provided, that if the infraction underlying the deemed admission is dismissed, any charges, fines, or penalties paid shall be reimbursed and points assessed or the suspension of a person&#x27;s license or privilege to drive may be vacated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
