<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2207.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2207.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_2207_02">
        <akn:num>50-2207.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Tinted windows prohibited.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets of the District of Columbia with a front windshield that allows less than 70% light transmittance above the AS-1 line, or within 5 inches from the top of the windshield.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who operates or parks a motor vehicle in violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be issued a $50 citation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any police officer or other authorized government agent of the District may order the immediate removal of a motor vehicle from the public streets to an official District Inspection Station if the police officer or other authorized government agent determines that the health and safety of the public is at risk due to window tinting in violation of subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person shall install window tinting on a motor vehicle which is not exempt pursuant to subsection (h) of this section, in the District of Columbia which would cause the motor vehicle to violate subsection (a) of this section if the vehicle were operated or parked on the public streets of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to modify or affect any federal law concerning the window tinting of motor vehicles that is applicable to manufacturers, importers, dealers, or motor vehicle repair businesses for new or used motor vehicles and equipment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles is authorized to promulgate rules to implement the provisions this section and to amend existing provisions of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to conform to its requirements. Rules promulgated or amended pursuant to this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, holidays, and days of Council recess.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice of an infraction issued pursuant to subsections (d)(2) or (e)(2) of this section shall be mailed by U.S. mail to the owner’s last known address in the Department of Motor Vehicles’ records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Violations of subsections (d)(2) and (e)(2) of this section shall be adjudicated as moving violations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Answers to notices sent pursuant to subsection (k) of this section shall be in accordance with § 50-2302.05(a), (b), (c), and (e)), and subsection (n) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall reject any vehicles appearing for inspection pursuant to Chapter 11 of this title whose window tint violates subsections (a) or (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2207_02_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No points shall be assessed for any violation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
