<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-211.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-211.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_211_01">
        <akn:num>50-211.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Alternative fuel” means fuels defined as alternative fuels by 42 U.S.C. § 13211(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bikeshare” means the Capital Bikeshare program or its successor programs that allow point-to-point bicycle sharing at stations throughout the District</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chauffeur” means a District employee who is assigned the official duty of regularly driving a supervising employee to and from the employee’s home, appointments, or work sites, and who does not have an official purpose for travel beyond driving the supervising employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Compact vehicle” means a vehicle with an interior volume index greater than or equal to 100 cubic feet but less than 110 cubic feet as set forth in the description of a compact car as defined by the vehicle class size set forth in 40 C.F.R. § 600.315-08 (a)(1)(iv), approved December 27, 2006.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Director” means the Director of the Department of Public Works or the Director’s designee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“DPW” means the Department of Public Works.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emergency vehicle” means a vehicle authorized by the District to exceed the speed limit to transport people or equipment to and from situations in which speed is required to save lives or property and that is equipped with audible and visual signals capable of being seen and heard from a distance of not less than 500 feet.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fleetshare” means the District’s centrally managed motor pool of passenger vehicles that are available for District employee use for official purposes through advance reservation and billed to the agency according to use.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fuel economy” means the average number of miles traveled by an automobile for each gallon of gasoline (or equivalent amount of other fuel) used, as determined by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Heavy equipment” means vehicles or vehicle attachments that cannot be classified as either passenger or non-passenger vehicles and that are used to perform road maintenance, construction, earth-moving, or another specialized function.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Large vehicle” means a vehicle with an interior volume index greater than or equal to 120 cubic feet as set forth in the description of a large car as defined by the vehicle class size set forth in 40 C.F.R § 600.315-08(a)(1)(vi), approved December 27, 2006.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Passenger vehicle” means any automobile, other than an automobile designed for off-highway operation, manufactured primarily for the transportation of no more than 15 individuals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Specialized vehicle” means a vehicle uniquely outfitted for service based on an agency’s mission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-211_01_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Vehicle” means an automobile or motorcycle classified for on- Highway operation, excluding a sub-class generally considered to be a specialized vehicle or heavy equipment. The term “vehicle” shall not mean bicycles, pedicycles, personal mobility devices such as Segways or motorized wheelchairs, or other non-motorized conveyances.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
