<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2511"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-2511/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_2511">
        <akn:num>50-2511</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Parking districts.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The establishment of a parking district shall be initiated with a petition signed by the owners of real property that represents 50% or more of the combined assessed value of all Class 3, Class 4, and Class 5 real property, as those classes of real property are established pursuant to ยง 47-813, located within a proposed parking district. Upon receipt of a valid petition, the Authority shall assess the parking needs within the proposed parking district and recommend to the Mayor the establishment of a parking district if the Authority determines that the establishment of a parking district is warranted.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A recommendation to the Mayor for the establishment of a parking district shall describe the metes and bounds of the proposed parking district and shall also contain the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Simultaneous with submittal of the recommendation to the Mayor for the establishment of a parking district, the Authority shall submit a financial plan for funding the public parking facilities within the proposed parking district which may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Mayor approves the recommendation by the Authority, the Mayor shall transmit proposed legislation to the Council for the creation of the proposed parking district within 60 days from the date the Mayor receives the recommendation from the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After the Council receives the proposed legislation for establishment of the parking district from the Mayor, the Council may establish by act the parking district.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Council is authorized in each fiscal year following the establishment of a parking district to levy and cause to be collected special real property taxes in the nature of ad valorem taxes from property owners in each parking district.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The special tax levied on the property owners in the parking district and other monies collected by the parking district shall be used to pay the following for the specific parking district for which the tax is levied:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Property owners who fail to pay the special tax authorized by subsection (g) of this section shall be subject to interest and penalties for nonpayment of taxes pursuant to ยง 47-1813.04 [repealed].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-2511_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On a date to be set by the Mayor, the Authority shall submit to the Mayor a budget, which shall be included in the annual or supplemental budget transmitted by the Mayor to the Council pursuant to ยง 47-204.42, covering all anticipated revenue, transfers, expenses, and capital outlays of the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
