<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-331"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-331/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_331">
        <akn:num>50-331</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Impoundment of a taxicab and passenger vehicle for hire.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any taxicab or passenger vehicle for hire being operated in the District of Columbia may be booted, towed, and impounded from any public street or public space in the District of Columbia by any member of the Metropolitan Police Department or law enforcement personnel, or any authorized agent if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, a notice of infraction is considered unpaid if the infraction has been deemed to have been admitted or sustained after a hearing, pursuant to §§ 50-2303.05 and 50-2303.06, § 50-2209.02, or subsection 323.3 of Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any vehicle impounded pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may be towed by a tow crane operator to the Commission or any other secured place designated by the Department of Public Works.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any vehicle impounded pursuant to subsection (a)(1), (2), or (5) of this section shall have the license removed, the vehicle operator’s license suspended, or both, as applicable, pending a hearing pursuant to subsection (e) of this section to determine the propriety of reissuance or return of the license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 3 business days of impoundment, the Chairperson of the Commission shall mail a notice, by first-class mail, certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, to the last known address of the owner and the operator of the impounded vehicle as identified in the records of the Office of Taxicabs. The notice shall contain the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner or operator of a vehicle impounded pursuant to subsection (a)(1) through (5) of this section may request a hearing, in writing. The hearing shall occur within 3 business days of the receipt by the Mayor of a written hearing request. The hearing examiner shall determine:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a determination is made, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section that, at the time of the impoundment, the vehicle was being operated without a valid license issued pursuant to § 50-301.19 or § 47-2829(c) [(c) repealed], (d), or (h), the hearing examiner shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The license of a vehicle owner who receives a favorable determination under subsection (f) of this section shall be reissued or returned.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a determination is made, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, that the vehicle was being operated, at the time of the impoundment, without a valid vehicle operator’s license issued pursuant to § 47-2829(e) or (i), the hearing examiner shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon a favorable determination from the hearing examiner under subsection (h) of this section the vehicle operator’s license shall be reissued or returned.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the hearing examiner determines, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, that the vehicle operator has 2 or more unpaid notices of infractions issued pursuant to 31 DCMR 825 or the vehicle has 2 or more unpaid notices of infractions issued pursuant to Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations or 31 DCMR 825 or the accumulated unpaid infractions equal or exceed $400 for which liability has been imposed, the vehicle owner or operator, as applicable, shall be ordered to pay the outstanding fines.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the hearing examiner determines, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, that the vehicle does not comply with Chapter 24 of Title 31, the hearing examiner shall impose an appropriate penalty upon the vehicle owner or operator pursuant to Chapter 24 of Title 31 and Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the hearing examiner determines, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, that the vehicle is not licensed in the District of Columbia and is observed providing intra-District transportation service, the vehicle and operator shall be considered unlicensed and the vehicle owner or operator as applicable, shall be ordered to pay the infractions issued pursuant to § 50-301.19 and 31 DCMR 824.3.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon completion of the hearing, the hearing examiner shall issue a written decision containing findings of fact and conclusions of law. If a favorable determination is issued for the vehicle owner or operator, as applicable, the hearing examiner shall issue a release form for the impounded vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any party adversely affected by a written decision of a hearing examiner may file written exceptions to the Panel on Adjudication pursuant to the Commission’s rules and regulations. The vehicle owner or operator shall first pay the subject fine and all other outstanding fines in order to file for written exceptions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In lieu of requesting a hearing, the vehicle owner or operator may satisfy all outstanding notices of infraction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon full satisfaction of all outstanding notices of infraction the Office of Taxicabs shall issue a release form for the impounded vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The owner of an impounded vehicle or other authorized person shall be permitted to secure the release of the vehicle from impoundment upon:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If within 15 calendar days of impoundment the vehicle has not been reclaimed, the vehicle shall be deemed abandoned and shall be released to the Department of Public Works to be processed as an abandoned vehicle pursuant to § 50-2402.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-331_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Metropolitan Police Department or law enforcement personnel, or any authorized agent acting pursuant to subsection (a)(6) of this section may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
