<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_301_05">
        <akn:num>50-301.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Taxicab Commission-Membership; appointment; terms; chairperson.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall consist of 9 members. Five of the members, who shall be public members, shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council, and shall be drawn from the public at large. Three of the members, who shall be industry members, shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council, and shall have experience in the field of transportation administration or regulation, the hospitality industry, public safety, or taxicab management or operations in the District. The remaining member of the Commission shall be appointed by the Mayor with advice and consent of the Council and shall serve as chairperson of the Commission. The chairperson shall have experience in the field of transportation administration or regulation. The Mayor shall transmit to the Council, for a 90-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess, a nominee for member or chairperson. If the Council does not approve the nomination by resolution within this 90-day review period, the nomination shall be deemed disapproved.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All members of the Commission, except for the chairperson who shall serve at the pleasure of the Mayor, shall be appointed for terms of 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to ยง 1-604.06 and subchapter IX of Chapter 6 of Title 1, the chairperson of the Commission shall be its chief administrative officer and shall have charge of the organization of the Commission and its panels, and shall superintend the duties of the Commission staff in carrying out the purposes and provisions of this subchapter. The chairperson shall be a public officer of the District who shall devote full time to the affairs of the Commission, and shall receive compensation commensurate with his or her duties and responsibilities established by this subchapter. The salary of the chairperson shall be determined by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chairperson of the Commission shall appoint the Secretary to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
