<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.15"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.15/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_301_15">
        <akn:num>50-301.15</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sinking funds; blanket policies.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_15_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any owner of a taxicab required to file a bond or policy of liability insurance under ยง 50-301.14 may instead:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_15_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any owner elects to comply with the provisions of this section, he or she shall file an admission of liability with the Commissioner, in conformity with the principles of respondeat superior, for the tortious acts of drivers of vehicles displaying the trade name or identifying design of the company, association, or the owner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_15_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any cash or collateral deposit or sinking fund provided for in this section shall be exempt from attachment or levy for any obligation or liability of the depositor except as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_15_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be unlawful to operate any vehicle subject to the provisions of ยง 50-301.14 and this section unless the vehicle is insured as provided in this subchapter, under threat of a civil fine not to exceed $500. Any violation of any regulation or requirement issued or ordered pursuant to ยง 50-301.14 or this section shall be subject to a civil fine not to exceed $500.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_15_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purpose of this section a blanket bond or sinking fund may be established by the owner of a trade name or identifying design and may cover taxicabs bearing the trade name or identifying design of the owner, multiple fleets of taxicabs bearing different trade names or identifying designs of the owner, or owners of individual taxicabs bearing different trade names or identifying designs of the owner, irrespective of whether the owner of the trade name or identifying design owns the taxicab so long as the registered owner of the taxicab consents in writing to the sinking fund or blanket bond established by the owner of the trade names or identifying design. For the purpose of this subsection a member of a taxicab association shall be considered to have consented to a blanket bond or a sinking fund duly established by the association and no consent in writing shall be required.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
