<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.14"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.14/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_301_14">
        <akn:num>50-301.14</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Insurance.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each owner of a taxicab operated in the District shall maintain a bond or policy of liability insurance covering accident risks for payment of judgments and legal claims arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or operation of a taxicab consistent with the provisions of the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982 Amendments Act of 1985 [D.C. Code § 31-2401 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bond or policy of liability insurance required by this section shall provide minimum coverage by a surety or insurer on any 1 judgment of $10,000 for bodily injuries or death, and $5,000 for damage to property, and $20,000 for bodily injury or death, and $5,000 for damage to property for all judgments arising out of the same subject of action, to be apportioned ratably among creditors according to the amount of their respective rights, until these requirements are superseded by the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982 Amendments Act of 1985 [D.C. Code § 31-2401 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The liability of a surety or insurer on an indemnity or policy of liability issued under this section shall be absolute for damages adjudged against an insured.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each owner of a taxicab operated in the District shall file with the Office evidence that a bond or policy of liability insurance meeting the requirements of this section is in force for the owner’s taxicab. The Office shall maintain accurate and current information on all insured taxicabs and shall maintain accurate and current records on all taxicabs for which insurance or a bond has been cancelled.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Policies of liability insurance shall be issued only by companies authorized by the Commissioner to do business in the District, and all sureties bonding taxicabs operated in the District shall be approved by the Commissioner. No insurer or surety shall engage in the business of insuring or bonding taxicabs unless a certificate of approval is issued by the Commissioner to engage in such a business, which approval shall be given upon a finding by the Commissioner that the company is qualified and its management capable of conducting such a business in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner shall issue reasonable rules in furtherance of the protection of the public governing:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner may, after a hearing, withdraw the certificate of approval of any insurer or surety violating a provision of this section or any rule issued by the Commissioner pursuant to the authority of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_14_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No bond or policy of insurance required by this subchapter may be cancelled unless not less than 20 days notice of cancellation or termination has been provided to the insured in writing, and notice of intent to cancel has been filed with the Commissioner and Office not less than 20 days prior to the date of cancellation or termination, except that cancellation for nonpayment of premium shall require not less than 5 days written notice to the insured, and the filing of notice of intent to cancel with the Commissioner and Office not less than 5 days prior to the date of cancellation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
