<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.20"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-301.20/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_301_20">
        <akn:num>50-301.20</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established within the District of Columbia Treasury a fiduciary fund to be known as the Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund. The Fund shall be a revolving, segregated, nonlapsing fund administered by the Commission. The Fund shall consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After June 24, 1987, continued resources for the Fund shall be provided through an assessment levied against taxicab and passenger vehicle for hire operators as determined by Commission rule. Monies deposited into the Fund after June 24, 1987, shall be used by the Commission for any investigation or proceeding by the Commission concerning taxicab and passenger vehicle for hire rates and regulations as determined by rules promulgated by the Commission and submitted to the Council for approval, in whole or in part, by resolution. No assessment imposed by the Commission on an operator pursuant to this subsection shall exceed $50 per year. Nothing in this subsection shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Commission by subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall assess each taxicab and passenger vehicle for hire operator $50 per year upon the issuance or renewal of each operator identification card license.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Procedures for the implementation and administration of a passenger surcharge amount shall be established by the Commission in accordance with its rulemaking authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds deposited into the Fund and allocated to the Commission shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall conduct a mandatory yearly review of the passenger surcharge amount and shall adjust the surcharge amount based on revenue over needed spending.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Auditor shall conduct an audit of the Fund at least once every 3 fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-301_20_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commission shall submit to the Council monthly revenue reports on the Fund by the 15th of every month.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
