<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-402"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-402/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_402">
        <akn:num>50-402</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Uniform classification and commercial driver’s license requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Adopt and administer a program to test and ensure the fitness of a person to operate a commercial motor vehicle in accordance with rules issued pursuant to § 50-409 that comply with the minimum federal standards established under § 12005(a) of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act (49 U.S.C. §   2704(a));</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Issue a commercial driver’s license to a person if the person passes a written and driving test for the operation of a commercial vehicle that complies with the minimum standards required by paragraph (1) of this section;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Issue a commercial driver’s license only to a person who operates a commercial motor vehicle and is domiciled in the District of Columbia (“District”);</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Authorize a person to operate a commercial motor vehicle only by issuance of a commercial driver’s license that contains the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not issue a commercial driver’s license to a person during a period in which the person is disqualified from the operation of a commercial motor vehicle or the driver’s license of the person is suspended, revoked, or cancelled;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not issue or renew a commercial driver’s license to a person who has a commercial driver’s license issued by another state unless the person first surrenders the driver’s license issued by the other state;</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not issue a commercial driver’s license to a person who is less than 21 years of age, except that a commercial driver’s license may be issued to a person who is at least 18 years of age and has at least 2 years driving experience; provided, that a commercial driver’s license issued to a person who is less than 21 years of age shall not be valid for:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Participate in a national commercial driver’s license information system established pursuant to section 12007 of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act (49 U.S.C. § 2706) to enable the District to have access to information regarding any person who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-402_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Comply with any other requirement mandated by section 12009 of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act (49 U.S.C. § 2708).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
