<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-503"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-503/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_503">
        <akn:num>50-503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Arbitration.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established in the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs a Board of Consumer Claims Arbitration for the District of Columbia. The Board shall consist of 7 members who shall be appointed by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The members shall be at least 18 years of age and residents of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Two members shall be attorneys admitted to the practice of law in the District, 1 of whom shall be designated by the Mayor as chairperson of the Board. Two members shall have training and experience in arbitration and mediation. One member shall be the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs or his or her designee. One member shall have experience or training in representing the interests of consumers. One member shall have experience or training in the manufacture or wholesale or retail sales of consumer goods.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall appoint the initial Board members within 60 days of March 14, 1985. Of the members first appointed, the chairperson and 1 other member shall be appointed for terms of 3 years; 2 members shall be appointed for terms of 2 years; 1 member shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and 1 member shall be appointed for a term of 1 year. Subsequent appointments shall be for terms of 3 years. This subsection shall not apply to the representative of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Board shall be compensated pursuant to § 1-611.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall issue, and may amend from time to time, rules and regulations to implement the provisions of this section and may establish reasonable fees for the filing of complaints.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board, in accordance with the rules and regulations issued pursuant to subsection (f) of this section, shall provide arbitration for claims filed by consumers against manufacturers, their agents, or dealers pursuant to §§ 50-502 and 50-505; for claims voluntarily filed by consumers against the provider of any consumer goods or services, who agrees to arbitration, pursuant to rules and regulations issued by the Mayor; and for claims filed pursuant to § 31-2405 by parties agreeing to arbitration pursuant to rules and regulations issued by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consumers may submit claims to the Board by completing forms which shall be approved by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receipt of a written claim filed by a consumer, the Board shall within 5 business days determine whether the claim qualifies for arbitration pursuant to this chapter and notify the opposing party.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall develop and maintain a roster of persons who are residents of the District, at least 18 years of age, and experienced in arbitration techniques who may be employed to serve as arbitrators for specific cases.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall assign cases for arbitration according to the following provisions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board is authorized to reject for arbitration consumer claims which are determined by a majority of the Board to be frivolous, fraudulent, or beyond the legal authority of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall promptly assign all cases accepted for arbitration to an arbitrator or arbitrators who shall appoint a time and place for a hearing and notify the parties personally or by registered mail not less than 5 days prior to the hearing. Hearings shall be public and shall be recorded electronically.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>At all arbitration hearings, the parties are entitled to present oral and written testimony, to present witnesses and evidence relevant to the controversy, to cross-examine witnesses, and to be represented by counsel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board may issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and for the production of books, records, documents, and other evidence. The Board or arbitrators designated by the Board shall have the power to administer oaths and affirmations and take acknowledgements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon application by any party to an arbitration proceeding, or upon its own motion, an arbitrator or arbitration panel may retain independent technical experts as needed to determine the facts in the case. The arbitrator or arbitration panel may assign the costs of the technical experts to 1 or both parties to the case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board or any party to a case may petition the court to issue an order compelling compliance with a decision by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-503_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
