<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-502"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-502/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_502">
        <akn:num>50-502</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Consumer’s remedy for defective vehicles.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a new motor vehicle does not conform to all warranties during the first 18,000 miles of operation or during the period of 2 years following the date of delivery of the motor vehicle to the original purchaser, whichever is the earlier date, the consumer shall during that period report the nonconformity, defect, or condition to the manufacturer, its agent, or its authorized dealer. If the notification is received by the manufacturer’s agent or authorized dealer, the agent or dealer shall within 7 days forward written notice thereof to the manufacturer by certified mail, return receipt requested. The manufacturer, its agent, or its authorized dealer shall correct the nonconformity, defect, or condition at no charge to the consumer, notwithstanding the fact that the repairs may be made after the expiration of the first 18,000-mile period of operation or the 2-year period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, after a reasonable number of attempts, the manufacturer, its agent, or authorized dealer is unable to repair or correct any nonconformity, defect, or condition which results in significant impairment of the motor vehicle, the manufacturer, at the option of the consumer, shall replace the motor vehicle with a comparable motor vehicle, or accept return of the motor vehicle from the consumer and refund to the consumer the full purchase price, including all sales tax, license fees, registration fees, and any similar governmental charges. In calculating a refund, the manufacturer may deduct from the consumer’s full purchase price a reasonable allowance not to exceed 10 cents per mile for the consumer’s use of the motor vehicle in excess of the first 12,000 miles of operation, and a reasonable allowance for any damage not attributable to normal wear or to the nonconformity, defect, or condition which significantly impaired the motor vehicle. Refunds shall be made to the consumer, and the lienholder, if any, as their interests may appear on the records of ownership kept by the Department of Public Works.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each of the following circumstances shall be an affirmative defense to any claim under this section:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be presumed that a reasonable number of attempts have been made to conform a motor vehicle to the warranties, if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The 30-day out-of-service period shall be extended by any time during which repair services are not available to the consumer because of a war, invasion, strike, fire, flood, or other natural disaster.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The consumer, in order to seek the refund or replacement provided by this section, shall first submit a claim to the Board of Consumer Claims Arbitration established pursuant to § 50-503. If the Board rejects the case for arbitration, or if the claim is arbitrated and the consumer rejects the arbitration decision, the consumer may then bring an action in court to seek the remedies provided by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-502_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
