<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-603"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-603/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_603">
        <akn:num>50-603</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bonding of automobile dealers and applicants; liability insurance; designation of Mayor as agent for service of process; limitation on bonds; action on bonds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-603_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In connection with the licensing of persons under the authority of Chapter 28 of Title 47, the Council of the District of Columbia is authorized to require either bonds or such other security as it may by regulation deem necessary, of persons licensed to engage in the business of buying or selling motor vehicles and of persons licensed to engage in the business of purchasing contracts for the retail installment sales of motor vehicles, and the Council may, from time to time, and in its discretion, establish classes and subclasses of such persons and, subject to subsection (b) of this section, specify the amount and conditions of the bond to be deposited by each of the members of any such class or subclass. In connection with the licensing of said persons, and the bonding of the members of any class or subclass of the said persons, the Council, in its discretion, may by regulation require applicants for licenses:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-603_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-603_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person aggrieved by the violation of any law or regulation applicable to the licensee’s conduct of the licensed activity shall have, in addition to his right of action against such licensee, a right to bring suit against the surety on a bond authorized by this section, either alone or jointly with the principal thereon, and to recover in an amount not exceeding the penalty of the bond any damages sustained by reason of any act, transaction, or conduct of the licensee, or of any officer, agent, employee, or other person acting on behalf of said licensee, which is in violation of law or regulation in force in the District relating to the licensed activity. The provisions of paragraphs (2), (3), and (5) of subsection (b) of § 1-301.01, shall be applicable to each bond authorized by this section as if it were the bond authorized by the first subparagraph of such subsection (b) of § 1-301.01; provided, that nothing in this subsection shall be construed to impose upon the surety on any such bond a greater liability than the total amount thereof or the amount remaining unextinguished after any prior recovery or recoveries.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
