<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-602"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-602/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_602">
        <akn:num>50-602</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Maximum finance charges; computation; proportionate adjustments; investigation of economic conditions to determine finance charges; regulations; classification of parties; waiver.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-602_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any instrument of security, refinancing contract, or other instrument to the contrary, made or entered into on or after March 5, 1981, no person shall charge, contract for, receive, or collect a finance charge if such charge exceeds the larger of $25 or an amount determined under the following schedule:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-602_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The finance charge authorized by the preceding subsection shall be computed on the principal balance payable for a motor vehicle from the date of the instrument or contract until the maturity of the final installment, notwithstanding that the balance thereof is required to be paid in installments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-602_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For a period less or greater than 12 months or for amounts less or greater than $100, the amount of the maximum charge set forth in the foregoing schedule shall be decreased or increased proportionately.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-602_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall from time to time investigate the economic conditions and other factors relating to and affecting finance charges, and shall ascertain all pertinent facts necessary to determine what maximum charges should be permitted in such transactions. Upon the basis of such ascertained facts, the Council of the District of Columbia, notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding subsections, shall from time to time by regulation or order determine and fix the maximum finance charges sufficiently high to result in a fair return on investment to persons engaged in the business of financing retail installment transactions, but not so high as to constitute an unreasonable economic burden on the purchasers of motor vehicles under retail installment contracts. The Council may from time to time, upon the basis of changed conditions or facts, redetermine and refix any such maximum finance charge, but, before determining or redetermining any such maximum charge, the Council shall give reasonable notice of its intention to consider doing so, and provide a reasonable opportunity to persons desiring to be heard with respect to any such proposed determination or redetermination. Notice of the action proposed by the Council shall be published once a week for 2 consecutive weeks in 1 or more of the daily newspapers published in the District. Any such changed maximum finance charge shall not affect any pre-existing instrument of security lawfully entered into between the seller and the purchaser of any motor vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-602_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-602_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No provision shall be inserted in any retail installment contract whereby the buyer waives or purports to waive any provision of this chapter, and any such waiver or purported waiver shall be void and of no effect. The Council is authorized in its discretion, by regulation:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
