<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-921.19"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/50-921.19/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_50_921_19">
        <akn:num>50-921.19</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-921_19_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director may inspect private property located on public space and private work performed within public space and may perform such other inspections necessary to protect the public space or public safety or ensure compliance with this subchapter, the regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter, or permits, notices, or orders issued pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-921_19_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Civil fines and penalties may be imposed as sanctions for any violation of this subchapter or any rules promulgated under the authority of this subchapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2 [§ 2-1801.01 et seq.] (“Civil Infractions Act”). Fines and penalties may be imposed for each day that a violation continues. Enforcement and adjudication of a violation shall be pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-921_19_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-921_19_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-921_19_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50-921_19_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director may recover 3 times the cost and expense of removing and disposing of property unlawfully occupying public space, repairing any damage to the public space caused by the violation, and taking action to protect the public from the effects and potential effects of the violation pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
