<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-107.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-107.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_107_03">
        <akn:num>5-107.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of District of Columbia Police Officers Standards and Training Board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is hereby established the District of Columbia Police Officers Standards and Training Board (“Board”).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Membership on the Board shall consist of the following 11 persons who shall be voting members:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, in consultation with the Chief of Police, shall appoint one Metropolitan Police Department Reserve Corps representative as an advisory, nonvoting member of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following persons may be advisory, nonvoting members of the Board:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The appointments to the Board shall be for a 3-year term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No member shall serve beyond the time when he or she holds the office or employment by reason of which he or she was initially eligible for appointment and any member chosen to fill a vacancy created otherwise than by expiration of a term shall be appointed for the unexpired portion of the term of the member whom he or she succeeds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The members shall receive no salary but members shall be reimbursed for their expenses lawfully incurred in the performance of their official functions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members appointed to the Board by the Mayor may be removed by the Mayor for incompetence, neglect of duty, or misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chairperson shall be appointed by the Mayor from among the voting members of the Board and the vice chair shall be elected from among the voting members.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall hold its initial meeting promptly after the appointment and qualification of its members. Thereafter, the Board shall meet a minimum of twice each calendar year and at other times as it or the Board’s Chairperson may determine. The majority of the voting members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, the performance of duties or for the exercise of any of its authority. Advisory members shall be entitled to participate in the business and deliberation of the Board, but shall not be entitled to vote. The Board shall establish its own procedures and requirements with respect to the place and conduct of its meetings.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
