<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-107.04"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-107.04/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_107_04">
        <akn:num>5-107.04</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties of the Board.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall establish minimum application and appointment criteria for the Metropolitan Police Department that include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the minimum standards established by the Board in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, the Chief of Police may deny employment to any applicant based upon conduct occurring while the applicant was a minor if, considering the totality of the circumstances, the Chief of Police determines that the applicant has not displayed the good moral character or integrity necessary to perform the duties of a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each applicant selected for appointment as a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department shall successfully complete an initial training program and initial firearms training program before deployment, including minimum requirements developed by the Board, unless the applicant receives a waiver pursuant to subsection (e) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall determine minimum requirements for the initial training program and initial firearms training program for Metropolitan Police Department recruits, including the appropriate sequence, content, and duration of each program, and:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief of Police may modify or waive the initial training program and initial firearms training program requirements for either of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall determine minimum requirements for a continuing education program for sworn members of the Metropolitan Police Department, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Metropolitan Police Department may utilize the services of other law enforcement agencies or organizations engaged in the education and training of law enforcement personnel to satisfy any portion of the initial training program, the initial firearms training program, or the continuing education program pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall establish the minimum requirements for any instructor of any component of the Metropolitan Police Department’s initial training program, continuing education program, or firearms training program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall establish minimum selection and training standards for members of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Board shall also review and make recommendations to the Chief of Police, the Mayor, and the Council, regarding:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The minimum standards set by the Board pursuant to subsections (a), (d), (f), and (h) of this section shall not preclude the Metropolitan Police Department from establishing higher standards, including standards regarding its application, initial training, and continuing education programs at the department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The minimum standards set by the Board pursuant to subsection (i) of this section shall not preclude the District of Columbia Housing Authority Police Department from establishing higher standards.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than December 31 of each calendar year, the Board, through the Chief of Police, shall deliver a report to the Mayor and the Council concerning the Metropolitan Police Department’s initial training program, continuing education program, and firearms training program. The report shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The administrative work of the Board shall be carried out by members of the Metropolitan Police Department as appointed by the Chief of Police.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any applicant who met the age requirement at the time of application and who was denied appointment on the basis of racial discrimination, as determined by the Director of the Office of Human Rights, may be appointed notwithstanding the applicant’s age at the time of that determination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Applications for appointment to the Metropolitan Police Department shall be made on forms furnished by the Metropolitan Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Appointments to the Metropolitan Police Department shall be for a probationary period to be determined by the Chief of Police. Continuation of service after the expiration of that period shall be dependent upon the conduct of the appointee and his or her capacity for the performance of the duties to which assigned, as indicated by reports of superior officers. The probationary period shall be an extension of the examination period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Police and Fire Clinic shall find any probationer physically or mentally unfit to continue his or her duties, that probationer shall be required to appear before the Police and Firefighters Retirement and Relief Board. That Board shall make any findings as are required pursuant to § 5-713, and those findings shall be incorporated in a recommendation submitted to the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_s">
      <akn:num>(s)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each police officer appointed shall maintain a level of physical fitness to be determined by the Chief of Police. The final determination with respect to inappropriate fitness levels shall be made by the Medical Director of the Police and Fire Clinic.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-107_04_t">
      <akn:num>(t)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
