<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-119.10"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-119.10/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_119_10">
        <akn:num>5-119.10</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Sale at public auction; motor vehicle with lien of record; disposition of proceeds from sale.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-119_10_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to all property (including money), except perishable property, animals, firearms and property of persons with mental illness, not otherwise disposed of in accordance with § 5-119.09, that shall remain in the custody of the Property Clerk for not less than 90 days without being claimed and repossessed, the Property Clerk shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-119_10_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If neither the rightful owner nor the finder appear to claim the lost property, title to such property shall transfer to the District government and the property may be retained by the Mayor for official government use or may be sold at public auction at  such place and time as the Property Clerk may direct and in such a manner as to expose to the inspection of bidders all property so offered for sale. The Property Clerk needs not offer any property for sale if, in the Property Clerk’s opinion, the probable cost  of sale exceeds the value of the property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-119_10_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The purchaser at any sale conducted by the Property Clerk pursuant to this section shall receive title to the property purchased, free from all claims of the rightful owner or the finder of the property and all persons claiming through and under the rightful owner or the finder. The Property Clerk shall execute all documents necessary to complete the transfer of title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-119_10_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All proceeds from any sale under this section shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-119_10_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-119_10_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
