<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-1107"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-1107/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_1107">
        <akn:num>5-1107</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Authority of the Office and processing of complaint.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall have the authority to receive and to dismiss, conciliate, mediate, or adjudicate a citizen complaint against a member or members of the MPD, and any other agency pursuant to subsection (j) of this section that alleges abuse or misuse of police powers by such member or members, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a complaint alleges misconduct that is not within the authority of the Office to review, the Executive Director shall refer the allegation to the Police Chief for further processing by the MPD, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any individual having personal knowledge of alleged police misconduct may file a complaint with the Office on behalf of a victim.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be timely, a complaint must be received by the Office within 45 days from the date of the incident that is the subject of the complaint. The Executive Director may extend the deadline for good cause.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each complaint shall be reduced to writing and signed by the complainant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Complaint forms shall conclude with the following words: “I hereby certify that to the best of my knowledge, and under penalty of perjury, the statements made herein are true.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Director shall screen each complaint and may request additional information from the complainant. Within 7 working days of the receipt of the complaint, or within 7 working days of the receipt of additional information requested from the complainant, the Executive Director shall take one of the following actions:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Director shall notify in writing the complainant and the subject police officer or officers of the action taken under subsection (g) of this section. If the complaint is dismissed, the notice shall be accompanied by a brief statement of the reasons for the dismissal, and the Executive Director shall notify the complainant that the complaint may be brought to the attention of the Police Chief who may direct that the complaint be investigated and that appropriate action be taken.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of § 1-616.01 [repealed], the receipt by the Office of an oral or written complaint shall not constitute knowledge or cause to know of acts, occurrences, or allegations contained in such complaint. For purposes of § 1-616.01, the MPD shall be deemed to know or have cause to know of the acts, occurrences, or allegations in a complaint received by the Office at the time the MPD receives written notice from the Office that an allegation in a complaint processed by the Office has been sustained.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This subchapter shall also apply to the District of Columbia Housing Authority Police Department and to any federal law enforcement agency that, pursuant to Chapter 3 of this title, has a cooperative agreement with the MPD that requires coverage by the Office; provided, that the Chief of the respective law enforcement department or agency shall perform the duties of the MPD Chief of Police for the members of their respective departments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1107_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>By February 1 of each year, the Office of Police Complaints shall provide a report to the Council on the effectiveness of the Metropolitan Police Department’s Body-Worn Camera Program, including an analysis of use of force incidents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
