<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-132.21"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-132.21/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_132_21">
        <akn:num>5-132.21</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>School safe passage emergency zones.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Chief of Police may declare any area within 1,000 feet of the perimeter of the grounds of a District of Columbia public school or public charter school or within 300 feet of the boundary of the area affecting passage between the school and proximate public transportation a school safe passage emergency zone during a school day for a period not to exceed 5 consecutive school days when the school is in session. The Chief of Police shall inform his or her commanders, the Mayor, and the Council of the declaration of a school safe passage emergency zone and explain the basis for it pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining whether to designate a school safe passage emergency zone, the Chief of Police shall find the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon the designation of a school safe passage emergency zone, the MPD shall mark each block within the school safe passage emergency zone by using barriers, tape, signs, or police officers that post or announce the following information in the immediate area of, and borders around, the school safe passage emergency zone:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates this section shall, upon conviction, be subject to a fine of not more than $300, or imprisonment for not more than 6 months.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-132_21_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or his or her assistants, shall prosecute all violations of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
