<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-1402"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-1402/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_1402">
        <akn:num>5-1402</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner; appointments, qualifications, and compensation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1402_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as a subordinate agency in the executive branch of the government of the District of Columbia, the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner (“OCME”).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1402_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall nominate, with the advice and consent of the Council, a person to serve as the Chief Medical Examiner (“CME”) within the OCME pursuant to § 1-523.01(a). The CME shall be responsible for the management and operation of the OCME. The CME shall appoint a Deputy CME, to be paid at an annual rate of $206,000, and any other medical examiners the CME finds necessary to carry out the duties of the OCME.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1402_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1402_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall fix the compensation of the CME pursuant to subchapter X-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1 [§ 1-610.51 et seq.]. The Mayor shall fix the compensation of all medical examiners appointed by the CME pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1402_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CME shall be appointed for a 6-year term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1402_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a vacancy in the position of Chief Medical Examiner occurs as a consequence of resignation, disability, death, or a reason other than the expiration of the term of the Chief Medical Examiner, the Mayor shall appoint a replacement to fill the unexpired term in the same manner provided in § 1-523.01(a). A person appointed to fill the unexpired term shall serve only for the remainder of the term.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
