<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-1501.07"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-1501.07/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_1501_07">
        <akn:num>5-1501.07</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Impaired driving program; certification and testing of breath alcohol equipment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1501_07_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall be responsible for testing and certifying the accuracy of any District instrument utilized by District law enforcement personnel to test the alcohol content of breath. A District breath test instrument shall only be used by District law enforcement personnel if it has been certified by the Department, or the Department’s designee, to be accurate. Certification of the accuracy of each breath test instrument shall occur at least once every 180 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1501_07_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the requirements under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1501_07_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall issue regulations to meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1501_07_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director may delegate by memorandum of agreement some or all of the responsibilities of this section, as well as some or all of the responsibilities for providing forensic science services pertaining to breath testing as provided by § 5-1501.08(a)(1) to the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-1501_07_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section shall apply as of October 1, 2012.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
