<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-335.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-335.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_335_01">
        <akn:num>5-335.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement of the post-and-forfeiture procedure.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The resolution of a criminal charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure is not a conviction of a crime and shall not be equated to a criminal conviction. The fact that a person resolved a charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure may not be relied upon by any District of Columbia court or agency in a subsequent criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding or administrative action to impose any sanction, penalty, enhanced sentence, or civil disability.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The post-and-forfeit procedure may be offered by a releasing official to arrestees who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever a releasing official tenders an offer to an arrestee to resolve a criminal charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure, the offer shall be accompanied by a written notice provided to the arrestee describing the post-and-forfeit procedure and the consequences of resolving the criminal charge using this procedure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The written notice required by subsection (d) of this section shall include, at a minimum, the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The written notice required by subsection (d) of this section shall comply with ยง 2-1933.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-335_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An arrestee who is provided the written notice required by subsection (d) of this section and who wishes to resolve the criminal charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure shall, after reading the notice, sign the bottom of the notice, thereby acknowledging receiving the information provided in the notice and agreeing to accept the offer to resolve the charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure. After the arrestee signs the notice, the arrestee shall be provided with a copy of the signed notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
