<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-331.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-331.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_331_05">
        <akn:num>5-331.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Notice and plan approval process for First Amendment assemblies — Generally.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall not be an offense to assemble or parade on a District street, sidewalk, or other public way, or in a District park, without having provided notice or obtained an approved assembly plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The purpose of the notice and plan approval process is to avoid situations where more than one group seeks to use the same space at the same time and to provide the MPD and other District agencies the ability to provide appropriate police protection, traffic control, and other support for participants and other individuals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, a person or group who wishes to conduct a First Amendment assembly on a District street, sidewalk, or other public way, or in a District park, shall give notice and apply for approval of an assembly plan before conducting the assembly.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person or group who wishes to conduct a First Amendment assembly on a District street, sidewalk, or other public way, or in a District park, is not required to give notice or apply for approval of an assembly plan before conducting the assembly where:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not enforce any user fees on persons or groups that organize or conduct First Amendment assemblies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not require, separate from or in addition to the requirements for giving notice of or applying for approval of an assembly plan for a First Amendment assembly, that persons give notice to, or obtain a permit or plan from, the Chief of Police, or other District officials or agencies, as a prerequisite for making or delivering an address, speech, or sermon regarding any political, social, or religious subject in any District street, sidewalk, other public way, or park.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not require, separate from or in addition to the requirements for giving notice of or applying for approval of an assembly plan for a First Amendment assembly, that persons give notice to, or obtain a permit or plan from the Chief of Police, the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or any other District official or agency as a prerequisite for using a stand or structure in connection with such an assembly; provided, that a First Amendment assembly plan may contain limits on the nature, size, or number of stands or structures to be used as required to maintain public safety. Individuals conducting a First Amendment assembly under subsection (d) of this section may use a stand or structure so long as it does not prevent others from using the sidewalk.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-331_05_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall not require, separate from or in addition to the requirements for giving notice of or applying for approval of an assembly plan for a First Amendment assembly, that persons give notice to, or obtain a permit or plan from, the Chief of Police, the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or any other District official or agency as a prerequisite for selling demonstration-related merchandise within an area covered by an approved plan or within an assembly covered by subsection (d) of this section; provided, that nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize any person to sell merchandise in a plan-approved area contrary to the wishes of the plan-holder.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
