<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-405"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-405/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_405">
        <akn:num>5-405</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Workweek established; hours of duty; days off duty; holidays.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning with the 1st day of the 1st pay period which begins not less than 120 days after enactment of this amendatory subsection or which begins on or after July 1, 1962, whichever is later, the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized and directed to establish a workweek for officers and members of the Firefighting Division of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia which will result in an average workweek of not to exceed 48 hours during an administratively established workweek cycle which the Mayor is hereby authorized to establish from time to time.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Firefighting Division shall operate under a 2-shift system and all hours of duty of any shift shall be consecutive.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is further authorized and directed to establish a workweek for officers and members of the Fire Department, other than those in the Firefighting Division, of 40 hours, and the hours of work in such workweek shall be performed on consecutive days in such workweek: Provided, that notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent or agents may, whenever the exigencies of the Fire Department require temporary or short-term services of 1 or more officers or members, order such officer, officers, member, or members to perform such services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The days off duty to which each officer or member of the Fire Department is entitled shall be in addition to his annual leave and sick leave allowed by law. In the case of any shift of the Fire Department beginning on 1 day and extending without a break in continuity into the next day, or in the case of 2 shifts beginning on the same day, the Mayor is authorized to designate the shift which shall be the workday, and the entire shift so designated shall be considered the workday for all pay and leave purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a holiday shall fall on any day off of any officer or member of the Fire Department, he shall be excused from duty on such other day as is designated by the Mayor of the District of Columbia, and if he is required to be on duty in lieu of such day off, he shall receive compensation for such duty at the rate provided by law for duty performed on a holiday. When any shift of the Fire Department begins on the day before a holiday and extends without a break in continuity into the holiday, or begins on a holiday and extends without a break in continuity into the next day, the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to designate either of such shifts as the holiday workday, and the entire shift so designated shall be considered as the holiday workday for all pay and leave purposes. As used in this subsection, the word “holiday” shall have the same meaning as such word has in § 5-521.02, and as supplemented by § 6103 of Title 5, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For fiscal years 2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015, and except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, no officer or member shall be permitted to earn overtime compensation for overtime work performed in a pay period after that officer or member has received sick leave in the same pay period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-405_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The restrictions in subsections (f) and (g) of this section shall not apply during pay periods 1 and 2 of calendar year 2013.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
