<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-543.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-543.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_543_01">
        <akn:num>5-543.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Minimum rate for original appointments; rates for reappointments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-543_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, all original appointments of police and fire privates shall be made at the minimum rate set forth in the schedule in § 5-541.01, and the 1st year of service shall be probationary.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-543_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, or the United States Park Police force who separates from that force, Department, or Division, and who is subsequently reappointed to such force, Department, or Division within 3 years after the date of such separation shall receive any scheduled rate of basic compensation provided in salary class 1 of the salary schedule in § 5-541.01(a) which does not exceed the scheduled rate of basic compensation being paid at the time of such reappointment for the class and service step he had attained at the time of his separation. For purposes of this subsection, no additional compensation authorized by this subchapter shall be used in determining service step placement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-543_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, employees appointed pursuant to § 1-610.72 shall be appointed at a step of Class 1 consistent with that officer’s law enforcement experience, without regard to any time in grade or prior Departmental service or incumbency requirements. Such employees shall serve an 18-month probationary period.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
