<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-544.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-544.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_544_01">
        <akn:num>5-544.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Service longevity.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-544_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-544_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this or any other law, individuals retired from active service prior to the effective date of the District of Columbia Police and Firemen’s Salary Act Amendments of 1972, and who are entitled to receive a pension relief allowance or retirement compensation under subchapter I of Chapter 7 of this title, shall not be entitled to receive an increase in their pension relief allowance or retirement compensation by reason of the enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-544_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this or any other law, each Deputy Chief of the Metropolitan Police force and of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia shall, upon completion of 30 years of continuous service on the police force or Fire Department, as the case may be, be placed in, and receive basic compensation at, the highest service step in the salary class to which his position is assigned in the salary schedule contained in § 5-541.01. For purposes of this subsection, in computing a Deputy Chief ’s continuous service on the police force or Fire Department, there shall be included only those periods of his service determined to have been satisfactory service and any period of his service in the Armed Forces of the United States other than any period of such service:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-544_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-544_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For employees transferred pursuant to § 5-409.01, any continuous prior service with the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department shall constitute years of continuous service to the District of Columbia for the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
