<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-633"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-633/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_633">
        <akn:num>5-633</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Medical leave for performance of duty injuries and illnesses; referral for disability retirement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (e) and (g) of this section, if the Director, in consultation with the Police and Fire Clinic physicians, determines that a member can neither perform the full range of duties nor work in a limited-duty status due to a performance-of-duty injury or illness, the member shall be entitled to non-chargeable medical leave and shall receive administrative pay for a period of not more than 2 years in accordance with rules established by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, if at any time the Director, in consultation with the Police and Fire Clinic physicians, determines that a member who has sustained a performance-of-duty injury or illness will not be able to perform the full range of duties after achieving maximum medical improvement, the Director shall recommend the member for retirement pursuant to ยง 5-710.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (e) and (f) of this section, and regardless of whether the prognosis is that the member will be able to perform the full range of duties after achieving maximum medical improvement, the Director shall process for retirement pursuant to ยง 5-710, those members of the Metropolitan Police Department who spend all or part of 172 cumulative work days in a less-than-full-duty status over any 2-year period as a result of any one performance-of-duty injury or illness, including any complications relating to the injury or illness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (e), (f) and (g) of this section, and regardless of whether the prognosis is that the member will be able to perform the full range of duties after achieving maximum medical improvement, the Director shall process for retirement pursuant to ยง 5-710, those Fire and Emergency Medical Services members who spend 64 cumulative work days in a less-than-full-duty status over any 2-year period as a result of any one performance-of-duty injury or illness, including any complications relating to the injury or illness.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a member has sustained a serious or life-threatening injury or illness in the performance of duty that may require more than 2 years of medical treatment for the member to achieve maximum medical improvement, and the prognosis is that the member eventually will be able to perform the full range of duties, the Director, in consultation with Police and Fire Clinic physicians, may recommend to the Chief that the member be provided with additional non-chargeable medical leave and disability compensation pay until the member achieves maximum medical improvement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall not apply to members who are unable to perform the full range of duties as a result of pregnancy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-633_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
