<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-701"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-701/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_701">
        <akn:num>5-701</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The terms “disabled” and “disability” mean disabled for useful and efficient service in the grade or class of position last occupied by the member by reason of disease or injury, not due to vicious habits or intemperance as determined by the Board of Police and Fire Surgeons, or willful misconduct on his part as determined by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “widow” means the surviving wife of a member or former member if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “widower” means the surviving husband of a member or former member if, in the case of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or the United States Secret Service Division, or the surviving husband of a member or former member who was a member or officer of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “basic salary” means regular salary established by law or regulation, including any differential for special occupational assignment, but shall not include overtime, holiday, or military pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “annuitant” means any former member who, on the basis of his service, has met all requirements of this subchapter for title to annuity and has filed claim therefor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “survivor” means a person who is entitled to annuity under this subchapter based on the service of a deceased member or of a deceased annuitant.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “survivor annuitant” means a survivor who has filed claim for annuity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “police or fire service” means all honorable service in the Metropolitan Police Department, United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, and the United States Secret Service Division coming under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “military service” means honorable active service in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard of the United States, but shall not include service in the National Guard except when ordered to active duty in the service of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designated agent or agents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “service” means employment which is creditable under § 5-704.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “government” means the executive, judicial, and legislative branches of the United States government, including government owned or controlled corporations and Gallaudet College, and the municipal government of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “government service” means honorable active service in the executive, judicial, or legislative branches of the United States government, including government owned or controlled corporations, and Gallaudet College, and the municipal government of the District of Columbia, and for which retirement deductions, other than social security deductions, were made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “department” means any part of the executive branch of the United States government, or any part of the government of the District of Columbia whose members come under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “average pay” means the highest annual rate resulting from averaging the member’s rates of basic salary in effect over any 36 consecutive months of police or fire service in the case of a member who is an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia and who first becomes such a member after the end of the 90-day period beginning on November 17, 1979, or over any 12 consecutive months of police or fire service in the case of any other member, with each rate weighted by the time it was in effect, except that if the member retires under § 5-710 and if on the date of his retirement under the section he has not completed 12 consecutive months or 36 consecutive months, as the case may be, of police or fire service, such term means his basic salary at the time of his retirement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “adjusted average pay” means the average pay of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, the United States Secret Service Division, the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia increased by the per centum increase (adjusted to the nearest one tenth of 1%) in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, between the month in which such member retires and the month immediately prior to the month in which such member dies; except that in the case of members hired on or after the first day of the first pay period that begins after October 29, 1996, the increase shall not exceed 3% per annum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “full range of duties” means the ability of a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department to perform all of the essential functions of police work or fire suppression as determined by the established policies and procedures of the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department and to meet the physical examination and physical agility standards established under §§ 5-107.02a and 5-451.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-701_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Internal Revenue Code” or “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Stat. 2085; 26 U.S.C. § 1 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
