<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-706"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-706/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_706">
        <akn:num>5-706</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Deductions, deposits, and refunds; order of persons entitled to refunds for deductions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>On and after the first day of the first pay period that begins on or after October 26, 1970, there shall be deducted and withheld from each member’s basic salary an amount equal to 7% of such basic salary for all members hired before the first day of the first pay period that begins after October 29, 1996, and 8% of such basic salary for all members hired on or after the first day of the first pay period that begins after October 29, 1996. In the case of a member who is an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, these deductions and withholdings shall be paid to the District of Columbia Retirement Board and shall be deposited in the District of Columbia Police Officers and Fire Fighters’ Retirement Fund established by § 1-712, and in the case of any other member, these deductions and withholdings shall be paid to the Collector of Taxes of the District of Columbia and shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the District of Columbia. Amounts deducted and withheld from the basic salary of each member of the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department shall be:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to facilitate the settlement of the accounts of each member coming under the provisions of this subchapter who dies prior to retirement leaving no survivor entitled to receive an annuity under the provisions of such sections, the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall pay all deductions for retirement made from the salary of such deceased member to the person or persons surviving at the time of death, in the following order of precedence, and such payment shall be a bar to recovery by any other person of amounts so paid:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to facilitate the settlement of the accounts of each former member coming under the provisions of this subchapter who dies leaving no survivor entitled to receive an annuity under the provisions of this subchapter and before the aggregate amount of the annuity paid to such former member equals the total amount deducted and withheld for retirement from his salary as a member, the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall pay the difference to the person or persons surviving at the time of death in the following order of precedence, and such payment shall be a bar to recovery by any other person of the amount so paid:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual withdrawing a distribution under this subchapter, which distribution constitutes an eligible rollover distribution within the meaning of section 402(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, may elect, at the time and in the manner prescribed by the District of Columbia Retirement Board, and after receipt of proper notice, to have any portion of an eligible rollover distribution paid directly to an eligible retirement plan, within the meaning of section 402(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, in a direct rollover in accordance with section 401(a)(31) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Retirement Board shall be entrusted with any transfer from another retirement plan for the purchase of service credit, including transfers allowed by sections 403(b) and 457 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. § 403; 26 U.S.C. § 457]. Before any transfer is received, the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall be presented with documentation sufficient to satisfy the provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 governing the substantiation of proposed transfers for the purchase of service credit.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this subchapter shall constitute a defined benefit plan and a governmental plan as described in section 414(d) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, which is intended to qualify under section 401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in this subchapter, Chapter 7 of Title 1 (§ 1-701 et seq.), or Chapter 9 of Title 1 (§ 1-901 et seq.), the provisions of this subchapter shall apply to and control the provision of an annuity payable. The District of Columbia Retirement Board shall administer the plan in the manner required to satisfy the applicable qualification requirements for a qualified governmental plan pursuant to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. If a conflict should arise with a qualification requirement, the provision shall be interpreted in favor of maintaining the federal qualification requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Retirement Board may adopt rules to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Effective January 1, 2007, benefits payable under this subchapter shall not be paid until at least 30 days (or shorter period as may be permitted by law) but no more than 180 days after a member’s receipt of all required distribution notices and election forms pursuant to section 402(f) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. The required notices must include a description of the member’s right (if any) to defer receipt of a distribution, the consequences of failing to defer receipt of the distribution, the relative value of optional forms of benefit, and other information as may be required by applicable regulations and guidance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provisions of this subchapter to the contrary, upon the employer’s request, a contribution which was made by a mistake of fact shall be returned to the employer by the trustee within one year after the payment of the contribution. A portion of a contribution returned pursuant to this section shall be adjusted to reflect any earnings or gains. Notwithstanding any provisions of this subchapter to the contrary, the right or claim of a participant or beneficiary to an asset of the trust or a benefit under this subchapter shall be subject to and limited by the provisions of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-706_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
