<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-710"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-710/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_710">
        <akn:num>5-710</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Retirement for disability — Incurred or aggravated in performance of duty.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (e) and (e-1) of this section, whenever any member is injured or contracts a disease in the performance of duty or such injury or disease is aggravated by such duty at any time after appointment and such injury or disease or aggravation permanently disables him for the performance of duty, he shall, upon retirement for such disability, receive an annuity computed at the rate of 2 1/2 of his average pay for each year or portion thereof of his service; provided, that such annuity shall not exceed 70% of his average pay, nor shall it be less than 66 2/3 of his average pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any case involving a member who is an officer or member of the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division, or the United States Secret Service Division, in which the proximate cause of injury incurred or disease contracted by the member is doubtful, or is shown to be other than the performance of duty, and such injury or disease is shown to have been aggravated by the performance of duty to such an extent that the member is permanently disabled for the performance of duty, such disability shall be construed to have been incurred in the performance of duty. The member shall, upon retirement for such disability, receive an annuity computed at the rate of 2½ of his average pay for each year or portion thereof of his service; provided, that such annuity shall not exceed 70% of his average pay, nor shall it be less than 66⅔ of his average pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member shall be retired under this section only upon the recommendation of the Board of Police and Fire Surgeons and the concurrence therein by the Mayor, except that in any case in which a member seeks his own retirement under this section, he shall, in the absence of such recommendation, provide the necessary evidence to form the basis for the approval of such retirement by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_e_1">
      <akn:num>(e-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Whenever the Board of Police and Fire Surgeons receives a recommendation from the Director for a disability retirement of a Metropolitan Police Department or Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department member pursuant to Chapter 6A of this title, the Board of Police and Fire Surgeons shall make a disability assessment and, if the member is unable to perform the full range of duties, shall retire the member as disabled regardless of whether the member is performing useful and efficient services that are less than the full range of duties. The member shall be retired on an annuity determined in accordance with subsection (e)(2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 90 days after November 17, 1979, the Board of Police and Fire Surgeons shall submit to the Mayor recommendations for regulations to establish specific criteria for determining whether an injury was incurred, or a disease was contracted, in the performance of duty and whether an injury or disease was aggravated in the performance of duty. The Mayor shall promulgate regulations establishing such criteria in a timely manner based on the recommendations of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-710_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
