<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-718"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-718/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_718">
        <akn:num>5-718</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Cost-of-living adjustments of annuities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each month the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall determine the per centum change in the price index. On the basis of this determination, and effective the 1st day of the 3rd month which begins after the price index shall have equaled the rise of at least 3% for 3 consecutive months over the price index for the base month, each annuity payable under this subchapter which: (1) is payable to a survivor of a member who was an officer or member of the United States Park Police force, the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division or the United States Secret Service Division; and (2) has a commencing date on or before such effective date shall be increased by 1% plus the per centum rise in the price index. For purposes of this subsection, the term “base month” means the month for which the price index showed a per centum rise forming the basis for a cost-of-living annuity increase under this subsection, except that, until the 1st cost-of-living annuity increase under this subsection, the base month shall be the last month which was the base month for purposes of § 5-716.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to any annuity payable under this subchapter which is payable to a member who was an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia hired prior to January 1, 1980, or to a survivor of any such member, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), and for payments of benefits accrued by police officers and fire fighters after June 30, 1997, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_c_1">
      <akn:num>(c-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With respect to any annuity payable under this section which is payable to a member who was an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Colombia, hired after December 31, 1979, or to a survivor of any such member, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_c_2">
      <akn:num>(c-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The monthly installment of annuity after adjustment under this section shall be fixed at the nearest dollar, except that such installment shall after adjustment reflect an increase of at least $1.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-718_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term “price index” means the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published monthly by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
