<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-712"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-712/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_712">
        <akn:num>5-712</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Optional retirement.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any member who first becomes employed on or after the first day of the first pay period that begins after October 29, 1996, and who completes 25 years of service, and gives at least 60 days written advanced notice to his department stating his intention to retire and stating the date of which he will retire, may voluntarily retire from the service and shall be entitled to an annuity computed at a rate of 2.5% of the member’s average pay times the number of years of the member’s creditable service; provided that such notice requirement may be waived by the department head when, in his opinion, circumstances justify such waiver; provided further, that whenever the Mayor shall determine that there exists an emergency which is likely to endanger the safety of the public and that the public safety cannot be adequately protected except by suspending the retirement provisions of this subsection, then the Mayor shall be authorized, upon notice to the District of Columbia Retirement Board, to suspend the retirement provisions of this subsection in any 1 or more of the departments under his jurisdiction until such time as, in the opinion of the Mayor, public safety can be adequately protected without such suspension. Any member who is an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia and first becomes such a member after the end of the 90-day period beginning on November 17, 1979, and who completes 25 years of police or fire service and attains the age of 50 years and any other member (other than a member who is an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia who first becomes such a member after the end of such 90-day period) who completes 20 years of police or fire service may, after giving at least 60 days written advance notice to his department head stating his intention to retire and stating the date on which he will retire, voluntarily retire from the service and shall be entitled to an annuity computed at the rate of 2.5% of his average pay for each year of service; except that the rate of 3% of his average pay shall be used to compute each year’s police or fire service in excess of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of the first sentence of subsection (a) of this section, the term “creditable service” means the period of employment with the Metropolitan Police Department for police officers and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia for fire fighters first employed on or after the first day of the first pay period which begins after October 29, 1996, and includes any United States military service including the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law, rule, or regulation, sworn members of the Metropolitan Police Department and the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department hired before or on September 11, 2008, may make a one-time election, at their option, in writing, to participate in one of the retirement programs created by subsection (a) of this section; provided, that any and all additional costs above the costs which would otherwise be incurred by the District for that sworn member pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be paid by the member, as determined by actuaries appointed by the District of Columbia. The District shall not be responsible for any additional administrative or program costs associated with a retirement program transfer authorized by this subsection. All costs associated with the transfer to a new retirement program under this subsection shall be borne by the member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other law, rule, or regulation, sworn members of the Metropolitan Police Department and the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department hired after September 11, 2008, shall make a one-time election, at their option, in writing, to participate in one of the retirement programs created by subsection (a) of this section; provided, that any and all additional costs above the costs which would otherwise be incurred by the District for that sworn member pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be paid by the member, as determined by actuaries appointed by the District of Columbia. The District shall not be responsible for any additional administrative or program costs associated with a retirement program selection authorized by this subsection. All costs associated with the selection of a retirement program under this subsection shall be borne by the member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any member of the Metropolitan Police force or of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia having reached the age of 60 years shall, in the discretion of the Mayor, and any member of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division or of the United States Park Police force or of the United States Secret Service Division to whom this subchapter apply shall, in the discretion of the head of his department, be retired from the service and shall be entitled to receive an annuity as computed under subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No annuity granted under subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall exceed 80% of the average pay of such member.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In computing an annuity under this section, the police or fire service of a member who has not retired prior to the effective date of this subsection shall include, without regard to the limitation imposed by subsection (c) of this section, the days of unused sick leave credited to him. Days of unused sick leave shall not be counted in determining a member’s eligibility for an annuity under this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any member who is an officer or member of the Metropolitan Police force or the Fire Department of the District of Columbia who completes 18 years of police or fire service may voluntarily retire from the service on or before December 31, 1980, and shall be entitled to an annuity computed at the rate of 2.5% of the average pay of such member or officer for each year of service; provided, that the amortization payment to the District of Columbia Retirement Board for the District of Columbia Police Officers and Fire Fighters’ Retirement Fund shall be made from appropriations of the Metropolitan Police and Fire Departments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the first sentence of subsection (a) of this section, Charles H. Ramsey, Chief of Police, may voluntarily retire from the service and, effective April 21, 1998, the date of his appointment as Chief of Police, shall be entitled to an annuity computed at a rate of 3.43% of his average pay times the number of years of his creditable service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the first sentence of subsection (a) of this section, at the time that Chief of Police Cathy L. Lanier voluntarily retires or is otherwise separated from the Metropolitan Police Department, she shall be entitled to an annuity computed at 71.5% of her average highest base pay for 36 consecutive months, including longevity payments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A member who meets the requirements for receiving an annuity under this subchapter, but for the fact that the member has not yet retired, shall be 100% vested in the member’s annuity.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-712_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each year, the District of Columbia Retirement Board shall set the applicable interest rate, mortality table, and cost-of-living factor to be used in the determination of actuarial equivalents or for other pertinent benefit calculations under the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
