<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-716"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-716/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_716">
        <akn:num>5-716</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Survivor benefits and annuities.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If any member:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the case of any member who dies in the performance of duty after December 29, 1993, and leaves a widow or widower entitled to all or a portion of the benefit described in subsection (a) of this section, an additional annuity shall be paid. This annuity shall be equal to 100% of the member’s pay at the time of death. The annuity shall be increased at the same rate as the change in the Consumer Price Index, as described in § 5-721. This benefit shall be paid in lieu of benefits provided for by subsections (b) and (c) of this section. However, after benefits provided for in this paragraph end, as provided in subsection (e) of this section, any remaining benefit pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall commence to be paid.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The determination of the Mayor authorized by subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to review and final determination by the District of Columbia Retirement Board.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In case of the death of any member before retirement, of any former member after retirement, or of any member entitled to receive an annuity under § 5-717 (regardless of whether such member is receiving such annuity at the time of death), leaving a widow or widower, such widow or widower shall be entitled to receive an annuity in the greater amount of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each surviving child or student child of any member who dies before retirement, of any former member who dies after retirement, or of any member entitled to receive an annuity under § 5-717 (regardless of whether such member is receiving such annuity at the time of death), shall be entitled to receive an annuity equal to the smallest of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each widow or widower who, on the effective date of the Policemen and Firemen’s Retirement and Disability Act Amendments of 1970, was receiving relief or annuity computed in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be entitled to receive an annuity in the greater amount of: (1) $3,144; or (2) thirty-five per centum of the basis upon which such relief or annuity was computed. Each child who, on October 3, 2001, was receiving relief or annuity computed in accordance with the provisions of this section, shall be entitled to benefits computed in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any member retiring under § 5-709, § 5-710, or § 5-712, may at the time of such retirement, and any member entitled to receive an annuity under § 5-717 may at the time such annuity commences, elect to receive a reduced annuity in lieu of full annuity, and designate in writing the person to receive an increased annuity after such member’s death; provided, that the person so designated be the surviving spouse or child of such member. Whenever such an election is made, the annuity of the designee shall be increased by an amount equal to the amount by which the annuity of such member is reduced. The annuity payable to the member making such election shall be reduced by 10% of the annuity computed as provided in § 5-709, § 5-710, or § 5-712. Such increase in annuity payable to the designee shall be reduced by 5% for each full 5 years the designee is younger than the member, but such total reduction shall not exceed 40%. The increase in annuity payable to the designee pursuant to this subsection shall be paid in addition to the annuity provided for such designee pursuant to subsection (b) or subsection (c) of this section and shall be subject to the same limitations as to duration and other conditions as the annuity paid pursuant to subsections (b), (c), and (e) of this section. If, at any time after such former member’s election, the designee dies, and is survived by such former member, the annuity payable to such former member shall be increased to the amount computed as provided in § 5-709, § 5-710, § 5-712, or § 5-717, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-716_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In the event a member to whom this section applies shall die after January 1, 2007, while performing qualified military service, the survivor or survivors of the member shall be entitled to receive any additional benefits provided under this section (other than benefit accruals relating to the period of qualified military service), as if the member resumed employment and then terminated employment on account of death. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified military service” shall mean military service in the uniformed services (as defined in 38 U.S.C. § 43) by a member, if the member is entitled to reemployment rights with respect to such military service, all within the meaning of section 414(u)(5) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
