<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-721"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-721/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_721">
        <akn:num>5-721</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Duties of Mayor; proceedings related thereto; disability retiree to report employment and undergo medical examination; overpayments.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-721_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall consider all cases for the retirement of members and all applications for annuities under this subchapter subject to review and final determination by the District of Columbia Retirement Board. In each case of retirement of a member the Mayor shall certify in writing the physical condition of the member for whom retirement is sought. The Mayor shall give written notice to any member under consideration by him for retirement to appear before him and to give evidence under oath. The proceedings before the Mayor involving the retirement of any member, or any application for an annuity under this subchapter, shall be reduced to writing and shall show the date of appointment of such member, his age, his record in the service, and any other information which may be pertinent to the matter of such retirement or annuity. The Mayor is authorized to administer oaths and affirmations, may require by subpoena or otherwise the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documents at any designated place. In the event of contumacy or refusal to obey any such subpoena or requirement under this section, the Mayor may apply to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order requiring obedience thereto. Thereupon the Court, with or without notice and hearing, as it in its discretion may decide, shall make such order as is proper and may punish as a contempt any failure to comply with such order in accordance with the provisions of ยง 11-944.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-721_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-721_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except in a case of fraud against the District of Columbia, the Mayor may waive collection of any amount less than $100 which was paid to an annuitant in excess of the amount to which such annuitant was entitled under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
