<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-761"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/5-761/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_5_761">
        <akn:num>5-761</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Retired police officer redeployment.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except for a disability annuitant, a police officer retired from the Metropolitan Police Department shall be eligible for rehire at the discretion of the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department as a fully sworn temporary full-time or temporary part-time police officer without jeopardy to the retirement benefits of the police officer.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A retired police officer who is rehired under this section shall be vested with full police powers, including, but not limited to, the authority to carry a firearm.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Service under this section shall not count as creditable service for the purposes of ยง 5-704.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A retired police officer who is rehired under this section shall be paid a salary of no more than that equal to the salary paid a Class 1, Step 5 Officer and shall not be eligible for longevity pay.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, a rehired annuitant shall not be required to refund any salary paid prior to January 5, 1993.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No retired police officer who is rehired under this section shall be detailed to any agency of the District of Columbia government other than the Metropolitan Police Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5-761_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall apply to any police officer hired after September 29, 1992.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
