<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1131"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1131/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1131">
        <akn:num>2-1131</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bid Proposal” means the bid formally submitted by WBRC 2012 to the USOC on December 15, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Host City” means the entity that has been selected by the International Olympic Committee to host the 2012 Olympic Games.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“International Olympic Committee” and “IOC” mean the International Olympic Committee, a body corporate under international law created by the Congress of Paris of 23rd June, 1894, and having perpetual succession.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Olympic Games” means the Olympic Games sponsored by and governed by the International Olympic Committee and any other educational, cultural, athletic, or sporting events related or preliminary thereto.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Organizing Committee for the Olympic Games” and “OCOG” mean the Committee formed by WBRC 2012 to organize and conduct the Olympic Games if WBRC 2012 is selected by the IOC as the Host City in 2005.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Regional Authority” and “Chesapeake Regional Olympic Games Authority” mean the instrumentality of the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Virginia, State of Maryland, and the City of Baltimore, which authority shall have the powers and duties set forth in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Regional Authority Advisory Committee” means a body formed by the Regional Authority that shall be composed of representatives from each of the local jurisdictions substantially impacted by hosting the Olympic games in the region.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Signatory” means Maryland, Virginia, the City of Baltimore, or the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“United States Olympic Committee” and “USOC” mean the United States Olympic Committee, incorporated by Act of Congress on September 21, 1950, and having perpetual succession.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“U.S. Candidate City” means the entity that has received the United States Olympic Committee’s endorsement to submit to the IOC the sole bid from the United States for the hosting of the 2012 Olympic Games.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1131_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“WBRC 2012” means Washington/Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition, a nonprofit corporation organized under the laws of the State of Maryland, and its successors.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
