<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.106"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.106/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_106">
        <akn:num>2-1217.106</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Payment and security.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_106_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District is hereby authorized to pledge the funds on deposit in the QZAB Pledged Account as security for the payment of principal of, and premium, if any, on the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_106_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall be payable solely from the funds on deposit in the QZAB Pledged Account and income realized from the temporary investment thereof, and other moneys as provided in the Financing Documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_106_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds for the payment of the bonds shall be deposited with the QZAB Collection Agent pursuant to the QZAB Collection Agreement and used only in accordance with the terms of the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_106_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may, without regard to any act or resolution of the Council now existing, designate a QZAB Collection Agent under the QZAB Collection Agreement. The Mayor may execute and deliver the QZAB Collection Agreement, on behalf of the District and in the Mayor’s official capacity, containing the terms that the Mayor considers necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_106_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Payment of the bonds shall be secured as provided in the Financing Documents and by an assignment by the District for the benefit of the bond owners of certain of its rights under the Financing Documents and Closing Documents, including a security interest in certain collateral, if any, to the trustee for the bonds pursuant to the Financing Documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_106_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The trustee is authorized to deposit, invest, and disburse the proceeds received from the sale of the bonds pursuant to the Financing Documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
