<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.79"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.79/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_79">
        <akn:num>2-1217.79</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Security for Bonds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_79_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A series of Bonds may be secured by a trust agreement or trust indenture between the District and a corporate trustee having trust powers, or secured by a loan agreement or other instrument giving power to a corporate trustee by means of which the District may do the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_79_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The Bonds and the interest thereon and the income therefrom, and all monies pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of the Bonds, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_79_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District does hereby pledge to and covenant and agree with the holders of any Bonds that, subject to the provisions of the financing documents, the District will not limit or alter the revenues pledged to secure the Bonds or the basis on which such revenues are collected or allocated, will not impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the Bonds, will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders, and will not modify in any way the exemptions from taxation provided for in this subchapter, until the Bonds, together with interest thereon, with interest on any unpaid installment of interest and all costs and expenses in connection with any suit, action or proceeding by or on behalf of the holders, are fully met and discharged. This pledge and agreement of the District may be included as part of the contract with the holders of any of its Bonds. This subsection shall constitute a contract between the District and the holders of the Bonds authorized by this subchapter. To the extent that any acts or resolutions of the Council may be in conflict with this subchapter, this subchapter shall be controlling.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_79_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consistent with ยง 1-204.90(a)(4)(B) and, notwithstanding Article 9 of Title 28:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
