<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.33f"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.33f/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_33f">
        <akn:num>2-1217.33f</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Bond details.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor is authorized to take any action reasonably necessary or appropriate in accordance with this subpart [§§ 2-1217.33a to 2-1217.33n] in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, security for, and payment of the bonds of each series, including, but not limited to, determinations of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall contain a legend which shall provide that the bonds are special obligations of the District, are without recourse to the District, are not a pledge of, and do not involve, the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than the Available Tax Increment, the Available Increment, and any other taxes and fees allocated to the City Market at O Street Fund), do not constitute a debt of the District, and do not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in § 1-206.02(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor, and attested by the Secretary of the District of Columbia by the Secretary’s manual or facsimile signature.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds of any series may be issued in accordance with the terms of a trust instrument to be entered into by the District and a trustee or paying agent to be selected by the Mayor, and may be subject to the terms of one or more agreements entered into by the Mayor pursuant to § 1-204.90(a)(4).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time in one or more issues and in one or more series.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The bonds, the interest thereon, and the income therefrom, and all funds pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of the bonds, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District pledges, covenants, and agrees with the holders of the bonds that, subject to the provisions of the Financing Documents, the District will not limit or alter the revenues pledged to secure the bonds or the basis on which such revenues are collected or allocated, will not impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the bonds, will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders of the bonds, and will not modify, in any way, the exemptions from taxation provided for in this subpart [§§ 2-1217.33a to 2-1217.33n], until the bonds, together with interest thereon, and all costs and expenses in connection with any suit, action, or proceeding by or on behalf of the holders of the bonds, are fully met and discharged. This pledge and agreement for the District may be included as part of the contract with the holders of the bonds. This subsection constitutes a contract between the District and the holders of the bonds. To the extent that any acts or resolutions of the Council may be in conflict with this subpart [§§ 2-1217.33a to 2-1217.33n], this subpart [§§ 2-1217.33a to 2-1217.33n] shall be controlling.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_33f_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Consistent with § 1-204.90(a)(4)(B) and notwithstanding Article 9 of Chapter 28:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
