<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1215.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1215.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1215_02">
        <akn:num>2-1215.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adjoining residential neighborhood” means any property zoned for residential use within a BID or within 800 feet of the perimeter of a BID.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Adverse impact on adjoining residential neighborhoods” means adverse impact on traffic, on-street parking, litter, trash collection, crime, noise, lighting levels, or other such factors affecting the quality of residential life.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Assessed value” means the valuation obtained by taking the assessed valuation of taxable real property as it appears on the last completed assessment roll for tax assessment purposes pursuant to § 47-801 et seq.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“BID corporation” means a nonprofit corporation that is organized pursuant to the District law for nonprofit corporations and registered pursuant to the terms of this subchapter. A BID corporation shall not be deemed to be a part of the District government as that term is defined in § 47-393(5).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Block” means the properties fronting on both sides of a street that are located between 2 intersecting streets.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business Improvement District Activity” or “BID activity” means a special service or activity conducted in a Business Improvement District designed to improve the economic development climate in the area pursuant to this subchapter, and which is designed and conducted so as to avoid any material adverse impact on adjoining residential neighborhoods and is otherwise in accordance with all applicable laws, regulations, and requirements of the District of Columbia and the United States, which services and activities may augment, but which may not replace, governmental services customarily provided in the regular course of the District’s operations. This term shall include the planning, administration, and management of activities designed to provide economic stimulus, stability, or benefit to the BID or its members, including, but not limited to, the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Business Improvement District” or “BID” means a defined geographic area in the District in which the preponderance of activity carried out is commercial or industrial in nature, which does not include any part of an existing BID previously established pursuant to this subchapter, and which area consists of not less than 5 contiguous blocks (or the maximum number of contiguous blocks in cases where there are fewer than 5 contiguous blocks), or noncontiguous commercial blocks within a generally recognized single neighborhood; provided, that noncontiguous blocks are not wholly located in an area that is not part of the general BID area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“BID tax” means an additional real property tax or possessory interest tax assessed and levied by the District on, and payable by, the owners of taxable properties or holders of a possessory interest in a Business Improvement District subject to the BID certification processes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“CFO” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Commercial tenant” means a lessee, or other lawful occupant, of taxable real property within a BID who is not an owner and who conducts a lawful commercial use as defined in the Zoning Regulations of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Fiscal year” means the same fiscal year as the fiscal year of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Lot” means the lots described in the District tax and assessment records.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or such administrative agency of the District that is designated by the Mayor to administer the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member” means a member of the BID Corporation, the membership of which shall be comprised of each owner of taxable property and each commercial tenant in the BID area, and each owner who becomes a member pursuant to § 2-1215.21.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Member of record” means a member that the BID is reasonably able to identify from District of Columbia property tax records or from other reasonably available sources.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_17A">
      <akn:num>(17A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Net rentable square feet” means the number of net rentable square feet reported to, or on record with, the Office of Tax and Revenue.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means an owner of taxable property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Owner’s property” means an owner’s taxable property located within a BID.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_21">
      <akn:num>(21)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, society, association, joint venture, stock company, corporation, limited liability company, estate, receiver, trustee, assignee, fiduciary, or any combination of any of the foregoing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_22">
      <akn:num>(22)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Reasonably ascertainable”, “reasonably available”, and “reasonably determined” mean, in relation to information, reasonably reliable information that is obtained by the BID and relied upon by the BID in good faith.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_23">
      <akn:num>(23)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Residential tenant” means a lessee, or other lawful occupant, of taxable property within a BID who is not an owner and who conducts a lawful residential use as defined in the Zoning Regulations of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_02_24">
      <akn:num>(24)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Taxable property” means real property subject to real property taxation or real property for which a holder of a possessory interest is subject to possessory interest taxation, including:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
