<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_03">
        <akn:num>2-1217.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certification of development project.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In order to be eligible for TIF, a development sponsor of any project located in a priority development area shall apply to the CFO for certification that the project complies with the requirements of this subchapter. The application shall consist of a development plan for the project, which shall consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Not later than 120 days after the receipt of an application which meets the criteria set forth in subsection (a) of this section the CFO shall certify or reject the project.  In determining whether to certify the project, the CFO shall consider the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the criteria enumerated in subsection (b) of this section, for projects located in the Downtown Area, the CFO shall consider whether the project will achieve development priorities identified in the Downtown Report that are consistent with the Comprehensive Plan and that satisfy one of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, upon consideration of the criteria set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the CFO determines to certify the project for Council approval, the Mayor shall enter into negotiations with the development sponsor to determine the boundaries of the TIF area for the project, the amount of tax increment allocation, the type of tax to be allocated, the terms and conditions of the agreement between the District and the development sponsor, and the termination dates for the tax increment revenues to be allocated to the project.  Upon completion of negotiations, the CFO shall certify the project, and prepare a proposed resolution for the approval of the Council consistent with the results of the negotiations and with § 2-1217.04.  If the project does not comply with the criteria, the CFO shall so notify the development sponsor in writing stating in what areas the project fails to meet the criteria. The CFO shall allow the development sponsor up to 60 days to comply and cure any defects.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Zoning Administrator; the Director, Office of Planning; the Corporation Counsel; the Director, Department of Housing and Community Development; and any other relevant agency of the District government shall furnish to the CFO information and certificates as may be required by the CFO to confirm a project’s compliance with the criteria enumerated in subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Subject to the consent of each development sponsor of a project within the affected TIF areas and the rights of the holders of its TIF bonds, the CFO may abolish a TIF area, merge TIF areas or alter the boundaries of a TIF area.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The CFO shall impose reasonable fees in connection with the issuance of the TIF bonds to defray administrative costs or burdens incurred as a result of the determination of the tax increment allocation and the issuance of such TIF bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of this title, may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
