<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.102"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.102/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_102">
        <akn:num>2-1217.102</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Authorized Delegate” means the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer, or the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, or any officer or employee of the Executive Office of the Mayor to whom the Mayor has delegated, or to whom the foregoing individuals have subdelegated, any of the Mayor’s functions under this subchapter pursuant to § 1-204.22(6).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Available Real Property Tax Revenues” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax under Chapter 8 of Title 47, including any penalties and interest charges thereon, exclusive of revenues that are or will be pledged pursuant to §§ 1-204.81 and 1-204.90, and payments in lieu of such taxes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bond Counsel” means a firm or firms of attorneys designated as District bond counsel from time to time by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bonds” means the District of Columbia revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, and other obligations), in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Chief Financial Officer” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Closing Documents” means all documents and agreements other than Financing Documents that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Eligible project” means the projects in the area of elementary, secondary, or college and university facilities undertaken at a Qualifying School which are subject to financing pursuant to § 1-204.90 as a qualified zone academy bond within the meaning of section 1397E(d)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 5, 1997 (111 Stat. 821; 26 U.S.C. § 1397E(d)(1)).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Financing Documents” means the documents other than Closing Documents that relate to the financing, refinancing or reimbursement of the costs of eligible projects to be effected through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the bonds, including any offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home Rule Act” means Chapter 2 of Title 1 [§ 1-201.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Issuance Costs” means all fees, costs, charges, and expenses paid or incurred in connection with the authorization, preparation, printing, issuance, sale, and delivery of the bonds, including, but not limited to, underwriting, legal, accounting, rating agency, and all other fees, costs, charges, and expenses incurred in connection with the development and implementation of the Financing Documents, the Closing Documents, and those other documents necessary or appropriate in connection with the authorization, preparation, printing, issuance, sale, marketing, and delivery of the bonds, together with financing fees, costs, and expenses, including program fees and administrative fees charged by the District, fees paid to financial institutions and insurance companies, initial letter of credit fees, compensation to financial advisors and other persons (other than full-time employees of the District) and entities performing services on behalf of or as agents for the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“QZAB Collection Agent” means any bank, trust company, or national banking association with requisite trust powers and with an office in the District designated to serve in this capacity by the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“QZAB Collection Agreement” means the collection agreement between the District and the QZAB Collection Agent authorized in § 2-1217.106.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“QZAB Pledged Account” means one or more accounts created and maintained by the QZAB Collection Agent for the benefit of the owners of a series of the bonds and funded by the deposit of some portion of Available Real Property Tax Revenues and other funds in amounts as determined by the Mayor in the QZAB Collection Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_102_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Qualifying School” means any public school or public charter school the Council approves, by resolution, for financing, refinancing or reimbursement of the costs of its eligible project pursuant to the provisions of § 1-204.90 and this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
