<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1210.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1210.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1210_02">
        <akn:num>2-1210.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of the Capital Access Fund.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1210_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Capital Access Fund, which shall be used solely for the uses and purposes set forth in subsections (d) and (e) of this section. The Fund shall be funded by appropriations and from other amounts received by the District for the administration of the program. All funds collected from these sources shall be deposited into the Capital Access Fund.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1210_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds deposited into the Capital Access Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsections (d) and (e) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1210_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All funds deposited in the Capital Access Fund shall be exempt from the requirements imposed by subchapter III-A of Chapter 3 of Title 47 [ยง 47-351.01 et seq.]. The Fund shall be administered as an agency fund under ยง 47-373(2)(I).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1210_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The funds in the Fund shall be used solely to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1210_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall administer the Fund and shall have the powers necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, including the power to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1210_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District may accept gifts, grants, donations, and awards from any source, including the federal government, for the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
