<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1225.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1225.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1225_02">
        <akn:num>2-1225.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transition to District control.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any leave that an employee who is hired pursuant to this section accrued during his or her tenure with the AWC, the NCRC, or any of their subsidiaries, shall be credited to the employee once the employee is hired by the District. The accrued leave of the employee shall be allocated between sick leave and annual leave in such proportions as the Mayor considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each employee’s length of service at the AWC or the NCRC, or any of their subsidiaries, and the employee’s service with the District government, if such service was immediately prior to the employee’s service with the AWC or the NCRC, shall be counted as creditable District government service for vesting in the District’s retirement program and for the rate at which the employee accrues annual leave.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an employee is hired by the District government under this section and was employed by the District government immediately prior to his or her employment with the AWC or the NCRC and funds were deposited into the employee’s District of Columbia retirement account during the employee’s term of employment with the District government and the deposited funds lapsed from the retirement account because of a break in employment with the District government caused by the employee’s service with the AWC or the NCRC, the deposited funds that lapsed shall be restored to the employee’s retirement account by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may transfer any property, records, rights, obligations, causes of action, legal or equitable title to any real property, or legal obligations of the NCRC and the AWC and any of their subsidiaries or predecessors in interest; provided, that all such property, records, rights, obligations, causes of action, legal and equitable title to any real property, or legal obligations under this subsection shall be transferred to the District on October 1, 2007, pursuant to §§ 2-1225.11 and 2-1225.12.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1225_02_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Council by July 12, 2007, a transition plan for the transfer of the functions, duties, powers, records, real and personal property, liabilities, and other rights, authorities, obligations, and assets from the NCRC and the AWC to the management and control of the Mayor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
