<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1215.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1215.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1215_06">
        <akn:num>2-1215.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Hearing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall hold a public hearing within 45 days of the issuance of his findings pursuant to § 2-1215.05(b)(2). The Mayor may designate the Department of Small and Local Business Development, or a successor thereto, to perform the functions described by this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notice to the public shall be made no less than 21 days prior to the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall advertise the notice of the public hearing along with the notice of preliminary finding in the District of Columbia Register.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No fewer than 21 days before the public hearing, the applicant shall send, by first class mail or electronically, notice of the Mayor’s preliminary determination, notice of the public hearing, including the date, time, and place and availability of the BID application for review, and a summary of the application stating the borders of the proposed BID, the BID plan, and the BID taxes to the following, to the extent reasonably ascertainable:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The BID application shall be made available to the public for review during normal business hours on weekdays in at least one location in the proposed BID area designated by the applicant on a publicly accessible web site and at a generally accessible District government office designated by the Mayor. The notice of the public hearing shall describe these locations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall use the public hearing on the proposed BID to determine whether the BID plan meets the purposes of this subchapter and the definition of BID activity in § 2-1215.02, and all other BID application requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 10 days after the public hearing (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) the Mayor shall either:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an order of rejection is not issued within 60 days from the date of the public hearing, the BID and the nonprofit corporation that submitted the application under § 2-1215.04 shall be deemed registered by the Mayor; except that, if the corrected application under subsection (g) of this section is determined by the Mayor to contain substantial changes, the Mayor may extend the review period for 5 business days. After such time the BID and the nonprofit corporation that submitted the application under § 2-1215.04 shall be deemed registered.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1215_06_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Proceedings and determinations under the provisions of this subchapter shall not be considered contested cases under Chapter 5 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
