<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.78"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.78/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_78">
        <akn:num>2-1217.78</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Details of Bonds.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_78_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may take any action necessary or appropriate in accordance with this subchapter in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, and payment of Bonds, including determinations of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_78_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds shall contain a legend, which shall provide that the Bonds shall be special obligations of the District, shall be nonrecourse to the District, shall not be a pledge of, and shall not involve, the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than the Tax Increment Revenues or any other security authorized by this subchapter), shall not constitute a debt of the District, and shall not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in § 1-206.02(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_78_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor. The Mayor’s execution and delivery of the Bonds shall constitute conclusive evidence of the Mayor’s approval, on behalf of the District, of the final form and content of the same.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_78_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The official seal of the District, or facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the Bonds.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_78_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time in one or more issues and in one of more series.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
