<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.71"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1217.71/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1217_71">
        <akn:num>2-1217.71</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Available Real Property Tax Revenues” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax under Chapter 8 of Title 47, including any penalties and interest charges, exclusive of the special tax provided for in § 1-204.81, pledged to the payment of general obligation indebtedness of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Available Sales Tax Revenues” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax under Chapter 20 of Title 47, including any penalties and interest charges, exclusive of the portion thereof required to be deposited in the Washington Convention Center Fund established pursuant to § 10-1202.08.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Bonds” means any bonds, notes, or other instruments issued by the District pursuant to § 1-204.90 and secured by Tax Increment Revenues or other security authorized by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“CFO” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Downtown Retail Priority Area” means the record lots that front one of the following street locations: 7th Street, N.W., between Indiana and Massachusetts Avenues, N.W.; 11th Street, N.W., between Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., and New York Avenue, N.W.; F Street, N.W., between 6th and 15th Streets, N.W.; and G Street, N.W., between 10th and 13th Streets, N.W., and includes portions of the following squares: 223, 224, 225, 252, 253, 254, 288, 289, 290, 319, 320, 321, 322, 346, 347, 348, 376, 377, 403, 406, 408.1, 428, 429, 430, 431, 452, 453, 454, 455, 456, 457, and 458.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Home Rule Act” means Chapter 2 of Title 1 [§ 1-201.01 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“LSDBE” means a local, small, or disadvantaged business enterprise certified by the Small and Local Business Opportunity Commission under subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of this title [§ 2-1217.71 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Retail Development Project” means the establishment of a business engaged in direct onsite retail sales to consumers or providing a unique entertainment attraction, including the following activities in connection with such business: acquisition, purchase, construction, reconstruction, improvement, renovation, rehabilitation, restoration, remodeling, repair, remediation, expansion, extension, and the furnishing, equipping, and opening for business. In the case of the Downtown Retail Priority Area, Retail Development Projects shall meet the requirements of § 2-1217.73a, shall be limited to restaurants (on a demonstration basis), grocery and specialty food stores and businesses engaged in sales of home furnishings, apparel, and general merchandise goods to specialized customers, or providing a unique entertainment attraction, and shall specifically exclude:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Retail Development Costs” means any costs associated with, arising out of, or incurred in connection with:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Retail Priority Area” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Rules of Operation” means the rules and procedures, established by the Mayor pursuant to § 2-1217.74, by which Retail Development Projects will be approved as TIF Areas and receive proceeds of Bonds to pay Retail Development Costs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Tax Increment Revenues” means the portion of the Available Real Property Tax Revenues, Available Sales Tax Revenues, or both, allocable to one or more tax allocation funds pursuant to § 2-1217.76.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“TIF” means tax increment financing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“TIF Act” means subchapter IX of this chapter [§ 2-1217.01 et seq.] or any successor act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1217_71_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“TIF Area” means a Retail Development Project that has been approved by the Mayor to receive proceeds of Bonds in accordance with the applicable Rules of Operation for the Retail Priority Area in which the Retail Development Project is located.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
