<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1212.31"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1212.31/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1212_31">
        <akn:num>2-1212.31</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of a healthy food retail program.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall establish a Healthy Food Retail Program within the Department of Small and Local Business Development to expand access to healthy foods in eligible areas in the District by providing assistance to corner stores, farmers markets, and other small food retailers.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Health, District Department of the Environment, Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, Office of Planning, and the University System of the District of Columbia shall, as requested by the Department of Small and Local Business Development, assist this program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Corner stores, farmers markets, and other small food retailers are encouraged to work cooperatively to expand access to healthy foods in eligible areas.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The benefits provided by subsection (c) of this section may be used by corner stores to improve the display areas, exteriors, and interiors of corner stores to expand capacity to sell healthy food.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department of Small and Local Business Development may contract with nonprofit organizations in promoting and implementing this program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1212_31_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The University System of the District of Columbia may provide nutrition education resources to eligible corner stores, farmers markets, and consumers in eligible areas.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
