<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1403.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1403.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1403_05">
        <akn:num>2-1403.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Investigation.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With the exception of complaints alleging unlawful discrimination in residential real estate transactions brought pursuant to this chapter or the FHA, the Office shall serve, within 15 days of said filing, a copy thereof upon the respondent, and upon all persons it deems to be necessary parties; and shall make prompt investigation in connection therewith.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 120 days, after service of the complaint upon all parties thereto, the Office shall determine whether, in accord with its own rules, it has jurisdiction; and if so, whether there is probable cause to believe that the respondent has engaged or is engaging in an unlawful discriminatory practice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the Office finds, with respect to any respondent, that it lacks jurisdiction or that probable cause does not exist the Director forthwith shall issue and cause to be served on the appropriate parties, an order dismissing the allegations of the complaint.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall complete investigations of complaints alleging unlawful discrimination in residential real estate transactions brought pursuant to this chapter or the FHA, within 100 days after filing of the complaint. The Office shall notify the parties in writing of the reasons for not timely completing the investigation, if it is unable to or it becomes impracticable to complete the investigation within 100 days.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office may join a person not named as an additional or substitute respondent upon written notice for complaints alleging unlawful discrimination in residential real estate transactions brought pursuant to this chapter or the FHA.  The Office, in the notice to the respondent shall explain the basis for determining that the person is properly joined as a respondent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The complainant, respondent, or an aggrieved person on whose behalf the complaint was filed, for complaints alleging unlawful discrimination in residential real estate transactions or violations of the FHA, may elect to have the claims asserted in the complaint decided in a civil action.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_05_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a timely election is made pursuant to subsection (f) of this section, the Director shall authorize, not later than 30 days after the election is made, and the Corporation Counsel shall file a civil action on behalf of the aggrieved party in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.  Venue for an action pursuant to this section shall be in the District of Columbia. Any aggrieved party may intervene in this court action.  The Court may grant relief pursuant to ยง 2-1403.16(b) if the court finds that a discriminatory housing practice has occurred or is occurring.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
