<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1403.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1403.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1403_01">
        <akn:num>2-1403.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers of Office and Commission; annual report by Mayor.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The activities of the Office and the Commission, under the provisions of this chapter, shall be considered investigations or examinations of municipal matters, within the meaning of § 5-1021; and the Commission, the individual members thereof, and the Director, shall possess the powers vested in the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office is hereby empowered to undertake its own investigations and public hearings on any racial, religious, and ethnic group tensions, prejudice, intolerance, bigotry, and disorder; and on any form of, or reason for, discrimination, in accordance with §§ 2-1401.01 and 2-1402.01, against any person, group of persons, organization, or corporations, whether practiced by private persons, associations, corporations, city officials, or city agencies; for the purpose of making appropriate recommendations for action, including legislation, against such discrimination.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office and the Commission may make, issue, adopt, promulgate, amend, and rescind such rules and procedures as they deem necessary to effectuate and which are not in conflict with, the provisions of this chapter. Such rules and procedures and amendments thereto shall be adopted and promulgated in accordance with procedures promulgated pursuant to the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act (§ 2-501 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In taking any action authorized or required by the provisions of this chapter, the Commission may act through panels or a division of not less than 3 of its members, a majority of whom shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor shall recommend to the Council any additional regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Investigations relating to the enforcement of provisions of this chapter shall be given priority over all other duties and activities of the Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1403_01_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office and the Commission shall enforce §§ 34-1240 [repealed], 34-1241 [repealed], 34-1242 [repealed], 34-1243 [repealed] and any other human rights provisions of Chapter 12 of Title 34.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
