<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1402.53"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1402.53/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1402_53">
        <akn:num>2-1402.53</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Affirmative action plans.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1402_53_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall not be an unlawful discriminatory practice for any person to carry out an affirmative action plan that has been approved by the Office. An affirmative action plan is any plan devised to effectuate remedial or corrective action in response to past discriminatory practices prohibited under this chapter and may also include those plans devised to provide preferential treatment for a class or classes of persons, which preferential treatment by class would otherwise be prohibited by this chapter and which plan is not devised to contravene the intent of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1402_53_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All banks and savings and loan associations, subject to this chapter, shall submit annually to the Office an affirmative action plan which shall include goals and timetables for the remediation or correction of past or present discriminatory practices. Such plan shall be reviewed by the Office and is subject to its approval.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1402_53_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>It shall be an unlawful discriminatory practice for any bank or savings and loan association, subject to this chapter, to fail to develop an affirmative action plan approved by the Office or fail to comply substantially with the terms of such affirmative action plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1402_53_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall develop and promulgate guidelines which will set forth the affirmative action requirements of this section and shall incorporate, but not be limited to, applicable federal guidelines. Such guidelines shall be promulgated by the Office within 120 days of the enactment of this law consistent with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (ยง 2-501 et seq.) and shall not become effective until 60 calendar days following submission to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
