<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1515.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1515.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1515_08">
        <akn:num>2-1515.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Transfers.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All real or personal property, leased or assigned to the Department of Human Services on behalf of the Youth Services Administration, positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to those powers, duties, functions and operations of the Department of Human Services as set forth in, and utilized to carry out, section III (S) and III (W) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, effective January 3, 1987, relating to the Youth Services Administration are hereby transferred to the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All of the authority and functions of the Department of Human Services as set forth in section III (S) and III (W) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, effective January 3, 1987, relating to the Youth Services Administration are hereby transferred to the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All real and personal property, Career and Excepted Service, Management Supervisory Service, trainee positions, assets, records, obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, operations, and administration of the Youth Services Administration shall become the property of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All real and personal property, positions, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, and operations of the “Compact Administrator” of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children, as authorized by subchapter II of Chapter 14 of Title 4 [§  4-1421 et seq.]. shall become the property of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All positions, real and personal property, assets, records, and obligations, and all unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, and operations of the Youth Services Administration of the Department of Human Services in operating and regulating secure and residential facilities, juvenile justice services, programs, and supports, shall be transferred to the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall recognize and bargain with collective bargaining representatives that have been duly certified by the Public Employee Relations Board and shall assume and be bound by all existing collective bargaining agreements entered into by the Youth Services Administration of the Department of Human Services, if those agreements have been approved by the Council, unless Council approval is not required by law, and, during a control year, as defined in § 47-393(4), the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every employee of the Youth Services Administration shall be transferred to the Department. An employee transferred to the Department shall be transferred in the same classification he or she held at the Department of Human Services, Youth Services Administration, or other department, at the time of the transfer. Subject to the District’s authority to convert them to the Management Supervisory Service and the Legal Service consistent with Chapter 6 of Title 1 [§ 1-601.01 et seq.], transferred employees shall retain all rights and privileges related to their individual pay and benefits, including retirement status, so long as the employee is continuously employed by the Department or the District government, including any applicable rights and privileges provided for in § 44-906.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following rules and regulations pertaining to the licensing, oversight, and regulation of residential placement facilities for detained, delinquent youth and PINS shall remain in full force and effect unless and until repealed or superseded by action of the Department:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
