<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1503"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1503/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1503">
        <akn:num>2-1503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Office of Youth Opportunity Services abolished and functions transferred; Division of Community-Based Programs for Children and Youth established.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1503_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Commissioner’s Order No. 70-93 (approved March 17, 1970) establishing the Office of Youth Opportunity Services, is hereby repealed and that Office is hereby abolished. All of the powers, duties, and functions assigned to that Office under any provision of law are hereby transferred to the departments and agencies as indicated in the following provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1503_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There are hereby transferred to the Department of Recreation (Organization Order No. 10; Commissioner’s Order No. 68-440, June 27, 1968, amended August 6, 1968, October 3, 1968, and March 14, 1970) the following functions, previously performed by the Office of Youth Opportunity Services:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1503_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1503_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There are hereby transferred to the Department of Manpower (Organization Order No. 46, Commissioner’s Order No. 74-144, June 29, 1974) the functions of the Office of Youth Opportunity Services relating to the coordination of programs designed to provide jobs for youth.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1503_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There are hereby transferred to the School of Continuing Education, Federal City College, University of the District of Columbia (D.C. Law 1-36) the functions of the Office of Youth Opportunity Services with respect to the administration and supervision of the District of Columbia Street Academy.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1503_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There are hereby assigned to the Board of Education of the District of Columbia the functions of the Office of Youth Opportunity Services with respect to the summer lunch program for children and youth.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
