<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1564"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1564/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1564">
        <akn:num>2-1564</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Organizational structure.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After June 25, 2002, the Mayor shall publicly announce and widely disseminate information to District residents that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A selection committee shall be formed by the Youth Advisory Council Taskforce with the approval of the Mayor. The selection committee shall screen, interview, and select the first 32 members of the Youth Council. Following the first year, Youth Council members shall select the next year’s members. The selection committee shall consist of:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Youth Council shall select 6 officers to serve leadership positions. In addition, the Youth Council may create other leadership positions as deemed necessary. In its first year of operation, the Chair shall be chosen by the selection committee from among the initial 32 Youth Council members, with the approval of the Mayor. The Chair shall serve for one year. The selection of these 32 members shall be made prior to the Youth Council’s initial retreat. All other officers shall be selected by the Youth Council at their retreat, and shall serve for one year. Thereafter, the Youth Council shall select all officers. The officers shall be as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Members of the Youth Council shall be selected to serve a 2-year term. Member shall only serve 2 terms. Youth Council Officers shall be selected to serve a one-year term. Officers may be re-elected, but shall not serve more than 3 terms in any office or combination of offices.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A group of 8 Advisors shall work with the Youth Council and shall provide assistance as needed. Advisors shall not vote on Youth Council business and shall only provide support upon the specific request of the Youth Council. Four of the 8 advisors shall be adults and 4 shall be youth. In the first year after the establishment of the Youth Council, 2 youth and 2 adult advisors shall be selected by the Youth Summit Advisory Board. The remaining 2 youth and 2 adult advisors shall be selected by the Youth Council members. Thereafter, the advisors shall be selected by the Youth Council.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To ensure an orderly transition from veteran outgoing Youth Council members to incoming novice members, terms during the first year shall be staggered as follows: Members of the initial Youth Council shall either serve one, two, or three year terms. Twelve members shall serve a one-year term, 12 members shall serve a 2-year term, and 8 members shall serve a 3-year term. Members who are selected to serve a one-year term, shall sit out at least one year before seeking re-election to the Youth Council. Terms shall be determined following the first year of the Youth Council based on two factors:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Youth Council shall establish standing committees. The Youth Council shall have the discretion to create other standing committees as needed. The 4 committees are:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The first Youth Council shall create the rules and bylaws to which all future Youth Councils shall adhere.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Youth Council Secretary and Assistant Secretary shall be the official record keepers. They shall be responsible for documenting and archiving all meeting minutes, and other relevant decisions or documents. The Youth Council Treasurer shall record and archive all financial transactions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Youth Coordinator shall assist with all phases of the publicizing, screening, candidate selection and operation of the Youth Council. In addition, some young people may be hired to work part-time for the Youth Council as needed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Youth Council Chair shall be responsible for calling meetings to order and for facilitating these meetings. Meetings shall be conducted following parliamentary procedures as described in Robert’s Rules of Order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Quorum requirements shall be as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Every Youth Council member shall serve on at least one committee. In order to serve as chair of a committee, members shall be in good standing and shall have knowledge of the committee’s subject matter. Committee chairs shall serve for one year. Committee chairs shall be eligible to serve more terms, if selected to do so.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_o">
      <akn:num>(o)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All members shall attend a minimum of 75% of Youth Council meetings. Members shall also attend the minimum number of committee meetings as determined by the committee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_p">
      <akn:num>(p)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Within 2 years of operation, the Youth Council shall initiate advisory groups or forums within each ward, and for the juvenile justice and foster care communities. These groups shall serve as both a source for future Youth Council members, and as a vehicle for soliciting input from around the District, and a method of sharing information about Youth Council activities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_q">
      <akn:num>(q)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1564_r">
      <akn:num>(r)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
