<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1515.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1515.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1515_02">
        <akn:num>2-1515.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment and purposes of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to § 1-204.04(b), the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services is established as a separate Cabinet-level agency, subordinate to the Mayor, within the executive branch of the government of the District of Columbia. The Department shall lead the reform of the District’s juvenile justice system by coordinating the collaborative efforts of government agencies, contracted providers, labor, and community leaders to:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall be headed by a Director, who shall report to the Mayor. The Director shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council, pursuant to § 1-523.01(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall have a minimum education of a Masters Degree in Criminal Justice, Social Work, or some related field, or shall possess equivalent work-related experience in the management of juvenile justice programs.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall have authority over the Department, its functions, and personnel, including the power to re-delegate to employees authority as, in the judgment of the Director, is warranted in the interests of efficiency and sound administration.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall have authority to organize and reorganize the personnel and property transferred herein within any organizational unit of the Department, including creating offices within the Department, as necessary, and exercising any other powers necessary and appropriate to implement the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1515_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Director shall have authority to implement an aggressive, District-wide program of reform within the juvenile justice system that leads to a system that can serve as a nationwide model.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
