<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1607"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1607/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1607">
        <akn:num>2-1607</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Appropriation; public grants and private contributions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1607_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There are authorized  to be appropriated to the Service in each fiscal years such funds  as may be necessary to carry out this chapter. The Service may arrange  by contract or otherwise for the disbursement of appropriated funds,  procurement, and the provision of other administrative support functions  by the General Services Administration or by other agencies or entities,  not subject to the provisions of the District of Columbia Code or  any law or regulation adopted by the District of Columbia Government  concerning disbursement of funds, procurement, or other administrative  support functions. The Service shall submit an annual appropriations  request to the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1607_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon approval  of the Board of Trustees, the Service may accept and use public grants, private contributions, and voluntary and uncompensated (gratuitous) services to assist it in carrying out the provisions  of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1607_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Service shall  not be subject to any general personnel or budget limitations which  otherwise apply to the District of Columbia government or its agencies  in any appropriations act.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1607_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>During fiscal  years 2006 through 2008, the Service may charge fees to cover the  costs of materials distributed to attendees of educational events,  including conferences, sponsored by the Service. Notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code [31 U.S.C. § 3302], any amounts received as fees under this subsection shall be credited  to the Service and available for use without further appropriation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1607_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Service shall,  to the extent the Director considers appropriate, provide representation  for and hold harmless, or provide liability insurance for, any person  who is an employee, member of the Board of Trustees, or officer of  the Service for money damages arising out of any claim, proceeding,  or case at law relating to the furnishing of representational services  or management services or related services under this chapter while  acting within the scope of that person’s office or employment,  including but not limited to such claims, proceedings, or cases at  law involving employment actions, injury, loss of liberty, property  damage, loss of property, or personal injury, or death arising from  malpractice or negligence of any such officer or employee.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
