<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_02">
        <akn:num>2-1831.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Establishment of Office of Administrative Hearings.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Office of Administrative Hearings is established as an independent agency within the executive branch of the District of Columbia government in the form and manner prescribed by this chapter. The Office shall be responsible for the administrative adjudication of all cases to which this chapter applies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall commence operations on the day that begins the first pay period after 180 days following Council confirmation of the individual who will serve as the first Chief Administrative Law Judge of the Office. On or after March 6, 2002, the Mayor may issue an executive order appointing an acting Chief Administrative Law Judge, pending his or her confirmation, and may authorize him or her to plan for the implementation of this chapter, including the commencement of operations of the Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any hearing officer in an agency covered by this chapter shall be subject to all rights, privileges, and requirements of this chapter, but his or her position and related costs shall continue to be funded by his or her originating agency until personnel authority, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, revenues, and other funds associated with an agency’s carrying out the functions assigned to the Office under authority of this chapter are lawfully transferred to the Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall be subject to Unit A of Chapter 3 of this chapter, subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of this chapter, Chapter 14 of Title 1, and Chapter 10 of Title 10.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
