<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1801.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1801.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1801_03">
        <akn:num>2-1801.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administrative law judges and attorney examiners.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1801_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in Chapter 18A of this title, the Mayor shall appoint 1 or more attorneys to serve as administrative law judges or attorney examiners to implement the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1801_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Administrative law judges or attorney examiners shall have the following powers:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1801_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each licensing or permitting authority or successor entity established by the laws and regulations amended by title IV may delegate to administrative law judges or attorney examiners, who are appointed pursuant to this section or pursuant to Chapter 18A of  this title [ยง 2-1831.01 et seq.], the authority to conduct hearings pursuant to the laws and regulations and to recommend appropriate action, including denial, suspension, or revocation of any permit or license, to the licensing or permitting authority.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1801_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to assuming any duties or responsibilities pursuant to this chapter, administrative law judges or attorney examiners shall have completed an orientation or training course established by the Mayor or the Chief Administrative Law Judge of the Office of Administrative Hearings for the purpose of familiarizing themselves with relevant rules, procedures, and substantive law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1801_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Administrative law judges and attorney examiners appointed pursuant to this section, or pursuant to Chapter 18A of this title [ยง 2-1831.01 et seq.], may hear cases pursuant to Chapter 39 of Title 28.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
