<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.12"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.12/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_12">
        <akn:num>2-1831.12</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Executive Director and other personnel.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_12_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>There shall be an Executive Director of the Office. The Executive Director shall be responsible for the administration of the Office, subject to the supervision of the Chief Administrative Law Judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_12_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Director shall be appointed by the Chief Administrative Law Judge as a statutory employee in the Excepted Service pursuant to ยง 1-609.08, and shall serve at the pleasure of the Chief Administrative Law Judge. In making the appointment, the Chief Administrative Law Judge shall consider experience and special training in administrative, operational, and managerial positions and familiarity with court and administrative hearing procedures and operations. The Executive Director need not be an attorney and may not concurrently hold an appointment as an Administrative Law Judge appointed under the authority of ยง 2-1831.08(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_12_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Director shall be a resident of the District of Columbia or become a resident not more than 180 days after the date of appointment, and shall remain a resident, unless temporarily or permanently exempted from these requirements by the Mayor for good cause.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_12_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall have a Clerk and may have deputy clerks who shall perform such duties as may be assigned to them. The Clerk and deputy clerks may be authorized to administer oaths, issue subpoenas, and perform other appropriate duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_12_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With the approval of the Chief Administrative Law Judge, the Executive Director may appoint and fix the salary of any attorney and non-attorney personnel appointed pursuant to the authority of this chapter, other than Administrative Law Judges, except that no individual appointed by the Executive Director may be paid at a rate greater than the rate of pay for the Executive Director. Law clerks and attorneys employed by the office in a capacity other than as an Administrative Law Judge shall be appointed non-competitively as Excepted Service attorneys under ยง 1-609.06, and shall not be appointed to the Legal Service or Senior Executive Attorney Service.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_12_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Executive Director shall not have supervisory authority over any person appointed as an Administrative Law Judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
