<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.08"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.08/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_08">
        <akn:num>2-1831.08</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Administrative Law Judges.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Administrative Law Judges shall be accountable and responsible for the fair, impartial, effective, and efficient disposition of cases to which they are assigned by the Chief Administrative Law Judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An Administrative Law Judge shall be appointed to the Excepted Service as a statutory officeholder pursuant to ยง 1-609.08, upon the affirmative vote of a majority of the voting members of the Commission after a selection process in accordance with rules promulgated pursuant to ยง 2-1831.11(a) and (b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>To be eligible for appointment, an Administrative Law Judge shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An individual occupying a position as a hearing officer in an agency at the time the agency becomes subject to this chapter is eligible to be appointed as an Administrative Law Judge in the Office; provided, that he or she satisfies all the requirements for appointment as an Administrative Law Judge specified in this chapter and in the rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No hearing officer shall be required to accept an appointment as an Administrative Law Judge pursuant to subsection (e) of this section. Any hearing officer who is not appointed or is ineligible to be appointed as an Administrative Law Judge shall be reassigned, without reduction in grade or step, to another position within the agency employing that individual, or by the Mayor to a position in another agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any Administrative Law Judge appointed pursuant to the authority of subsection (e) of this section who is not reappointed after expiration of his or her initial 2-year term may be appointed to the Legal Service, and be placed in a position in the agency that employed the individual immediately before he or she accepted the appointment as an Administrative Law Judge or in any other position designated by the Corporation Counsel.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_08_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The compensation of an Administrative Law Judge shall not exceed the compensation level available to attorneys of the Senior Executive Attorney Service created by ยง 1-608.53.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
