<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_03">
        <akn:num>2-1831.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Jurisdiction of the Office and agency authority to review cases.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>As of the day that begins the first pay period after 180 days following Council confirmation of the individual who will serve as the first Chief Administrative Law Judge of the Office, this chapter shall apply to adjudicated cases under the jurisdiction of the following agencies:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those agencies listed in subsection (a) of this section, as of October 1, 2004, this chapter shall apply to adjudicated cases under the jurisdiction of the following agencies:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those adjudicated cases listed in subsections (a), (b), and (b-1) of this section, as of January 1, 2009, this chapter shall apply to all adjudicated cases involving:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_3">
      <akn:num>(b-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those cases described in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), and (b-2) of this section, as of May 5, 2010, this chapter shall apply to adjudicated cases required to be heard pursuant to § 42-3141.06.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_4">
      <akn:num>(b-4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those adjudicated cases listed in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), and (b-3) of this section, this chapter shall apply to all adjudicated cases involving the impoundment of a vehicle pursuant to § 22-2724(a).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_5">
      <akn:num>(b-5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall apply to appeals pursuant to §§ 47-857.09a and 47-859.04a.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_6">
      <akn:num>(b-6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those adjudicated cases listed in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), (b-3), (b-4), and (b-5) of this section, this chapter shall apply to all adjudicated cases involving the failure to report known or reasonably believed child sexual abuse pursuant to subchapter II-A of Chapter 30 of Title 22 [§ 22-3020.51 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_7">
      <akn:num>(b-7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those adjudicated cases listed in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), (b-3), (b-4), (b-5), and (b-6) of this section, this chapter shall apply to all adjudications involving the imposition of a civil fine for violations of § 48-1201.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_8">
      <akn:num>(b-8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those adjudicated cases listed in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), (b-3), (b-4), (b-5), (b-6), and (b-7) of this section, this chapter shall apply to appeals pursuant to § 2-218.63(g).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_9">
      <akn:num>(b-9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to  those cases described in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), (b-3),  (b-4), (b-5), (b-6), and (b-7) [and (b-8)], this chapter shall apply to adjudicated  cases under the jurisdiction of the District Department of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_b_10">
      <akn:num>(b-10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to those cases described in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), (b-3), (b-4), (b-5), (b-6), (b-7), and (b-8) [and (b-9)], this chapter shall apply to adjudicated cases involving a civil fine or penalty imposed by the Higher Education Licensure Commission under § 38-1312(a-1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Those agencies, boards, and commissions that are not included in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), or (b-3) of this section may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to grant a right to a hearing not created independently by a constitutional provision or a provision of law other than this chapter, except with regard to the discipline or removal of an Administrative Law Judge or the Chief Administrative Law Judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, no agency of the District of Columbia to which this chapter applies shall adjudicate adjudicated cases under the jurisdiction of the Office of Administrative Hearings or employ hearing officers, either full- or part-time, for the purpose of adjudicating cases under the jurisdiction of the Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any case initiated by, or arising from a decision or action of, an agency or a portion of an agency in receivership shall not be heard by the Office unless the receiver has entered a binding agreement that any order issued by the Office in the matter would have the same force, effect, and finality as it would if the receivership did not exist.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit the authority of an agency covered in subsections (a), (b), (b-1), (b-2), or (b-3) of this section, if the authority exists pursuant to other provisions of the law, to have an agency head or one or more members of the governing board, commission, or body of the agency adjudicate cases falling within its jurisdiction in lieu of the Office. This authority may not be delegated in whole or in part to any subordinate employees of the agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_03_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person who has filed a protest of a proposed assessment under § 47-4312 and requested a hearing with the Office shall be deemed to have elected adjudication by the Office as the exclusive means of adjudication of all challenges to the proposed assessment, and to have waived any right to adjudication of a challenge to the proposed assessment in any other forum. Nothing in this subsection limits the right of any person to judicial review of an order of the Office pursuant to § 2-1831.16.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
