<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.16"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.16/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_16">
        <akn:num>2-1831.16</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Judicial review and administrative appeals.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order of the Office shall be effective upon its issuance, unless stayed by an Administrative Law Judge sua sponte or upon motion of any party. Any party may file a motion for reconsideration of an order or a motion for a new trial within 10 calendar days of service of an order. Unless otherwise ordered by an Administrative Law Judge, the filing of such a motion shall not stay the effectiveness of an order. If such a motion is timely filed, the order shall not be final for purposes of judicial review until the motion is ruled upon by the Administrative Law Judge or is denied by operation of law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any agency, board, commission, or body of an agency identified in subchapter III of Chapter 18 of this title [ยง 2-1803.01 et seq.], other than the Board of Appeals and Review, shall retain jurisdiction to entertain and determine appeals from orders of Administrative Law Judges, as granted in that chapter. The Rental Housing Commission shall have jurisdiction to review orders of the Office in all adjudicated cases brought pursuant to Chapter 35 of Title 42 [ยง 42-501.01 et seq.]. A board or commission that delegates a matter pursuant to ยง 2-1831.03(i) shall have jurisdiction of any appeal by any party from an order of an Administrative Law Judge issued in that matter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any person suffering a legal wrong or adversely affected or aggrieved by any order of the Office in any adjudicated case may obtain judicial review of that order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any agency suffering a legal wrong or adversely affected or aggrieved by any order of the Office in any adjudicated case may obtain judicial review of that order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Judicial review of all orders of the Office in contested cases shall be in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in accordance with the procedures and rules of that court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Judicial review of any order of the Office in a matter that is not a contested case shall be in accordance with other applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In all proceedings for judicial review authorized by this section, the reviewing court shall apply the standards of review prescribed in ยง 2-510. A reviewing court may not modify a monetary sanction imposed by an Administrative Law Judge if that sanction is within the limits established by law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_16_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, neither the Office nor an Administrative Law Judge shall be a party in any proceeding brought by a party in any court seeking judicial review of any order of the Office, or of any order of an agency head or governing board, commission, or body of an agency that decides any appeal from any order of the Office. Only the parties before the Office or any other party permitted to participate by the reviewing court shall be parties in any such proceeding for judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
