<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1802.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1802.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1802_03">
        <akn:num>2-1802.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Hearing.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The administrative law judge or attorney examiner shall conduct a hearing on a notice of infraction in accordance with Chapter 5 of this title, except as otherwise provided by this chapter. The Mayor shall bear the burden of establishing an infraction by a preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a respondent fails, without good cause, to appear at a hearing of which the respondent has been served a notice, the administrative law judge or attorney examiner may proceed with the hearing and enter a final order in the case.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After due consideration of the evidence and arguments, the administrative law judge or attorney examiner shall determine whether the Mayor has established the infraction. Where the Mayor has not established the infraction, the administrative law judge or attorney examiner shall enter an order dismissing the notice of infraction. Where the Mayor has established the infraction, the administrative law judge or attorney examiner shall enter an appropriate written order, which shall set forth findings of fact, conclusions of law, and a sanction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An order entered pursuant to this section is civil in nature.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon a finding that the respondent has committed the infraction, the administrative law judge or attorney examiner may order the respondent to pay a civil fine and, where appropriate, penalties pursuant to § 2-1801.04(a)(2) and costs pursuant to § 2-1801.04(b).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The administrative law judge or attorney examiner may suspend any permit or license which authorizes the respondent to engage in the activity to which the infraction relates if the respondent fails to pay any fines, penalties, and costs, with interest thereon, in accordance with the administrative law judge’s or attorney examiner’s order. Suspension of the permit or license shall continue until the respondent complies with the administrative law judge’s or attorney examiner’s order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon request of the respondent, the administrative law judge or attorney examiner may stay the imposition of any sanction imposed pending administrative review.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may cause to be entered any final order requiring a respondent to pay fines, penalties, or costs as a judgment against the respondent in the Civil Actions Branch of the Civil Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. The Mayor may enforce the judgment in the same manner as any other civil judgment may be enforced under District law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1802_03_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Mayor may enforce payment of the fines, penalties, costs, and interest imposed against the real property of the respondent as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
