<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.13"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.13/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_13">
        <akn:num>2-1831.13</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Interaction of the Office with other agencies; other procedural matters.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All components of the District of Columbia government shall cooperate with the Chief Administrative Law Judge, the Executive Director, and Administrative Law Judges in the discharge of their duties.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office shall be subject to audit and examination on the same basis as other District of Columbia government agencies.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>When a case is brought before the Office, any agency that is a party shall take no further decisional action with respect to the subject matter in issue, except in the role of a party litigant or with the consent of all parties, for so long as the Office has jurisdiction over the proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All documents filed in any case before the Office shall be available to the public for review unless a statute, protective order, or other legal requirement prohibits disclosure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Beginning November 15, 2004, and by November 15 of each year thereafter, the Chief Administrative Law Judge shall transmit to the Mayor, the Council, and each agency to which this chapter applies, a written summary of the Office’s caseload during the previous fiscal year that is attributable to any provision of law administered by or under the jurisdiction of each agency. The summary shall also include comparative data on caseload from prior fiscal years. Each agency to which this chapter applies shall provide a written response to the summary to the Mayor, the Council, and the Office within 30 calendar days of issuance of the summary. The response shall state whether the agency knows or believes there is a reasonable possibility that such caseload will increase or decrease by more than 10% in the current or following fiscal year based on any planned or ongoing agency actions, or any other reason, and specifying the anticipated amount of the increase or decrease and the reasons therefor. For purposes of this subsection, the existence of a 10% or greater increase or decrease shall be measured pursuant to rules promulgated under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Prior to any agency promulgating a rule (other than an emergency rule) that will materially affect the number or types of cases heard by the Office, the agency director shall consult with the Chief Administrative Law Judge regarding fiscal and operational impact of the proposed rule, and shall submit to the Chief Administrative Law Judge a statement containing the agency’s projections regarding increases in case volume and case complexity likely to follow promulgation of the rule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The director of any agency that becomes subject to this chapter shall direct that all employees of the agency provide the Office with any financial and programmatic information requested by the Office relating to any operational or personnel responsibilities of the Office, including, without limitation, any information the Chief Administrative Law Judge deems necessary in order to absorb the transfer of an agency’s adjudication function into the Office. The information shall be provided promptly and in no event later than the 15th day after the request is received. The Chief Financial Officer shall also issue the directive called for in this subsection with respect to the employees under his or her control.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_13_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No person outside the Office shall participate in or in any way influence or attempt to influence, except through the ordinary litigation process, the fair and independent decisionmaking process in an adjudicated case before the Office.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
