<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.09"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-1831.09/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_1831_09">
        <akn:num>2-1831.09</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Powers, duties, and liability of Administrative Law Judges.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An Administrative Law Judge shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any case in which he or she presides, an Administrative Law Judge may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any rule promulgated pursuant to subsection (b) (12) of this section shall include all protections provided by Rule 204 of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A person may not refuse or decline to comply with a lawful interlocutory order or lawful order issued by an Administrative Law Judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any other sanctions that an Administrative Law Judge may lawfully impose for the violation of any order or interlocutory order, an Administrative Law Judge, or a party in interest in an adjudicated case, may apply to any judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order issued on an expedited basis to show cause why a person should not be held in civil contempt for refusal to comply with an order or an interlocutory order issued by an Administrative Law Judge. On the return of an order to show cause, if the judge hearing the case determines that the person is guilty of refusal to comply with a lawful order or interlocutory order of the Administrative Law Judge without good cause, the judge may commit the offender to jail or may provide any other sanction authorized in cases of civil contempt. A party in interest may also bring an action for any other equitable or legal remedy authorized by law to compel compliance with the requirements of an order or interlocutory order of an Administrative Law Judge.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An Administrative Law Judge has no authority to commit any person to jail.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-1831_09_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An Administrative Law Judge shall be subject to suit, liability, discovery, and subpoena in a civil action relating to actions taken and decisions made in the performance of duties while in office on the same basis as a judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
