<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.39a"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.39a/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_218_39a">
        <akn:num>2-218.39a</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Certified joint venture.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A joint venture shall be eligible for certification as a certified joint venture if the joint venture intends to submit a response to solicitation in which the joint venture will provide goods or perform services, and has a member that owns a majority or minority interest in the joint venture and meets the definition of a certified business enterprise pursuant to § 2-218.02(1D). A joint venture shall be certified for a specific solicitation. The Department shall promulgate regulations that provide for a simplified procedure for the certification of a joint venture if the joint venture, having the same participants and structure, has been certified by the Department on a previous government-assisted project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall have the authority to certify a joint venture for all public, public-private, and private projects.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In determining whether a joint venture is eligible to be certified as a certified joint venture, the Department shall consider the totality of the circumstances, including the defined contributions and defined benefits provided by each member of the joint venture, which shall be demonstrated by the following information:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Decisions concerning the affairs of the business shall require the consent of those members with voting rights holding at least a majority interest in the business.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A joint venture shall relinquish its status as a certified joint venture if it has not been awarded the contract or if the solicitation has been withdrawn or cancelled.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Unless a joint venture’s certification is relinquished pursuant to subsection (e) of this section, a certified joint venture shall retain its certification for the duration of the contract awarded through the solicitation for which it was certified, including any extension of the contract.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A joint venture shall not be certified:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_39a_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A certified joint venture shall receive preference points or price reductions in accordance with § 2-218.43 as follows:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
