<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.53"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.53/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_218_53">
        <akn:num>2-218.53</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Agency reporting requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_53_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each agency shall submit a quarterly report to the Department and to the District of Columbia Auditor within 30 days after the end of each quarter, except for the 4th quarter report. The 4th quarter and annual report shall be submitted together. When submitting a quarterly report, the agency shall list each expenditure as it appears in the general ledger from the expendable budget of the agency during the quarter. For each expenditure, the report shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_53_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In addition to the report of prime contracting activity required by subsection (a) of this section, each agency shall also submit to the Department and the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor within 30 days of the end of each quarter, a report on a contract basis of payments made by beneficiaries to subcontractors that are certified business enterprises and such payments shall be reported against the amounts included in the approved detailed certified business enterprise subcontracting plan.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_53_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each agency shall submit to the Department and the District of Columbia Auditor, within 30 days of the issuance of the Comprehensive Annual Financial Report, an annual report listing each expenditure as it appears in the general ledger from the expendable budget of the agency during the fiscal year which shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_53_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall monitor agency compliance with the reporting requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_53_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Auditor shall review the annual report of each agency to determine whether the planned activities of the agency for the succeeding fiscal year are likely to enable the agency to achieve the goals set forth in § 2-218.41. The District of Columbia Auditor shall make recommendations on activities the agency should engage in to meet or exceed the goals set forth in § 2-218.41. The District of Columbia Auditor’s recommendations shall be submitted to the agency, the Council, and the Department.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_53_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Department shall review the annual report of an agency to determine whether the planned activities of the agency for the succeeding fiscal year are likely to enable the agency to achieve the goals set forth in § 2-218.41. The Department shall make recommendations on activities the agency should engage in to meet or exceed the goals set forth in § 2-218.41. The Department’s recommendations shall be submitted to the agency, the Office of District of Columbia Auditor, and the Council within 30 days of the agency’s annual report submission.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
