<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.46"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.46/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_218_46">
        <akn:num>2-218.46</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Performance and subcontracting requirements for construction and non-construction contracts; subcontracting plans.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each government-assisted construction and non-construction project for which a certified business enterprise is utilized to meet the subcontracting requirements pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this subsection shall include a requirement that the certified business enterprise perform at least 35% of the contracting effort with its own organization and resources.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each government-assisted construction and non-construction project of $1 million or less for which a certified business enterprise is selected as a beneficiary and is granted points or a price reduction pursuant to ยง 2-218.43 or is selected through a set-aside program under this subpart shall include a requirement that the certified business enterprise perform at least 50% of the on-site work with its own workforce.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, a design-build project shall not be required to identify specific subcontractors as a condition precedent to performing preconstruction services; provided, that a detailed subcontracting plan that meets the requirements of subsection (d) of this section shall be submitted before entering into a guaranteed maximum price or such other contractual action authorizing the contractor to commence construction.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No beneficiary shall be allowed to amend the subcontracting plan filed as part of its bid or proposal except with the consent of the Director. Any reduction in the dollar volume of the subcontracted portion resulting from such amendment of the plan shall inure to the benefit of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No multiyear contracts or extended contracts which are not in compliance with this subchapter at the time of the contemplated exercise of the option or extension, shall be renewed or extended, and any such option or extension shall be void.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The subcontracting requirements of this section may be waived pursuant to ยง 2-218.51.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A beneficiary shall submit to the agency contracting officer, project manager, District of Columbia Auditor, and Director copies of the executed contracts with the subcontracts identified in the subcontracting plan. Failure to submit copies of the executed contracts shall render the underlying contract voidable by the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_j">
      <akn:num>(j)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_k">
      <akn:num>(k)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The beneficiary shall provide written notice to the Department and District of Columbia Auditor upon the initiation and completion of a project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_l">
      <akn:num>(l)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a certified business enterprise or certified joint venture is the beneficiary and must meet the subcontracting requirements as set forth in this section, it shall fulfill the requirements of subsections (h), (i), (j), and (k) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_m">
      <akn:num>(m)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A beneficiary, certified business enterprise, or member of a certified joint venture that fails to meet the requirements of this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in ยง 2-218.63.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_46_n">
      <akn:num>(n)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>With regard to government-assisted projects, the obligations under this section shall expire upon completion of the development or other activity that serves as the basis for such activity qualifying as a government-assisted project; provided, that the Mayor shall have the authority to negotiate any extensions under this section in the transaction documents that qualify an activity as a government-assisted project.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
