<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.45"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-218.45/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_218_45">
        <akn:num>2-218.45</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Mandatory set-asides of contracts in the District of Columbia Supply Schedule for small business enterprises or certified business enterprises.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_45_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, each agency shall award contracts of $250,000 or less to a qualified small business enterprise included on the District of Columbia Supply Schedule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_45_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If an agency determines in writing that there are not at least 2 qualified small business enterprises on the District of Columbia Supply Schedule that can provide the services or goods that are the subject of the contract, the agency may use any qualified certified business enterprise to fulfill the requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_45_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An agency may decline to award a contract or procurement set aside under this section, and may thereafter issue the contract or procurement in the open market, if the agency determines in writing that the bids for the contract or procurement set aside for a small or certified business enterprise are believed to be 12% or more above the likely price on the open market.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-218_45_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each written determination pursuant to subsections (b) or (c) of this section shall be submitted to the Director, who shall post a copy of the determination so that it can reasonably be accessed by the public via the Department’s website or such other locations as the Department may establish.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
