<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-219.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-219.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_219_01">
        <akn:num>2-219.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Beneficiary” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employment agreement” means the contract referred to in paragraph (1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“All jobs” means any union and non-union managerial, nonmanagerial professional, nonprofessional, technical or nontechnical position including: clerical and sales occupations, service occupations, processing occupations, machine trade occupations, bench work occupations, structural work occupations, agricultural, fishery, forestry, and related occupations, and any other occupations as the Department of Employment Services may identify in the Dictionary of Occupational Titles, United States Department of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“First Source Register” means the Department of Employment Services Automated Applicant Files, which consists of the names of unemployed District residents registered with the Department of Employment Services.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Government-assisted project or contract” means any construction or non-construction project or contract receiving funds or resources from the District of Columbia, or funds or resources which, in accordance with a federal grant or otherwise, the District of Columbia government administers, including contracts, grants, loans, tax abatements or exemptions, land transfers, land disposition and development agreements, tax increment financing, or any combination thereof, that is valued at $300,000 or more.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Unemployed District resident” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Hard to employ” means a District resident who is confirmed by a District of Columbia government agency as:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Direct labor costs” means all costs, including wages and benefits, associated with the hiring and employment of personnel assigned to a process in which payroll expenses are traced to the units of output and are included in the cost of goods sold.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Indirect labor costs” means all costs, including wages and benefits, that are part of operating expenses and are associated with the hiring and employment of personnel assigned to tasks other than producing products.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-219_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Workforce Act” means the Workforce Intermediary Establishment and Reform of the First Source Amendment Act of 2011 [D.C. Law 19-84].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
