<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-223.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-223.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_223_01">
        <akn:num>2-223.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Contract” means any contract for goods or services between the District government and another entity but excludes any collective bargaining agreement.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Contributing factor” means any factor which, alone or in connection with other factors, tends to affect in any way the outcome of the decision.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Illegal order” means a directive to violate or to assist in violating a federal, state, or local law, rule, or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Instrumentality” means a quasi-governmental entity that operates in part with District funds, including, but not limited to, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, established by § 34-2202.02(a); the Health and Hospitals Public Benefits Corporation, established by Chapter 11 of Title 44; the Public Service Commission, established by § 34-801; the Washington Convention and Sports Authority established by § 10-1202.04; the Committee to Promote the District of Columbia; the National Capital Revitalization Corporation, established by § 2-1219.02 [repealed]; and the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, established by subchapter IV of Chapter 11 of Title 9.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prohibited personnel action” includes but is not limited to: recommended, threatened, or actual termination, demotion, suspension, or  reprimand; involuntary transfer, reassignment or detail; referral for psychiatric or psychological counseling; failure to hire or promote or take other favorable personnel action; or in any other manner retaliating against an employee because that employee has made a protected disclosure or refuses to comply with an illegal order, as those terms are defined in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_6A">
      <akn:num>(6A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Prohibited procurement action” includes any recommended, threatened, or actual proceeding, based wholly or in part on a protected disclosure made by an employee, officer, or owner of a contractor:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Protected disclosure” means any disclosure of information, not specifically prohibited by statute, by an employee to a supervisor or to a public body that the employee reasonably believes evidences:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Public body” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_8A">
      <akn:num>(8A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Security officer” means an individual appointed under § 5-129.02, and shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2100 of Title 17 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Supervisor” means any individual employed by a District instrumentality, a District government contractor, or a person who or entity that employs security officers who has authority to do the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-223_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Whistleblower” means an employee or contractor who makes or is perceived to have made a protected disclosure as that term is defined in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
