<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-273.06"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-273.06/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_273_06">
        <akn:num>2-273.06</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Public-private partnership agreements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>After selecting a solicited or unsolicited proposal for a public-private partnership project, the Office or a designated public entity shall enter into a public-private partnership agreement for a qualified project with the selected private entity or entities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A public-private partnership agreement approved and entered into by the Office or designated entity pursuant to this chapter shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Public-private partnership agreements approved and entered into by the Office or designated public entity may include review and approval by the Office or a designated public entity of the private entity&#x27;s plans for the development, operation, and maintenance of the public-private partnership project facilities.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No public-private partnership agreement shall contain any noncompete provisions limiting the ability of a public entity to perform its government functions.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office or a designated public entity shall have access and the right to inspect the public-private partnership project or facility at any time with reasonable notice.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office may apply for and accept funds from the District or federal government and other sources of financial aid to fund public-private partnership projects or otherwise further the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-273_06_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Office or designated public entity may enter into public-private partnership agreements with other local and state government agencies that are regional in scope as long as the regional scope is expressly stated in the request for proposals submitted to the Council pursuant to ยง 2-273.05.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
