<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-352.02"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-352.02/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_352_02">
        <akn:num>2-352.02</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Criteria for Council review of multiyear contracts and contracts in excess of $1 million.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Pursuant to ยง 1-204.51, prior to the award of a multiyear contract or a contract in excess of $1 million during a 12-month period, the Mayor or executive independent agency or instrumentality shall submit the proposed contract to the Council for review and approval in accordance with the criteria established in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Proposed contracts submitted pursuant to this section may be submitted electronically and shall contain a summary, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No proposed multiyear contract and no proposed contract in excess of $1 million for a 12-month period shall be awarded until after the Council has reviewed and approved the proposed contract as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, review and approval by the Council of a definitive contract in excess of $1 million during a 12-month period shall constitute the Council review and approval, required by ยง 1-204.51(b), of the definitive contract and the merged letter contract contained therein.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any employee or agency head who shall knowingly or willfully enter into a proposed multiyear contract or a proposed contract in excess of $1 million without prior Council review and approval in accordance with this section shall be subject to suspension, dismissal, or other disciplinary action under the procedures set forth in subchapter XVI-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1 [ยง 1-616.51 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_02_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Review and approval by the Council of the annual capital program of federal highway aid projects shall constitute the Council review and approval required by ยง 1-204.51(d)(3) of individual federal-aid highway contracts that make up the annual program.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
