<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-352.05"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-352.05/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_352_05">
        <akn:num>2-352.05</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Privatization contracts and procedures requirements.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_05_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before issuing a solicitation for a privatization contract pursuant to this section, the District government agency on whose behalf the solicitation will be issued shall prepare an estimate of the fully allocated cost associated with providing the relevant goods or services using District government employees. The agency shall transmit this estimate to the contract specialist responsible for the solicitation, who shall retain the estimate as part of the official contract file.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_05_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A solicitation for a proposed privatization contract issued pursuant to this section shall include information describing how current District government employees may exercise the right to bid on the contracts.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_05_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Before awarding a privatization contract, and prior to modifying a contract, the Mayor, instrumentality, or independent agency head shall transmit to the Council a determination and findings that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_05_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A privatization contract, or any contracting policies and procedures relating to these contracts, to provide goods and services to or on behalf of the District government, including a contract resulting from a process of managed competition, shall provide that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_05_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If a privatization contract is awarded, the Mayor, instrumentality, or the independent agency head shall make efforts to assist affected District government employees and to promote employment opportunities for District residents with the contractor. These efforts shall include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-352_05_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An agency shall not attempt to circumvent the requirements of this section by eliminating the provision of goods or services by the agency before procuring substantially the same goods or services from a person who is not part of the District government.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
