<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-354.03"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-354.03/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_354_03">
        <akn:num>2-354.03</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Competitive sealed proposals.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A contract may be entered into by competitive sealed proposal when the use of competitive sealed bidding is not practicable or not advantageous to the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Proposals shall be solicited from the maximum number of qualified sources and in a manner consistent with the nature of, and the need for, the goods, services, or construction being acquired.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Proposals shall be solicited through a request for proposals. The CPO shall provide public notice of the RFP of not less than 21 days, unless the CPO issues a determination and findings that it is appropriate to shorten the notice period to a period of not less than 14 days. In making the determination and findings, the CPO shall consider factors including the complexity of the procurement, the type of goods or services being purchased, and the impact of a shortened notice period on competition.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_d_1">
      <akn:num>(d-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>An RFP for the construction of a road, bridge, other transportation system, or a facility or structure appurtenant to a road, bridge, or other transportation system, may allow prospective offerors or contractors to submit alternative technical concepts as a part of their proposals. The agency’s determination on the alternative technical concepts may be considered by the contracting officer as part of the evaluation and ranking of proposals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The contract shall be awarded by written notice to the responsive and responsible bidder whose bid will be most advantageous to the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Upon receiving the responses to an RFP, the contracting officer shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-354_03_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
