<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-381.01"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-381.01/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_381_01">
        <akn:num>2-381.01</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Claim” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Custodian” means the custodian, or any deputy custodian, designated by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia pursuant to § 2-381.07(j)(1).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Documentary material” includes the original or any copy of any book, record, report, memorandum, paper, communication, tabulation, chart, or other document, or data compilations stored in or accessible through computer or other information retrieval systems, together with instructions and all other materials necessary to use or interpret such data compilations, and any product of discovery.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“False claims law” means this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“False claims law investigation” means any inquiry conducted by any false claims law investigator for the purpose of ascertaining whether any person is or has been engaged in any violation of a false claims law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“False claims law investigator” means any attorney or investigator employed by the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia who is charged with the duty of enforcing or carrying into effect any false claims law, or any officer or employee of the District government acting under the direction and supervision of such attorney or investigator in connection with a false claims law investigation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Knowing” or “knowingly” means:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Material” means having a natural tendency to influence, or be capable of influencing, the payment or receipt of money or property.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Obligation” means an established duty, whether or not fixed, arising from an express or implied contractual, grantor-grantee, or licensor-licensee relationship, from a fee- based or similar relationship, from statute or regulation, or from the retention of any overpayment.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Original source” means an individual who:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Person” includes any natural person, corporation, firm, association, organization, partnership, business, or trust.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-381_01_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Proceeds” means civil penalties as well as double or treble damages as provided in § 2-381.02, and criminal fines as provided in § 2-381.09.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
