<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-411"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-411/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_411">
        <akn:num>2-411</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia, or his designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Court” means the court in the District of Columbia having the necessary civil jurisdiction pursuant to § 11-501 or § 11-921.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“District” means the government of the District of Columbia, a municipal corporation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emergency run” means the movement of a District-owned vehicle, by direction of the operator or of some other authorized person or agency, under circumstances which lead the operator or such persons or agency to believe that such vehicle should proceed expeditiously upon a particular mission or to a designated location for the purpose of dealing with a supposed fire or other emergency, an alleged violation of a statute or regulation, or other incident requiring emergency action, or the prompt transportation to a place of treatment or greater safety of an alleged sick or injured person.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Emergency vehicle” means a vehicle assigned:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Employee” means a person serving as an officer or employee of the District, whether or not paid by the District, or a person formerly so engaged, or the representative of a deceased officer or employee of the District.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Vehicle” means every type of conveyance or machine capable of movement on land, or in water or air, including an animal being ridden and any animal-drawn machinery or conveyance.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-411_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>“Medical employees of the District of Columbia” shall include physicians, psychologists, dentists, optometrists, podiatrists, nurses, nursing assistants, emergency medical technician, emergency medical technician/intermediate paramedic, emergency medical technician/paramedic, physicians’ assistants, laboratory technicians, physical therapists, osteopaths, chiropodists and chiropractors in the employment of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
