<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-502"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-502/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_502">
        <akn:num>2-502</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “agency” includes both subordinate agency and independent agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “subordinate agency” means any officer, employee, office, department, division, board, commission, or other agency of the government of the District, other than an independent agency or the Mayor or the Council, required by law or by the Mayor or the Council to administer any law or any rule adopted under the authority of a law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “independent agency” means any agency of the government of the District with respect to which the Mayor and the Council are not authorized by law, other than this subchapter, to establish administrative procedures, but does not include the several courts of the District and the Tax Division of the Superior Court.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “rulemaking” means Mayor’s or agency’s process for the formulation, amendment, or repeal of a rule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “contested case” means a proceeding before the Mayor or any agency in which the legal rights, duties, or privileges of specific parties are required by any law (other than this subchapter), or by constitutional right, to be determined after a hearing before the Mayor or before an agency, but shall not include:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “person” includes individuals, partnerships, corporations, associations, and public or private organizations of any character other than the Mayor, the Council, or an agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “party” includes the Mayor and any person or agency named or admitted as a party, or properly seeking and entitled as of right to be admitted as a party, in any proceeding before the Mayor or an agency, but nothing herein shall be construed to prevent the Mayor or an agency from admitting the Mayor or any person or agency as a party for limited purposes.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “order” means the whole or any part of the final disposition (whether affirmative, negative, injunctive, or declaratory in form) of the Mayor or of any agency in any matter other than rulemaking, but including licensing.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “license” includes the whole or part of any permit, certificate, approval, registration, charter, membership, statutory exemption, or other form of permission granted by the Mayor or any agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_13">
      <akn:num>(13)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “licensing” includes process respecting the grant, renewal, denial, revocation, suspension, annulment, withdrawal, limitation, amendment, modification, or conditioning of a license by the Mayor or an agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_14">
      <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “relief ” includes the whole or part of any Mayor’s or agency’s:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_15">
      <akn:num>(15)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “proceeding” means any process of the Mayor or an agency as defined in paragraphs (6), (11), and (12) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_16">
      <akn:num>(16)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “sanction” includes the whole or part of any Mayor’s or agency’s:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_17">
      <akn:num>(17)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “regulation” means the whole or any part of any District of Columbia Council statement of general or particular applicability and future effect designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy or to describe the organization, procedure, or practice requirements of the Mayor, District of Columbia Council, or any agency.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_18">
      <akn:num>(18)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “public record” includes all books, papers, maps, photographs, cards, tapes, recordings, vote data (including ballot-definition material, raw data, and ballot images), or other documentary materials, regardless of physical form or characteristics prepared, owned, used, in the possession of, or retained by a public body. Public records include information stored in an electronic format.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_18A">
      <akn:num>(18A)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “public body” means the Mayor, an agency, or the Council of the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_19">
      <akn:num>(19)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “adjudication” means the agency process, other than rulemaking, for the formulation, issuance, and enforcement of an order.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-502_20">
      <akn:num>(20)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “publish” means, for the official publications described in § 2-504, to issue, in print or electronic format, textual or graphic material for sale or distribution to the public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
