<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-534"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-534/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_534">
        <akn:num>2-534</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Exemptions from disclosure.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-534_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The following matters may be exempt from disclosure under the provisions of this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-534_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-534_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any reasonably segregable portion of a public record shall be provided to any person requesting the record after deletion of those portions which may be withheld from disclosure pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. In each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing, and the extent of the deletion shall be indicated on the portion of the record which is made available or published, unless including that indication would harm an interest protected by the exemption in subsection (a) of this section under which the deletion is made. If technically feasible, the extent of the deletion and the specific exemptions shall be indicated at the place in the record where the deletion was made.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-534_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>This section does not authorize withholding of information or limit the availability of records to the public, except as specifically stated in this section. This section is not authority to withhold information from the Council of the District of Columbia. This section shall not operate to permit nondisclosure of information of which disclosure is authorized or mandated by other law.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-534_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this subchapter shall not apply to the Vital Records Act of 1981.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-534_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All exemptions available under this section shall apply to the Council as well as agencies of the District government. The deliberative process privilege, the attorney work-product privilege, and the attorney-client privilege are incorporated under the inter-agency memoranda exemption listed in subsection (a)(4) of this section, and these privileges, among other privileges that may be found by the court, shall extend to any public body that is subject to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
