<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-532"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-532/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_532">
        <akn:num>2-532</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Right of access to public records; allowable costs; time limits.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any person has a right to inspect, and at his or her discretion, to copy any public record of a public body, except as otherwise expressly provided by § 2-534, in accordance with reasonable rules that shall be issued by a public body after notice and comment, concerning the time and place of access.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_a_1">
      <akn:num>(a-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In making any record available to a person pursuant to this section, a public body shall provide the record in any form or format requested by the person, provided that the person shall pay the costs of reproducing the record in that form or format.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_a_2">
      <akn:num>(a-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In responding to a request for records pursuant to this section, a public body shall make reasonable efforts to search for the records in electronic form or format, except when the efforts would significantly interfere with the operation of the public body’s automated information system.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_a_3">
      <akn:num>(a-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A public body shall make available for inspection and copying any record produced or collected pursuant to a contract with a private contractor to perform a public function, and the public body with programmatic responsibility for the contractor shall be responsible for making such records available to the same extent as if the record were maintained by the public body.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A public body may establish and collect fees not to exceed the actual cost of searching for, reviewing, redacting, and making copies of records. Documents may be furnished without charge or at a reduced charge where a public body determines that waiver or reduction of the fee is in the public interest because furnishing the information can be considered as primarily benefiting the general public.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_b_1">
      <akn:num>(b-1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any fee schedules adopted by the Mayor, an agency or a public body shall provide that:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_b_2">
      <akn:num>(b-2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Review costs shall include only the direct costs incurred during the initial examination of a document to determine whether the documents must be disclosed or withheld in part as exempt under this section. Review costs may not include costs incurred to determine issues of law or policy related to the request.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_b_3">
      <akn:num>(b-3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>No agency or public body may require advance payment of any fee unless the requester has previously failed to pay fees in a timely fashion, or the agency or public body has determined that the fee will exceed $250.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p></akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Any failure on the part of a public body to comply with a request under subsection (a) of this section within the time provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall be deemed a denial of the request, and the person making such request shall be deemed to have exhausted his administrative remedies with respect to such request, unless such person chooses to petition the Mayor pursuant to § 2-537 to review the deemed denial of the request.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-532_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, the term:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
