<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-553"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-553/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_553">
        <akn:num>2-553</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>District of Columbia Register.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Office of Documents shall also supervise, manage, and direct the preparation, editing, and publishing of the District of Columbia Register which shall serve as the only official legal bulletin in the District of Columbia government and the temporary supplement of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Register shall contain the entire text of the following:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Administrator is authorized to publish in the District of Columbia Register:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Administrator may exercise the discretion of omitting from the District of Columbia Register the publication of the entire text of a document if:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the text of an adopted act or rule is the same as the text of the previously published proposed act or rule, the Administrator may insert in the District of Columbia Register a notation to this effect, giving the publication date of and citation to the District of Columbia Register issue containing the proposed act or rule.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If, after a proposed rule has been published initially in the District of Columbia Register, an agency decides to alter the initial text so that the proposed rule is substantially different from the initial text, the agency shall submit the altered text as though for initial publication. The alterations shall be indicated by the use of symbols determined by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The District of Columbia Register shall be published on at least each Friday, or, if Friday is a legal holiday, on the next working day. Each year the Administrator shall publish a cumulative index of all matters published in the District of Columbia Register during the year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_h">
      <akn:num>(h)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Each issue of the District of Columbia Register shall be published on the issue date, which shall appear on the 1st page of the issue. If for any reason the issue is published after the issue date that appears on the District of Columbia Register, a notice stating the actual date of publication shall be separately published and attached to each issue. All time computations based upon publication in the District of Columbia Register shall commence from the later of the issue date and the actual date of publication.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-553_i">
      <akn:num>(i)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>All documents published in the District of Columbia Register shall be formulated in accordance with the requirements of ยง 2-632.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
