<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-579"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-579/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_579">
        <akn:num>2-579</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Enforcement; authority.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_a">
      <akn:num>(a)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The Open Government Office may bring a lawsuit in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for injunctive or declaratory relief for any violation of this subchapter before or after the meeting in question takes place; provided, that the Council shall adopt its own rules for enforcement related to Council meetings. Nothing in this subchapter shall:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_b">
      <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>In any lawsuit filed under this section, the burden shall be on the public body to sustain its action or proposed action. The court shall determine the matter de novo and may examine the record of a closed meeting to determine whether this section has been violated.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_c">
      <akn:num>(c)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the court finds that a public body plans to hold a closed meeting or portion of a meeting in violation of subsection (d) of this section, the court may:</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_d">
      <akn:num>(d)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the court finds that a resolution, rule, act, regulation, or other official action was taken, made, or enacted in violation of this subchapter, the court may order an appropriate remedy, including requiring additional forms of notice, postponing a meeting, or declaring action taken at a meeting to be void. Actions shall not be declared void unless the court finds that the balance of equities compels the action or the court concludes that the violation was not harmless.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_e">
      <akn:num>(e)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>If the court finds that a member of a public body engages in a pattern or practice of willfully participating in one or more closed meetings in violation of the provisions of this subchapter, the court may impose a civil fine of not more than $250 for each violation.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_f">
      <akn:num>(f)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The court may grant such additional relief as it finds necessary to serve the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-579_g">
      <akn:num>(g)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>A public body may seek an advisory opinion from the Open Government Office regarding compliance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
