<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="dc-code">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-601"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#dc-council"/>
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-dc"/>
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-dc/code/2-601/eng@2025"/>
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31"/>
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en"/>
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
      </akn:identification>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_2_601">
        <akn:num>2-601</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading>
<akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_1">
      <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “act” shall have the same meaning as is ascribed to it in § 1-201.03(7).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_2">
      <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “agency” means any officer, employee, office, department, division, board, commission, or other agency of the government of the District of Columbia including both those which are independent of and those which are subordinate to the Mayor and Council but not including the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_3">
      <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Board of Commissioners” means the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia established by Act of June 11, 1878 (20 Stat. 102).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_4">
      <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the District of Columbia established by subsection (a) of § 301 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (81 Stat. 949).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_5">
      <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia created by § 1-204.01(a) unless the phrase “District of Columbia Council” is used in which event the term shall mean the District of Columbia Council created by subsection (a) of § 201 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (81 Stat. 948).</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_6">
      <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Council year” means the legislative period of the Council beginning on January 2nd of each year and ending on January 1st of the following year.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_7">
      <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_8">
      <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “District of Columbia Register” means the District of Columbia Register mandated by § 2-504.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_9">
      <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia created by § 1-204.21(a) or his or her designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_10">
      <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “rule” means the whole or any part of any Board of Commissioners’, Commissioner’s, District of Columbia Council’s, Mayor’s, or agency’s statement of general or particular applicability and future effect designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy or designed to describe organization, procedure, or practice requirements.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_11">
      <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “regulation” shall have the same meaning as the term “rule.”</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2-601_12">
      <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
      <akn:content><akn:p>The term “resolution” means a resolution of the Council unless the term “Congressional resolution” is used in which case it shall mean a resolution of the Congress of the United States or either House thereof.</akn:p></akn:content>
    </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
